Brother Man, we're here
I'm sorry to be such a bother
Don't mention it
This place has been idle for a few months.
I've informed the owners, they are nice folks
Thank you
Is this suitable for your school?
Wow, this place is huge!
Is this ok?
Yes, yes
Very spacious...
Master Yip
You haven't gotten any disciples yet?
What's up, 3rd Aunt?
You have such a big place here.
I'd like to hang my laundry here
Sure, no problem
Yong
Sigh, I told you before... let me do this
I don't know what to do with you
There'll be no more water left by the time you come
Then I'll come back earlier
next time. Let me do these chores
I've told you not to exert yourself
How are you feeling?
Mama, I need to pay school fees
Ok, hang on
Who's that?
Pay your rent! Mr and Mrs Yip!
Don't open the door. We don't have enough money for rent
Mr and Mrs Yip! Pay your rent
Master Yip, still no students?
I'll go hang my laundry...
Let me help you...
Thank you very much!
Hey, are you the one teaching Wing Chun?
Master Yip! Someone's here to learn kung fu!
You wish to learn Wing Chun?
I don't even know what Wing Chun is
Then let me tell you. Wing Chun is the Southern art of close combat....
Enough! Spar with me. If I lose, I'll be your student
Fine
Wing Chun. Yip Man
So, what do you think?
You haven't won yet
Do you yield?
Yield? I don't even know what you're doing
Do you know now?
Master Yip, I didn't know
you're so skilful! Fantastic!
Hey, young man! You should be his disciple!
I think you can start paying tuition fees now
Hey! How can you leave like that?
Master Yip, what now? Your potential student is gone
That's him
How good can his kung fu be?
Would I lie to you?
He looks like he couldn't even hurt a fly
If you hadn't told me, I'd have
thought he's just a laundryman
You're not really here to learn kung fu. Please leave
Ok, then we'll fight you
No need to take them off
Why not?
Oh, nevermind
The Yip Man Palm
Told you not to take off your shirts...
Master! I am Huang Liang, please take me as a disciple!
- Master, I am Xiu Shi Chang!
- Wei Guo Jian
- Wang Kun
Please accept us as students!
Eh, I asked first. You must address
me as "Eldest Brother"
Serve tea to Master!
No need to trouble yourselves
Pay tuition fees first
In Wing Chun, we attack and defend in one motion
Attack, and defend
To disable an opponent in the shortest time
This is block and attack
Block and attack
Follow up with a dozen quick punches
Understand?
(Blank looks)
Who is Master Yip?
Master!
Liang, did you ask them to come?
Master, do you think you can fight off 10 men?
The best thing is not to fight at all
Continue training
What if they use weapons?
Run
Time to collect tuition fees
Ok
You always say that
I will collect soon
Hang on a sec
What's up?
It's time to pay tuition fees
What's happening?
Time to pay tuition fees
If you have the money, please pay up
Here you go Master
Master, I can only pay $2... My mother...
she needs the money. I'll pay the rest later
Pay next time... next time
Go home for dinner
Bye Master
It's so little... what shall we do?
No choice. You also know things aren't so good now
The students asked for help, I can't refuse
Then we need to appeal to the landlady
Yes, things will work out eventually
2 pieces of cake please
- You want the egg tarts?
- No, thanks
Stop! Hold it right there!
Thief! Return it to me!
Please don't beat up my dad
No money? Then we'll get him
Please let him go!
Stop, stop! Don't beat him up
What's happening?
He stole our roasted duck
I'll pay for him
Give it here!
Let's go
Jin Quan?
Uncle Man, I know where Dad is
Bring me to him
Here
Jin Quan!
Uncle Man, he doesn't recognise anyone
The Japanese shot him in the head once. He doesn't recognise anyone anymore
Jin Quan, I'm Yip
Jin Quan!
Get away! Get out! Go! Go!
Let's go, Uncle Man
It's my fault. I did this to you
Let's go
My dad hasn't chased me away yet
That's why I'm still here
On good days I can get odd jobs and buy food back
On bad days, we starve
Don't worry, Kwan
I'll help you take care of him
Since you are recommended by
Master Yip, I'll definitely hire you
Kid, if you agree to half salary, you can start now
No problem
Have a seat. I'll arrange work for you
Brother Man, don't leave. I'll treat you to tea
Thank you
Don't mention it
Have a seat
This is good
Thank you Uncle Man
Kwan, you must work hard
I will
What do you think? I can bring you there later
I'm from Hong School. I don't need to learn from you!
Since you aren't interested, why tear my posters down?
I don't care what you learn. You're blocking my poster
Want to know what Wing Chun is?
You're looking for trouble?
We won't bully you
One on one. No helping!
Ok
Also, don't poke eyes
Enough talk. I'm in a hurry
So you yield?
No!
No?
Do you yield?
When you strike, don't move from this line
Relax
Relax more
Who is Yip Man?
Yes?
Your disciple Liang has beaten up our brother
We took him hostage. Bring money to rescue him at the fish market
Let's go
Brother Jin
Are you his Master?
That's right
I believe it's just a misunderstanding
Let's talk it over
Can you release my disciple?
Release him!
Are you all right?
I'm fine
Why did you beat him up?
We sparred and he lost. It's not my fault
What? I can't beat you?
Don't be rash
You're all young men
Sometimes you get minor injuries during sparring
Next time I'll come specially to
clarify things with your Master
May I know who your Master is?
You don't need to know who he is.
He's better than you
Enough talk. Did you bring the money?
No
Don't be rash
Attack!
Behind you!
Chop him up!
Master!
Liang!
Master! I'm here
Master, you really can beat up more than 10 men!
Only if we can escape
Stay close to me
Follow me!
Go, Liang
Go!
Jin Shan Zhao?
Nobody move!
What are you doing?
Master Yip, you are free to go
Thanks
You're asking for it!
Break it up!
Master!
You stirring up trouble again?
No, Master
I was sparring with him, but he brought
his Master here to intimidate us
Ji
You trying to be Big Brother here?
No of course not
Big Brother Hong, let's talk things over
You want to talk with a knife in your hand?
No, no
That son of a bitch tried to cause
trouble on my turf. That's why I was....
This isn't your turf
This is my road. Your patch of ground is mine.
So you tell me, whose turf is this?
It's yours, of course
You can leave now. It's not your concern
Which style and school are you?
Greetings Master Hong. I'm Yip Man
of the Wing Chun sect from Fo Shan
The situation is like this. My disciple sparred with yours
My disciple definitely went too far and injured your disciple
You're saying my Hong style is inferior?
I didn't mean it like that
Who allowed you to teach martial arts? Do you know the rules?
I don't know of any rules
Ok I'll tell you the rules now
You must accept challenges from the various schools
If you win, then you are fit to teach martial arts
So now you know the rules for opening a martial arts school
Enough talk. There are rules for martial
arts schools, and then there are rules of Law
Now that you're done
Wan, Po! Take these 2 into custody
I have a spare set of handcuffs. Arrest him too
Huh? Me too?
Master!
Stop squirming! Let's go
Move it
Settle your affairs, and let's go in. The Chief is waiting
Sir
The Chief is asking about the manpower and security arrangements
Everything is arranged. No problems
So how much will I get for the competition?
Please excuse us a moment
Don't worry, I'll take care of it
So how much is his cut? You
tell me, I'll tell Master Hong
Speak!
Are you going to tell me?
Don't worry. These cops are just strutting around acting tough
It'll be ok once we make bail
Master Jin, I'm sorry to get you involved
I'm sorry to get you involved today
Hang on a bit
I'm deaf in this ear after you wacked me there the other time
So what were you saying?
I said, I'm sorry to get you involved today
It's nothing
If it weren't for your wake up call the other time
I don't know what I'll do here in Hong Kong
Open up, Police!
Open up!
What's wrong?
Any of Yip Man's relatives here?
I'm his wife
Your husband is arrested for fighting
Bring money to bail him out
Mr Liang! Mr Liang!
Mr Liang!
What's wrong, Mrs Yip?
Please save my husband! I don't
have enough money for bail
Wait here
It's very troublesome to open
a martial arts school here in Hong Kong
There's too many schools, too many masters
Too many rules too
And that Master Hong has many supporters
Many disciples, and a lot of money
So what? I'll get him once I'm out of here
I'll destroy his fish stall and poison all his fish!
What's the difference between you and them, then?
Hey kid, you fight pretty good
I'm not a kid!
Which part of me looks like a kid?
Liang! Don't use that tone
Master Jin is your elder
It's all right, he's young
He reminds me of myself when I was young
If you want him to turn out well, get him a wife
Just like me... wife, kids, family. It changes a man
I want to post bail for my husband
What's his name?
Yip Man
Did you bring the money?
Yes, here
Yip Man, you're free to go
Hurry up
I'm here to bail Jin out
Wife!
Brother, please open the door
Quickly!
That's my wife
Liang, is anyone coming for you?
No
Don't worry Master. They'll release
me in a couple of days
You go on
I won't be able to see you out
Brother Geng, I need to impose on you again
I want to bail my disciple out
Is it ok?
Brother Man, I didn't bring enough money
Master Yip
Master Yip, wait a bit
Wife, do you have any money?
What do you need it for?
It's an emergency
You're always like this. No money!
Help people out here, Wife
This is the last time
Mum's the best!
Master Yip, here's the money
I'll return it to you as soon as I can. Thank you
No problem, don't mention it
It's so difficult to open a school here.
Why don't you just give up?
I'll just have to go visit the other masters. It's nothing
I don't want to worry every day like before
We made it through the war,
there's nothing to worry about
Don't dwell on it. Go to sleep
I've fought this type of matches many times before
They were blades below then, not stools
Have you heard of this Yip Man before?
The name means nothing to me. No
I'm sure he's no match for you, Master Luo
Likewise, Master Zhang
Will you be going up there?
I'll go if you go
Enough talk. Let's drink tea
Cheers
Master
He's here
Fellow Masters
This is Yip Man
He wants to establish his sect here in Hong Kong
That's why he's here today to accept your challenges
Yip Man
If you surrender, you lose
If you leave the table, you lose
If you're the last man standing on
the table after all the challenges
I'll greet you as "Master Yip"
If there are no questions, we can begin
What, he's just going to walk up to the table?
He's not supposed to touch the ground
Greetings fellow masters. I am Yip Man
I'm from Wing Chun sect from Fo Shan
I hope my fellow masters will
go easy on me
Which master will have a go?
Master Luo, aren't you going?
I'll wait and see if anyone else is going first
Fine then, I'll be the first
Please
Lightning Kick
Beware, brother
Are you all right Master Luo?
I'm fine!
He'd be dead if it were blades below
This is too much
The table is really slippery!
Thank you for going easy
Come on, don't let him stop
Master Zhang, your turn
Master Zhang, go on... go on
Master Zhang, the table is really very slippery
Please
I yield!
Thank you for showing mercy
Thank you for going easy on me
Any other masters want to have a go?
Please
Master Yip
Master Hong
To join this association, you must pay a monthly fee
What fees?
It's the rules. Everyone pays $100 a month
Pay and you'll have no trouble
If there's any masters that still think
I'm not worthy, I'm game anytime
But I won't fulfil your personal financial
interests by paying this "fee"
As you wish. Don't look for me
if you're in trouble next time
You may go now
Medication
Master, here's the medication
Are you insane? Drawing these on my newspaper?
I just wanted readers to understand the content
Is the feedback that bad?
Everyone in Hong Kong now wants to learn Wing Chun!
This is fantastic!
Continue the drawings. I'm counting on you
Get back to work!
Well done! Good job!
(Wing Chun fights Hong Style to a stalemate)
Mei, stop doing your homework. Eat
Eat first, ok?
Wife, more porridge please
You've not been eating well lately. Eat more
Where are you going?
You blind? I'm going up to do my laundry
Are you really just doing your laundry?
What do you think this big basin
is for? Washing my head?
151.... 152...
Where are you headed?
To learn Wing Chun
Wing Chun? It's not here
The newspapers say it's here
No it's not. Go away!
You're better off learning Hong style
Hey!
You bunch of rascals are preventing
people from learning Wing Chun!
You son of a bitch!
Come down!
What are you doing?
You deaf?
Come down!
What? No, you come up
Come down if you have the guts
Come down if you dare!
You're crazy! So unbecoming!
Look, Wing Chun disciples!
Attack!
They're coming down
Hurry
Come out!
The owners are thinking twice after what happened today
I understand
They've decided not to lend this rooftop to you anymore
I understand. I'm sorry
I'm sorry too. I'll be going now
Goodbye
Bye, Brother Geng
Master...
I'm sure you know by now
We can't train here anymore
Master, it's not our fault! They started it!
Yes they started it
Let's go look for them to settle this
Pack this place up before you go
Bring the wooden men to my house
Master...
Ji
Give these to the disciples. They've earned it
Thank you Master
- Here's yours.
- Thanks
Good work everyone
You still dare to show up here?
I'm here to see your Master
Ji... you may all retire
So, your school in a bit of a jam?
I'm here to tell you that I'll continue
teaching martial arts even without a school
And I'll never pay you a single cent!
Don't ever harass my disciples again
And don't get other people involved
You are causing trouble by not following the rules
If it weren't for me placating the Westerners
Do you think everyone else can teach martial arts in peace?
You chose to collude with the Westerners
Yip Man, you only think about yourself
You don't have 200 disciples, of course you
don't need the blessings of the Westerners
Of course you can take it easy
I understand what you're saying
As Masters, aren't we are obligated to guide our own disciples first?
My conscience is clear
As you wish. If you're upset with
me in the future, come directly to me
Goodbye!
Hold it!
You're not leaving that easily
What do you want then?
We did not finish our match earlier.
It's time to finish it
Watch out!
Husband, we've been waiting
for you to start dinner
The children are hungry. Are you finished
discussing business?
Master Hong, do you think it's more important to
have dinner with your family, or to finish the match?
What does everyone want to eat?
Ice cream!!
I'll bring you all out for ice cream after dinner
I'll take my leave, Master Hong
Please see yourself out
Master
Come in
Put it over there
Here, over here
Why are the wooden men brought back home?
The rooftop is being rented
to someone else
So I've brought them home
Ok, you go on home. We'll start
training here tomorrow morning
- Train here?
- Yes
Be here early tomorrow morning
Bye Master
Go home and relax
Goodbye Master
Master, I wish to talk to you
Have some tea, Liang
Have a seat
Master, it's my fault that
you lost the school. I'm sorry
Please, get up
Get up
Come, sit down and we'll talk
Liang, do you think I'm very skilful?
Of course! You can fight off 10 men!
What about 20 years later?
In 20 year's time, you can beat me easily
People will grow old
No one's invincible forever in this world
Actually, you have a knack for martial arts
However, you're only focusing on the fighting techniques
I want to you to understand the spirit in Chinese martial arts
It enbodies the Chinese heart, mind and soul
Understand?
I'm trying to
Want to hear a story?
Years ago, I smacked the butt of that Master Jin we met in jail
Back at Fo Shan, he came to my house
to fight me and messed my place up, so.....
Are you practicing kung fu?
Yes, I'll teach you when you grow up
Come on let's go
Master, look
Continue your practice
Fancy meeting you here
I was in the neighbourhood
What do you want?
I have extra tickets, and wondered
if you'd like to come too
It's a Western boxing match
Goodbye
Master Hong, your eyes are red
Are you all right?
Oh I've had it since morning. I'm
probably coming down with something
I'll be fine after some herbal tea
This is a nice place for training
Place 3 rows here
3 rows over there too
Hurry up
Master Hong
Come over and say hi. I'll
introduce you to the Champion
Hello
Ignore him. Westerners like to leave things around
So when will we get our money?
He keeps avoiding the subject
Do it for free this time
Free? My men stopped working at
the fish stall to set this place up!
Don't be upset, or else there'll be
trouble. Take it as going on a diet
This isn't the first time
Master Hong!
Chief
It's ok not to pay me. However my men
need to eat. You have to pay them
Don't speak to me about money now
If not money, then love?
Now you've made him angry
If he's not paying, I'm quitting
If you quit, he'll take your
fish stall too. Just bear with it
Bear with it? I've tolerated it for a long time!
Speak Chinese, not English!
You heard him. Let's go
We quit too! Let's go
Let's go
Hold on!
Look, they'll get in trouble because of you
You guys stay and work
Let's get back to work
Come on
Don't be angry. He will get his retribution
- Master Yip
- Master Hong
Thank you for the tickets
There will be a demonstration of kung fu
from every school on stage later
Please ask your disciples to show yours off
Let more people learn about your Wing Chun
Yes of course
See you later
Hey you, get ready
- You 2 go up too
- Ok
Go up and join them
Let's go
This isn't good
It's not your money that is used to
promote Chinese martial arts
Stop fighting!
Break it up! Stop fighting!
What do we do?
Everyone, stop fighting!
Stop fighting!
Break it up!
Stop!
Stop fighting!
Stop it!
Calm down!
Stop fighting!
Everyone please calm down
Liang!
Bring him down
Xin, help please
Slowly! Slowly!
Come here, MC
If you don't like our demonstration,
you are free to leave
But you've caused injuries,
you need to apologise
I will fight!
I will flatten him to the ground!
Until he apologises!
Kill the Westerner!
Fellow masters, leave this to me
Everyone please stand down
Fine, we'll stand down
Thank you
Master Hong, are you good?
I'm good, no problem
In the next round, don't go head on
with him. Attack his biceps
It won't be that easy
Oh no! Master's having an asthma attack
Please stop the fight, Master Hong
I won't let these Westerners belittle us
Don't get maimed just for pride
I can tolerate if it's only my life
But not if it's the entire Chinese martial arts world
Master...
Master, yield!
Master!
Master Hong, I have the utmost respect for you
(Master Hong of Hong style school killed in a Western boxing match)
- What's happening?
- Sit down!
None of your business. Sit down
Who's the editor?
What's up?
Arrest him
Sir!
Please don't!
No, please!
No!
Sir!
It won't look good for you. He'll continue
to give you bad press if you continue the beatings
I will deal with him. Leave it to me
Fat Aunt, you must set him straight
How can he say such things?
The Chinese don't use joss sticks just to mark time
The Chinese practice of burning joss sticks
Other than measuring time, and more
importantly, it is to honour our ancestors
It's the Chinese culture
Mr Milos
I challenge you
Chun, eat quickly. Don't let Mrs Fang wait
I'll see you off later
Mama, why must we stay over at Mrs Fang's?
Because Daddy wants to train
Here, let me
- Sorry for the trouble
- It's no trouble
The boy is Yip Chun
Mr Yip, you must beat that Westerner!
I'll bring these in first
Don't worry about us. Concentrate on your training
But don't stay up too late
You must win
Let's go
You go on home
Normally I live alone. Just make yourselves at home
This is your bed
It's ok. Continue
I said, continue!
What's wrong?
Police!
What are you writing?
Still dare to write?
Not afraid of another beating?
"Wing Chun Master accepts challenge to a Western boxing match"
Do you think that's good enough?
Why not "Western Dog Soundly Defeated"?
"Reporter endures Police brutality for the truth"
But did you get the truth?
I have the truth!
You have guts. I'll give you the truth
and you write about him till he is ruined
Ok, ok!
That Chief hates us Chinese. Always bullies us
I'll break the real news to you,
you report it. It will finish him off!
Mrs Yip, what's wrong?
Oh you're in labour! Chun, go fetch your father!
No, I don't want to distract him
Then I'll go get a midwife
Chun, take care of your mom
Master Zhang, over there!
The Hong Kong Chinese-Western Boxing Match will start soon
The hall is packed with both Chinese and Westerners
It's very lively here
There are Chinese judges in the judging panel this time
Hopefully it will be a truly fair and impartial match
Don't go away folks!
I tell you, he'll go down in 3 strikes
No, I mean he'll defeat the Westener in 3 strikes
Master Yip, are you confident of beating him?
You must win!
Are you fighting for yourself, or for Chinese martial arts?
The Twister is making an entrance
Good! Yip Man can't wait to kick his ass
Master...
Master Yip, kick his ass like how you kicked mine!
Anyone can kick your ass
Shut up!
Both of them are sizing each other up
Master Yip!
Master!
Master Yip has been knocked down! They're going to start the knockout count
Master Yip! Get up!
He appears to be injured. I'm not
sure if he can even stand up
Master Yip seems ok, and he's up
This time it's The Twister that's knocked down
Good work, Master!
That bloody Westerner... still standing even after so many hits
Master Yip is attacking with his Wing Chun
(chanting) Master Yip! Master Yip! Master Yip!
Hey that's cheating!
You animal! The bell has gone!
Master, Master!
Master!
Oh my God! Master Yip is down after
a knockout blow from The Twister!
Master, get up!
Get up! Get up!
Get up, Master!
"We cannot allow the Westerners to belittle us"
"I can bear it if it's just my life"
"But I cannot tolerate it if it's the entire Chinese martial arts world"
"Master Hong, don't go head on with him. Attack his biceps"
"It won't be that easy"
10!
Daddy's won! Daddy's won! Yay!
I know Yip Man!
Dude, everyone here knows Yip Man
Huo Yan Jia, Huang Fei Hong, Yip Man
and me. The 4 Dragons of Fo Shan!
Master Yip!
What do you want to do now?
I want to go home
He looks like you
What shall we call him?
How about Yip Ching?
I want him to be an upright person
Ok
He looks like you
Uncle Man
I have a new friend, and he
wants to learn kung fu from you
Come in
I want to learn from you. How much?
What's your name?
I'm Bruce Lee
Why do you want to learn how to fight?
So that I can beat up people I don't like
Very spirited
Come back when you've grown up
(In 1956, 16 year-old Bruce Lee became Yip Man's disciple)
(Bruce Lee studied Wing Chun extensively and helped promote it)
(Yip Man spent the next 22 years teaching Wing Chun
and spreading it all over the world)
(For the glory of Chinese martial arts)