Accio!
The day I left for the seminary
just my brother saw me off.
My brother is an only child
Ulixes, Diomedes, Tessander.
The Achaeans wanted to conquer Troy.
Epeius built a wooden horse,
then inside hid Menelaus, Ulysses...
Excellent!
Manrico came to visit sometimes,
but he was the only one!
A photo of my girlfriend.
- Maybe she'll work a miracle!
- What miracle?
The miracle to make you normal.
Religion, it's all false.
Jesus was a revolutionary
who pissed off the Romans.
The Bible? Adam created from clay?
- No?
- Bullshit, we come from monkeys!
Get out of here while you can.
That's what I think,
but it's up to you.
He gave me a photo of his girlfriend
and it made me commit a sin.
This is an actress.
Marisa Allasio.
I'm in mortal sin, what should I do?
Is this your first impure act?
Six Hail Marys and six Salve Reginas.
You absolve me?
- It'll happen again.
- Oh, come on!
It's not certain.
It is! I don't want to be absolved.
You're a little upset,
we'll discuss it tomorrow.
Purity is everything for a priest,
punish me!
To sin can happen,
we'll discuss it in a few days.
In Cuba,
on the other side of the ocean,
the Soviet Union is sending ships
with nuclear missiles
to be aimed at the USA.
A third World War could break out,
let us pray.
- How can they be Communists?
- Benassi, join in prayer.
- Don't they realize?
- Don't question, pray.
God, let me die of pneumonia,
but convert Khrushchev,
convert the Communists.
You touched yourself?
So?
Next time let me do it for you.
If they ask who broke your nose
say Antonio Benassi, a.k.a. Accio.
I'm having a conscience crisis,
what should I do?
Open to strangers like that?
Stark naked!
- You're a stranger?
- Did you know it was me?
- You're so boring!
- Mom?
All we needed was
this great decision of yours.
Give me a kiss.
What's this thingamajig?
Serves to make ends meet.
With your father's salary
after mid-month
all I can give you is bread,
water and sugar!
Marisa Allasio worked a miracle.
- Did Mom buy you this?
- It's borrowed, try it.
Know where you can put those sticks?
- What are you doing on my bed?
- I sleep here now.
- And me?
- In the hall for now.
On the pull-out couch.
- Yeah, sure!
- Am I the ugly duckling?
I want to sleep in Manrico's room,
hear me, Pop?
There he is!
Nowwhat do we do with you?
Hi, Pop.
A priest in the family
could have been handy.
I'll take the exam and
go to Classical High School.
- I was tops in Latin.
- Go to Technical so you'll get a job.
- I don't wanna.
- Why not?
I can't get numbers into my head.
If you get a B+ average,
you can go to Classical,
otherwise, Technical.
Let me get changed.
What if I forget school
and come work with you?
The factory? Are you nuts?
- So I'll be on your side.
- Whose side?
- The woeful masses.
- Get lost, off to Mom!
What a homecoming!
Cool it!
That's how it was at home,
luckily there was Mario.
- What was that?
- The American Military Cemetery.
- Soldiers who died at Anzio.
- Poor guys.
Poor guys?
They should have stayed home,
not be pains in the ass to Fascism!
Till 200 years ago they were bushmen,
now they teach us democracy?
What can they do
besides skyscrapers? Nothing.
Fascism, in the middle of the desert,
built Asmara and Tripoli.
If you went around Asmara,
it seemed like Rome.
- I'd like to go.
- To Asmara?
Rome, because it's an eternal city
and I like eternal things.
Hey baby, come here a sec'!
- They're not eternal.
- Yeah, I see that.
Promoted with a B+ average.
Good, that's 50% of your duty.
Now register me at Classical.
Your father made that promise.
You knew it too.
By law, the decisions made
by only one parent aren't valid.
- What the hell law is that?
- Watch your mouth! Come here!
Use proper language.
- Come here.
- You'll smack me.
- I sure will!
- How come she can and I can't?
She's a girl, she'll marry
and her husband will support her.
- No way!
- Yeah...
- See? She won't marry.
- She'll be a concert musician.
Can't I become a "Latiner"?
Manrico isn't going to University,
so why should you?
How come Violetta goes to Classical?
Enough!
Concerts pay, Latin doesn't.
It doesn't, use your head!
- You done?
- Outta the way!
Can hear you for miles around,
take Mom's bags!
Get a load of him!
What's it to you?
There's been no peace
since he came home.
- Go home.
- Get lost.
- Get home so I can knock you around.
- Get lost, I said!
I'll knock you around!
You suck on that bike!
- Still talkin'?
- Shut up.
I couldn't stay in that house
a minute longer.
You see, my mother had voted
for the "houses party".
Our house was falling apart,
she'd seen a house on the ballot
and hoped
they might give us a new one.
The road for Genoa ends here?
Where the hell do I go?
I wanted to follow
the coast road for Genoa
and from there set sail for Africa,
or elsewhere, to help the masses.
No one told me
that the coast road for Genoa
ended at Ostia, 500 kms before.
I told you
they'd release him right away.
The Carabinieri brought me home.
Try to get along.
I've great patience and great hope.
- What did we do to you?
- Injustices.
What injustices?
- You could have told your mother.
- She's the first to do them.
Don't you dare speak of
your mother like that.
She'd give her soul for you.
She would for them, not for me.
Whose son are you?
We're not supposed
to say anything to him!
I want to know what we did to him.
I'd like to know some things too,
we're not to say anything!
Knock it off,
you're making her cry.
She makes me cry too, doesn't she?
- You're pissin' me off.
- Don't touch me.
- The little prince's back.
- I'll be leavin' again.
So go!
Accio's got the devil in him,
our son is possessed.
Come and see, ladies,
beautiful tablecloths and sheets.
Embroidered with our colors
reminding us that honor
and country... look how lovely...
aren't stains to be washed away.
Like them, ma'm?
I'm over here.
Feel the cloth,
it's Terital, not cotton,
they don't wrinkle, need no ironing,
just don't smoke in bed.
Do you smoke?
Your husband? Not even after?
These are yours.
Your husband smokes though.
Can I ask something?
If the Italians liked him so much,
why did they let him
end up like this?
Never mind...
Take your foot off the clutch,
look in the mirror.
The first rule is honor,
meaning: Don't betray a friend,
your country or the Idea.
Shift!
Slow down, now into second.
- Know why you never betray the Idea?
- Why?
Because the Idea is the Idea.
Clear?
Hello, Maria.
Aren't you hungry?
- You remember Accio?
- Sure!
A handshake? Give me a kiss.
Handsome!
- He's eating with us.
- No, thank you.
He'll just watch.
Good thing you weren't hungry!
It's delicious,
I'm really enjoying it.
How many in your family?
Me, my brother, my sister,
all raised the old-fashioned way.
- Meaning?
- The belt, spankings.
Nowadays no one
raises kids like that.
That's why we grew up so well.
- But they call you "Accio".
- 'Cause I'd beat up everyone.
There's a Fascist in you.
You were born a Fascist,
a real thug.
You have to join the party.
Il Duce invented rational
architecture, know what that means?
- That he was always right.
- Good.
Look up there.
How many days did it take
to build Sabaudia?
It says 253 days.
Eight and a half months, it takes
nine to make a human being.
Human... maybe!
If he comes out a fruit,
what do you do?
Look, see that?
He gave his speech from that balcony,
I can almost hear him.
Crowds of people cheering,
waving flags.
Then, in 1944, the Americans came
and the Fascists disappeared.
- All of them, vanished!
- Pieces of shit!
Italians like to help
the guy who wins.
Tell me who's ever done
what Il Duce did!
He took from the rich
and gave to the poor.
Who did that? Only Il Duce.
- Sure?
- Sure.
Duce!
Suddenly I realized
Latina wasn't so bad,
and also Aprilia, Ardea, Pomezia.
Gratitude sprang up in me
for the man who'd built them.
Is it true you're a Communist?
Look at you.
My family was what it was...
but I felt that from that moment
I'd never be alone again.
- What brought you here?
- A bus.
Funny kid.
- Who sent you here?
- I want to join.
I don't believe you,
Fascists don't grow on trees.
I worked with Mario Nastri,
the tablecloth seller.
- You could have said so.
- Didn't know it was important.
Fill this out.
We're the best, oi aristoi...
Listen.
We have to be wary.
Fascism in Italy crumbled
because of the traitors.
Millions of Italian traitors.
I know, but what can I do?
Give me your personal reasons.
Listen, Secretary Bombacci...
or Section Chief?
Secretary.
I want to redeem
the lost honor of this country.
- Well, will you register me?
- With reserve.
I'll keep my eye on you.
Now what do I do?
An action or something...
What action?
Go play with my nephew.
I'm prepared to do certain things.
Then go play.
I obey.
Hey, I've been ordered to play.
- Passes with or without goal-kicks?
- Without.
- I've done that all afternoon.
- And I care?
Since faith is life
and those who have not
the courage to profess a faith
and live it,
show blatant...
- Where did I put my keys?
- Hear him?
He's listening to Fascist speeches,
even joined the movement.
- I'm busy, got to see a girl.
- Just talk to him.
- I'll end up beating him up.
- So!
What do you want?
We'll make him reason, if not then...
- You're such an ass!
- What did I do?
- Give me the card.
- It's my choice.
Great choice!
Know why they call it MSI?
Mussolini, Sun Immortal.
Know where we'd be
if it weren't for him?
With a load of people alive,
not dead in war.
Forget politics, understood?
Are you the only ones who can have
a political conscience?
Who's "you"?
Talk to me directly.
And Stalin, the Communist crimes?
You don't know shit,
Exterminator of Jews.
The extermination of the Jews
isn't true.
Do you know
what the fuck you're saying?
Know how quick the Americans
can shoot a fake film?
Get out, or I'll kill him myself.
You piece of shit!
I'll get these fucking ideas
of yours out of your head.
I'll wash 'em out.
Enough?
Well?
You're a jerk!
I've told you a thousand times
it bothers my nose.
- Wash this.
- Do it yourself.
Thanks a lot!
- Do the Benassis live here?
- Yes.
Looking for Violetta?
No, I'm one of Manrico's
party comrades.
He's not here.
Can I wait for him?
Sure...
- Can I wait inside?
- Yeah.
- I have to pick up some flyers.
- Flyers?
Sure, of course.
- Is that his bed?
- It's mine, the chair opens...
He and my sister sleep in there.
I'm better off because
it's a little more private.
- Who plays the cello?
- My sister.
Don't touch it,
she'll get pissed off.
- They're not here?
- No.
I knewit, my brother
told you as an excuse.
You fell for it...
I guess I like falling for it.
It's nice here.
I think it stinks.
Your brother told me
all you like is Latin.
Then why are you in Technical?
Good question.
Here he is.
There's a friend of yours
who's looking for flyers.
- Let's go out?
- Sure.
- Mom?
- She's not here.
When'll she be back?
Why don't we stay here?
I'll pour you a vermouth,
even better, some coffee.
Accio, make us some coffee?
Listen...
I have an important
interview at the factory,
if it goes right, they'll hire me.
Since we still
have things to discuss,
stay with her,
I'll be back in half an hour.
- No, I'm busy.
- Come on, half an hour.
Does it show she wore me out?
What a drag!
I just remembered
I have an appointment,
be back in half an hour.
- I'll come with you.
- No, stay here.
- To do what?
- Stay with Accio.
Half hour.
- You're not from Latina.
- No, I'm half French.
You're kidding!
My mother is from the north too...
of Italy, though.
How come you're in Latina?
My father's an engineer
at the electric plant.
Are you active in politics too?
Look, I'm on the other side.
- Meaning?
- What's your guess?
That I'm a Fascist.
Yeah, I'm not as original as Manrico.
No way!
I'll show you my card.
Believe me now?
Antonio Benassi, a.k.a. Accio
for reasons I'm not getting into now.
You Communists feel the weight
of the supremacy you've...
Never mind.
You say you're French,
say something.
You are the magnificent magistrate,
you have the right to life and death,
every power, every freedom...
Really French.
And you're really Fascist.
And proud of it.
Good for you.
You've never been
in one of our divisions,
we have discussions...
Anyway... are you French for real?
We'd better go out,
if Mom finds you here...
it's in your best interest.
- Anyway we'll just end up arguing.
- I think so.
Ma, yeah...
Is Manrico back? No, nothing.
He's still not back.
Your brother's really...
Is he always like this?
- Meaning?
- You can't depend on him.
Worse than that.
I don't mean show up, but anything...
Caring for him is a joke.
I must be crazy.
Where are you going? Francesca!
You're an idiot to think about him,
Know how many I've seen like you?
They call youAccio
because you're mean.
I'm leaving.
See if I care!
Manrico got hired at the factory:
Day one he bought overalls,
day two, he got indebted for life
buying himself a car.
Did you finish the assignment?
- Let me see?
- Why? You don't have a clue.
You're such a good kid!
I'll beat you up!
- Jeez!
- I did it for Francesca, not you.
I'm going back to work.
Did I take the keys?
I did your translation.
It was a piece of cake.
Sounds like a passage on Manrico:
"Devious, fickle, passionate,
abundant eloquence, little wisdom."
Virtually my brother.
See how a Fascist behaves?
How many of our men
did you kill after the war?
This again?
They were a bunch of innocent people.
- A bunch of murderers!
- Wasn't it peacetime?
First there was war,
you started it and dictatorship too.
You guys don't have
the courage for dictatorship.
Let's drop it.
Convenient, first kill,
torture and then...
Do you know what Decima MAS was?
The dungeon in Via Tasso?
I like this.
You, dancing?
I'm a complete man!
I'm moving to Turin next month.
I'm moving to Turin,
my father's being transferred.
Where?
- What does Manrico say?
- He'll come up on weekends.
What do you say?
If he doesn't, I will.
I wanted all of us, men and women
to come up here
to say how it feels to work
50 hours a week in a factory.
They want to make us become machines,
we need to talk, communicate,
we need a human relationship,
a real one!
Mothers, I turn to you,
tell your children
that the factory is a bad place,
that it hurts you,
we shouldn't tolerate it.
We have to break free.
They treat us like slaves,
freedom from the master!
Manrico was courageous,
it came natural to him.
Like making people fall in love.
That day,
in the middle of all that racket
looking at those women, you knew
they loved him, one especially.
We should be anti-American,
they were our enemies.
Means nothing,
we have to go man by man.
Go man by man, understand?
Meantime we get fucked.
What's with the kid, he seems sad.
- He is, in fact.
- Some girl making him suffer?
The opposite, that's why he's sad.
- Don't be disrespectful!
- Is it my fault the door is low?
Do you understand
the magnitude of this motto?
"Eia eia alala",
Know what it means?
Nothing, and everyone behind him.
Great!
Doesn't even say goodbye?
You're going and
who knows when he'll see you.
Why not look around,
maybe you'd see somebody else.
Hitting on your brother's girl?
You crazy?
You don't like me 'cause I'm Fascist,
you like him 'cause he's Communist?
I like Manrico because he's Manrico.
See what he's like?
You can't depend on him.
And it's not true I don't like you.
I love arguing with you.
Is that your father?
Long live Italy!
The working class will win!
Freedom for Russia!
What the fuck are you doing?
Think a night in jail scared me?
It's an honor,
because I served the Idea.
Fuck off, Benassi,
isn't one pain in the ass enough?
What a fuckin' family!
"We don't give a damn about jail,
to the black shirts, all hail."
See what a fucking country,
can't even yell
"Freedom for Russia"...
Don't you dare go on strike
at school again.
You crazy?
Clear?
Manrico's strikes are okay,
mine aren't?
His are good, yours aren't.
Real democratic!
"Princess Ruspoli European
Trapshooting Champion."
The Borgheses, the Torlonias,
the Ruspolis...
Why the fuck is this our paper?
Because we're aristocrats.
Have you looked at yourself?
"Sweet black face peering,
hope and wait..."
Sometimes we'd go to Rome
to express our Ideas
at some Leftist conference.
The Roman division
had the strategic leadership.
- Quartasponda.
- Accio, we've been here 2 hours.
We had to get the stuff,
eggs, paint, bags of shit,
to treat these assholes royally.
- The clowns!
- They're coming out!
Europe, Nation, Socialization!
They must be big shots!
Who are they?
Writers, journalists,
film people, a bunch of fags.
Let's treat them right.
Stop, we're far enough.
But where are our leaders?
When we do certain things,
the leaders don't come.
Have fun?
Let's get a cappuccino.
Violetta, it's Accio.
I'm in Rome,
I didn't come home last night.
We noticed.
I'll be here another few days.
I'm starting a civil war.
You're making civil war, I get it.
I'll have to talk to some big shot,
Michelini, Almirante.
Hello?
Bye!
You're talking to a guy
who set up the Social Republic.
I don't give a fuck what you did!
I want to see a real head,
someone in the executive.
Who's the real head?
Did you guys bring this moron?
He's been here a week,
wants to see someone.
- Simmer down.
- You sound like a Mobster.
Be respectful.
- Take him in there.
- Let's leave.
Anyway, you sounded like a Mobster.
Mobster!
Knock it off!
What's going on?
What the fuck you doin'?
Discussion's over, Benassi.
Wake up, we're almost there.
- Know your problem?
- I don't want to know.
I'll tell you anyway:
You gotta get laid!
You'd think it's easy.
I come home,
everyone's happy, kisses, hugs...
What's to be happy about?
Living in this rat-hole
Or you cracking people's heads?
This time they were cracking yours.
- The world's full of injustice.
- Sure!
In fact, I fight it.
With action, not with a lotta yap
like Manrico and Violetta.
- I have a favor to ask.
- To mind my own business?
A real favor,
beat up Peppe di Bari.
What had he done to her?
Who knows, just so she did.
Are you Peppe di Bari?
A Fascist in the family
is always handy...
like a doctor!
Don't go around saying
I beat you up as a Fascist,
I did it as a brother.
Several months later,
in my sister's purse,
Mom found a mysterious object,
a kind of plunger
used against pregnancy.
A serious thing.
"I love my boyfriend."
This is all we needed.
Look, he's my age.
Who'd guess Violetta...
I have to talk to this scum.
Just imagine if the masses
had access to culture.
Yes.
Do you think that by giving culture
to the lower classes
there would be more well-being?
Sure, but the social model
would have to change,
substituting Parliament with...
- the Assembly of Corporations.
- That's a Fascist concept.
Don't listen to him,
he's a black-shirt thug.
I asked a question
so I could understand.
Is that the professor?
Whole family's here?
How come Mom's not here too?
She's home crying, come with us.
- I'm not coming.
- You're coming home with me.
I'm going to Rome, think I'm going
to die in this shit hole?
Calm down!
- Have something to say?
- Step outside!
- Hands off!
- Your father will handle this.
I'm armed.
And here's my weapon.
- This.
- Fuckin' embarrassing.
Think of your parents,
they're decent people.
Put yourselves in his shoes!
Getting out here?
How does it open?
Your friends
are going to burn my car.
Who said?
The Celestini woman at the Union.
You doing stuff with her?
You do stuff only within your party?
I'm thinking about Francesca,
she still writes you.
Did you hear me?
You're thinking about Francesca?
Think about me!
Know who organized it?
Nastri, the tablecloth guy.
What? He'd have told me.
What would you have done?
Would you have told me or not?
- I'd have told you.
- Why?
What do you mean... you joking?
'Cause you're my brother.
And?
Who the fuck did you take after?
Glad they're doing it.
- Don't slam it!
- They're burning it anyway!
So it's true,
you're burning my brother's car.
It's a demonstrative action,
your brother's gone too far!
- He's a worker.
- He's no worker!
Workers work their asses off,
he's a fanatic.
He's still paying for it.
Who gets it, gets it,
that's democracy.
Since when do we give a fuck
about democracy?
Since when have you
become democratic?
You laying your hands
on the Youth Secretary?
Okay, but don't touch
Manrico's car.
Okay, but we burn the others.
Not the others either.
You deciding everything now?
Get outta here.
Good thing you're an old man,
I don't beat up old men.
That night Mario
got stopped by the police,
they found stuff in the trunk
and arrested him.
The police showed up
and he got arrested.
Miracle you didn't get caught.
What kind of man did I marry?
What's in his head?
You know I fell in love
out of compassion?
He said he'd had pleurisy
during the war.
The car was full of weapons.
Who knows how it'll end up.
I'll throw out all that stuff
he keeps in my mother's cellar.
The building might go sky-high
with the poor old thing inside.
What stuff?
Nothing.
Why are you so sweaty?
Come here, I'll give you a T-shirt.
No need, Bella.
Take your pants off too.
I grew up with men around, think
I'm shocked by a pair of underwear?
It's not that, they're dry.
Embarrassed to be in underwear
in front of a woman?
What embarrassed?
You look like my father, you know?
I'll show you a photo.
His forehead.
He loved me so much.
Lie on the bed and rest.
Why are you shivering?
Are you cold or afraid?
- I'm not shivering.
- I'll warm you.
Okay?
- Why are you laughing?
- Nothing, I'm happy.
Congratulations,
Mr High School Graduate.
This car?
- Want to drive it?
- Whose is it?
Yours, I bought it in installments.
Like it?
- Remember to double-clutch.
- Not with this model.
Intuition told me
the things Bella taught me
would come in handy
even after the '60s.
In May of '68, the great
revolutionary wave had swept Paris.
By July, China,
in August, Czechoslovakia,
In Latina it never came.
I think I spent that year
in the kitchen
eating my mother's soup.
Then Violetta invited us to Rome
for her first concert
at the occupied Conservatory.
We thank the comrades
at the Rome Conservatory.
- How are you?
- Fine.
Let's look at you.
- What do you think?
- You look a little worse.
I'm in great shape!
You've put on weight.
Tell the truth, a little...
Where is he?
They're all buddies of yours, huh?
This concert is art and solidarity.
Art by itself is masturbation,
solidarity by itself is charity.
Art, uprooted from the people,
is a huge two-fisted jerk-off.
The comrades will play Beethoven
to demonstrate that even he,
great as he is,
is immortal, but not unchangeable.
Comrade Montagna and I...
have de-fascistized
the text for Ode to Joy.
Allow me
a slightly sentimental aside.
A word about Comrade Benassi...
She's my sister and when,
as a kid, I'd hear her play, I'd cry.
Now, over to the great, deaf,
handicapped genius, Beethoven.
"Mao,
Mao Tse-Tung, Marx, Lenin, Stalin,
are marching proudly
towards the dawning sun.
Rise, Oh dawning sun...
Forward all peoples, to the revolt,
Oh red flag, Oh red flag..."
- Don't touch the immortal.
- Fucking clowns!
Leave Beethoven alone,
or we'll bust your ass.
Duce!
What the fuck are you doing?
What the fuck do you want?
When did you ever
give a shit about Beethoven?
When the fuck did you ever care?
This won't ever happen again, right?
What?
This.
Swear to me.
No, I won't.
Why not?
Don't bullshit me.
I'm not the one bullshitting you.
It's true I've put on weight,
know why?
I'm pregnant.
Did you hear me? I'm pregnant!
- How far along?
- Three months.
Then a guy gets pissed off...
Three months!
- We write, you could have...
- I found out yesterday.
- And Manrico?
- I told him yesterday.
He doesn't want it.
I'm keeping it anyway.
What are you doing?
Put your shoes back on.
Put them on, you're pregnant,
you'll catch something.
The flu...
Why don't you take yours off too?
Thankfully, I have sound principles
that my mother taught me,
like wear an undershirt
or I might get the flu.
Do I have to get sick too?
Great!
I fight in the revolution
and you guys tan.
What?
Why are you looking at me like that?
I'm so happy.
I always knew you weren't a Fascist,
you were the only one who didn't.
I did what I did for the music.
Anyway...
But, if I had to sit and look at that
moron with the cue cards...
I know.
Those are the contradictions
within the people.
You love the people, even though
you know there are tons of jerks.
We have to celebrate
you're not a Fascist any more.
I have to make a bone pile?
- Make what?
- A bone pile.
Then you have to remember
how the bones were laid out.
No rough-housing with her.
We have to protect the future.
You don't know
how you've made me cry.
We used to see each other everyday,
then suddenly you disappear.
Bella...
I've changed.
I know you left the Fascists,
but I don't care about politics.
It's not just that.
You too, what did you expect?
You're married...
I'm in love with someone else.
Where are you going?
What's the matter?
You've started smoking?
One, after dinner.
Right, and you just had dinner?
How's Mario?
He's out of jail,
and I told him everything.
About us?
How did he take it?
He says if he sees you,
he'll kill you.
That girl you love,
does she love you?
Does she love me...
Accio, Bella called.
Nastri's wife called again.
She said she saw you in town
and you didn't say hello.
What's she want from you?
What are you looking at?
- In order.
- What's in order?
- Benassi, everything's in order.
- Wait a minute!
You put it there, it gets buried
and that's the end of it.
- Teaching me my job?
- We've been waiting for ages.
Know what 'ages' means?
Here's my husband's pay slip,
it's in small print, but it says
that every month they take out money
because the government's
building houses with it.
For 25 years the money's been
taken out, but where are the houses?
The keys to our homes are there.
- Where's the key for Benassi?
- There's been no assigning.
Why not?
- Takes time to decide.
- We're dying inside there.
The only time I voted,
I voted for the houses party.
Tell him, help me.
Taking it out on me?
You could have called Manrico.
Calm down! Quiet!
I've decided, I want a party card.
We don't issue membership cards.
- Why not?
- This isn't a party.
- What is it?
- A movement.
Then write:
"Benassi in the movement..."
No need, you told me, that's enough.
- Can I sit here?
- Right over there.
I'll do some reading.
Is here okay?
Almost done.
I've studied, read tons of books.
I know, you did good.
I like this idea where no one
tells you to do things,
decisions are made together.
This is the biggest difference
in fact,
we're all equals here,
a guy stands up, has his say,
if his idea's good...
- Everybody's the same!
- Sure!
Democratically, raise your hands,
all in favor of an action?
I'm in favor.
- In favor?
- In favor.
"The struggle is tough
and we can't get enough!"
- I'll do it.
- Know how many I've done?
- Show me?
- Trust me!
Who gave you that?
Have it explode in your hand!
- His friends gave it to him.
- Ex-friends.
Then each his own way.
How'll you light it?
The matches...
Comrades, let's have a game.
- Get moving.
- Not a soul around.
Cover your ears.
Where are you?
- How's it goin'?
- Fine, you?
Don't run off,
I got things to say.
- I got nothing to tell you.
- But I do!
I'm still paying for your car.
This is for what I taught you.
This, is for fucking my wife.
And this...
is for my treating you like a son.
In fact, you are a son,
a son of a whore.
Quit joking.
Don't be an asshole.
I didn't even touch you.
God dammit, Mario!
It was the worst night of my life,
I ran so far I reached the beach.
I knew you were here.
Did you hear?
I didn't kill him.
He was out of his mind, we fought.
More like, he beat me.
Then he just...
Don't know how...
Poor Mario.
Come on!
Don't let it get you.
You're shaking!
Why are you shaking?
Manrico's head was somewhere else.
What's up?
Sir?
They shot Marotti,
the head of the factory.
What the fuck are you saying?
- Did they kill him?
- No.
Shot in the legs,
his briefcase was full of money.
I have to get out of here.
You too, why hang around?
Waiting for them to come for you?
Where do I go? I don't know a soul.
To friends of mine, I'll send you.
I'll give you some money
from petty cash.
What petty cash?
What are you into?
Are you guys involved
in this thing at the factory?
You shot him?
What are you saying?
What are you saying!
You can stay as long as you want,
you're safe here.
Fabio,
Manrico's brother is here.
Come in.
My exile in Piedmont
lasted almost a year.
I'd taken myself too seriously
as a fugitive too,
Nastri had had a heart attack, the
Prosecutor had dismissed the case,
no one was looking for me,
but Manrico
had forgotten to tell me.
Then he remembered
and sent somebody.
Uncle Accio.
Not "Accio uncle".
Daddy's brother, looks like me too.
Doesn't he look like me?
We broke up a few months ago
and then got back together again.
I'd like to tell him
to stay away, but I can't.
I see him and it starts over.
What's Manrico doing now? Is he
in some radical political group?
I don't know...
- He was reported for robbery.
- Making a career!
I'm cut off from my parents,
they hate me,
they hate Amedeo, can't stand
the idea he's the son of a worker.
You can stay with me a while,
if you want.
In Turin?
The last place I should be staying
is with you.
His father's never there...
- Who gives a shit!
- What's the matter?
Take me to the station,
I'm already fed up with you.
I told him you'd take him
on the merry-go-round.
You told him what?
Come on!
For the merry-go-round
he's got Mommy and Daddy,
Uncle Accio has his own life,
even though it's shit.
You'll scare him.
Let me out.
They say we get better with age,
I was just plain aging.
Manrico had been in the north
2 years, organizing the revolution.
Then one day...
It's Manrico.
How are you? It's been ages!
On my wardrobe
there's a bag with money.
Take what you need to get to Turin
and bring it to me.
Who's this?
Accio, don't you recognize me?
I'm here.
- Where?
- In Turin!
- Didn't Manrico tell you anything?
- Haven't seen him for two years.
You two fighting again?
Me again, he hasn't seen
the kid in two years?
- Leave it alone!
- When I see him, I'll talk to him.
He had me come here to Bar del Peso.
These two are really in love.
The bag?
I took money for the train,
a sandwich and coffee.
How are Mom and Pop?
What?
I need this money to buy a house
for me, Francesca and the baby.
All together?
What's so funny? I'm not joking.
Why tell me all this?
Do what you want with it.
Make this revolution, finally.
But do you really think
the working class will follow you?
Guys like Pop are the working class.
Can you see Pop with a gun?
It's your business.
In fact, you're right,
we should make a joke of life,
I'm always so serious...
- What the hell are you sayin'?
- What the hell do I know?
All the beatings I gave you
weren't enough?
I'd give you one right here.
You jerk, don't you dare.
Be respectful.
Lowerthose hands!
You're a bastard.
Damned bastard!
I missed you.
- What?
- It's Francesca.
Where is she?
- Did you call her?
- I told her we were here.
What is it?
Gotta go.
Freeze, police!
Francesca was arrested
as a suspected accomplice,
I was released a few days later.
We're here.
Are you okay?
Look, Grandma and Grandpa's house
is all broken.
I was scared
you'd been killed with Manrico.
Come on!
Here we are with Grandma.
We'll go to the kitchen
to see if there's
a cookie for Amedeo.
He's like his father.
Let's hope not.
And like you too.
Even worse.
What a bastard!
Violetta...
Come on!
That's enough.
Is this Mrs Biancopane?
Sorry for the hour, I'm calling
from the Home Assignment Office.
You've been waiting...
Sorry for the hour, the homes are
ready and we're going to take them.
They're ready.
Mr Perotti, there are papers here
for us who've been waiting...
There are surnames,
they were assigned months ago.
What, you dreamed it?
See? But now though...
Wake up the kids,
grandparents, everybody,
we all have to go together
and occupy the homes.
We have the keys, but if we all
go in, they won't kick us out.
Violetta, how's Mom?
Wake her up and put her on the phone,
I have good news.
Relax, there's a place for everyone.
This is our home!
I never had a balcony.
I'd put the flowers in the tub.
If Manrico were here,
he'd be bringing you roses.
Translation
Charlotte Lantery
subtitles edited by Elvira de Majo
OMBRE ELETTRICHE - Roma