Have a good journey!
Open your mouth
What's the matter?
No, no... nothing.
My girlfriend's left me.
Why have you got a white
streak in your hair?
Is something the matter?
Alfred, it's not that
you don't dance well,
but we need a woman in the team,
the rules of the contest say
the team has to be mixed...
with three members...
One of us will have to leave.
I don't feel well... you have
no idea how bad you make me feel.
I've been training for this for months.
It was me who told you of the
contest and registered the team,
and I chose the music
we're going to dance to.
Alfred, don't make things
even more difficult.
This isn't happening...
this isn't happening...
this isn't happening.
So why have you got that white streak
if you know people will ask?
PAULA; SORRY. LET'S GET BACK
TOGETHER, NICOLÁS.
Julio.
Nicolás.
Paula's father...
- The shirt I gave you for Christmas.
- Yes.
- It suits you.
- Thank you.
Nice tennis shoes.
Thanks, Paula gave them to me.
Paula's gone to the country.
She needed time.
Where to? What time?
Time. She went to one
of those places to relax...
...where they do yoga...
- Yoga?
When has she ever done yoga?
How's the toy shop?
Are there sales?
Yeah... so so.
- Well, I'm off. Bye.
- Bye.
Hurry up. You still have the quince
and the sweet potato jam to do.
Did you hear?
What's your game, misery!
Do you want to get us both fired?
- I'm not motivated.
- You're not motivated?
You're not Fred Astaire. You're Alfredo
Jiménez... J-i-m-é-n-e-z...
- OK, dad.
- We'll speak about this at home.
Alfred.
Why don't you stop your dad
hitting you in the store?
My dad doesn't hit me.
Can you lend me
your stick deodorant?
Why don't you play football?
Because I had an accident.
- Car accident?
- No, a sports accident.
Your call took me by surprise.
I never thought you'd decide to do it.
The rabbi gave me them
three months ago.
To Miramar, right?
- Don't say a thing.
- I won't say a word.
Our religion forbids cremation.
It's not right.
But I know it's what
your grandfather wanted.
He was a great friend of the rabbi.
I'm a great friend of the rabbi.
I often go to the temple.
Are you sad?
Yes.
You know you're
blocking your emotions.
- Be careful, otherwise you'll explode one day.
- Thanks.
Hello, hello, how are you?
A warm welcome to the Creative Show,
a programme in which
we like to show the most creative
commercials from around the worid.
We also like to analyse the business
so you know the main trends
in advertising in other countries.
Today's programme will be
dedicated to trends.
One trend that we've
detected is balloons.
Suddenly there are balloons
everywhere... for birthday parties...
And there are commercials
such as this one...
Yes? Come in.
Hey, it's the Clio show.
It's incredible Gujis's relevance
Gujis is happy...
and I'll tell you why in a moment.
He's perfect... he was born to it.
Does a juice stain come out with soap?
Use Ariel soap powder. It's very good,
it's sold all over the worid.
But it should come out
with normal soap, right?
Use Ariel, it's good.
- Hi.
- Nicolás, Abril, Abril, Nicolás.
- How are things?
- Fine. You?
- Fine... fine
I'll be right back...
I'm going to change...
Alfred, can you come
here a moment, please?
Who's that girl?
Aren't you going to open the Scalextric?
I don't know.
We look forward to seeing
you all next Saturday
with a new Creative Advertising Show.
We've come to get
you to do something.
I was planning to stay in.
But it's Saturday...
Saturday evening. Everyone goes out.
I always feel as if I'm out of it.
- Out of what?
- Out of everything.
What was your plan?
Why don't you play
with the small bowls?
Don't you see they're
all going down the side?
Let me make my own decisions.
Your shoes are different to mine.
That's because they're mine.
Oh...
- Didn't they give you special shoes?
- No... they said I could use these...
They left me out of the dance team.
It's all very strange.
They said the team had to be mixed.
A woman with a white
streak in her hair appeared.
I still don't get it.
I've got the ashes.
We'll go all the same.
My job is to direct operations
at the toll stations,
and to collect the toll in force both
quickly and efficiently,
interfering as little as
possible with the traffic.
Since the motorway opened
in 1994, the number of drivers
choosing this form of payment
has seen constant growth.
There are currently
over 110,000 clients
and we're still growing.
- You like your job?
- Very much.
Why take the ashes to Miramar?
We used to go there on holiday...
he loved it.
- I don't know it.
- I know.
- Is it big?
- No.
When were you last there?
Twenty years ago.
Like Michael Fox in
'Back to the Future'.
Well, I was hoping to pick up
speed in a straight line.
- In the film, he...
- Yes... yes.
...he goes really fast
as he's being chased,
but then suddenly a car appears...
and guess what he does?
The skateboard
passes under the car
and he goes over the top,
at full speed and
- comes down the front just in time to fall
onto the skate. - Yes.
I did exactly the same thing
but with a park bench.
I tore the ligaments in my knee,
broke my wrist and split
my head open on the ground.
Everybody laughed and
I've never done any sport since.
I was forgetting, Abril's coming with us.
She's visiting her family.
But it was our trip...
It's just three days.
She won't be with us the whole time.
A breadcrumb...
So... we're leaving tomorrow?
- Yes.
- Sleep well.
- You too.
Bye.
AWKWARD
Is everything OK?
Fine...
There's Abril.
Help her with her stuff.
- Hello.
- Is something up?
- No, no.
Shall I help you with your things?
Hello.
- You have a Ford.
- Yes.
I couldn't have got lost...
- Do you know why Father Christmas
wears red and white? - No...
Because he was invented by Coca Cola.
He wasn't invented by Coca Cola.
They dressed him like that for an ad...
and that's how he stayed.
- Oh, yeah... so how did he dress before?
- No idea... in blue.
Maybe it was in blue...
Blue and white like
the Argentine flag.
Father Christmas isn't Argentine...
he comes from Alaska.
Have we passed a
sign saying 'Pipinas'?
- This isn't the way to Miramar...
- No, I know it's not.
It's just a little detour
as I need to see Paula.
- Who?
- His ex-girlfriend...
She's not my ex-girlfriend.
We've just cooled things a bit.
Do you love her?
- Let me go with you.
- No, stay here. It'll be OK.
What are you doing here?
What do you mean, what am I doing
here? I've come to get you.
- You're not well, Nicolás.
- Yeah, I'm not well.
I put up a banner in your street;
'Paula, forgive me. Let's get back
together, Nicolás.'
We can't split over a Scalextric.
Nicolás, that was our money
to go to Colonia,
and you spent it on a track
for model cars.
But why go to Colonia?
Every couple goes to Colonia.
What, do we have to go to Colonia
to be considered a real couple?
No, we were never a real couple
because you've got problems.
You need to grow up.
You're very immature.
- Good morning.
- Hello, how are you?
- I haven't opened the Scalextric.
- Go ahead and open it.
- I love you.
- I love you too.
But love is one thing
and being there is another.
It'll be the best thing
for us both, you'll see.
You've still not had
that tooth out, have you?
What are you doing?
Nothing, I'm just giving you courage.
You're working through a failure...
the failure of a relationship.
You need to mourn, everyone
does in their own way.
- I'm thirsty. Is there nothing
to drink? - Me too, very thirsty.
Don't worry, a bit further on...
there's a place where they hand out
mineral water and yogurt.
That's not there any more...
it was years ago.
Anyway, it was in summer, not winter.
- Hello.
- What's wrong?
- With me?
- No, the car. - Uh... well, it suddenly
started making a noise and stopped...
Sorry, are you a nun?
What do you think?
- Where are you going?
- To Miramar.
What are you going
to do there in this cold?
She'going to see her family.
- Is she a writer?
- No, she works in a toll booth.
- What's she jotting down?
- I don't know... I swear I don't.
And the other one?
He's going to a dance contest
but he doesn't know
if he'll be able to dance.
And you?
I'm going to scatter
my grandfather's ashes.
A lovely journey...
- What?
- You were going to say something.
- No, it was nothing...
- I'd never spoken to a nun before.
- Really?
No, I've never much
to do with religion.
- I'll pay.
- One coffee and seven mineral waters...
- How many?
- Seven.
We can start a kitty later...
Thanks. Shall we go?
Why are you so overdressed?
His father left him in a swimming pool
when he was seven.
He stayed there all night, alone and cold.
It left him traumatised.
So he's always much more warmly
dressed than the others.
Even in summer he doesn't go out very
much because he's embarrassed.
Is that true?
Well... we're here because of a tree.
A tree you reported as stolen, miss.
Is that right?
- What have you got in that urn?
- My grandad's ashes.
- I've got nothing to do with that...
- That's enough.
We've all got our problems.
We don't always know what
others are going through.
Don't worry. Irma, the village
kleptomaniac, has got your tree.
It happens to most tourists.
Bring her in.
What does 'kleptomaniac' mean?
Irma, do me a favour and give
the tree back to this young lady.
Give it back, Irma.
We'll cut you another later.
Come on, woman! Give it back!
So... room 127 for the young lady,
and room 140 for the gentlemen.
Breakfast is served between
seven and ten every morning,
and dinner is from 9 to 9.30
in the evening.
Would it be possible to have
those necklaces with pearis,
where each pearl has a certain
value so they can be exchanged
for things here in the hotel...
like those little soaps
or wooden dolls?
Would it be possible to have one?
To avoid handling money in the hotel.
Would that be possible?
No.
The buffet's closed.
Shall we go out for a quick bite?
OK, let's meet here in twenty minutes.
There are three possibilities;
I sleep in the big bed
and you in the small one,
or me in the small one
and you in the big one...
or both of us sleep in the big one...
No... you take the big one
and I'll sleep in the small bed.
Actually, that's the one I wanted
because as a dancer I need
to stretch my muscles at night...
No problem.
Thanks.
Look, Nico, we've got a hairdryer!
Everything's closed,
there's nothing open.
These places only come alive
in season, they're dead right now.
Just as well we said
something quick...
I hate bicycles and
those little pedal cars,
because you always get your
trouser turn-ups caught in them.
- What?
- Nothing.
In Japan, 34,187 people commit
suicide every year.
Exactly half that number
of people, that is 17,093,
came together for the inauguration
of Miramar in 1915.
Sorry, I couldn't find the
key to lock the room.
Shall we go?
Good evening.
- Good evening.
- Will you be dining?
- Yes.
All we have left is meat pie
and a little alphabet soup.
Um, I don't know.
Meat pie.
Me too, meat pie.
Fine. And to drink?
Still water.
Coke.
A coke for me, too.
Welcome.
Don't bother with dessert.
I'm going to the toilet.
Sorry, that was two meat pies
and an alphabet soup, right?
No, no... did you order soup?
No, three meat pies.
- Oh... I thought the young lady had
ordered soup. - No, no...
Welcome.
It's good to know the
day you're going to die...
because every day before that
you can do what you like knowing that
nothing's going to happen to you.
But the thing is you know the day
when everything's going to finish.
Besides the physical body, the ashes,
feelings are what really matters.
You should see how
clean the loos are.
- Feelings.
- What feelings?
What are you talking about?
He killed himself because
he was old and bored.
I was only away for a minute.
What did you talk about?
- Who said this had to be fun?
- What?
You mean life, metaphorically speaking?
- What? What's up?
- Nothing, Alfred, calm down?
That's not Coke!
- It's just that... that's the brand we sell.
- Water then!
Sorry... Miramar's weird,
I'm still not used to it.
- I've got no idea where to scatter them.
- What? The ashes?
- Didn't he tell you where?
- No, he said Miramar.
You've still not had
that tooth out yet, have you?
- Do you know who's staying at this hotel?
- No, who?
- Gujis.
- The presenter of the Clio Show?
That can't be right. What would
Gujis be doing in Miramar?
Do you know who's
staying at this hotel?
Horacio is the receptionist's nephew.
He knows Miramar better than anyone?
He's a lifeguard,
but he's out of work right now.
As you don't know
where to throw the ashes,
I thought we could do
a tour, visit a few places.
You can choose where to scatter them,
and we can get to know the place.
What do you think?
- Well, here we are at...
- Mickey's.
...a famous café known
for its delicious waffles.
Well, it's closed right
now as we're off season,
but it's almost impossible
to get a table in summer.
If you come in season
I'd recommend their 'Miramar Mickey',
which has lots of caramel and cream,
melted chocolate with pieces
of chocolate dessert.
Is there a savoury one, too?
This is the first breakwater in Miramar,
which was built in 1916.
You can always find anglers
here from very early on,
from five or six in the morning.
Well, there's nobody here
today as nothing's biting...
but if you like we can
come back another day,
it's no trouble for me.
This is the beach.
Well, the excursión ends here.
- Thank you very much.
- That was very nice.
Thank you.
- Give him something out of the kitty.
- What kitty?
And what do we do with it now?
What about over there?
Shall we scatter them here?
Yeah... yeah.
Do you want us to hold hands?
No, no, no!
Are you going to say a few words?
No, no. What could I say?
I don't know, something about Marcos.
I'll do it. Let me speak.
Marcos, you killed yourself
because you were old and bored.
You used to say that
life was good for arseholes
and that you thought
you were intelligent.
It's true we may not be
the happiest people in the worid,
but happiness is an invention, which is
something you never understood.
And now you want us to scatter
your ashes in Miramar,
because you used to come here on
holiday. What holidays, I wonder!
You never used to work.
Nicolás spent all
day in the shop while
you played the lottery,
searching for the sort of luck
you never had in your life,
because your negativism
spoilt everything around you.
Like when you're
about to feed a dog
you approach the bowl
and as you do so
the dog starts running around,
jumping, wagging its tail...
but once you've given him
his food, he stays completely still...
I mean that the food gives
him less satisfaction
than the expectation you
create in him just before.
I reckon that's what's
happened to you.
While you were full
of excitement and uncertainty,
you were alive and reached
a maximum of happiness.
But once you had
what you wanted,
your dopamine level dropped
and you were left like the dog,
staring at nothing.
Do you know what
dopamine is, Marcos?
You haven't got a clue.
It's a mediator of nerve impulses.
It's the level of expectation
and excitement
that we all have in the blood
and that goes up to the brain.
I don't know if I can remember
all I've just said...
It's as if he didn't want to leave.
Shall we eat?
I'm not hungry, I'm going to bed.
You didn't celebrate your
Bar Mitzvah, did you?
You can tell.
I'm not cold.
Watch out!
SORRY, PAULA. LET'S GET BACK
TOGETHER, NICOLÁS.
Your mouth's bleeding.
What's the time?
If it's the same time in Miramar
as in Buenos Aires
then it's seven in the evening...
you've been asleep all day.
What's up?
- Hello, dad.
- What are you doing here?
- I've brought the tree.
- That was for Christmas.
Well...
Today's my birthday.
We can celebrate both things together.
These are my sisters...
Mabel...
Raquel...
and this is my father.
- Mum?
- Here she is, can't you see her?
Hello, mum.
You haven't visited in seven years...
you could have warned us.
You can't be sad, mum,
it's Abril's birthday.
We must all be happy for her.
- Shall we call the doctor, mum?
- It'll pass.
Lionel Ritchie's going to do
a concert in Los Ángeles,
but if the plane lands in Mississippi
you can go overland
and see the heartland
of the United States.
He has a white daughter.
So either his wife is white,
or there's a white
ancester somewhere.
Eat up before it gets cold.
Eat it, it's soft.
He's got problems
with his teeth, that's why...
Teeth are the only things
that survive an accident.
The dead are identified by their teeth.
They leave us before we die and
remind us we're just passing through.
They're important, very important.
Some diseases start in the teeth,
a cousin of ours who's
a dentist once told us.
The worst thing that could happen
to you is going to the dentist
on a camp site. I hate camp sites.
I hate astrologers even
more than dentists!
But we were talking
about something else.
Can I go to the toilet?
Yes, over there.
- That boy's got a problem.
- He'll get over it.
Your hands are a mess.
You're looking beautiful
but your hands are a mess.
You don't look after them.
I work in a place where
I'm always handling coins.
Coins...
You collect coins?
No, mum.
I work in a place where
I'm always handling coins.
In a bank?
No.
In a casino?
In a toll booth.
- Who are you?
- Nicolás.
- Isn't my daughter lovely?
- Mum!
Let him tell you you're lovely...
- Tell her...
- Mum...
You're lovely... really lovely.
That's it.
See? Nothing to it.
Alright?
I'm worried about global warming.
- Family affairs...
- No... about the glaciers...
No, I mean what's just happened...
family affairs.
You choose your family,
but not your friends.
I mean, you don't choose your family
but you do choose your friends...
I liked the idea of you meeting them,
especially you.
I don't know... since you've been
abandoned by so many people...
your grandfather's died,
your girlfriend's left you...
so you could see a few people.
Well, thanks.
All the same it wasn't
because of them I threw up...
We all have our problems.
But I still don't know yours.
- Are you busy?
- Right now?
No... well... I'm driving, but tell me...
I know we're not going
out together or anything but...
- Won't you give me a kiss?
- What?
On the mouth...
- A kiss?
- Please...
Look, why don't
you pull up over there?
Don't get me wrong, I won't...
If I'm asking you for a kiss...
it's because I think it would
do me good and I need it.
You may see me rabbiting on but
inside I'm crying, but don't worry.
Will you give me a kiss?
Thanks... that's it... let's go...
Abril?
Happy birthday, dear Abril...
happy birthday to you.
Alfred...
You choose your friends,
not your family...
No, you don't choose them.
- Good morning.
- Morning.
I've come to register for
the competition today.
Alone?
You're the hotel receptionist, aren't you?
Do you remember me?
- Alone?
- Alone.
- Name?
- Alfred...
Surname?
Elliot... Alfred Elliot...
Registration costs fifteen pesos.
How did this competition
get onto Internet?
Everything's on Internet.
How are you?
Well, very well.
- And how are you?
- Fine, fine...
They sang you
Happy Birthday last night...
Ah... yes...
- Did you already know him?
- Who?
- The guy who plays the piano in the
hotel... - No...
And how did he know
it was your birthday?
Don't you think that's weird?
He reminds me of the Wizard of Oz.
What's a pianist doing in that hotel?
The Wizard controls everything...
It's as if he knew things about us.
And in the end he helps them...
I feel he's following me.
How old are you?
Hey, look! Little fish.
Alfred...
- Hello.
Hello.
Hello. I've had this
white streak since I was 12.
- You never let me answer you...
- It looks good on you...
- lf I'd known it meant so much for you...
- Don't worry.
Good luck.
What are you doing out here?
The following contestant is
Alfred Elliot...
from the capital.
- Good evening.
- The microphone's for the presentation...
Well, first of all I'd like to apologise.
I'm here to dance supposedly,
to do something that makes me happy,
that distracts me from
the misery around me.
And I want you to know
I'm not going to do it,
I'm not going to dance.
It's nothing to do with you.
Miramar's lovely... the people too.
Actually, I've not met
many people because...
well, I don't know why but
I've not seen anyone anywhere...
maybe because of the cold,
maybe because everyone's warm at
home and doesn't want to go out.
I've got a real problem with happiness.
Stable people scare me.
I'm not going to get
all sensitive and say;
'the way things are in this
worid you can't be happy.'
No, no, no...
I knew I knew the way things
would be in the worid.
This has only just begun. The way things
are we deserve much more...
I don't want to generalise...
I don't like to generalise...
although I do like surveys.
I'm a caring sort. We have to care.
I walk down the street and
if a guy gives me a flyer I take it.
I realise that the guy
'has' to give out flyers,
I also know he's going to give me
two stuck together instead of one.
But I'll take it and I won't drop
it in the street, no, no, no...
I carry on walking until
I find a bin to throw it in.
And don't tell me I'm immature
and refuse to grow up.
No... why grow up?
Have you seen this?
I'm dying, I'm dying...
You danced really well last night...
- Were you there?
- Of course I was there.
Did you think I'd miss it?
- I danced well, didn't I?
- Very well.
But it was all for nothing.
Why did they leave?
Why did they leave me alone?
Alfred... Nicolás loves you. Abril too,
but they need each other right now.
But that doesn't mean
you are worth any less.
You were great last night, fabulous.
You've got a marvellous
future ahead of you.
You don't need me or anyone
to tell you what you're worth, see?
Have you tried the cake
they serve at breakfast?
- Delicious.
- Isn't it?
I'm off, Alfred, see you around...
See you...
Is something wrong?
What are we doing here?
I don't know. You were the one who
wanted to come.
What's wrong, Nicolás?
Do we have to stay
here much longer?
No, for just as long as you want.
Here...
I... I brought you to my room because...
so you wouldn't wake
up alone, because...
well... as... as you
weren't feeling too good...
so that... I mean, if you needed
anything... that's why I brought you.
I also brought you your breakfast,
but the thing is that...
...well... there was a chair and I tripped
over it... I dropped the lot...
...I got a bit burnt, nothing serious...
...the croissants are all that's left...
...but you can't eat solids anyway...
so it doesn't matter.
I don't know why I always end up
explaining everything...
like that... too much... I realise...
that I speak about things
of no importance...
well... I do realise...
but it still comes out...
I don't know, at times...
sometimes it seems that...
I speak too much.
I want to leave Miramar.
Me too.
Hello.
I danced really well last night.
I know you had to leave.
Don't worry.
- Did it hurt?
- What?
Having your tooth out.
Ah... I don't remember.
We're going back, Alfred...
Yes, I know.
That's fine.
Our last breakfast together...
- I'm staying.
- What?
I'm staying.
- Where are you staying?
- Here.
- But you have to go back.
- Why?
What do you mean 'why'?
I have to stay and live here.
The air's different.
Don't worry...
I'll be alright.
- Thanks.
- You're welcome.
- Alright?
- Yes.
I think the three of us have something
to say to each other...
I want to say that there
are three people just like us
having breakfast at our table.
That cake...
I want to say thank you
for having come with me...
We've come for each other,
each with the problems of the other...
Yes, well... right... thanks.
I wanted to say,
Nicolás, I love you and
you're a good friend.
OK, shall we go?
What?
What's wrong?
- Nothing...
- What?
- The horoscope...
- The chewing gum horoscope?
What? What does it say?
What does it say?
Subs. riped by bluciano for
www.clan-sudamerica.net