What happened to the dog?
I don't know. He must be around.
They're getting scarce.
Yes. And we'll be out soon.
There must be something we can do...
If you need them?
Use them. Period.
And don't ask any questions...
Fran Zembrino, the actress' son
Disappeared in this cave
with two others guys.
Renzo, this isn't
really news!
Not yet, but it could be.
- I want you there just in case.
- We'll be the only ones there.
Better still.
Did you explain it to him?
Trust me.
- I want us go back there right now.
- What's the matter?
We still have all afternoon.
- We have all our life.
- One moment please,
they're sleeping.
They'II be right with you.
- Thanks.
- Let me decide what's best for me.
Maria I'd write a blank check
for each and every word.
Beware of those fantasies smart ass.
Or you'll end up with nothing.
You dote on those fantasies.
I live on fantasy.
Happiness wasn't meant for me.
- Hello.
- Sorry. Did I wake you?
Yes, this is a town. At this time
of day, we are all sleeping.
- Can I make a reservation?
- No, you can't. It's siesta time.
OK. Sweet dreams.
Just leave me alone.
I could never be faithful.
Not you, nor anybody.
This is Lala Zembrino,
one of her last photos.
And this is a photo of the cave...
And you want us there because
Lala Zembrino's son is missing?
Yes. And because she
may show up in the town.
Will they come and get us?
No. They'll wait for us to leave.
Why?
No one in this town
dares come in here.
- I thought she was dead.
- Who knows?
There was no funeral...
One day she just vanished.
That was forty years ago.
He disappeared a few days ago
and the mother had been in that cave
- Do you have enough?
- Yes. I still have some.
Here, take a few more in case...
See? It's got rhythm.
No matter what he says,
he keeps his rhythm.
Keeps them glued to the TV.
- I won't be able to speak that fast.
- Don't worry.
It's easy.
I'll explain later. Love you.
I tried to make reservations
by phone but no one took them.
Don't worry about it.
Renzo's made them already.
Renzo?
Julieta. Isn't this all a bit strange?
Don't worry about it.
Just be careful.
- What do you mean, careful?
- Yes, it's one a day,
a while before recording.
Why? What happens?
I have no idea.
But just in case, take only one.
No, really. I don't know...
maybe we shouldn't be...
Trust me.
They can't harm you.
Everybody's taken them
and nothing ever happened.
OK?
Is this the Pablo
you mentioned?
Yes.
Take it.
Come on, don't worry.
I'll register you in.
Who's this beauty in the photo?
Ah... a friend.
Don't you recognize her?
It's Lala Zembrino, the actress.
Of course.
I meant the other one.
Ah... her?
That's me. Why?
Hello.
Is something the matter?
No. I was... like transported.
That rhythm...
An allegro con fuoco. Right?
Yes.
You're the guy who...
called yesterday, right?
The very same.
What's your room number?
Room five.
This way.
- You treated me really badly.
- Normal.
- Don't you want people to stay here?
- Don't really care.
I just want to get out of here.
- You're journalists, aren't you?
- Yes.
I didn't imagine you like this.
- How then?
- I don't know.
I didn't expect
sensitive souls to music.
- Well, let me be the exception.
- Sure.
You can ask my aunt for breakfast
between 8:30 and 10:30.
The towels are in the closet...
Don't throw the paper
in the toilet. It clogs.
Don't worry. We sensitive souls
don't use the bathroom.
- And where do you want to go to?
- To Buenos Aires.
- What for?
- I'm preparing for a piano audition.
You play really well.
- How old are you?
- How old do you think?
- I don't know, not old.
- Well, I'm older than you think.
- Here are the keys.
- Thanks.
How'd you know the rhythm
on the metronome?
I can't tell you.
It's a secret.
And if I told you how old I am?
In that case, it's different.
- But you'd have to go first.
- Forget it. I don't trust you.
OK. Come here.
Give me your hand.
Well... what about our deal?
Fourteen...
on Saturday.
Tree explorers disappear in a cave.
Fran Zembrino, Igor and Mauricio.
Fran is trapped where his mother
disappeared years ago.
Lala Zembrino,
the renowned actress.
Just a few pictures remain.
Fran was raised
by nannies far from his mother,
of whom we've known
nothing in 40 years.
Witness report to saw her...
What does seek in the cave?
What lies behind the lady's veil?
Everything that happens, happens,
Be the first to know, beforehand.
That's great! See.
It wasn't so bad.
What's that?
Don't touch it!
- Why?
- I don't know.
Mauricio,
I'm getting tired of this...
- This was the guide.
- What guide?
My mother's.
How do you know that?
He was the one who died.
- Is him?
- No, this is Narciso.
Metronome.
What's the matter, Ana?
- I'm losing my rhythm.
- You should practice more.
The class is over.
Ana, you have a good ear.
But it's not enough.
Let's leave this piece for now.
- But the exam is on Wednesday.
- You need to increase the speed.
Let's leave it for next year.
They won't have me next year.
I'll be too old.
- Bye.
- Who is she?
- Just a friend.
Now she's going to start again.
It's a difficult piece.
And very fast.
It reminds me of something.
- Isn't it from a film?
- No, but it resembles "The Hands of Orlac"
- Could be. How'd it go?
- He's a pianist
who loses his hands in an accident.
He has a hand transplant.
That's it! He wanted to play
this piece but couldn't.
- Why?
- His hands belonged to an assassin
and when he started playing,
he had criminal urges.
Those films are all the same.
You cannot alter the natural order.
He who rebels
suffers terribly in the end.
- That's the way it is.
- Not always.
- Let's change the subject?
- Don't worry.
For something to happen, she has to
play two consecutive musical phrases
At last!
What will you have for dinner?
- Need any help?
- No.
You should use gloves for that.
This is how we do it here.
- What are you doing up so early?
- I couldn't sleep.
Must be your heart.
It beats too fast.
- Could be...
- Where's your girlfriend?
- Sleeping.
- So... she is your girlfriend.
No. She's my wife, actually.
- What's the matter?
- Nothing.
You should care for your hands
if you play the piano.
- It's nothing.
- Show me.
- What for? I'm fine.
- Let me see.
- Let me put cream on that.
- You use cream?
Not me, my wife.
Nice!
What do you keep inside it?
It's a secret.
Aren't you going to tell me?
- No.
- Why not?
If you won't tell me, don't.
You'll tell me at some point.
I'll find something
to negotiate with.
We'd have to get to know
each other too well.
I don't think
I'd even tell you then.
Stop. Don't you feel
something weird here?
Something that's holding us back...
No, not me. And you?
Me neither.
Let me see the map?
We're here,
there should be a trail here.
And where is it?
The place caves in, Mauricio.
That can change the trails.
What do you mean by
trails can change?
Yes... maybe.
So, the places we've passed
they don't exist anymore?
Fran.
What now?
Well, if the trails change
our only chance is to get lost.
If so, we're doing great.
Little is known of the explorers
who escaped from the cave.
No one ever said a world.
As if they all...
guarded a common secret.
They say that the cave
gradually swallowed.
The few men who ventured in.
Maybe Fran
needed to travel
to the end of this labyrinth
where his mother was lost
many years ago.
Everything that happens, happens.
Be the first to know, beforehand.
Good.
- What's the matter?
- Nothing.
- Are you sure?
- Yes, everything's fine
- You're acting weird.
- I'm a little dizzy.
It's happened before.
I feel as
if you were talking slower.
When, before?
Why didn't you tell me?
I told you it was weird
from the beginning.
- How much did you take?
- Just one. Count them.
- What are you doing?
- I'm keeping them.
You're not taking any.
- You'll get in trouble, Julieta?
- I don't care.
They'd be stupid to fire me
because of this.
They'll fire you then.
I'll find something else.
I don't yet understand
why you wanted me to come.
I thought it would do you good.
That if we could share something
maybe things got better between us.
Or... did you want me to meet Pablo?
That has nothing to do with it.
Although, maybe, this needed
a definition of some sort.
Let's head back guys!
- How?
- I don't know. Let's try that way...
I'm not going back.
Well then, I'm leaving by myself.
I think you should come with us.
- Why?
- Because you're really scared.
And that attracts danger.
Let him go then, Fran.
I'm not following you.
I'm not going with a madman.
Can you hear that?
- What?
- The absolute silence.
It's gone. It rarely happens.
It's as if the whole world stopped.
The animals are quiet and the wind
is still for a few seconds.
Hey!
Are you going to town for dinner?
Yes, to see what's happening.
If you want, we can have dinner
then, you can do your thing.
Thanks. I prefer to do my own thing.
- I'm dead tired.
- OK. Bye.
- Another time.
- See you.
- Excuse me. Have you seen my niece?
- No
- We saw her this morning.
- She's nowhere.
I'm going into town.
Maybe somebody saw her.
Don't worry,
she must have a boy somewhere.
I don't think so.
She should be back.
I rarely go out myself. I don't
like going out alone at night.
- Shall I go with you?
- It's not necessary.
- You must have things to do.
- No, I'll go with you.
Remember we have
an early start tomorrow...
He's dead, Fran.
In the end, he was right.
There is something funny here.
She only cares about her piano.
She says the town boys
are all stupid.
I think she's left town.
She's obsessed with leaving.
It's my fault for letting
Carmen put those ideas in her head.
- Who is Carmen?
- Her piano teacher.
Let's go to her house. I called her
today but she didn't answer.
Carmen!
I think we found her.
Felipe, we have to talk to Carmen.
Come on Felipe...
Just for a second.
What is it that you want?
Don't just stand there
like an idiot?
Have you seen my niece?
She's definitely not here.
Just what we needed.
- Did she say anything about leaving?
- No.
Hello.
Just keep on putting
those ideas into her head.
Don't start that again.
I'd better not say
what I'm thinking.
There are men present.
But if she's left,
it's on your account...
If so, don't worry. She hasn't
got a chance at the audition...
Excuse me.
Are you coming from the cave?
- Did you see my niece?
- No.
Are you sure?
We haven't seen her for hours.
The last time someone saw her,
she was around there.
Don't worry, Ma'am.
She'II show up.
All right. Thank you.
What was that?
I don't know.
Fran!
It's her writing.
- Fran, did you see that?
- Yes.
Look at that.
Were you out all night?
Yeah. We didn't find her.
I'll take a shower and we can go.
It's OK to worry...
but don't forget we're working.
I won't neglect the work.
She must have run away a hundred
times. It's like that in small towns
She probably dates
the milkman since she was seven.
You're adorable, today.
Thanks, love.
Sometimes,
you look like the fourteen year old.
Fourteen?
I thought she was older.
She's a kid.
Are you jealous?
Sorry. I didn't mean to scare you.
- Any news on your niece?
- No.
- What do you want?
- I'm a little hungry.
- So?
- I woke up and couldn't sleep.
Ah... you slept?
Why? Does it worry you?
No, look this is off limits.
The dining room opens at eight.
So what then? I'm hungry.
I told you.
You can't be in here, wait outside.
OK.
Call me if you need anything.
I'm fine. Don't go looking for me.
You won't find me. Ana
I'm waiting for you
Are you OK?
Can you hear me?
Let me see.
Are you Ana?
Can you hear me?
Can you talk...
What took you so long?
Why? How long has it been?
For you, it's been a night.
But for me, a long time.
- No, don't.
- Don't worry, she can't see us.
- Why?
- Because we're moving too fast.
Are we moving too fast
or is it that they've stopped?
No, they're moving as usual.
It is us who are in fast motion
and see them like that.
So, you were waiting for me?
Yes. I'd hoped
you'd know how to get back.
But, it seems you have no idea.
I guess the effect
must wear off at some point.
Or, we'll just have to get
used to one other.
Yes.
Well, I'm going to bed.
I'm a little tired.
- What? Are you still taking siestas?
- It's not a nap.
- Yes it is. It's day time.
- But it's a long time before dark.
No, wait. I had a busy day.
- Pick your house of choice.
- Cool.
Good morning.
How long did I sleep?
A few seconds with any luck.
That's more than enough.
- How did you now I was here?
- It's the biggest house and bed in town.
I used to come here too at first.
If you've tried it all, then tell me
what's best and we can save time.
Mine's the best but,
I'm not going to share it with you.
The bed or the house?
Neither.
Did you have an allergic reaction?
My back itches all over.
That's not a symptom,
it's just the grime.
I think I preferred you
as a teenager.
I don't think so.
- What are you doing?
- I'm trying to scratch myself.
If only it had longer legs.
Can you help me?
A little more to the left and up...
Harder and further down.
Towards the centre,
Lower...
Lower.
There.
That's enough.
Come with me.
I'll show you something,
you'll want to see.
I discovered a way out of the cave.
No one knows it.
- How did you find it?
- I had lots of time.
When I went in, I left signs to
avoid getting lost.
- And, did you see them?
- Yes. I signaled the way out.
Look.
- What about the rest?
- One died.
The other, didn't follow the signs.
- Or he didn't see them?
- Yes he did.
He decided to stay,
to find something.
- Looking for what?
- I don't know.
They found a manuscript.
It mentioned a substance
it could only be found
in that type of soil.
- Do they have enough food?
- I don't know.
Now they can leave
if they want to.
Come on. I need more clothes.
It will be hot when the sun is out.
- Are you wearing your old clothes?
- No, I'll use my mother's.
- And where is she?
- She died.
My aunt told me
she kept her old clothes.
She tries them on
to see if they fit...
but she never gets thin
so they must be in the closet.
- We should come back another day.
- What's the matter?
- Nothing.
- Let me see.
Ana, come here!
I'd better not.
- Why? It's something natural.
- But she's my aunt.
So? Don't aunts have sex?
- What?
- Don't they have sex?
- OK. Well...
- Come on, choose some clothes.
Don't tell me that you've never
spied on anyone in all this time.
- That's what you'd have done.
- You know, I don't believe you.
You'II never know, will you?
So you think you know me well?
I don't see how when
I was a girl, you would...
- I... what? Tell me.
- Nothing.
Well... I haven't talked
to anyone in a while.
So if you'd just keep quiet.
He's finally opened. Going in
through the back was uncomfortable.
Why is there so little food?
I've been eating it all.
Could I make dinner?
Please yourself.
But mind you, I'm not easy.
You're not?
How about roast lamb
with mashed peas and mint sauce?
You won't find that here.
There are chips, nuts...
That sort of thing.
No. You'll like it.
- I don't know, I'd have to try it.
- You'll see...
Why don't you pick the wine?
You'll like this one,
it's expensive.
No, this doesn't go with lamb.
We should take... A young Malbec.
- As you wish. I'm having coke.
- No you're not!
- What are you doing?
- I taking them just in case.
No.
- I'll take them.
It's the best with chips.
- What are you doing?
- We'll get it later.
- I don't have much money.
- Are you going to pay?
Sure.
I've known the owner all my life.
I'm not going to steal.
Not this either.
- Where are you getting the money from?
- Stealing it from the bank.
What's wrong?
Nothing, I'll be fine.
It must be the poor diet.
You are going to have a proper meal.
A while ago, you told me
it would take a minute
Good things take time.
Are you OK?
I don't know.
- Maybe the effect is wearing off?
- I hope not.
And why not?
Will you bring me the chips?
Don't eat junk.
I'll speed up dinner.
Are you eating junk?
It doesn't cook.
I don't know why.
To cook with this fire
you'd need years.
- Why didn't you tell me?
- Because you didn't ask.
But we went to the supermarket,
got the meat...
- Did you know this would happen?
- Yes.
But you had to
experience it for yourself.
I see you're feeling better,
aren't you?
And I'll be even better
when you beg me for chips.
- That'll never happen.
- Are you going to starve then?
No. You'll give me one
without my asking.
- You're crazy.
- Then, I'll take it by force now.
- I'll report you.
- To whom?
You're taking advantage
of the situation!
No, you are. Come here!
At last. I thought
I'd never manage it.
Here is your prize.
I'm tired of breakfast.
What will we do when
there is nothing left in this town?
- Move to another one.
- Did you ever try that?
Yes...
but I came right back.
I knew you'd find me someday.
Plus, there were no pianos in tune.
I often imagined this...
- but something is missing.
- And what is that?
To be able to tell somebody.
Tell it to me. I'm Carmen.
Well...
Remember this guy
we didn't like that much?
Who? The good looking one?
No, he was normal.
OK. Well, I'm giving him a chance.
Why is that?
I don't even know why.
And... what else?
- He has a problem.
- What?
He's married...
He must look at this
as a minor episode in his life.
I don't think so. I know the sort.
He seems pretty hooked.
Plus, I feel so weird.
I don't let him even get close.
What about him?
He's a little slow.
He respects my space.
What a fool. I thought
they didn't make those anymore.
It seems that they do.
I think you should choose
your friends better.
Yes. I agree.
- OK. Now it's your turn.
- For what?
Your turn to tell someone.
Mine? I don't need to tell anyone.
Come on, your go.
Talk...
- I know what I'm doing.
- Don't get angry.
- Any news on your niece?
- Yes. She left a letter...
She'll be back
when she runs out of money.
Good morning.
Will you be staying?
- No, I just want something to eat.
- You look familiar.
- Is this your first time here?
- No, I was here as a child. See?
- I never forget a face.
- Yes, you seem very observant.
- I can only offer you tea or coffee.
- I have no toast or croissants.
- I need to eat.
- I've been robbed.
- That's terrible.
We're all missing things.
You must have
something hot and salty.
Some pasta perhaps...
At this time of day?
I have money, to pay you.
- Hello?
- Hello, Gise.
- Where have you been?
- Here... Wasting my time.
- Anything on our story?
- Not that I've seen.
People have been asking about you.
Really? Put Renzo on.
He's not here.
We haven't heard from him lately.
If you see him,
tell him to call me.
Bye.
- Have you seen Alex?
- No.
Where are you?
Here. Hugging you
How do I go back?
A matter of time
- How are you?
- OK.
- OK, I think.
- You're back so soon!
- To me, it seemed forever.
- I was going to wait.
- Obviously. I waited for you.
- What did you wait?
- For years, for you to grow up.
- That was really fast.
But I was ready to wait
for as long as it took.
- What a liar!
- No, I mean it.
I must get to Buenos Aires.
- The audition is today.
- I'm going with you.
What?
And what will you tell your wife.
It doesn't matter. Don't worry.
I want us to stay together.
After all we've been through...
Don't exaggerate.
It was only three minutes.
Wait for me
at the door at the theatre.
OK. I'II count on you.
- Finally. Where have you been?
- I went for a walk.
- What's the matter?
- I took too many.
How many? Are you crazy?
I told you it could be dangerous.
Don't worry. Now, just tell me
everything you know about this.
What I know is that Renzo
buys them from a so called Narciso.
When you recover,
we have work to do.
They are asking too many questions.
If they catch us,
- we'll be wasting the morning.
- I can't go on.
I can't go on,
this is all crazy.
Maybe. But you should
have listened. Look at you...
so dirty...
Didn't you just take a bath?
I'm quitting
and I think you should too.
Let's get today over with.
We'll talk about it later.
Narciso.
I couldn't find you
and was really scared.
- Why?
- I don't know.
I though something could happen...
For a second,
I thought you wouldn't come back.
He's delirious.
Says he saw a virgin
who helped them get out.
- Igor?
- Who are you?
- I believe you.
Then tell them to follow
the signs and get Fran.
Why doesn't he follow them?
What is he looking for?
He wants to know
why he was abandoned.
I took something.
I was the first woman
to even try it,
Narciso and I traveled
to the centre of the cave...
Where there was a spring
of red glowing liquid.
He was always afraid
of the unknown...
and wanted me to try it first.
Everything began to slow down.
Narciso was petrified...
when he saw me... disappear.
The pills are more dangerous
than we thought.
I need you to give them all back.
Why? What happened?
They found Renzo's body.
It looked 120 years old...
- I don't have any left.
- They need to study the pills.
- I don't have any.
- Where are the missing pills then?
I don't know.
It's hard to explain.
What are you saying?
And what the fuck
are you looking at?
Stop.
- What are you doing?
- Let me see.
- Why did you take them?
- I didn't. Ana did...
- Who's Ana?
- She's the girl you saw
this morning
when you were with Pablo.
- How do you know that?
- Because I saw you.
I was looking for you
while you were spying on me?
No. It's hard to explain.
And, you wouldn't believe me.
It doesn't matter!
Say it regardless.
I was so accelerated
that you couldn't see me.
To me, it was
as if time had stopped.
For you,
time stopped a long time ago.
- You're right. More than a year ago.
- Since you stopped working.
No, since you lost interest in me.
- Why do you say that?
- Because it's true.
- Tell me who Ana is.
- What for? It's not worth it.
- I want to hear it.
- She's the hotel owner's niece.
For you it's been a moment,
for us, much longer.
- I don't understand.
- It's weird but that's how it is.
But she grew old and you didn't.
I accelerated for a moment.
She accelerated all night.
Where are you going?
To Buenos Aires.
What?
Don't do this to me.
You were a one night stand.
- And you did for love?
- No, I'm fine on my own.
Are you in love
with the chauffeur?
- No! Lord, no!
- Lf it's serious, ask him to stay.
- The guy is up for grabs.
- You're crazy?
- Let him go.
- So... what's all the fuss about?
- What's the matter?
- Nothing. Just pay and let's go.
What is happening here.
It won't start.
Let's see... start the car.
- What's happening?
- Come on, give it some more.
- Go on...
- Well? What's wrong?
It won't work.
Call the mechanic.
If a normal minute...
equals 1440 minutes
of accelerated time...
This girl...
the kid...
spent nine hours,
it means she's been 7.000, 700...
Alex, it was much easier
to say it's over between us?
Excuse me.
Are the auditions over?
- Yes.
- I'm looking for a friend.
Ana Berardi. Have you seen her?
Let's see...
No, there's no one with that name.
Could you check again?
She has light brown hair,
she's thin, has blond curls,
wears an antique locket.
I know!
Her ID said she was fourteen.
- Come on!
- Did she audition?
No, she was too old
for the orchestra.
- Why? What's the age limit?
- Fifteen.
Though, she said she'd audition
for the symphonic orchestra.
- And when is that?
- Tomorrow. At 10 am.
- She has to learn all repertoires
- She may just make it...
From one day to he next?
She won't have time.
Plus, there is something
you can only achieve with time.
Sorry.
Ana, I thought I'd never find you.
Renzo's dead.
Give me the pills...
- Why weren't you here before?
- It got complicated, Ana.
This is very dangerous...
It's too late now.
What did you do?
I thought you wouldn't come.
No, give it to me.
I'II go with you.
I don't have any.
I hope we meet again.
Who are you?
Your son, Fran.
Stay there.
Don't move.
How could you
lock her up like this?
I didn't force her.
She wanted to isolate herself.
To stop time
and be remembered like that.
I had to create a world...
in which nothing moved.
You are a coward!
You gave her something
you'd never have taken.
I had to spare her
from the passing of time.
And did so as best I could.
Now it's your turn to take it
and die in the same way Renzo did.
These are for you.
All for you.
- Fran!
- Who are you?
I need to find the person
who helped you out of the cave.
Is this what you want?
- Yes.
- No.
This is the last of it.
There are no more raw materials.
- The cave is dried up.
- Give it to me! I have to find her.
It's not worth it.
They'll ruin your life.
- They took everything I had.
- And me.
But I still have
some time to get her back.
Is this staying?
No, we're taking it.
I've had it since I was a child.
Don't you want to take that one too.
- You always liked it.
- OK. Thanks.
What did you tell him?
That you were my uncle.
- Shall we go in?
- I'll be right there.
Ripped by Skywalker for
www.clan-sudamerica.com.ar