I don't understand why
they took a night flight.
They should have taken
the one I told them.
I hope Meme is ready
or we'll be late.
Don't forget. Tell Olguita
to make meat pie.
With the mad cow matter, they
haven't had meat in months.
Ana called yesterday. I told her:
Our kids are arriving.
- Good morning.
- Hello.
Look at Silvina Chediek's house.
Lovely! This is so fun.
Mona told me they are not
their houses.
They borrow them
for the photos.
They look so comfortable.
They seem to be at home.
In their dressing gowns.
I hope Montse will not wear
again...
...that horrible dress
from Barcelona
I just remembered
when I pinched Vilas' ass.
I had not met you yet.
I couldn't resist.
Yes, yes.
No, no, no.
Okay, I'll tell her.
I won't forget.
Yes. Bye. See you.
- Who was it?
- Ana.
She wouldn't stop talking about
designs she's making with Mom.
What are you watching?
A documentary about
pandas born in captivity.
It's strange.
As the mother can't handle two
cubs, she ignores one until...
...it dies, but first, she goes
crazy trying to handle two.
I don't know if she can't raise
them as a consequence of...
...captivity or because
that is her nature.
Captivity, for sure.
A big animal can handle
two cubs.
It's over.
- Let's go to my room.
- Okay.
I bought Bowie's record.
- You queer!
- You're prettier every day.
- My baby!
- Hi, Olguita!
Hello. We missed you here!
- Children, we're home.
- Olguita!
It's so nice to see you!
- Olguita, Montse, my wife.
- How do you do? - Hi.
- Montse, she's Olga. - Pleased to
meet you. - Come in, Montse.
- I'm coming.
- Come on.
Let me help you, Dad.
- Let me take it, Olguita.
- No, my boy.
Let me do it, Olga.
Hi. You must be Meme.
Hello.
Hi!
How are you?
- Hi! How are you?
- Fine.
- She is Montse, my wife.
- Yes, we met.
My baby! Olguita made
meat pie for you.
His favorite. Leave your
luggage and wash your hands.
Dinner is served.
Wash up! Come eat!
I'll tell him to call you
after lunch.
Yes, mother.
He'll call you after lunch!
He looks great, as usual.
Thinner than when
he got married.
I'll tell you later. They're
upstairs. They're leaving...
...their luggage and...
Lunch, mother.
Well, not much.
They told me about Julio,
Daniel's brother.
The one I think
is an asshole.
They're all assholes, yes.
A wedding suite?
- My mother. Everything okay?
- Yes.
A little shaken but fine.
I'm exhausted.
I could not sleep.
You're so stubborn. I told you
to take something.
But you didn't.
Thanks, Olguita.
What's wrong with her?
She doesn't like cigarettes.
No smoking when she's around.
- Not even Lucía nor me.
- I didn't know.
- She never liked it.
- I didn't remember.
- Eze, call Granny.
- I'll call her later.
I'm going to Ariel's.
No, call her now. She's been
calling all morning.
We have a busy day today.
Okay. I'll see Ariel tomorrow.
Invite him to dinner.
Everyone's coming. Granny...
...Grandpa, Inés,
all your cousins. - Alright.
Jere, you and Meme
go get groceries...
...for tonight.
- I don't want to!
Meme, what are you doing
there? Don't make a scene.
- This is no time for your moods.
- Leave me alone.
Meme, don't answer back.
Come here.
Let's have a minute of peace!
Not if you'll always
be nagging us.
You make me sick.
You're so selfish!
- You're exaggerating.
- Am I?
You've been away too long.
- Excuse us, Montserrat.
- Don't worry.
Families argue.
They make a scandal every
time I ask them something.
That's enough, Mom.
- Cold drinks are bad for you.
- Their attitude...
...is bad for me. Jeremías,
we must talk things over.
I won't listen to you.
You two are unbelievable!
Always fighting.
If it's not one, it's the other.
But if it's against me...
...they come together.
- Your kidneys maybe.
- Yes?
- Yes, what else?
- I don't know, it hurts.
Your girlfriend from Escobar,
Vanina Cohen is here.
- So? - Nothing.
I'm having some memories.
She's fatter. I haven't seen her
in a long time.
- And you?
- What?
- Are you dumb? - Sometimes
you're impossible, you know?
How was it?
- Lucía...
- What, Mom?
Horrible wedding invitations!
They are the ones they chose.
You shouldn't have left
them up to them!
The letter is not subtle
and the watermark is huge.
- They look cheap!
- They like them.
What's this? "Santa María's
ranch. 25 de mayo county.
- Province of Buenos Aires."
- What's wrong with that?
That one.
No, that's a plane.
They're two males.
Meme might feel left out.
We, women, are very jealous,
you know?
But they fight like cats
and dogs.
They haven't helped me a bit
with the wedding party.
We would scratch our eyes out
when we were kids.
This is different. We fought
over boyfriends, clothing...
...normal stuff because
we lived together.
They fight too much.
Really. But I can understand...
...Jere because she's too
intolerant. That girl!
Always, since she was a kid.
So delicate. Yes.
- Now she's not only vegetarian,
she's "vegan". - "Vegan"?
- Yes. - "Vegan"? - It's very
weird. She eats nothing.
Olguita has to cook
very special food.
Hold on, Inés, tell Mom
to wait for me.
I have to pee.
I'm sorry!
What are you doing
locked up in the bathroom?
- We're talking.
- Finally you made up.
Now get out. I have to pee.
You should talk in your room
not in the bathroom.
Lucio, come on.
- You're fatter.
- Don't tell me.
- Bye.
- See you at the ranch.
I'll see you to the door.
- Bye, auntie.
- Bye, Power.
- Bye.
- You're so mean.
- Bye, aunt.
- Say hi to the children.
- Let's go, Mom.
- Bye, bye.
Bye.
Stop that, Ezequiel.
We have enough noise.
Come in.
Let's go.
There we go.
Occupied!
Sorry.
- Good morning.
- Hello.
Good morning.
Did you sleep well?
No, the jet lag
and the noise from outside...
...made it impossible
for me to sleep.
We'll have only ladies
for breakfast.
Ezequiel is sleeping like a log.
No, they're both awake.
I heard them talking...
...at Jere's room.
- Eavesdropping?
No, it was an accident.
Meme, how can you think that?
I went up and overheard them.
I didn't want to interrupt them.
Hand me a piece.
It's a pity your parents
couldn't make it.
They must have sad memories
from that time. Poor them!
- We interrumpt anything?
- Only your daughter's moods.
What did I do?
I didn't open my mouth.
I know your silence.
I'm looking for
my wedding dress...
...to show it to Montse. Here.
The bride's veil...
...my Mom made me, remember?
You look very pale.
Are you alright?
I overdid it last night.
- Mom, why keep all this?
- For my grandchildren.
Look, Mom.
Remember my fencing?
Careful with that!
- Stop it!
- I found it! Here it is!
Look! Unbelievable!
This is great! Fantastic.
The wreath must be here
somewhere. Yes!
Here!
Oh my God! It's okay,
it's wonderful. Look.
Yes, yes. We can tidy this up.
The flowers.
Great! I found it.
Let's go out to dinner
to celebrate, okay?
Lucía, we have other plans.
Don't stay out late.
We leave early...
...for the country tomorrow.
We won't go to bed.
And your sister's moods?
Mom, Montse wants
to see Buenos Aires.
What are you doing?
Mom!
Try it on.
Here!
- How much is it?
- Dad gave me money.
Let's go, come with me.
- You don't drink alcohol?
- No.
How can you stand up a whole
night drinking only water?
I've been with girls too.
There's no problem.
- What?! - I have many
dyke friends. I don't care.
- What?
- Dykes! Lesbians!
So?
Sorry. I thought
you were gay.
Ecstasy?
- What?
- Ecstasy, for fun.
- I'm having fun!
- Try it.
Try just a quarter!
Ezequiel is making Jere try it!
Go ahead! Tune up!
Do I leave first?
Magdalena.
What?
Nothing. I like to say your name.
- Watch out!
- Stop it! Let me go, asshole!
Wed...
...ding. 3 points.
I'm brilliant.
- I'm starving, Mom.
- Hold on a moment.
Your sister isn't back yet.
What's keeping her?
She hates the village.
- Who's winning?
- Me, of course.
- Proper names don't count, so...
- They count!
- No, they don't. That's cheating.
- Don't fight!
- That's cheating, Mom!
- Says who?
- It has always been like that.
Smart ass! - That's enough.
This isn't a competition.
It's for fun, isn't it?
- Always on his side.
- I'm not!
Don't fight over
a lousy Scrabble game!
- Jere is right.
- That's none of your business.
You're always cheating!
You can't play without cheating!
- You don't like losing.
Chicken-shit! - Stop it!
Stop that noise, please!
- You won cheating. - That's okay.
I'll remove that word.
- Leave it! - Stop it! - Leave it!
- Don't fight!
- Cheater!
- Chicken-shit!
That's enough!
- What are you doing?
- Your brothers are fighting...
...like 8 year-old brats.
What took you so long?
Jeremías, come here, please.
- The car ran out of gas. It's
Ezequiel's fault. - Fuck off!
- Ezequiel!
- All of you against me.
- Stop it!
- You always fuck me!
I ran out of gas, sucker.
- Enough!
- Stop yelling!
I yell all I want!
This is my house!
It's unbelievable!
Always the same!
Our family has
more serious problems...
...than running out of gas...
...or a Scrabble game.
- What problems?
- Olguita.
- What is it?
Close the door.
Jere, come.
Jessica, Olga's daughter,
is pregnant again.
- How old is she? - 15.
It's her second pregnancy.
- I have a theory.
- Leave the kids out of this.
You're not sure.
They're old enough. They should
get in touch with real life.
I think Olga's husband
sleeps with his daughters.
- That's impossible, Mom.
- Olga works at home...
...from Monday to Saturday.
Her husband...
...is alone with the girls
all week long.
Olga never mentions
any boyfriends.
- You make things up. - I don't.
I think about these things.
Susy's maid has
the same problem.
The lower classes in this
country have that problem.
In Spain, women die fighting
with their husbands.
You can't compare.
They're two grown-ups.
Poor Olguita. She has
a hard life, hasn't she?
How does she manage
to go on?
A car.
They must be bringing
the car.
I had to leave it at La Rábida.
No. It's only one car.
Poldo must have found it,
put some gas on...
...and brought it here.
- No, Mom, it's a city cab.
This far in a cab?
Who might be?
A cab?
- It's your mother.
- My mother?
Jeremías, Granny is here.
Get Olguita.
- They must have luggage. Let's
help them. - Let them get out.
- Hold on.
- Get under the eaves.
- Hold on a minute.
- They'll get wet. Dad!
Olga!
How can you not trust me?
How can you think that
about me?
Who else could have been?
Tell me.
- Ana Luisa.
- I don't believe it.
- What are you watching, Olga?
- The soap opera.
- It's too early.
- No. It's a foreign channel...
...from Caracas.
You don't drop by anymore.
I'm a little crazy.
Why, Male?
That woman is upsetting you.
You can't think clearly.
- You should stop seeing her.
- Who's that?
The twin sister.
That's the evil sister.
The other is the good one.
Carlos Alberto,
Ana Luisa and you...
Ana Luisa and me what?
...are brother and sister.
- What were you doing?
- Nothing.
I can't sleep.
Me neither.
Jere, turn off the fan.
What are you doing here,
Ezequiel?
- What the fuck are you doing?!
- Get out!
Are you crazy?
- Look at me!
Look at me!
- Get out!
- Look at me!
Get out!
Mom must never know.
Next time I see you, I'll kill you!
- She wouldn't believe you,
shit-head! - I'll kill you!
Asshole!
Look, they're here.
Hello. Hello, everybody.
Uncle, the mare!
I'll take it today.
- Hi.
- Take it!
Nodody's here yet?
Girls!
- You'll slander me?
- Hi.
- How are you? - Olguita,
be careful with the clothing.
Mom, leave Olga alone.
You won't find anything.
- Your kids? - Sleeping.
They're making me upset.
They're acting like
brats since they got here.
Javier and María do the same.
They fight like cats and dogs.
Now that María's married, a little
less. Everything looks great.
- How nice! How did you do it?
- I don't like those clouds.
It rained yesterday.
My sandals are ruined.
- The bride's dress?
- Simple.
Well, you know her.
Mom, stop looking at the sky.
Everyone must get ready.
The time will come
and we won't be ready.
Are those children
still sleeping?
- Hi!
- Where are you going?
- Horseriding.
- You wanna drive me crazy?
Go and get ready.
What happened to you?
- How did you get that?
- I bumped into the door.
You're so careless, son!
He'll look terrible
in the photos.
- Just a little.
- Let me see.
- This is an old lace.
- It's beautiful!
Stand up straight.
The best man looks
really handsome.
What is it?
Come here.
Do you remember the twin
sister that was kidnapped?
The old man rescued her.
But she remained hidden...
...to expose her sister.
- Her boyfriend never returned.
- No, poor guy.
They told her he died
in an accident abroad.
The waltz!
- You won't waltz?
- No, I don't feel like it.
Like on your 15th birthday.
You looked so beautiful.
- Remember? - Yes. But I can't
dance. I get confused.
- It's really easy. I'll teach you.
- I don't want to dance.
- I'll make a fool of myself.
- At your brother's wedding?
He married in Spain.
This was all mother's idea.
But you have to go.
Your granny will say...
I hold you back here and that's
why you're not on the photos.
Nobody will miss me.
Your brother will.
Your mother for sure.
Poldo, get the mare
for a photo!
What are you doing here?
They'll drive me crazy.
Look at you. You're all dirty.
Your suit is ruined.
That black eye.
Stay out...
...of the photos.
You're so stubborn!
- Vanina Cohen is looking
for you. - Vanina Cohen?
Someone invited her.
She's looking for you.
Vanina?
I can't remember her.
I don't want to ride.
I'm scared.
- Is it necessary?
- Stop fucking around.
Why can't you please my Mom?
Is it so hard?
Take a good picture
of the mare.
I have a good joke. What's
worse? To be Jew or gay?
- Jew.
- No, gay, because...
...you have to tell
your parents.
- Smile at the camera.
- Relax.
Smile, smile.
- So tense!
- It's just a mare.
Oh God!
Criticizing me?
We were remembering
when that horse...
...threw that servant.
A sack of potatoes.
You don't remember?
He died the next day.
No, that was another who
was kicked in the head.
- Don't you remember?
- You ruined my party!
- I have a knot in my stomach.
- Really.
Let's change the subject.
Oh God!
- She does it on purpose.
- Don't pay attention to her.
Don't worry about it, please.
What?
- I remembered something.
- What?
When I pinched Vilas' ass.
Remember?
- That wasn't you.
- What do you mean?
- I pinched Vilas' ass.
- No, it was...
...when we went to the races.
- We weren't at the races.
We were at the Lawn Tennis.
I was the one who pinched...
...Vilas' ass.
- Let's not fight over it.
No, but Mom tried to ruin
the party all day long...
...my children drive me crazy...
...that Spanish girl makes
a scandal with the mare...
...and now you pinched
Vilas' ass!
- No, no.
- Cheers!
It was you, my mistake.
What is it?
Can't I look at you?
You're crazy.
Get out, Ezequiel!
You shouldn't mind.
- No, that's a plane.
- And Spanish girls?
- No, they're uglier. - Uglier?
I thought they were nicer.
- They're over us.
- They're slutter.
- Some don't depilate.
- And their tits?
Lucía fell!
Daniel, Jorge, come!
- Come! Lucía fell!
- What do you mean?
We were arguing over some
nonsense. You know her.
- She tripped.
- What a fool!
- Over the walnuts.
- Lucía! What a fool!
- Lucía!
- Mom!
Your sister told me you
were fighting like two kids.
We weren't arguing
anymore.
- Are you okay? Don't move.
- I can't lie here...
...all night, can I?
- Jorge, bring the truck.
- Let's take her to the hospital.
- I'm coming, Mom.
We'll go back to Buenos Aires
right now. All the guests...
...have left.
Get the kids.
Slowly, Mom, there's no hurry.
Careful.
Where's Meme? She'll be late
for my funeral.
Let her drive.
She doesn't drink.
- Mind that you don't levy...
- Lavish, Lucía.
It's the same. Get her to drive.
- Be careful.
- Okay.
Careful, walk slowly.
You're up. Olga is not
coming today. She's dealing...
...with her daughter's
trouble. I'll be out all day.
I have to go to Ana's to work
on that design...
...I put off due to the wedding.
The wedding was
just an excuse.
I've never seen such bad taste
in a house.
You look awful. What is it?
Are you okay?
- I just got up.
- Close your eyes.
Don't dry it. I'm leaving.
I'm in a hurry.
It's impossible to look
elegant...
...in this boot.
Bye.
I can't stand this boot anymore.
As I can't drive, I took
a cab. The driver...
...drove me all over the town.
The house looks gorgeous.
Yes, I changed some things.
Tell me about you
and then we'll get to work.
- How are you with all these
changes. - Coffee?
- Yes.
- I do what I can.
- You heard about my husband
and his student? - Awful! I knew...
something was wrong when you
didn't show up at the wedding.
Then I heard. But I'd rather
you called me.
- Did you sue him?
- No. How could I?
Lucía, I just started
the divorce.
At your own home!
We should cut men's...
I won't say it.
Justina!
- Coffee or tea?
- Coffee. Light.
- Two coffees, please.
- Yes, Madam.
This maid is an angel.
How long have you had her?
My upstairs maid has
her husband sick.
I don't know what's wrong
with him. And Olguita...
...can't cope with everything.
The drawings?
I forgot them.
I forgot them!
Cover yourself, Jeremías.
You're too old for this.
Mom's gone.
Let's jacuzzi.
Answer the phone!
Oh God! They're home.
But they won't answer.
Unbelievable!
I'll drive you over.
But they're home.
- You know where they are?
- Of course.
- Careful!
- Yes.
Let me see.
No.
Where are they?
Meme!
Jere!
Where are they?
Anybody home?
No! No! No!
Let her go!
Let her go, for God's sake!
Mom! Mom!
Forgive me, Mom!
Forgive me!
Mom!
Lucía!
What are you doing, Mom?
Bring champagne.
Let's make a toast.
What are you saying, Mom?
What did you do, Mom?!
I don't know.
Bravo! Bravo!
Long live the groom
and the bride!
Need help, Daniel?
No, thank you.
Long live the groom
and the bride!
- I don't get it. - These things
happen all the time.
- I can't understand.
- I told you a thousand times.
I was in my room
and Meme was in hers.
I heard some noises in the
kitchen. I went down and found...
Mom pointing a gun at her head.
I struggled with her
and got hurt.
Can't have a gun in the house.
This fucked-up country.
- Olguita, dinner at 9.
- Yes, Madam.
It stopped raining.
I love rain.
- The kids?
- Downstairs with their father.
- And Ezequiel? - He lives
in Barcelona, remember?
Yes, sure.
Daniel hates the rain.
When the kids were little,
we went every weekend...
...to the country.
He got furious when it rained
because he couldn't...
...ride his mare.
He loved that mare.
I don't know if the kids
liked to go to the country.
I didn't.
I hate horses.
They scare me.
But I learned how to ride.
I got used to it.
But when I grew old,
I quit.
Do you have children?
No.
Touch me slowly
Kiss my mouth
...almost indifferently
Kiss my mouth...
Caress me
Why is it so easy
to love you?
Life will be reckless
Desire. Live.
Touch you, lose myself
How can I know you
without having you?
Life will be reckless
Suffer. Cry till you break
How can I love you
without fearing you?
How can I know you
without having you?
How can I love you?
Life will be reckless
Touch me...
...slowly
Kiss...
...my mouth
Ripped by www.clan-sudamerica.com.ar