It's a question I ask myself
all the time.
It's not easy for me
to find an answer.
Can destiny be changed?
How much can we change
things?
My father asked himself the
same thing.
But he believed
it was impossible.
That each one, each person...
...was destined to an irreversible
story and we are prisoners of it.
And even though you struggle,
everything stays the same.
One day he thought
he had the answer.
IS THERE A WAY OUT?
Beloved ones, we are gathered
here today to pay farewell to...
Angel. Our beloved husband,
father, brother, and friend.
For whom we are going to pray
that his soul finds the path...
...to peace and divine salvation.
Our father who art in heaven...
...hallowed be thy name. Thy
kingdom come, thy will be done...
...on earth as it is in heaven.
Give us today our
daily bread...
...forgive our trespasses as we forgive
those who trespass against us.
Lead us not into temptation and
deliver us from evil. Amen.
How can it come to this?
Can you tell me how this situation
can can come about?
How a railroad
worker comes to this?
It was a long time.
It was 35 years. Do you
understand what I say?
Lmagine it. My father
was a railroad worker.
My brother was a
a railroad worker.
I was 15 when I began.
It was my only job.
We are railroad workers.
Maybe that's not
worth anything now.
For us it was very important.
It was our source of work, but...
...it was also... our second home.
Everything was shared. Even
more so when far from home.
For us it was very important.
We took it very seriously.
That's why we often worked
under hard conditions.
- It's nothing.
- Hurry!
- Come on!
- An ambulance!
Shit!
But the rules of the game
changed now?
- No.
- What happened?
No, the rules of the game didn't
change. There is no more game.
It doesn't matter how we look at
it. This is clear. After a full...
study and investigative work,
where it was proved that parts...
of the northern route are
greatly deteriorated and the cost...
of repairs is greater than
the profits, the representative...
commission of the rights of the
South Railroad Company has...
decided the closure
of the route.
Stop it. You've already read it 7
times. We won't learn it by heart.
It's all lies. And you know that.
The route's perfect.
The train can run. It's just they are
not interested because of business.
They don't give a shit about
anything. About the towns that...
lose the train. They don't
give a shit about us.
Let's see. If we retire voluntarily
and accept the money they're...
offering, we have to forget
about everything. Isn't there...
...anything in between that we
can negotiate? - We have to...
to negotiate keeping our jobs.
That's essential.
We must keep working.
At the same time we...
have to call the press and draw
attention. Television. Everyone.
- They have to know what's
happening here. - No, Paquito.
There's no keeping our jobs. They've
already told you they don't need you
They don't care about
ending up without trains.
And the chance for a
transfer?
No, that's impossible.
We aren't the only route
that closed. And it...
seems to me they're going
to close quite a few more.
What we have to do is
the same as they did at...
La Estrella meat packers.
They won't like that.
That way
they would understand.
What did they do
at La Estrella?
They threw the manager into the
meat grinder.
- They ground him up?
- No, just an arm.
Why don't we take the station?
That's what we should do.
The situation is complicated. I
honestly don't think any forceful...
...measure would get results.
What we have to do
is negotiate...
the best possible severance pay.
Why are we...
we going to take a station
where no trains go by?
This was decided some time ago. We
can't think it's going to get fixed.
It's like Raul says, this was
something they had pending.
Boys, let's see if we understand. We
don't work for that State anymore.
These guys are different.
What's wrong with you, Antonio?
Are you in favour of them?
You keep saying
that we settle.
Don't fuck with me, Gomez.
You know the Union always tries
to get the best for the workers.
The money is there now.
After a while, these guys
will get up and leave...
this goes over to the Work
Ministry, to the lawyers.
And who knows
when we'll get paid.
No, I say there is nothing to
negotiate. Nothing.
No severance pay, transfer
or television. Nothing.
Because if there were something
to negotiate...
poor Angelito wouldn't have
killed himself.
- Come on, Braulio, don't talk
bullshit. - Am I? And what...
...the hell are you saying?
I'm not talking bullshit.
So I am the only one talking
nonsense? If you like them...
sticking a finger up your ass,
it's your thing.
As for me,
nobody touches my ass.
- Why don't you go to hell?
- Don't disrespect me.
Don't disrespect me.
Look at yourself, deadbeat.
- Suck mine!
- Calm down.
Stay out of this,
you fucking brat!
- Don't yell at me!
- Who's yelling at you?
Stay out!
You prick!
No, Carlitos. They are a bunch
of sons of bitches.
How long is it until my
retirement? ¿2 years? And...
they want me to retire now.
Don't they want me to hand them my
ass too? Besides, did you read this?
Yes, I did.
- Did you read it well?
- Yes.
This was written by a terrible
son of a bitch. No, this is a crime.
Signing this is signing
a deal with the devil.
At least the devil throws in
a couple of naked women.
It's a bunch of shit,
but there's no other way.
There aren't any balls left,
that's what happens!
Everyone protests and complains
but nobody does anything.
- Are you using this cloth?
- What cloth? - This one.
- The covers? - Yes.
- No, I left them there just in case.
- I'm going to take a few.
- Take the ones you want.
I don't think they will ever be
used again. We can't sign!
That's the thing!
If they sign, within two years
you will be able to tell me...
what happened.
I'm not signing.
I know it's hard. But at some
fucking time we have to say no!
Shit!
Tute, listen to me. That friend
of yours from Constitución.
- Who?
- The one...
Careful, leave it. That's fine.
The one beaten by his wife.
- That's fine.
- Vargas.
- That one. Ask him to get you
into Vias del Sur. - No.
Antonio said that with the closure
of the route, there are no transfers.
Well, Antonio says a lot of
stupid things.
You have to move on your own.
You know that, uh?
It's more expensive. But
it's worth it because it's fresh.
The meat doesn't darken.
That guy is a lier.
There's no wine.
Can we use one of these bottles?
- No, there aren't any more.
- Are you sure?
I'm moving. I went with Carlos
to see a guy from Vias del Sur...
he said there are no
transfers.
Don't go with him. It'd be easier
to get a job for just one person.
Carlos knew the guy.
Tell me,
how long have I known you?
I don't know.
Almost 30 years.
You were a pretty guy.
Do you remember what I always
told you?
What? You told me
so many things.
What I always told you.
Yes, that you were going
to be rich.
It's not going to happen.
Is something wrong, dad?
No, nothing.
Representative of the rights of
the company.
The closure of the route because
the workers signed a voluntary...
retirement agreement.
Bunch of sons of bitches!
Who the hell
do they think they are?
Do they think I am an idiot?
You know what I'm gonna
do with this? You don't know?
No, it's not
even good for that.
It's too rough.
Hey, you.
Sign and that's it. With that
money we can pay back my brother.
I know you'll find something.
You're very handy.
If we give him the money,
we'll be broke.
We have to pay it back.
Did I say we weren't? We'll give
him part now and the other part...
When? If you
don't find anything?
New TV.
Does your head still ache?
Yes, a little.
When can I see you?
I will call you.
Don't take too long.
What did you do then?
We signed.
There was no choice.
Only the old guy
didn't sign.
They owed us two months salary. They
included that in the severance pay.
It wasn't much money.
Some debts were paid.
It didn't last long.
We had to start over again.
So... each of us did what he could.
- What do you know about guns?
- What I learned as a soldier.
What you learned as a soldier?
That's bullshit.
I am going to show you real
guns. This is a nice piece.
It's a. 45 colt. 11.25 calliber.
We'll talk about it later.
This is Israeli. Jerico. It carries
16 bullets. It's like having...
16 friends on your belt.
This is a Colt 38 special
revolver. 6 shots. This is a gem.
It's light, doesn't weigh a thing.
Take a look. Take it.
- Seems like a toy.
- Yes, but it's not a toy.
Guns are loaded by the devil
and emptied by idiots.
- Who are the idiots?
- We are.
No, not us. The idiots who stand
in front of this.
- Do you think this will work?
- How can't it work?
See Lujan tomorrow. In a few
days you'll be an expert.
The rest is easy. What?
You aren't afraid, are you?
Laura. Come on, it's late.
You could've woken me up.
The alarm didn't go off.
Didn't you heat the water?
There's water in the thermos.
The alarm did go off.
I overslept.
You could've woken me the same.
You got mad yesterday.
I brought you coffee in bed.
- Because it was 5 am.
- It was 5:30. When I get a job...
- I won't be here to wake you.
- We won't have to stay up until...
2 am figuring out what to do
about house, the mortgage.
Stop arguing. Dad, will you
turn on the water heater?
You can't take a bath now.
There's no time.
- I'll finish quickly, I swear.
- Hurry up. It's late.
OK.
- Can I have one?
- No.
Take your bath. We
won't get going if not.
Get going. Hurry up.
What job does Osvaldo have now?
What?
Osvaldo, where is he working now?
In a company. In a laboratory.
What is this idiot doing in a
laboratory?
Dad, could you open the door?
It's Juan.
Hello. How are you?
I've come to get Laura.
She's taking a bath, she overslept.
So I'd be leaving.
There's no problem. I'll wait.
Laura, this boy
is waiting for you.
Juanchi, wait for me.
I'm washing my private parts.
Don't worry.
- What job does Osvaldo have at
the laboratory? - I don't know.
- Hello. - Hi.
- It must be on the card I gave you.
- Where is it?
- Which...? - Here.
It's those products that are sold
everywhere. What's their name?
- I don't know, Susan.
- Body Herbal, here it is.
I told him you'd be
there at 3:30.
- Laura, let me in the bathroom.
- Come in, mom.
- Hi, Juan. How are you?
- Hurry. - It's late. Let's go.
- Bye, mom.
- Wait for me.
I'll be right there.
I'll take you.
Yes?
Mom, did you ring for a car?
Yes, go on and get in.
I'll take you to school.
Okay.
- A car? Look at that.
- It's late. It only costs $3.
I'm leaving. Bye.
Dress up. I ironed the shirt
your mother gave you. Bye.
Yes, Poggi?
He's outside.
The one with the flowered shirt.
Thank you.
Hello. I came recommended by
Marciani. Mingo Marciani.
Are you Poggi?
No.
Do you know where
I can find him?
He's outside talking
with a new guy I don't know.
Don't you know where he is or
how long he will be?
- Who?
- Poggi.
If you are looking for Poggi,
Poggi isn't in or out.
So he's not coming. Now, if you
are looking for Mr. Poggi, it's me.
I'm not inside because
I told you I was outside...
talking to a stranger,
who is you.
- Atilio. I was recommended by
Marciani. - Mingo. That's good.
I was looking for drivers
with their own car...
because the first
2 weeks we...
have to see how you move.
We can't give you one of ours.
- No.
- So it's better that you have one.
After that, it's 50 %.
Half and half. Partners.
- I have a car.
- A car?
Let's see it.
If you have one to start...
you give us 20 % plus a
percentage of the expenses.
- Yes. - You keep the rest
after deducting the...
gas and the flat tires.
- And, of course, you have to be
very neat. Is that clear? - Yes.
You want to work with this?
Why?
Putty.
Tires.
Give me the keys.
The way it is, the commission is 25 %
To buy flowers for your funeral.
Check it out.
Bring the papers and follow me.
Hello.
Come this way, please.
- Come in.
- Thank you.
I was telling you I was
recommended by Marciani.
- Mr. Marciani.
- Yes, of course.
So, not another word.
Let me see.
- Give me that. Do you want a mint?
- No, thanks.
I eat them because I quit smoking.
Here, babe. Look this over.
- The permit.
- No, I don't have a permit.
Marciani, Marciani. Leave it. I'll
fix that for you. Take it down, babe.
License?
- Debt-free form? - No...
- Professional driver's license.
No, Marciani knows me well.
He knows how I can drive.
That's why he sent me here. If
not I wouldn't even think of it.
Relax. He knows me, too.
That's why you are here.
I'm going to help you out.
But like this it's impossible.
I'm an orderly guy.
I don't like having to hide.
Of course not. So then?
You are a working man.
You pay me with work.
Then we photocopy everything
and in 3 days I'll get it fixed.
- How much?
If it wasn't for him,
I wouldn't take a car like that.
You take care of the mechanics
and I'll legalize...
everything.
That's 400 pesos.
400?
You pay me with a percentage.
50 and 50 until you pay back.
If you like to
work, 400 pesos...
The guys have the list of the
things you have to do to the car.
You fix it and begin.
Atilio...
- say hello to Marciani for me.
- Thank you.
- Here you have the list.
- Who's Marciani? Do I know him?
- I don't know if you know him.
But I don't have the slightest
idea who Marciani is.
- Hello, my love.
- Hello, ma.
They came from the railroad to
bring some of dad's things.
That was there for you.
- Aren't you going to read it?
- Later.
What else can I say...
except as for your
forgiveness. Forgive me, son.
How can I explain that I love
you infinitely if I am...
going to abandon you? How can I
tell you without asking for...
forgiveness that you are
my light, if I am blind.
All that I see ahead
is dark and terrible.
Why go on? Everyday becomes
longer and more difficult.
Not you or your mother deserve the
torture of having me next to you...
with this endless anguish and
everyday has more reasons to grow
and grow and turn
into such a big wall.
But it's OK. I won't give them
the pleasure of changing my mind.
Even though I have to go far from
you. I take your look with me.
What is this? A love letter?
- Juan, give it to me.
- Who's the letter from?
- Tell him to give it back.
- Take it here.
- Let's see.
- Who wrote it?
- Tell him to give it back.
- He will give it to you.
- Forgive me. I didn't know.
- It's OK, he' already dead.
- Do you miss him a lot?
- Yes.
When Marcelo showed me the train
it reminded of my old man.
I thought he
was gonna get mad.
What an ass. I had forgotten
that he wasn't here anymore.
I remember when he used to
take us for a ride on the engine.
- Do you remember when you
drove it once? - Yes.
What a shame that the engine
isn't here anymore.
- There's nothing left. They took
everything. -No, the engine is there.
- No, it's not. - The engine
is there in the workshop.
Yes.
Hello? No, he's not here now.
Who's calling? Which Karina?
Wait. He just got here.
Wait a second, please.
- Who is it?
- Karina. I don't know.
Hello? Yes, how are you?
No, there's no problem. Tell me.
Yes, I'll be there at that hour.
Good bye.
- The baby?
- He's sleeping.
He had a fever the whole day.
Did you buy the medicine?
No, I was waiting for you to
bring the money.
Wasn't your father going to lend
us the money?
We can't depend on him all the
time. He's not a bank.
- What's wrong with you?
- Who is Karina?
- Caloviero's secretary.
- He has a secretary now?
- What did she want?
- Nothing.
Why did she call then?
- For a job.
- A job?
Yes, a job. I got an interview
tomorrow in a supermarket.
- Something to do with maintenance.
- Why didn't you tell me?
I just found out.
Tomorrow...
What does Caloviero have
to do with supermarkets?
Do you have 30 cents?
Where are you going?
To my dad's house to ask for
money. Then to the drugstore to
buy the medicine. At 4 o'clock
he has to have the antibiotic.
If he wakes up give him milk.
He didn't eat much today.
Bye.
You know we aren't just talking
about a product to lose weight...
but about a revolution in the
Argentine feeding system.
That's to say, the whole world.
A feeding system proposal to...
which 15 million North
Americans have said yes to.
You are saying it. You are
witnesses. The day will come...
when you give thanks to Body
Herbal for this opportunity.
Team. Family. Before you leave
I would like to share something
deeply emotional for me. This is
something very personal.
A man, a friend, a great worker
has come into the room.
He has come to us and will
surely become another...
member of Body Herbal.
I want to introduce Carlos
Delmar. An applause, please.
Look, we've known
each other for a long time.
Believe me,
this is a unique opportunity.
You can grow with this. The
company offers 47 products.
- How about the investment?
- They give you a name.
The best is they don't ask you
to work for them...
but to work for yourself.
Do you understand?
- Sincerely, I don't...
- What do you mean you don't?
To be able to work, I have to
pay $1,200?
What do you think globalization is,
Carlos? Freedom.
It's the chance for people
like us to get into the world.
Don't get left out.
How much is it? $1,200? You'd
have your first lot of products.
How long would you
take to sell it?
Do know how many
people want to lose weight?
No.
What are you doing, Gomez?
I'm doing this.
It's the only thing I could find.
The owner is someone I know.
It's just a job
on the side for a few days.
I have to find something.
If not, I don't know what to do.
- You have a cell phone?
- No. Well, yes.
I did a paint job and they paid
me with this. 200 minutes.
It's Carmen.
The number appears here. The
only one who calls me is Carmen.
She wants me to keep coming.
Without paying her.
I can't do that.
I always paid her.
Now that I don't have
money, I can't. It's her job.
I don't have a job.
She doesn't have to lose hers.
That's why I'm telling you,
Carlitos. I have to get one.
Do you want me to help? Is
there anything you need?
A train that works.
I'm so nervous.
I hope the dog comes.
I hope he says
he wants talk with me.
I want we go for a walk down
the avenue. Have an icecream.
Hello.
- Hello, dog, how are you?
- Fine. I was looking for you.
. I'm listening. I'm listening.
- I wanted to tell you that...
- That what?
- That I...
Say it once and for all!
I played ball with the kids.
What? Do you want me to tell
you what you are?
I'll tell you later. Mom just
got here and she's sure to have...
an excuse
for scolding us.
Will you give me a kiss?
He's asleep.
Did his fever go down?
I don't know.
I didn't take it.
You gave him his medicine
at 4, didn't you?
No, I forgot. What time is it?
We have to give it to him, right?
- I gave him a vapour bath.
- Let's see.
- Don't smoke here.
- I didn't think about it.
Will you stay still?
You make me nervous.
Are you sure they said to do
this? It seems stupid to me.
Yes, they said I it has to be
in perfect shape.
This seems so strange to me.
The whole hired car thing...
...doesn't go down well with me.
Why? I don't have to spend any
money. I can capitalize.
When I finish paying for the
license and paperwork...
I'll renew the unit.
Renew the unit. Look at that.
A wallet, "renew the unit".
Your occupation is noticeable.
- Did you talk with the doctor?
- Yes. - What did he say?
- Bathe him in cold water until his
fever goes down. - He coming?
No, I'll call him in 10 minutes.
Hand me the ice tray.
Why doesn't he come here?
He's not coming because we
don't have health coverage.
It's enough that he
attends us by phone.
- Into the water.
- I don't want to.
Come on, you have to.
- No.
- Don't splash me!
- Will you give him to me?
- No, let go!
Will you give him to me?
Come with dad. He's cold.
- Slowly. Let's get into the water.
- It's cold.
Let's get in slowly.
I know it's cold.
It'll be over soon.
It's OK.
This will be good for you.
Right, my love?
It will go down. It will go down.
You'll be better soon.
It's Ok.
- Are you his mother?
- Yes.
- What is he taking?
- Ventoline, Teosona, and vapour.
We are going to listen
to your breathing.
Breath with your mouth open.
That's fine.
And again.
Very good.
- Excuse us, please.
- Doctor, please.
Wait for me.
I'll be right away.
- Can you wait outside.
- She told us to wait here.
- She'll be right out. Wait outside.
- She just told me...
Se'll be right out and will
inform you, please.
Take the temporary permit and
free-debt certificate.
- Everything fine?
- Everything.
That's better. I wanted to know
if I could talk with Poggi?
Not now. It would better at
another time.
Fine. There will be time.
Here, Laucha. On the
corner of the bar.
Here. You do this one.
That way you start right away.
Me?
Thank you.
You haven't been in this
occupation very long, right?
No, it's my first day.
How did you know?
- Do you believe in destiny?
- Yes. Not completely, but yes.
Don't you think our
destiny is predetermined...
like a road that goes around
and finally gets to where...
it has to and what has to
happen occurs?
Yes, that's true.
- And more and more.
- I don't.
You don't?
- I believe in free will.
- I do too.
Without will, 24 years
working on the railroad.
No, that's consistency.
Willpower and desire can do
much more than we believe.
I don't know you. If I look at
you with consistency just to...
know you, I will only see what
you want to show me.
Now, I want to know you well.
So I apply willpower. A lot.
And I see. With this energy I
throw light onto things.
It seems like a discovery,
but it isn't.
That way for me things are
clear and everything is easier.
- Can I ask you a question?
- Yes, ask away.
Besides, this is like a
confessionary.
Do you know the way? Please
don't be offended.
Well, more or less.
If you want to show me the way.
Of course. What point would it
be for us to get lost together?
Yes.
You see? Your willpower failed
there. Willpower is useless...
if you don't know where you are
going or where you want to go.
Go ahead.
Take that little dirt road.
This way, ma'am?
You sure?
Yes,
I get out at that crossroad.
- Are you sure?
- Stop. It's here.
How much?
- That's 11.50, ma'am.
- How much?
- Well, 11.
- It can't be. First you said 11.50.
The same, it's impossible.
But Ma'am, the kilometres
are shown here.
Why do they
always charge $16?
I don't know, ma'am.
Here. 10...
11. I don't have 50 cents.
- I never pay with coins.
- Leave it. It's not necessary.
No, give it to me.
Give me.
Take this.
Charge me 15.
Don't worry about it, ma'am.
You are honest. Give me the
chance to return good for evil.
I don't think I have change.
Yes, I do. No.
- I'm short by 3.
- That's fine.
I told you I believe in free will.
- Yes? - I know you want to. When
you can you will give them to me.
Can you show me the way out?
Ma'am?
- Hands on the wheel!
- Shu up, asshole.
- Relax. - Keep still. Search
everything. Hands on the wheel.
What have you got there?
Open your hand, asshole.
- Where do you have the money?
- Who gave you this?
- Who gave this to you, idiot?
- The lady just paid me with that.
Damn it. That shitty old lady
screwed us again. Let's go.
We filled out all the papers.
It's an oxygen condenser for a
five year old boy.
But the cooperative can't
authorize this.
Why not? My wife lost
her job and I just lost my job.
I don't have medical coverage.
I can't pay that.
It says here that you weren't
fired. You renounced.
What do you mean?
They closed the route.
The train doesn't go by
anymore. I renouced?
You aren't the only person who
doesn't understand. 78 people...
were left without a job
and they don't understand.
They didn't decide to stop
working. I didn't either.
The company left us in the street.
Do you know why?
You don't?
We don't know either.
You are telling me I renounced?
But you signed for voluntary
retirement.
Shit!
I'll send it right away.
- Hello.
- Hello. How did it go?
- More or less. I got a flat.
- You got a flat?
For a tire you are too slow. For a
passenger, too fast.
Forget him. Quite a few
trips for the first day.
Go render to Poggi.
He's about to leave.
Come on, Paco. You have a trip.
367 Lavalle Street. Go on.
- So you had a flat?
- Yes. That's bad luck.
Let me see.
$62. What was our agreement?
Fifty-fifty, right?
- Yes.
- Keep this to fix...
...the flat
and have a spare tire.
These $12 are mine. The small
change doesn't count.
Juanito, how much is it?
$4, like always.
We haven't raised prices.
Do you have change for 50?
No, I don't.
Hang on, don't worry. I'll send
the girl. Sandra? Sandra?
Alberto always has change.
He collects payments, people...
...pay him with change.
- Sure.
Go to Alberto's and get change.
Ask this man.
Now he has a machine to check
the bills and sounds an alarm...
if they are false.
The other day they stuck him
with a fake bill of 100.
You OK?
Yes, it's nothing. I'm tired.
My stomack's a little upset.
- You need a toilette? The
girl's coming. - No, I'm fine.
Atilio, where are you going?
Hello?
Karina. How are you?
I know I had to go for the practice.
That's why I'm calling. Something
came up. I won't be able to go.
Oh, yes? I didn't know that.
Karina, I'm out of credit and I
don't have any coins. Hello?
Thank you for calling, Pitu.
And now the weather.
We're going to have storms.
Get ready for the cold...
and rain and for staying at home.
And now, a musical...
I don't know why I found you. +
I suppose everything we do has
to cause movement elsewhere.
Like a chain reaction.
May dad once told me if you
throw a stone into the water...
it's waves change the whole lake.
Sometimes I'd like to have
that stone's power and that my
acts change my surroundings.
Maybe it can be.
Maybe you just have to try to.
Didn't the train close down
because the tracks...
weren't in good shape
and some parts were dangerous?
No, it closed down because it
wasn't profitable. It's that simple.
But they couldn't say it, so they
invented that about the tracks.
The route is in perfect shape.
What a nice super locomotive
that Uncle fixed for you.
- Yes. - It's nice,
isn't it? I like it a lot
- Do you feel better today?
- Yes.
Really?
I'm going now but you stay with
your Mom. I'll come tomorrow.
Give me a kiss.
Let's tuck you up.
My baby.
Bye, champ.
I'll be right back.
I'll say bye to Dad.
You know what I think?
Everything is our fault.
It's our fault?
I broke my ass for 9 years in a
company so they could fire me...
and it's my fault? I just missed
work one time in 9 years.
When Mati was born.
Once.
They fired me anyway. Now it
turns out it wasn't them.
It's the same.
We saw this coming
and didn't do anything.
- What the hell could we do?
- I don't know. Something.
All the birds shit on on us.
We must be doing something wrong.
What we did wrong was work.
Here the guy who works is a loser.
Everyone tells the same,
"it'll pas, it'll pass".
I don't know when
the hell it will. I don't know.
Atilio?
Atilio? Is that you?
What the hell
has he dropped?
Atilio?
Don't be an ass.
Workshop. Babe! How are you?
How strange of you to call now.
Because there is no money.
It ran out.
How are you?
Fine, I'm fine.
Yes, I went. Yes... No. I'm fine.
Yes, I take care of myself.
The doctors don't know
anything, babe.
Your boyfriend?
Did he get a job?
No?
About time he started, isn't it?
He's going to be 32 years old.
I know things are screwed up,
babe. Listen to me.
I am 68 and still working like a
dog every God given day.
No, they didn't fire me. I didn't
sign shit. Do you understand?
I'm here at the foot of the
cannon. Firm and solid.
Bye. Kisses.
Hope all goes well.
Hello? Take care of yourself.
They want to convince me?
He should move his heavy ass.
He can't? I wonder if you
could say that before.
Cheers.
- What are you doing?
- How was it? I'm lost.
If you'd just concentrate
a little. Take a look.
This in. Hammer in.
That will make it easier.
It only enters one way. There is
only one position. You see?
You slide it overt there.
You close it.
It returns to it's place.
Ready. Bullet clip.
- A piece of cake.
It's not to difficult.
Pay more attention
or we won't get anywhere.
- You're right. You're right.
- Leave your problems outside.
You say yes, but it's no. What's
wrong? What are you thinking?
- More of the same.
- What more of the same?
- Money.
- Yes.
Matias needs an oxygen
condenser. A piece of...
equipment that purifies the air.
Health care doesn't cover it.
This Matias turned out weak.
Take this.
200 bucks.
Let's see if we...
...can let up a little.
You concentrate a little more.
This isn't a joke matter.
Well...
Load the 38 and come here.
Why don't you try with your
eyes open?
God, this cough. I'm going to
need that... What's it called?
- Oxygen condenser.
If you keep smoking
like that.
- Is it expensive?
- 1,200 pesos.
- 1,200 bucks?
Used.
I better stop smoking.
Do you know how many bitches
I could pay with 1,200 bucks?
Here. Take it. I'm giving it
to you. It's yours.
It's for my personal use. I'll
bring you the papers tomorrow.
Take it.
What for?
It's good
to have a 2nd gun.
What's wrong? Are you afraid?
Fear has killed more people
than emphysema has.
Come on, come here.
Where are you?
Atilio?
Where the hell did you go?
You old asshole.
Hey.
Atilio.
Ati.
Atilio. Son of a bitch.
What are you doing there?
I know that my dream is possible.
I know I couldn't reach it.
I know you are clean
and strong. You have...
inherited part of that dream
to adapt it to your story...
that will be different
from mine. I love you, son.
But I can't go on anymore.
If I want a world without hate,
I am going to free it of the
hate I feel for it. Why go on?
I only need you to understand
and forgive me.
Until always. Your friend, Papa.
Why did I come here?
Why did your
grandfather come here?
The train brought us.
This whole
town was born with the train.
Then the workshops. Do you
know how many worked here?
People who believed in what
they were doing.
Who believed in working. They
believed in the country.
Take a look now.
The train is gone.
The country, let's face it,
is gone too.
Nobody cares about anything.
Nobody gives a damn.
It's sad but that's the way it is.
What draws my attention is that...
no one reacts. No one says stop.
Enough. It's over.
Why the hell are we always the
ones who have to slacken?
- Do you understand what I'm saying?
- Yes, of course.
I also ask myself why...
my old man gave up instead
of staying here to fight.
Was he a coward?
Hello.
Laura?
Carlos?
What are you doing?
What is this?
- Did you put this on the door?
- Yes, it was me.
How could you put something
like this on the door?
With scotch tape.
- I know.
- Lf you know, why do you ask?
It's the foreclosure.
Are you going to put this wig away
or should throw it away?
Why are you cleaning?
Is there a rat?
Yes,
there's a rat that cleans.
There is a rat that hides things.
Wasn't it there wasn't anymore?
- Did you want to drink it alone?
- Give it to me.
- It's going to fall and break.
- No, it's not.
What's wrong?
Hug me.
Let's stay together a little while
and not think of anything.
Just for awhile.
Please.
What's wrong?
I can't. I can't.
I'm sorry, I can't.
Be calm. Relax.
- It will go by.
- Forgive me Susana.
It's OK, honey.
Everything's fine.
Hug me like this, tightly.
What are you doing?
It's quarter to seven.
How can you do this now?
Lisa?
Lisa. Lisa. Lisa. The boy?
- Last night, what time did you...?
- Who stayed with him?
He was with my mother.
What time did you come back?
Are you going
to tell me?
Caloviero invited me to dinner.
We were talking and...
About what? What were you
talking with him about?
He's going to get me a job.
What are you into?
Please, tell me.
- Good morning. Poggi?
- He's not here.
- Where can I find Poggi?
- Who? - Poggi.
Mr. Poggi is...
Check it out. Bring the
papers and follow me.
Let's see if this one
passes the inspection. Open it.
Atilio?
- Are you deaf?
- What's up?
You must go to Todo Home to pick up
a TV set and take it to this address
Shit.
I'm the freight mover again?
Dad?
- What's with all this?
- What do you want?
Where's the letter from the bank,
the one nailed to the door?
- Your mother had it.
- She doesn't remember.
Mama, he says you had it.
Ask Mom to call the workshop and
ask Braulio if he
...still has the solder machine?
- Yes.
Mom, can you call the
workshop and ask Braulio.
If he has the
solder machine?
Hello?
It's me. Hired car.
Freight mover. Todo Home.
Come in.
The TV set.
How are you? It
fell on you to bring it?
Antonio!
- This is where you live?
- What's up, Atilio?
- So, you are with Todo Home?
- Not Todo Home. I hire the car.
Since I had a car, you see.
Besides, Todo Home...
Yes, they are more particular.
That's the way it is now.
- It's not fair.
- No, they aren't particular.
They are lucky you went in.
Nobody goes in there.
That don't sell a thing to
anyone.
- No even a... - It's a TV set.
- Yes, yes. Here?
Here?
- That's 20 inches.
- And this one?
29 inches.
The inches are heavy,
right?
Not bad, Antonio.
The truth is if you didn't
imagine I'd come carrying...
your TV set like a mule, much less
would I imagine this were your home.
My what? No, Atilio. I'm a
slave. I never told you?
- What?
- I never tell anyone out of shame.
Everything you see here,
the house, the TV set...
...even this robe.
Everything is Zulma's.
- Who's?
- My wife Zulma.
She made all of this
with the hair shop.
Highlighting came into fashion,
so we haven't died of hunger.
Do me a favour, Atilio.
Bring it inside, will you?
Yes.
And take it.
The small one. The TV set.
Take it. It's for you.
- A gift for a friend.
- No.
- Take it.
- I can't accept that.
Come on. Take it.
- Antonio, workmate.
- Go on. Take it with you.
Thank you.
- Bye, Atilio.
- Bye.
It's OK, I'll helpe you.
- Hey, deaf guy. Hey.
- What?
Can you turn the music down?
Can you turn it down more?
More.
Thank you.
We're going a little out of the way.
We have to go get the doctor.
- Turn here.
- Fine.
We're going to go back down
the avenue in the same way.
- Stop just before the corner of
the supermarket. Got it? - Yes.
Gomez,
what are you doing here?
Hello, Atilio. How are you?
So you're a doctor now?
No, it's their joke.
You are a hired driver?
- Yes.
- So you are broke?
I told them. I told them.
Now it's not important.
Atilio, do us a favour. Go a little
bit faster. We are in a hurry.
- Fine. It was for the TV set.
- What TV set?
I've got it in the trunk.
You won't guess
who gave it to me.
He bought a giant screen and
gave me the one he had.
- Antonio. Antonio gave it to you.
- Yes.
What other son of a bitch that
we knew could give it to you?
- You found out about his wife?
- What wife?
The one with the hair shop.
Don't tell me he made you
believe he got that fortune and...
has that house with that slut
working as a hairdresser?
- And manicure. - That bitch could've
made some money in her life...
sleeping with
someone influential...
with some politician, even with
some railroad boss. Understand?
He screwed you, Atilio.
He screwed you, understand?
I always said that worm was
going to betray us. Atilio.
No. I can't believe you.
You don't want to believe me.
- Many of us didn't listen to you.
- To die alone o in a heap...
what's the difference?
I know you weren't only idiot
who didn't believe me.
I said that worm was going to
betray us.
That son of a bitch. He always
worked as an informer, a traitor,
coward, inside man, miserable.
That's it. No way to fix it.
Do me a favour.
Over there...
Cross the corner and stop.
Susana, did you call the
workshop?
Hey, Susana?
I'm looking for the paper
you lost. It must be at the...
- bank tomorrow.
- I lost it?
I left it stuck to the door.
Who took it off?
How much is it?
Don't worry about it.
It was worth it.
Charge me, please.
The dead don't charge.
Bye, Atilio.
This is a robbery!
Get down!
To the floor. Nothing's gonna
happen. You too, ma'am.
Now!
- Come on, hurry up!
- The money!
You too! On the floor!
What are you looking at?
Hurry up! Hurry up!
Come out, Antonio you bastard!
I brought the TV back. I won't need
need it because I don't have
enough to pay for electricity.
It's your fault
you son of a bitch. Come out!
- Stop it! What are you doing?
- Come out, coward!
Stop it! What's wrong with you?
Are you crazy?
What did you do? How can you
live with that? Traitor.
Who where you talking with?
With Grimaldi, right?
Do you believe that wretch?
He's envious.
- It was him, uh?
- It was me when I opened my eyes.
No, it was Grimaldi.
Come on, you shit!
Open up!
I won't open for an animal
like you who can't reason.
I didn't do anything. All of this
would've happened the same.
You and I are nothing.
What's to it...
- if some bucks stuck to a few
of us? - Open up and I'll...
- explain it to you.
- No, I won't.
- I'll throw you out like a dog.
- Yeah? Take this.
Stop!
What are you doing?
What am I doing? You'll see.
Stop it! What're you doing?
Calm down. Stop it once and for all.
Take it!
Stick it up your ass!
Son of a bitch.
We'll see each other again.
You sold us out, rustler.
You're a piece of shit. Bad
workmate. It's because of shit...
like you we are like this.
You'll remember. We'll get you.
Susana, I asked you 4 times
to call the workshop.
If I don't have the soldering
machine I won't ever finish.
Braulio?
Son of a bitch.
The phone, Braulio.
Why doesn't
this idiot answer?
Hello? Hello?
Braulio!
No, don't do this to me.
Not you, my friend.
Do you know you were right?
We shouldn've signed.
They screwed us, Braulio.
They screwed us.
I want to go to the bathroom.
- How long until you finish?
- I asked you 5 times to call...
the workshop. Did you do it?
You didn't. I don't have the tool.
- It's not my fault.
- And I don't have my tool!
- I need the bathroom.
- Use the neighbour's.
What neighbour? You've been
in here since 7 am...
It's 8 pm. You pretend to be a
plumber without knowing about pipes!
- Call a plumber and pay it yourself.
- With what money?
If you had at least accepted
Osvaldo's offer?
What do you want me to accept?
He's selling the car!
He's selling the car because
he's buying a SUV!
Why don't you and Osvaldo and
this shitty pipe go to hell!
Damn son of a bitch!
Be careful!
- Hurry up!
- Take this! Laura!
- Give it to me.
- Hold this here.
- I'll bring something.
- No, hold this here.
Help your mother.
Grab this.
Put a towel.
Give me a towel.
Calm down.
- What happened? - I don't know.
This shitty pipe broke. Come here!
- Carlos! - I'll be right there.
- Help me, I can't do it!
Look for a pail, Laura.
The police have begun to
identify some of the assailants.
One of them is Luis Gomez.
A 56 year old man.
The second man is 43 year old
Mariano Andres Vitalli.
Married and with two children.
We don't have too much...
information about the third
member of the gang.
The only thing we know is he's
no more than 40 years old.
Hello? Carlos, this is Atilio.
I called to...
Nothing
is turning out for me.
I don't even know how to say it.
I'm here in the workshop...
Braulio passed away. I don't know.
It seems to have been a heart attack
Call me when you can.
This is the situation.
Trapped again by the terror
caused by delinquents.
Violence is again the protagonist.
From railroad employee to criminal.
Do you understand it?
I don't.
Come here, dad!
What are you doing?
Come here!
Carlos! What's wrong?
Will you shut up, ma'am?
Kid, see if you can calm her down.
- I'll go.
- Fine.
- Did you see the news? - Yes.
Gomez in a supermarket. I saw it.
No, no.
How can a working man, a
worker transform?
Transgress his history, his
culture, his education and...
end up like this? With these
irrational criminal acts which
were never part of his life?
This is what happens when they
don't give you any way out.
You start looking for the
solution anywhere.
People are desperate.
When you are desperate...
everything looks black.
You don't see any light.
There is no light.
That happened to us when they
closed the railroad.
That's why it comes to this.
That's fine. Let's agree
this is not the way.
- There're innocent people there.
- Yes, you're right.
What is the way?
Tell me. What is the way?
Because I still haven't found it.
My brother didn't find it.
Braulio didn't find it either.
Let's go to our mobile unit in
front of the supermarket.
Monica,
is there anything new?
The activity here is intense and
we know the logistical work...
is in an advanced stage.
The police have begun to...
surround the place and we don't
know yet the course of action.
If they'll try to enter the
supermarket by force or if they'll
try to establish a dialogue
with the criminals to get the...
release of the hostages.
I feel now is the time to do
something. Maybe we're capable...
of changing the world
and we don't realize it.
Now is the time to try it.
Guide me Braulio.
First,
see if there's a spark.
Help me Braulio. I'm tired.
Then fuel must get in there.
Let's see, Braulio. If there is a
spark everything is all right.
A spark and fuel. It has to light.
Come on. We did everything
right.
Come on.
You see, Braulio? It worked.
Take this old wagon. You'll
enjoy it more than I.
I'm worthless.
I only screw up.
You're the mechanic.
I am nothing. A failure.
- We should be...
- Excuse me.
Relax, ma'am.
Everything will be all right.
Let's go back to the supermarket.
Monica, any news?
According to the information we
have from neighbours, the...
delinquents entered the
supermarket on foot stemming...
from the hypothesis there were
no suspicious cars in the area.
The situation is very tense. The
police continue trying to...
negotiate with the delinquents.
Even so, direct communication...
TO MY BELOVED GODSON, YOUR
GODFATHER WHO LOVES YOU. CALOIERO.
We are able to confirm what
was just a...
...a hypothesis until now.
The supermarket's security
guard is among the hostages.
His name is Daniel Sanabria.
If they don't come up,
nobody's going out from here.
Clear the area and people
will come out in 15 minutes.
Daniel!
Gomez.
What are you doing?
- What're you doing?
- Put it down.
Everything all right, Gomez?
Yes, everything is all right!
Carlos Delmar. Railroad worker.
Will you tell me how we...
...got to this situation?
I don't know how we got
to this situation.
And I don't know how we are
going to get out, either.
Is that you, Gomez? What
happened? Answer me, please.
Gomez! Don't do anything stupid.
Please.
I want us to be together.
Shit! It's not here!
It was here.
Come on, Juan, look for it.
Look for it, please.
Here it is.
Let's go.
The special police squad
surrounds the place...
without abandoning attempts to
negotiate with the individuals.
They are asking for the
road to be freed.
Two of them have been
identified. They are Mariano...
Vitalli and Luis Gomez.
Back to you, Monica.
Fortunately, it has stopped
raining. Although here the...
...situation remains tense.
We're walking towards the...
rails of discord. The train
stopped passing by here a long...
time ago with the resulting
loss of jobs for many men.
Some of whom are
inside the supermarket...
in situation with
an unclear ending.
THE TRAIN IS OURS
I'm not sure if we can change
destiny.
I believe we shoul do...
everything within reach to
change the things we don't like.
Something happened that night.
It would change us forever.
Something that had to do with
the anger...
the injustice,
with the laws, the rights...
and above all
with every one of us.
Something that had to do with
our identity. With being part of...
something that always belonged
to us. I don't know why we...
thought it was not ours and
unreachable.
I still ask myself why my old
man didn't see any way out.
I'm sure there has to be one.
And I won't stop until I find it.
That night we didn't watch as
the train passed by.
We started it up.
Ripeados por Tylerg|
Visita www.clan-sudamerica.com.ar