I'm all ears.
What I'm most concerned about,
Mr. N˙Òez, are the people.
If we'd close down, five thousand
employees will be left on the street.
Stop talking nonsense, Fraga.
Mr. N˙Òez is not here
to listen to sentimental statements.
We are not here to discuss families,
we're here to talk about money.
I want to make it clear.
Lot of dough was spent with this.
None of you realized it beforehand.
None of you...
sent an accurate report
to headquarters.
This is not forfree.
I can tell you right now
that we could leave,
liquidate assets,
put up with the tide...
or sell everything.
Of course, we'll evaluate
whaùs the best forthe corporation.
Soon, I'll send you a memo
with the final decisiÛn.
Now, I don't have much more to say.
We'll keep in touch.
I'm not ajerk, N˙Òez.
I knowwhy you're here.
You've already made a decisiÛn.
Just a compensation
won't be enough for me.
Tell those that if they don't pay
all they have to pay,
I'll talk.
I knowmany things.
Howthey went off with everything.
I knowabout the off-shore funds,
I knowabout the money transfers.
I can talk and you
and all those damned Galicians...
will appear on the newspaper covers.
We already are on the papers.
We already are the devil.
People won't be scared of us.
Iùs your family
who will be scared of you.
We have recorded you in all formats.
Frame by frame, second by second.
If you wish,
I'll send them a DVD
so they have a better defined image.
By the way, here's zone 4, isn't it?
D'you knowwhom you remind me?
You look a bit like Anna Karina
in "Vivre sa vie".
No, no, sorry, iùs not Anna Karina.
You look exactly like Delphine Seyrig
in "LannÈe derniËre ‡ Marienbad".
Have you ever acted in a movie?
I think you're most suited for that.
In two months,
I'll be filming my second movie.
If you want, you could give
me your phone number...
and, who knows? Maybe...
you could be my Geena Rowlands.
Ch°ldren, stop!
MartÌn, get out ofthere!
MartÌn, have you listened to me?
Naughty kid, get out ofthere!
Naughty!
I am calm.
In any case,
iùs them who must not be calm.
Just because!
To you... a ten per cent, I think.
You're very polite, Freddy.
I didn't say that.
I said "polite".
We're a bit touchy, aren't we?
Touchy and out of place.
At my house.
Yes.
Well, no, I don't think so.
No, no...
No, Freddy, no. No, no.
Who threwit to the toilet? Who?
We'll talk later.
What I do think
is that we should send something,
a registered letter.
I don't know, whatever...
Hold a second, don't hang up...
Where are you going?
To look for ajob.
- Hi!
- Hi.
Weren't you getting out tonight?
I don't know.
I don't want to miss the nominations.
Go, I'll record them foryou.
I'm sure all them
are leading successful lives.
If I were you, I'd go.
Be my light, be my light.
I'll change to anothertopic
that I don't want to overlook,
as we had been trying to solve it
for a long time and we couldn't.
It might be trivial...
but I have it written down.
Mr. Lacrose!
Mr. Lacrose, we're right now
dealing with your situation,
and we've decided,
by unanimous vote,
that your case
will be filed with the Court.
Mr. Rafaeli has offered
his services as lawyer.
Well... I don't know.
Please, allowme until the 15th.
Can you?
Eleven thousand pesos
in service charges...
Listen Lacrose,
we can't wait foryou any longer.
How strange,
a Lacroze who's poor...
But this Lacrose is written with "s".
I'd l°ke to tell you...
a dream.
Iùs a very strange dream...
I've had today early morning.
On this dream, God appeared to me.
I was accompan°ed
by several professors...
from d°fferent parts of the un°verse.
The s°tuat°on was very tense,
as God accused us...
of hav°ng wasted a whole generat°on.
Because of that, and to separate
the righteous from the s°nners,
God dec°ded...
to take us a test.
He would choose one of
my alumn°,
that means one of you,
and would testyou
to challenge a l°m°t s°tuat°on.
Prov°ded th°s student...
made the right decisiÛn
and achieved a happy end,
I would pass the exam,
and the reward was
that I could wake up from the dream...
and go on living.
Otherwise,
as a punishment
for my poor performance as educator,
I would be condemned
to never wake up aga°n.
It was then...
that the idea of
coming to this meeting...
had new value for me.
I began wondering...
about what kind of people I'd meet.
Will they be loyal ortraitors?
Will they be capable
of sacrificing fortheirfellows...
or will they live only
fortheir personal satisfaction?
Will they be ready
to be coherent with theirfeelings...
or will they prefer...
the comfort of hypocrisy?
Well...
excuse my solemnity,
and please, don't confuse it
with despair.
Leùs make it clear,
I do not only fervently wish
to wake up tomorrow,
which isjust the 5th.
And I get my retirement payment,
but I also wish to be invited,
to attend...
and to deliver a better speech
at the 25th anniversary...
of the day you've graduated.
Giris, boys!
Atoast to the 20 years!
Congratulations!
Just because you were friends
and I did love you a lot,
because I earn my living with this.
Leùs see...
You must be patient, not that much,
cause you'll be successful in a very,
but very short term.
What else?
You'll be successful,
what else dyou want, dear?
What about me?
- Her name is Lara.
- Howpretty she is!
She takes exactly afteryou!
What a pity, since herfather is very,
very handsome.
Who could have sa°d that?
I went forthe two of you.
Me too.
Iùs never late.
Anybody knows something
about soft-headed PequeÒo?
What a pity he didn't come, isn't it?
Don't you miss the dumb flying
from side to side in the classroom?
PequeÒo!
Whaùs up, Lacrose?
Have you become evangelist?
No, I'm not evangelist,
but we behaved badly,
we ruined the best years
that a boy, jerk, can live.
Ajerk boy or a boy, comma, jerk?
We didn't behave well.
We were simply soldiers.
You gave the orders.
Don't you remember when he told us
to piss on him at the locker room?
And it was you who made him
kiss Pochola in the bathroom!
And the one who followed him
to his house, too.
Poor wretch, not even
when we left school you left him alone.
In the end, boys,
the only son of a bitch...
was Lacrose, you see!
Voglio a entrare!
- Per la finestra?
- Hello!
Howare you?
I'm so happy to see you!
- Howare you?
- Let me see...
- Have I interrupted anything?
- No.
I can't believe it!
This is a lie, isn't it?
Tell me this is not true,
that iùs a dream.
Or better tell me...
that what I'm living
is absolutely, but absolutely real.
Shit! Say what you want,
but please say something!
- Howare you?
- Me?
What does it matter about me?
Howare you?
What do you do?
Are you married?
Do you have children?
Well, I made a movie.
I can't believe
you've made a movie!
And whaùs the title?
"Corollary of a Sleeping Twilight"
It wasn't premiered in Spain, was it?
Otherwise, I'd have rushed to see it.
There's a great boom
with Argentine movies.
Many ofthem have been premiered.
"The Bride's Son",
- "Seven Queens"...
- But you knowwhat?
What I do is more for...
I don't know...
Iùs no so much for export, leùs say.
And you, Franquito?
Hitachi, shit! Howgood you look!
You have not a single grey hair!
What dyou do? Apart from keeping
yourselfin formol, of course!
D'you want me to lie
or do I spoil you the night?
Have you seen him well?
- Whom?
- Guido!
- Yes, whaùs up?
- He's got tits.
Sorry, but NÈstor
also looks very decayed...
Yes, you're right!
They're those typical characters
one meets in the subway...
frustrated because
they don't get a pay raise,
feeling blue
because they are almost forty,
and terrified cause
they no longer get an erection.
Queers, bah!
Andjust think that in the past,
men loaded their swords...
and fought to death.
Where will those warriors be now?
In the movies, Romi,
only in the movies.
Excuse me...
- Howare you, Lacrose?
- D'you knowanything of PequeÒo?
I call him from time to time...
Once a year...
but as he never answers
I just leave a message in his voicemail.
Maybe thaùs not longer his number...
So you've got his number.
Could you give it to me?
Please?
You knowwhat?
Don't take it bad,
but I'd rather not be me
the one who gives it to you.
The time machine.
The time tunnel.
- Iùs brilliant!
- Iùs good...
but the grass is better.
Hash makes me feel a bit down.
Have you given up smoking?
Iùs not the right moment.
Iùs very hard.
I understand you.
DiscÈpolo was right!
Look at me!
I've always been disastrous at school.
I've ever had not
a dammed talent for anything.
Even gymnastics I didn't pass.
Something must be very wrong that now
I'm a winner and you are doing so badly.
But don't give up!
This will change, we're living
the last throes of capitalism.
In a short time,
you'll get what you deserve...
and I'll get what I deserve.
You did well.
I mean your parents! They guessed
what was coming, and left in time.
Since you left, everything went to hell.
There's no employment already.
Now, I don't knowif you've read
any paper, kidnapping is in vogue.
Everybody complains but iùs the only
possible industry in this country.
As for me, every time
a businessman is kidnapped...
I feel like celebrating with champagne.
More if considering that those turds
have kidnapped ourfuture.
Iùsjust that I don't have the guts...
Don't give up.
Don't indulge them.
This will change.
And it will have to do with the South.
Argentina is the future.
- Argentina kills you.
- No way! Argentina will take off.
There are good people here,
I knowwhat I'm saying!
Hey, has anybody brought eye drops?
Hey! Leonor, and you?
What do you do?
Because you played thejerk
and didn't tell us anything.
- Sorry, but why Leonor?
- For Benedetto.
The woman
was with Sacrist·n six months...
and when she returned, she had a thicker
accent than Fernando Fern·n GÛmez.
I understand.
Don't get angry,
iùsjust that I don't get used
to the accent.
Anyway, you didn't answer us
on what you do.
Finances.
Oh! I see.
Here, those of your race
have cleaned us out.
I've heard something about that.
As to me, to take a case in point,
they conned me out
of the only 2,000 dollars...
I could had saved in all my life.
With that money
I intended to make my next movie.
And as to Franco?
Tell him.
He was also swindled
of all his severance pay.
Hey! Leonor, by any chance,
you don't work
for the Asturian Bank, do you?
Sorry! Did I get you?
Can you make a movie with 2,000 dollars?
I film in digital system
and everything is done by me myself.
And the actors?
Real people.
Actors are a fraud.
Listen! Mr. Robert de Niro
is not a fraud at all.
- Please! He always does the same thing.
- No way!
Travis Brickle is not the same
that Jack La Mota.
This is over.
Why don't we go somewhere?
Sure! Today is my only
and last night here.
Tomorrow early,
I'm leaving back to Madrid.
In fact, I feel like going over the city
and if you don't have anything to do,
what would be better
that doing something together?
- And?
- Nothing.
They must have been re-painted.
I think it wasn't that one...
We wrote them
when we began to sit together,
dyou remember?
I think iùs that one.
Do you dare?
THE BEST PIANISTOF THE WORLD
THE BEST SINGER
Whaùs up with your life?
Nothing special.
And you?
I'm fine.
Melina, there's no sense in it.
We'll keep on talking about the past.
No way! I want to know
what you're up to now.
- You'll get too bored.
- Leùs go. Come on!
Come on...
Are you leaving, Palombo?
- Lf you let my hand go, I will.
- Iùs okay!
Tell me about your life.
As you know,
some lives are ideal for a film...
Well, mine would just serve
for a short-length film.
What a fool you are!
Here your are, colleague,
you drive! I look.
- No! What ifl scratch it?
- No, it belongs to the company!
Hey, and the Italpark?
D'you remember the Matter Horn?
Sure! Howcan I forget it?
It was the best of all the attractions.
In 1992, one ofthe cars
detached with a girl inside.
Iùs said that the car crossed
all through the avenue.
- What the hell is this?
- Aflower.
It has a computerthat,
according to the time ofthe day,
is opened or closed.
Here was where I first saw
"Close Encounters ofthe Third Kind".
My granny took me.
The old lady fell asleep,
buy deeply asleep,
as soon as the first UFO appeared.
I sawit five times.
Five times! We entered
at 11:00 in the morning...
and went out at 11:00 night.
Good grief! Howl cried seeing
that movie, especially at the end.
I wished an UFO came and took me...
far away, but well far away.
I'm still waiting.
Hey, would you...
Would you allowme a moment,
just a fewminutes?
Could you leave me alone, please?
Mister, Mister,
don't you have a coin?
No, nothing, no!
What a son of a bitch!
I'm leaving!
- Stop! Be smart.
- Be smart what?
My mother always told me to take
advantage of contacts made at school.
That I had been sent
to a private school for a reason.
At then, I took it badly.
I thought that the worid was ruled
by merits and not by contacts.
But now, look at me!
And look at yourself, too!
We've been not successful at all,
Alexis.
Instead... Look at him!
D'you have the "Pelo" magazine?
"The imaginary express"?
How excellent
were thejingles in the past!
Yes?
Excuse me, could you tell...
which apartment
PequeÒo family lives?
Seventh B.
Has someth°ng serious occurred?
I heard shouts,
thaùs why I'm ask°ng.
You are the doctor, aren'tyou?
No... I'mjust a friend.
A friend?
Get out or I'll call the pol°ce!
Act°on Lu°s, act°on...
Yes?
PequeÒo family?
Come in.
I suppose you remember me.
Iùs me, Luis MarÌa.
Lacrose.
Sit down.
I don't knowhowto begin...
Iùs been so many years.
I don't expect that with what I've come
to tell you, we can be friends.
I'm happy just to know
that you're okay.
I'vejust come
from the graduates meeting...
and I was told that something
was wrong with you.
Lfiùs any consolation to you,
during these years...
I also went through
many bad situations.
It seems that God punished me
for all I did,
and among all the wrong I did,
I also include what I did to you.
I just want you to know
that I've changed,
I swear you I've changed.
Imagine howl've changed...
that nowl work as a coach
at the school club,
and when I see a boy
is bothering another,
I suspend him, immediately!
Because rugby's not that.
Rugby's good, iùs camaraderie,
friendship, stamina.
And dyou knowwhat made me change?
A book...
A book I read made me change.
One year ago, I went
to the supermarket to buy whiskey.
When I was queuing to pay,
I sawa book with a cover which read:
"Manual ofthe Warrior ofthe Light".
I got caught by that title.
That same night,
instead of drinking up the bottle,
I began to read it.
What I like best from the book...
is when it says
that a warrior ofthe light...
always has a second chance.
Then, I decided I could be
that warrior ofthe light,
and for that, I only need
to have my personal experience,
a missiÛn in my life.
And then I realized that my missiÛn...
is to find all the people
I had done harm to in the past...
and apologize to them.
Just nowl've become aware
of how cruel I've been to you,
and that I've robbed you
ofthe best years.
I want you to know
that I feel indebted to you.
I want to apologize to you.
Except for money... anything!
I'm glad you feel so worried.
I'm very grateful for your attitude,
iùs very nice,
very moving all you've said.
If you really want
to ingratiate yourselfwith Germ·n,
who's been 20 years
without getting out,
and consequently, with me, since
I took care ofhim during all that time,
if your remorse is so sincere,
I'll ask you for a favor...
A small one.
Stay tonight to take care of my brother.
How's Germ·n?
What does he sufferfrom?
Is it related to all I did to him?
It is. Of course it is.
Anyway,
what he couldn't overcome...
wasn't so much the physical affliction,
but the psychological.
You'll see him,
since you're going
to make me the favor, aren't you?
Sure, man, yes! What time dyou think
you'll be back, approximately?
I don't know...
A movie, a coffee,
see what the night is about,
they say so many things ofthe night,
so many temptations.
Four or five hours, I think...
I want to be sincere.
No, iùs okay.
But please, do have fun!
How do I look?
D'you think any chick
will give me a second glance?
Whaùs most important
is what we have inside, friend.
The worid is like a mirror...
which reflects
our own image to each of us.
I almost forget...
Twelve o'clock is the time
for his medication.
Don't forget, okay?
And when you enter his room,
just do it quietly, don't be afraid.
I don't think he'll recognize you.
Bye, see you!
For me,
iùs been the best time in my life.
I just remember
there was nothing we agreed on.
I liked The Avengers
and you liked Charlie's Angels.
You liked Billy Joel and I hated him.
I still listen to him.
- Really?
- Whaùs wrong with it?
Iùs the same ifl tell you
that my favorite movie is Bambi.
I don't know.
One is supposed to grow, to evolve.
Sorry, but I don't agree.
Howare you?
I'm looking for "Easy to love",
by Ella Fitzgerald.
Here it is, "Easy love",
but here appears as ifby Ray Conniff.
No, I said "Easy to love",
by Ella Fitzgerald.
Watch carefully, please.
I hate these supermarkets.
You'll see,
he's about to shake his head.
See?
The best is already over...
The best °s already over...
Here, I've got it.
Iùs in "Ballads".
D'you want it?
Thanks.
What do we do?
Pee. First of all, I need to pee.
You should come to Spain.
You won't pay for anything.
Just the ticket.
I'll take you to my beach house
in Marbella.
Iùs a very posh place,
six rooms, sauna, tennis court...
What I do ask you
is that you try to come alone.
You can't imagine
howwinners we're in Spain.
Women get crazy about us.
Well, no longer with me,
but ifthey listen to you talking...
Spanish ladies
love our accent very much.
Hey! Leonor,
as you're in the worid of finances,
don't you knowanyone
who wishes to invest money in cinema?
As a matter of fact...
ifthere's something that has nothing
to do with my worid is art...
You don't get me,
what I'm asking is
if you want to invest money in my movie.
And whaùs your movie about?
I still don't know
Anyway, I can tell you
that I work without a script.
I don't need an instruction manual
to express myself.
My movies shinejust by themselves.
Sorry Alexis,
but if your movies had shined,
they wouldn't have done so badly.
Lfthe audience
is not on a par with my movies,
iùs not my responsibility.
Besides, I won't change
to please the audience.
As for me, fuck the audience!
What I do is different.
Iùs the State's responsibility
and not mine...
that people dare face my work.
Isn't it?
Lito, the situation must be different
for a professional, no?
How's the situation there
for a physicist?
I have a good background to try.
Things are not that easy.
Careful! What I do
is not limited just to research.
I've developed an engine...
thaùs a system oftwo opposed rotors
that operate over a common main shaft.
The main advantage is that it
absolutely lacks of centrifugal force...
in the torque box.
A cam chain joins both opposed rotors,
and this allows the main torque
to turn up without hysteresis.
I give you all these details because it
can be used as a hydroelectric turbine,
and reduces energy cost to half.
Is it clear or not what I mean?
Look, guys,
iùs not that I want to disappoint you,
but ifiùs for employment,
forget about going there.
This fascist of Aznar
has taken his back on immigrants,
and even more with Argentineans.
You know, with all this of the default,
we're not at all well considered.
I think, if you allowme the advice,
that the action
will not take place in Europe.
You may find it hard to believe,
but I'm one ofthose...
who think that Argentina
has an amazing potential.
Here, all we need
is an ethic revolution.
We have to pull our native wit
and cunning idiosyncrasy to pieces.
We should call a group of notables...
- Like Bioy Casares...
- He died.
- Favaloro.
- He also died.
AlfonsÌn then! No statesman in the worid
can be compared with AlfonsÌn.
This country has everything
to be the future potency.
We have everything!
We have minerals!
We have oil! We have food!
We have kilometers
and kilometers of rich soil!
Are you Carlos N˙Òez?
The very same.
I worked foryour bank.
You could have told us!
This man,
if we can call him a man,
is the regional manager
ofthe Asturian Bank!
This bank is one ofthe banks...
that seized the savings
of millions of Argentine citizens!
It was yourfault that my daughter
lost everything and left the country!
I wish you the worst, N˙Òez!
I wish you a cancer...
that gradually breaks you up,
son of a bitch!
You're a thief, N˙Òez!
Don't let yourselfbe fooled by him!
- Son of a bitch!
- Thief!
I'll be back in a moment.
- D'you have a pen?
- I haven't got one.
Hey, you...
A pen, please.
Quickly, a pen, a pen!
Quickly, please!
Thanks.
What are you doing?
Afriend comes from abroad.
He seems to be a charming guy.
His friends believe the guy
is worth his weight in gold,
and they don't realize that,
as a matter of fact,
he's responsible
for having taken all their savings,
their marriages, the future
oftheir children. Everything.
It should be a bit exaggerated.
Instead of working for a bank,
he could be an emissary ofthe IMF.
The thing is that...
that very same night,
his friends decide to kidnap him,
and thus, recover all they've lost,
and by the way, take revenge on him.
Isn't it brilliant for a movie?
Iùs a noirfilm,
a mixture between Chabrol,
Bresson and Lynch.
Iùs obscure, bizarre...
Iùs really bizarre.
Guys, leùs pretend
that nothing has happened here.
We won't allowthis fucking crazy woman
to spoil our night.
Disgusting.
Worse than disgusting.
- Come in.
- Where's the bathroom? There?
Wait, wait, wait!
Wait a second.
- Come on Guido, it doesn't matter!
- It does matter!
You can go in now.
So, finally you're
what you dreamt about.
Iùs my worst nightmare.
Here I see you
with a crowded audience.
Melina, I play at restaurants.
I am a functional musician.
D'you understand?
What am I doing here?
THIS IS YOUR LAST NIGHT
WWACH YOUR BACK
PequeÒo...
PequeÒo!
Iùs me, Luis MarÌa...
Lacrose, dyou remember?
Keep quiet, PequeÒo! Keep quiet!
Your brother will be here soon,
but be quiet, I'm here.
PequeÒo, keep quiet!
Keep quiet, please!
My God! What I've done to you, PequeÒo!
I never wanted you to be like this!
I was a shit
but I swear I've changed.
You'll notice my change, really.
I've changed.
I won't hurt you!
Stop it, you jerk!
Sorry, I didn't mean to call you jerk.
I knowyou hate me.
I knowyou wish I were dead,
and I understand.
You're absolutely right.
I deserve all you wish me.
Even more.
If you want to hit me, just do it.
I promise I'll let you.
Come on! Come on, hit me!
No, but don't be afraid, hit me,
break my face.
I'm sorry, PequeÒo.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry...
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
Iùsjust that I can't believe it.
And tell me,
what did your girlfriends say...
when they found me there?
Nothing.
I don't believe you.
What would you like to drink?
Did any of them get angry?
Any one?
Guido, you aren't lying to me, are you?
Wouldn't it be that you had
no girlfriend in all this time?
Iùs that, isn't?
I've been the only one.
Yes or no?
Don't get nervous.
Whaùs the problem in telling me
that I've been your only girlfriend?
- Because you weren't.
- Yes, I was.
- You weren't.
- Yes!
- No!
- You got angry, that means I was.
Okay, dyou want to knowthe truth?
Yes.
Ifl didn't have a girlfriend...
it wasn't because I didn't want.
It was because I couldn't.
Now... D'you want to know
why I couldn't?
Look at me. Would you get out
with someone like this?
And dyou want to know
why I became this?
Ah! So you don't want to know...
Twenty years ago
I didn't look like this.
I think you do know very well
that I wasn't like this.
What dyou mean?
Anyway, I'm on a diet now
In a year, I'll be the same I was.
D'you want me to believe
that you got fat...
because I left you 20 years ago?
- I didn't say that.
- You're reproaching me.
Forget what I've told you.
I don't even remember
howl got here.
It was gradual.
Gradually, I was getting fat outside...
and gradually I was thinning inside.
I got so thin inside that...
Any time I'm introduced a girl,
I feel hair will growin my nose,
that my teeth
will become full of parsley,
that ifl speak,
my voice will be shrill...
or my tongue will twist,
orthat my belly
will start to make noises.
I have such a bad time...
that I asked my friends
not to introduce me to anyone else,
- and thaùs it.
- And how dyou manage with sex?
Whaùs this?
An interpellation, Your Honor?
Iùs that it surprises me.
Really, how dyou manage?
I pay.
Howawful!
Melina. Ifl don't pay,
who'd like to go to bed with me?
I know some friends of Eduardo...
uglier than you,
who are engaged with somebody.
Thanks, Melina.
Do I call foryour radio taxi?
No, I meant fatter than you,
and are engaged.
Buy dyou know?
They don't care, they laugh at that.
- They laugh because they have money.
- Don't think they have much.
Look Melina, I prefer to be alone.
I have a good time.
Besides, I know of
any inspiring couple relation.
Mine is not bad.
"Iùs no bad",
with that is enough!
I love Edu,
but iùs another kind oflove.
Eduardo's an excellent father,
a great supplier.
So did you marry Wal Mart?
He has other ways
to demonstrate love...
He wears himself out working...
so that Lari and I
can have everything.
I appreciate all that sacrifice.
I don't expect him to bring me flowers,
as for him to bring his salary
is more or less the same.
Melina, thaùs not love.
Thaùs habit.
What dyou knowabout love?
Maybe nothing.
But the day I find someone,
I'll feel love and not resignation.
- I feel love.
- I don't think so.
- What dyou knowwhat I feel?
- That you aren't happy.
- I am happy.
- I don't think so.
And you?
Mister "iùsgoddamnedworhtliving",
are you happy?
No. But I'm not telling everybody
that I am...
by showing the picture of a daughter.
No Meli, no!
Stop, stop!
Hey! That story
you were telling me about...
Which ofthem?
The one about the film that came
to your mind at the grill restaurant...
- Yes. What about it?
- How do they handle the deal?
What dyou mean
by how do they handle the deal?
Sure. Are they barefaced?
They should use hoods.
If not, they're two idiots.
Maybe they could cover his face.
With ajacket, for example.
I think they should wear hoods
or women panty hoses.
Thaùs silly.
The one who should wear a hood
is the Galician.
The victim must never know
the place where he'll be kept.
Okay, okay, okay...
When the Galician least suspects,
they cover his face with ajacket,
thread it into a knot with the sleeves
and threaten:
"You take it off, and we'll kill you".
As to my l°ved exper°ences,
I always have the fondest memories,
my emot°on doesn'tforget them,
t°me goes by and I remember even more.
Three fr°ends, we were always,
during that pastyouth...
It was the mostfamous trÌo...
that could have walked...
those south streets.
Where are you, Pancho Als°na?
Where are you, Balmaceda?
I wa°tforyou on the corner...
of Su·rez y Necochea.
Today, none of you come to my call.
Already my l°fe goes off at a tangent.
Today, the old guard shouts:
Who has d°spersed that trÌo?
But I st°ll rememberyou,
my two fr°ends of the past...
- Look at Leonor...
She's deeply moved.
Hurrah! Hurrah!
Master, please...
Master...
Is that you?
Excuse me, master...
I don't pretend to be a flatterer,
but you're really unique!
You're more than unique,
you're a genius!
Don't pull my leg, boy!
I swear I'm not kidding.
You've made me feel as nobody else has.
You're a milestone in my life.
I'd like to thank you
for what you've done for me.
Charge it to his table.
Iùs been years since I have experienced
what you made me feel.
Juan!
Just ten pesos.
- Sorry, ten what?
- Just ten euros.
Listen, Master,
I don't want to be inopportune.
But I'd really like to knowhow can I
thank you for what you've done for me.
And what fucking thing
have I done foryou, boy?
You've been real close
of making me cry.
Just a second, just a second!
Here it is! Here it is!
A warrior of the l°ght,
when he beg°ns someth°ng,
he gets to the end.
Putyour hands to work, Lu°s!
Meli...
Meli, are you okay?
Who am I to tell you
thatyou're not happy?
Anyway,
if you don't want to forgive me,
I understand.
But if you do want to forgive me,
it would be better you do it right now,
because we won't meet
till next school meeting.
D'you understand?
Can you call a tax°for me?
Or I'll call to the one I know.
Valdemar, affectionately...
- Whaùs your name, boy?
- Carlos N˙Òez.
Lito for my friends.
Lito, man...
There you go.
- How can I thank you forthis?
- Iùs 30.
- Thirty tangos!
- Euros, boy... euros!
- Hey...
- What?
And where do they keep the Galician?
Whaùs up?
D'you want to become a scripter now?
You didn't answer me.
Where do they hinder him?
In an apartment in Mar del Plata.
In winter, iùs a ghost city.
- Iùs brilliant!
- You're crazy.
I can't involve my wife in this!
What dyou mean by "this"?
You knowthat apartment
is my wife's.
Wait, madman!
Iùs a script for a movie.
She can't get angry because I include
something ofher in my script.
Don't pretend to be stupid.
I don't understand
what you're talking about.
Be smart, Alexis.
I'm fed up with your "be smart".
What dyou mean by "be smart"?
Okay, she's go°ng.
Is the door open downstairs?
Yes.
Bye!
Keep calm, Lu°s.
A warrior of the l°ght
does not l°sten to provocat°ons.
- He's a friend, Franco...
- Friend?
He's the one who ripped us off
ofthe little dough we had in the bank.
Don't feel pity for him, Alexis.
He doesn't deserve it.
Iùs time to cash it.
Destiny handed him to us on a platter.
Beatricce told us
when she read his palms.
Sorry,
but I'm an artist, not a criminal.
Not even you believe that.
I knowwell what I am.
I open the papers
and find no news on you.
I look at the covers
of show supplements...
and your picture's neverthere.
Some time ago, on TV, they were talking
about the new Argentine cinema...
and I thought: Now, they will surely
mention my friend, but nothing...
They talked about Caetano,
Burman, Trapero, Martel...
They never mentioned your name.
D'you want me to tell you
howl predict yourfuture?
In a year, you'll give up the cinema.
Rather, you've already given it up.
The point is that you didn't realize it.
Who's going to invest money in you?
Howmuch money your last movie made?
Howlarge was the audience?
What the hell dyou know
of cinema business?
Nobody will risk dough on you, dear.
Here the only one who can invest
money on your movie is yourself,
and as far as I know,
you'll never be able to afford it,
except that tonight
we do something...
Howmuch will you ask?
Have you decided?
We've been driving around for 5 minutes
and you don't say where we're going.
Did you hear me?
I'm thinking over and over
about coming back.
Leave everything and get back here.
Maybe here...
I could be myself again.
Maybe I could have feelings again.
In fact, just tonight
I've felt more sensations...
than in all past seventeen years.
D'you see those two guys?
Last time I cried, they were with me.
In 1985, when they came
to see me off at the airport.
Here, people still kiss each other.
They feel, they hug.
Here, one walks on the streets
and feels vertigo.
Here, you get splashed
from the loose tiles of sidewalks.
I love that.
I love when loose tiles splash.
In Europe,
everything is too well done.
Your Argentina of caramel...
doesn't longer exist, boy...
Ladies and gentleman...
I have just had a close encounter
ofthe third kind...
Don't laugh. Iùs real.
I met a Martian who told me...
that this is the best country
of the worid.
The Martian says
he likes Argentina very much...
because here the people
kiss one each other.
Hug one each other.
Feel one each other.
Other ofthe things this Martian loves
are the loose tiles ofthe sidewalks.
He likes their splashing.
Itjust remained he told me he likes
AlfonsÌn and that capped it all...
Isn't it time
you leave forthe airport?
Leùs go.
Oh! The camera!
I've left the compact...
D'you want me to bring it to you?
Do I call for an ambulance?
No. Go on, go on.
In the e°ght month you laugh
w°th f°ve lemon blossoms,
w°th f°ve l°ttle feroc°t°es...
Sleep l°ttle boy,
that I'll br°ng you the moon...
when °ùs needed...
- Dummy!
Where have you put your dummy, baby?
Little box,
Dummy... little box.
Here's the dummy.
Don't let me down.
Take good care of yourself, friend.
Everything's going to be okay,
dyou understand?
- Okay...
- Okay.
Listen, Franquito.
Thanks for everything.
- Don't look
- You either.
If you don't let me see your belly,
I'll showyou nothing.
- First, you showme.
- No, you first.
Well, I have an idea.
We count up to three and we show
each other everything at the same time.
- Okay?
- Yeah.
One...
Two...
Three!
No...
- Are you crazy?
- No...
Get a rubber right now.
I suppose you have...
Alex°s...
I didn't want to say anything
in the presence of Franco,
because you know
howproud and stubborn he is.
I thought maybe you could understand me
and at the same time, help me.
I've seen he's very bad, very blue...
Okay, leùs don't go deeper.
The thing is that, as a friend,
I feel indebted.
I knowthere's nothing better
than the physical presence,
the hug, the comforting word.
But being ten thousand kilometers away,
what can I do for my friends?
I thought that maybe
you and Franco...
could accept,
from a distant friend,
a kind of help, minimum, symbolic,
but which surely alleviates.
I mean, I was thinking...
of an amount oftwo thousand dollars.
But these are from the Asturian Bank.
Who will cash them?
- Are you kidding?
- Jeez! You're right!
But I can solve this immediately!
I give you my word that no later
than tomorrow... right today!
Before leaving, I'll send
a message to the accountant...
telling him to give you
the money in cash. I swear.
Tell me something, Leonor...
Did you do anything
to make your dream come true?
Sons of bitches like me
don't have dreams,
we have objectives.
Well specific and profitable.
- Then, I must be a son of a bitch.
- What are you talking about?
Someday, you'll realize.
Ouch, my hand!
Ouch, shit!
What a fucking tile!
Iùs not what you think!
I knewyou were up to something.
I've been suspecting.
I knewyou wouldn't let me
go by myselfto the airport!
Howmuch I love you, damn it!
TODAY IS YOUR LAST NIGHT
IT'S BEEN A MISTAKE
NOTTO LETME CHEATATTHE EXAM
WATCH YOUR BACK!
- Hello!
- No t°me left, °ùs urgent,
write th°s number.
7 to the right once,
6 to the left tw°ce,
8 to the right once,
9 to the r°ght three t°mes,
3 to the right tw°ce.
Go to my bedroom
and look beh°nd Grac°ela Alfano.
You'll f°nd everyth°ng beh°nd her.
There you'll f°nd enough money
for Germ·n's ma°ntenance,
to afford your costs
and even to treatyourself somet°mes.
As you see, I'm not coming back.
Don't misjudge me.
Stop, stop dude,
what is it that you're not coming back?
Except for money... anything!
Or have you already forgotten?
Be good, Luis.
Be good this time.
Stop dude, listen to me,
just one thing!
I'm not obliged
to assume this responsibility, man!
What a glor°ous n°ght...
W°ll she be feel°ng the same?
Maybe not, maybe she's happy,
maybe everyth°ng's okay °n her marr°age.
Iùs been long s°nce I've felt so well.
Maybe Gu°do's right.
Maybe I'm not happy.
But °f she's happy,
why °s she w°th me ton°ght?
Maybe she st°ll loves me.
Bah! Iùs °mposs°ble
she could love me.
Maybe Gu°do °s much more
than a teenager boyfriend.
Maybe... I st°ll love h°m.
Maybe, he also st°ll loves me.
If she st°ll loved me,
she would have told me.
But °f he st°ll loves me,
why d°dn't he tell me?
But she's the love of my l°fe,
and I d°dn't tell her, e°ther.
Maybe, he d°dn't tell me because
he's afra°d that I don't feel the same.
As soon as I get there,
I'm go°ng to tell her the truth.
That I'm not happy.
Thatfrom now on,
I feel l°ke wak°ng up °n the morn°ng.
That we're t°me proof.
Thatfor her,
I will lose twenty thousand k°los.
That w°th h°m by my s°de,
I'll be happy.
A warrior of the l°ght °s rel°able.
A warrior of the l°ght
may make a m°stake somet°mes.
does not comm°t treason.
A warrior of the l°ght
adapts to the c°rcumstances.
always holds the hand of h°s ·ngel.
A warrior of the l°ght
deserves a reward.
A warrior of the l°ght does not rob.
A warrior of the l°ght
pays h°s apartment charges.
Men, what a night we've had.
- D'you have e-mail?
- D'you have anything to write it down?
Soyfranco@hotmail.com
yobrillo@hotmail.com
Great, I'll write...
and you'll get my e-mail address.
Well, iùs time...
Have that wrist examined, to check
if you've really broken it, okay?
Today, they'll take you the dough.
See howyou tell this to Franquito.
What a disaster...
Look at the positive side ofthe night...
We made a brilliant image
with the guy.
Did you have a good time?
Anton°o Banderas as Leonor,
Pabl°to Echarri as me
and the lame Suarfor Franqu°to.
Maybe he even produces °t.
What °f °nstead of k°dnapp°ng a male
fr°end they k°dnap a female friend?
Sure, as the fat woman
from the Internat°onal Monetary Fund,
but pretty.
Aracel°would be su°table
for that role.
Bes°des, everybody wants to see her
engaged w°th Adri·n aga°n.
I'll get an aud°ence of 100,000 people
at the f°rst weekend show.
Th°s t°me, °ùll be a h°t.
Iùll be a h°t!
Everything must have to be done
very quickly.
When he takes me home,
I'll ask him to accompany me
to the door,
and he'll certainly do so
because he loves kissing...
in such a disgusting and filthy way.
Well, I enter into my apartment,
I close the door
and he gets back to the car.
There you showup,
and cover his head with thejacket,
thread it into a knot with the sleeves,
and I get out to help.
Then, to the trunk, to your house,
keys, Mar del Plata, and next.
Isn't °t br°ll°ant?
One further po°nt...
When you talk to h°s w°fe,
you'll tell her not to even th°nk
of a bank draft.
You'll tell her to send the money...
by Federal, °n l°ttle rolls...
and °ns°de three v°deotapes.
How dyou know he's marr°ed?
When he opened h°s wallet I saw
the p°cture of h°s w°fe and k°d.
Leùs hope they love h°m.
Leùs hope they love h°m,
and very much.
Subs. ripeados por bluciano para
www.clan-sudamerica.net . VisÌtanos.