I'm going to the market, Idella.
Yes, ma'am.
Pepsodent's new improved formula
cleans teeth whiter than ever.
Are you all right, Miss Daisy?
That's good!
You two get back to work.
Yes, ma'am.
-Mama.
-No.
-Mama?
-No!
It's a miracle you're not lying
at Emory Hospital or at the funeral parlor.
Cucumbers are pretty this summer.
You didn't even break your glasses.
It was the car's fault!
-You had the car in the wrong gear.
-I did not!
Idella, want a pickle with lunch?
Not me.
I'm putting up a jar
for you to take home to William.
Yes, ma'am.
You backed the car into the Pollack’s' yard.
You should have let me keep my LaSalle.
It wouldn’t have behaved this way.
Mama, cars don't behave.
They are behaved upon.
You demolished that Chrysler by yourself.
Think what you want. I know the truth.
The truth is you just cost
the insurance company $2,700.
You're a terrible risk.
Nobody will issue you a policy now.
You're just saying that to be hateful.
Okay. Yes, I am. I am making it all up.
Look out on the driveway!
Every insurance company in America
is out there...
...waving their pens
trying to get you to sign up.
If you're going to stand in my pantry
and lie like a rug, go somewhere else.
Okay.
I better get back to the office.
Florine will have a fit
if I don't get home on time tonight.
You all must have plans tonight.
The Ansleys' dinner party.
This is her idea of heaven on earth.
What?
Socializing with Episcopalians.
You are a doodle, Mama!
I'll stop by tomorrow evening.
How do you know I'll be here?
I'm not dependent on you for company.
Fine, I'll call first.
But you know, we have got
some real serious talking to do.
No!
Mama.
I need you now. I have to be
at the beauty shop in half an hour.
No, I most certainly did not know you
had to call a minimum of two hours ahead.
Why call yourself a taxicab company
if you can't provide taxicabs?
Why don't you call your son?
He'd send someone to carry you.
That won't be necessary.
I'll cancel the appointment
and fix my own hair.
Sometimes I think you ain't got
the sense God gave a lemon.
Two dots. I want that!
And a five bamboo.
Well, this is not my day for mah-jongg.
Nine bam!
Thank you all for coming here again.
I am a real pariah without my car.
-Oh, nonsense!
-Three bam.
When do you get the new one?
I don't know!
Boolie's being real pokey about it.
I'll come after you for temple tomorrow.
That's sweet of you, honey.
Mama, you there?
It's just us!
Why didn't you call?
We can't stay.
So I gather.
The Millers are giving a hayride.
I had these made.
Doesn't your baby look cute?
Well, it's not exactly the word I'd pick.
New Graham Greene?
I been wanting to read that.
Sorry, but it's due back
at the library tomorrow.
-Want me to return it for you?
-No, thank you.
I'll go to the library on the streetcar.
Damn it, Mama! Quit being so stubborn.
You know perfectly well--
Go on! Don't keep the horses waiting.
'Bye!
Is that door making contact?
Oscar?
I'm here.
-Are you all right?
-No, sir, I'm stuck.
I know. Fiddle with the lever.
It fiddled out. I done all I know how.
Call Bell Elevator.
I already did.
They're backed up until around 1 :00.
Did you tell them it's an emergency?
You don't have to holler, Mr. Werthan.
I didn't break the elevator.
Got that stuff for Davis & Paxon?
Wrapped and ready to go!
I told them they'd have it yesterday.
Call Bell again.
I hear you.
Look up where the gate
is supposed to close. See a doohickey?
Wait a minute.
Right here!
Reach up and mash it up until it catches.
I done it. Now what?
Operate the lever.
Do you work here?
No, sir. This here Hoke.
Hoke Colburn, sir.
How'd you know about the elevator?
I used to drive for a dairy, sir.
Their elevator was worse than this one.
Hoke's the one I told you about.
Of course.
Excuse me, sir.
Y'all people's Jewish, ain't you?
Yeah, we are. Why?
I'd rather work for Jews.
I know folks say they stingy and cheap.
But don't say none of that around me!
Good to know you feel that way.
What was your last job?
I worked for Judge Harold Stone,
a Jewish gentleman.
You drove for Judge Stone?
Seven years. I'd still be there
if he didn't up and die.
Mrs. Stone asked me
to move to Savannah with her.
Of course, my wife was dead by then.
But I said, ''No, thank you, ma'am.''
I didn't want to be too far
from my grandbabies.
Judge Stone was my father's friend.
You don't say?
-Have a seat.
-Thank you.
Later, Miss McClatchey.
Oscar said you needed somebody
to drive for your family.
Will I be taking your children to school...
...and your wife to the beauty parlor?
I don't have any children. What I need--
You're still a young man.
Don't worry too much.
Thank you. I won't.
Hoke, I need somebody
to drive my mother around.
Your mother?
Yes. Well, if you don't mind asking, sir...
...why ain't she hiring for herself?.
It's a difficult situation.
She done gone around the bend a little.
That will happen as they get on.
No, she's all there!
Too much there is the problem!
I want you to understand something.
My mother is a Little high-strung.
The fact is, you would be working for me.
She can say anything she likes...
...but she can't fire you. Understand?
Yes, sir.
Yes, sir, I sure do.
Don't worry, Mr. Werthan.
I'll hold on no matter
which way she run me.
When I was a Little boy back on the farm
above Macon, where I come from...
...I wrestled hogs to the ground
during killing time.
Well, sir, there ain't a hog that's got away
from me yet!
How are you, Idella?
Living.
-Where's the new vacuum cleaner?
-In the closet.
She won't touch it.
It gives me a shock every time I'm near it.
It works for me.
Good! Then you clean
and I'll go down and run your office.
Where's Mama?
Up yonder.
I guess you know who this is.
I'll be right back.
I wouldn’t be in your shoes...
...if the sweet Lord Jesus came down
and asked me Himself.
'Morning, Mama.
Just come down and say hello.
You listen here.
Unless they rewrote the Constitution
and didn't tell me, I still have rights!
Of course.
What I do not want,
and absolutely will not have, is...
...some chauffeur sitting in my kitchen,
gobbling up my food, using my phone.
I'd hate that in my house.
You have Idella.
Idella's different!
She's been coming to me for years.
We stay out of each other's way.
Even so,
there are chips in my wedding china.
You think Idella has a vendetta
against your wedding china?
Don't be sassy.
When we couldn’t afford them,
we did for ourselves.
That's still the best way.
''Them?'' ''Afford them?''
You sound Like Governor Talmadge.
What a thing to say! I'm not prejudiced!
Aren't you ashamed?
You might as well make the best of it.
I knew a Miss Idella once,
back down in Macon.
You don't say?
She could sing!
What are you talking about?
I'm talking about
this woman had some lungs!
She'd be a whole church choir by herself!
I declare!
Fat, too!
She was as big as that stove!
Don't talk to Idella! She has work to do.
What are you doing?
Dusting the bulbs, Miss Daisy.
That's the silliest thing I ever saw.
Who cares if lamp bulbs are dusty?
Get down from there!
Put that ladder away
before somebody trips on it.
I'm going, Miss Daisy.
All right, Idella. See you tomorrow.
-I'm going too, Miss Daisy.
-Good.
Good morning, Miss Daisy.
Thought I'd see after your zinnias.
You leave my flower bed alone.
You got a nice piece of ground
behind the garage that ain't doing nothing.
I could put in tomatoes, butter beans--
If I want a vegetable garden,
I'll plant it myself.
What are you doing?
I just love a house with pictures,
Miss Daisy.
It do make a home.
I don't want you nosing
through my things.
-Good morning, Miss Daisy.
-Good morning.
It was right cold in the night.
I wouldn’t know. I was asleep.
Idella says we're running short on coffee...
...and Dutch cleanser.
We are?
Yes, ma'am.
We're low on silver polish, too.
I know.
I'm fixing to go to the Piggly Wiggly
on the trolley.
On the trolley!
Why don't you Let me carry you?
No, thank you.
Ain't that why Mr. Werthan hired me?
That's his problem.
All right. But I'm going to find
something to do here.
You Leave my things alone!
I'm going to the market, Idella.
Miss Daisy, it's a shame.
You have this fine Hudson automobile
out there in the garage.
It hasn't moved an inch
from when Mr. Werthan drove it here.
That insurance company
gave you a brand new car for nothing.
That's your opinion.
My other opinion is that
a fine, rich, Jewish lady Like yourself...
...has no business dragging herself
onto a trolley carrying grocery bags.
I'll carry them for you.
I don't need you!
I don't want you! And don't say I'm rich!
-I won't say it no more.
-Is that what you and Idella talk about?
I hate being discussed behind my back
in my own house!
I was born on Forsyth Street.
Believe me, I know the value of a penny!
My brother brought home
a white cat once.
We couldn’t keep it
because we couldn’t afford to feed it!
My sister saved up money...
...so I could become a teacher!
We had nothing!
But you're doing all right now.
What are you doing?
I'm trying to drive you to the store!
Where are you off to this morning,
Miss Werthan?
Just a Little shopping.
Go away! I've ridden the trolley
with groceries plenty of times!
But I can't keep taking
Mr. Werthan's money for doing nothing.
How much does he pay you?
Miss Daisy, that's between him and me.
Anything over $7 a week
is highway robbery!
You sure are right about that!
Especially since I don't do nothing...
...but sit on a stool all day.
All right.
Piggly Wiggly...
...then home. Nowhere else.
Oh, I just Love the smell of a new car.
Don't you, Miss Daisy?
I am nobody's fool, Hoke.
I know!
My husband taught me to run a car.
I remember everything he said.
So don't think even for a second you....
Wait. You're speeding.
I can see it!
We're only going 19 miles an hour.
I Like to go under the speed limit.
But the speed Limit is 35 here.
The slower you go the more gas you save.
My husband taught me that!
Ain't hardly moving. Might as well walk...
...to the Piggly Wiggly.
Is this your car?
No.
Do you pay for the gas?
-No.
-All right, then!
My son thinks I'm losing my abilities...
...but I am still in control
of what goes on in my car!
Where are you going?
To the store, Like you said.
Why didn't you turn on Highland?
Piggly Wiggly ain't on Highland.
I know where it is!
Now take Highland Avenue.
-That's three blocks out of the way.
-Go back this minute!
-I can't turn around now.
-I've been driving to Piggly Wiggly...
...since it opened for business.
This isn't the way!
Go back this minute!
Miss Daisy, look.
Yonder is the Piggly Wiggly. See?
Get ready to turn.
Careful. There's a Little girl.
Yes, I see her.
Pull in here.
Wait a minute.
Give me the keys.
Stay right here by the car.
And don't tell everyone my business.
Mr. Werthan?
Yes, sir, it's me! Guess where I'm at.
I just drove your mama to the store!
You know, she flapped around some,
but she's all right. She's in the store.
Oh, Lord, she just looked out the window
and seen me.
She'll probably throw a fit
right there at the check-out counter.
Yes, sir. You are right about that.
It only took me six days.
Same time it took the Lord
to make the world.
Yes, sir. All right. 'Bye.
Hey, Oscar, Junior.
How're you old boys doing today?
How's the Lady been treating you?
I'll tell you one thing:
she knows how to throw a fit.
What's so funny?
Nothing, Miss Daisy. We just carrying on.
Oscar and Junior been doing cleaning here
for 15 years. Never carried on before!
-Leave them alone.
-Yes, ma'am.
-Put your coat on. We're late.
-I'll be right there.
Idella, I'm going now.
I'm right behind her.
Hear, O Israel, the Lord our God,
the Lord is one.
Such a nice man. And such a good,
short sermon, wasn't it?
I can get myself in!
Hurry out of here!
-Is something wrong, Miss Daisy?
-No.
-Something I've done?
Yes.
I ain't done anything.
You parked the car right in front of the
temple, Like I was the Queen of Romania.
Everybody saw you!
I said to wait for me in the back.
Yes, ma'am, but l was just trying to....
There were two chauffeurs
right behind me.
You made me Look Like a fool. A g.d. fool!
Oh, Miss Daisy,
Lord knows you ain't a fool!
Slow down!
Miriam and Beulah, I could see what
they were thinking when we came out.
What's that?
That I was pretending to be rich!
-You is rich.
-No, I'm not!
Nobody can say I put on airs.
On Forsyth Street we made many meals
out of grits and gravy.
I have done without plenty of times.
Miss Daisy, if I was to ever
get my hands on what you got...
...shoot, I'd shake it around
for everyone in the world to see.
That is vulgar! Don't talk to me!
Never gonna understand some white folks.
What was that? I heard that!
Now, Miss Daisy, you need a chauffeur...
...and, Lord knows, I need a job.
So why don't we just Leave it at that?
Hello.
Good morning, Mama. What's the matter?
No, I don't always think
something's wrong when you call.
Just when you call so early.
What?
All right. I'll be there as soon as I can.
I better get on over there.
'Bye.
Come on.
It's not healthy to rush Like this.
I eat too much, anyway.
Besides, it sounds Like she needs me.
When doesn't it?
Give Mother Werthan my Love.
Coffee, Katie Bell!
I didn't expect to find you in one piece.
I wanted you to be here when he comes.
I wanted you to hear it for yourself.
What is going on?
He's stealing from me.
Hoke? Are you sure?
I don't make empty accusations.
I have proof!
What proof?.
This! I found it hidden in the garbage
under some coffee grounds.
-He stole a can of salmon?
-Here it is!
I knew there was something funny.
They all take things, you know,
so I counted.
-You counted?
-The silverware first.
Then the linen napkins.
And then I went into the pantry.
And the first thing
that caught my eye was a hole...
...behind the lima beans.
And I knew right away.
There were only eight cans of salmon.
I had nine!
Three for $1 on sale.
Very clever, Mama.
I missed my breakfast
and I'm Late to a meeting...
...for a 33ç can of salmon?
You want 33ç? Here's $1 !
Here's $10!
Buy yourself a pantry full of salmon!
Why, Boolie, the idea!
Waving money at me Like that!
I don't want money. I want my things!
-One can of salmon?
-Well, it was mine!
I Leave him plenty of food every day.
I tell him exactly what it is.
They're Like children.
If they want something, they just take it!
He'll never admit this.
''No,'' he'll say,
''I don't know nothing about that! ''
I don't Like it!
I don't Like living with no privacy.
Go ahead, defend him. You always do!
I give up! You want to drive again,
arrange your own insurance.
Take the trolley.
Buy yourself a taxicab!
Anything you want!
Just Leave me out of it!
Why, Boolie!
What do you reckon he's doing here
this time of morning?
Can't be good, I promise you that!
-Good morning.
-Good morning, Miss Daisy.
I think it's fixing to clear up out there!
Excuse me, Mr. Werthan. Y'all busy?
We have to have a Little talk, Hoke.
All right, just Let me get out of my coat.
Yesterday while you were out,
I ate a can of your salmon.
Now I know you said to eat
the leftover pork chops.
Well, they were kind of stiff.
So I stopped by
the Piggly Wiggly and got you another can.
Do you want me to put it on the shelf?.
Yes, thank you, Hoke.
I'll be right with you, Mr. Werthan.
Well, I got to get dressed now.
Good-bye, Son.
You know, Miss Daisy, I was just thinking.
We been out to this cemetery
three times this month already.
It ain't even the 20th yet.
It's good to come in nice weather.
Yes, ma'am. You sure right about that.
Sure is.
Mr. Sig's grave is mighty well tended.
I think you're the best widow
in the State of Georgia.
Boolie's always pestering me
to have the staff here tend to this plot.
''Perpetual care,'' they call it.
Well, don't you do it!
It's right to have a member of the family
Looking after you.
I'll never have that! Boolie will have me
in perpetual care before I'm cold.
Miss Daisy,
you ought to go on away from here!
Put that azalea on Leo Bauer's grave.
Leo Bauer.
Is that Miss Rose Bauer's husband?
She asked me to bring it out here.
Where is his grave at, Miss Daisy?
I'm not exactly sure.
I know it's two rows over that way.
You'll see the headstone, ''Bauer.''
What's wrong?
Nothing wrong. Nothing the matter at all.
Now, you say--
I told you it's two rows over that way.
It says ''Bauer'' on the headstone.
What's that Look Like?
What are you talking about?
I'm talking about I can't read, ma'am.
What?
I can't read, Miss Daisy.
You Look at the paper all the time.
Well, that's just it. I just be looking!
I try to dope out what's going on...
...from the pictures.
You know your letters?
Yes, ma'am. I know my ABC's.
I just can't read.
Stop saying that! You're making me mad!
If you know your Letters,
then you can read.
You just don't know you can read.
I taught some of the stupidest children
God ever put on this earth.
And they all could read enough
to find a name on a tombstone.
The name is ''Bauer.''
''Bauer! '' What does that ''buh'' letter
sound Like?
-B?
-Of course!
''Er.'' That is the Last part. ''Bauer! ''
What Letter sounds Like ''er''?
R!
-So the first Letter is....
-B!
And the Last Letter?
R!
B-R. ''B''-''er.''
It even sounds Like Bauer, doesn't it?
It sure do, Miss Daisy! It sure do!
-That it?
-That's it.
-We won't worry about the middle?
-Not right now.
This will be enough for you to find it.
Go on, now.
B at the beginning.
R at the end.
B...R.
That's it.
That's all right!
-Miss Daisy.
-Yes?
I sure do appreciate this!
Don't be ridiculous! I didn't do anything!
Let's get all this back in the car.
I'm burning up out here.
Here we go.
Of course I told you!
How can I be expected to buy it
if you don't write it down?
I'm sorry, Miss Florine.
I need you.
I'll be right there.
Do you have any idea what it takes
to give a Christmas reception?
It takes an eye for detail.
I told you a million times,
Katie Bell, write it down!
More I cannot do!
We're out of coconut.
I'm sure we can manage.
-I told her.
-But you didn't write it down!
I don't need to stand and listen to excuses
on Christmas.
You figure out how to serve ambrosia
to 50 people without coconut. I give up!
Don't worry, Katie Bell.
It's not quite the end of the world.
Everybody's giving the Georgia
Power Company a merry Christmas.
Bet Miss Florine beat them all,
especially with the new house.
Absurd!
If I had a nose Like Florine, I wouldn’t say,
''Merry Christmas'' to anybody.
I really do enjoy a Christmas
at their house.
No wonder. You're the only Christian
in the place.
They got that new cook.
Florine never could keep help.
Of course, it's none of my affair.
Too much running around:
the Garden Club this...
...the Junior League that.
As if they'd give her the time of day.
She'd die before she'd fix a glass
of iced tea for the Temple Sisterhood.
I hope she doesn't take it
into her head to sing this year.
Lord, have mercy!
Look what Miss Florine done.
If her grandfather, old man Frietag,
could see this....
What is it you say?
I bet he'd jump out of his grave
and snatch her baldheaded.
Jump up and snatch her baldheaded.
Oh, Miss Daisy, you go on away from here.
Wait a minute.
This isn't a Christmas present.
You know I don't give Christmas presents.
I happened to run across it this morning.
Well, go on, open it.
Look at that.
Ain't nobody never gave me
no book before.
''Zaner Method Writing.''
I always taught out of these.
I saved a few.
It's faded, but it works.
If you practice, you'll write nicely.
But you have to practice.
I taught Mayor Hartsfield
out of the same book.
I sure do thank you.
It's not a Christmas present.
Jews have no business
giving Christmas presents.
You don't have to go yapping about this
to Boolie or Florine.
This is between you and me.
Merry Christmas, Mother Werthan.
I hope I don't spit up.
Merry Christmas, Mama. Hoke.
She fought me on this one...
...but it is time for a trade.
I'll bet you'll miss the old one.
No, sir, I don't expect
I'll miss it that much.
Come on, you're the only one
who's driven it all this time.
Won't you be a Little sorry to see it go?
It ain't going nowhere. I done bought it.
You didn't.
I sure did. Already made the deal
with Mr. Red Mitchell.
How much?
That is for him and me to know.
Hey, Boolie!
Got a gem here.
Got that paper, Hoke?
I got it right here.
Be right there.
Why didn't you buy it from Mama?
You would’ve saved money.
No, sir. Your mama is in my business
enough as it is.
I ain't studying about making
monthly payments to her.
She is mine the regular way.
The Hudson's a good car.
Nobody knows that better than you.
Best that ever come off the line.
And this here new one,
if Miss Daisy don't take to it...
...I'll Let her ride in this one.
Mighty nice of you.
We do what we can.
It is three after seven.
Yes, ma'am. You said we were leaving
at fifteen to eight.
At the latest, I said.
What business you got dragging
this mess out of the house by yourself?.
Who was here to help me?
Lord, have mercy!
It don't take more than five minutes
to load this car.
You're fixing to break your arms and
your legs before we even Leave the manor.
You're taking on too much.
I hate doing things at the Last minute.
What you talking about?
Been ready to go for a week and a half.
-Give me that.
-No, don't touch that.
It sure is pretty.
Is that Mr. Walter's present?
Yes. It's fragile. I'll put it on the seat.
Good morning, Mr. Werthan.
You nearly missed us.
You were Leaving at quarter of.
-She's taking on.
-Be still!
Florine bought this for Uncle Walter.
Mama, it's not a snake!
I think it's notepaper.
How appropriate. Uncle Walter can't see.
Maybe it's soap.
How nice that you take an interest
in your uncle’s 90th birthday.
Don't start up with me, Mama.
I can't go to Mobile with you.
I have to go to New York for a convention.
The convention starts Monday.
And I know what else I know.
Leave Florine out of this.
She ordered the tickets eight months ago.
I'm sure My Fair Lady is more important
than your relatives.
Those Christians will be impressed.
I can't talk to you when you're Like this.
-We're expected in Mobile for supper.
-You'll be there.
-How will you stand her all day?
-They'll fix crab. All that trouble.
She's just worked up.
Here's $50 in case you have trouble.
Don't show it to Mama!
-Have you got a map?
-She's got it in the back seat.
It's 7:16!
You should have a job on the radio
announcing the time.
-I want to miss rush hour.
-You will.
Congratulate Uncle Walter for me
and kiss everybody in Mobile.
The air conditioning...
...did you check it, Like I said?
I got the air conditioning checked.
I don't know why.
You never Let me turn it on!
Hush up!
Goodbye.
Good Luck!
Good God!
Turn left.
No, right! Turn right!
Did I ever tell you about
the first time I Left Georgia?
When was that?
A few minutes back!
Go on!
My daughter...
...is married to a Pullman porter.
She is always on the go.
New York, Detroit, Saint Louis....
l say, ''That's all well and good,
Tommie Lee...
''...but l don't feel the need for it. ''
So here it is.
The first time.
I might tell you, Miss Daisy...
...Alabama ain't Looking Like much so far!
Idella sure does stuff eggs good!
You stuff yourself good.
I was thinking
about the first time I went to Mobile.
It was Walter’s wedding. 1888.
1888! You were nothing
but a Little bitty thing.
I was 12.
We went on the train.
Oh, I was so excited.
I'd never been in a wedding party.
And I'd never seen the ocean.
Papa said it was the Gulf of Mexico, not
the ocean, but it was all the same to me.
I asked Papa if it was all right
for me to dip my hand in the water.
He laughed because I was so timid.
And then I tasted the salt water
on my fingers.
Isn't that a silly thing to remember?
No sillier than what most folks remember.
Boy!
Yes, sir.
What are you doing with this car?
This is my car, Officer.
Can I see your registration,
please, and your license, boy.
What's this name? Wertheran?
Werthan.
Never heard that one before.
What kind of name is it?
It's of German derivation.
German derivation.
Thank you, ma'am.
An old nigger and an old Jew woman
riding down the road together.
Now that is one sorry sight.
Oh, my God!
The sign says Phoenix City 30 miles.
We're not supposed to go to Phoenix City!
Oh, my God!
Maybe you read it wrong.
I didn't. Stop the car. Stop the car!
Lord, have mercy.
Here. You took the wrong turn at Opelika.
You took it with me, Miss Daisy,
and you got the map.
I was getting the Lunch!
Go on back. My God!
It ain't been more than 30 minutes
since we turned.
They fixed crab for me.
Minnie always fixes crab.
They go to so much trouble.
It's all ruined by now.
We going to have to pull over.
What's wrong with the car?
There ain't nothing wrong with the car.
I got to be excused.
I got to go make water.
You should have thought of that
at the service station.
You know colored can't use the toilet
at any service station, Miss Daisy.
There's no time to stop.
We'll be in Mobile soon. You can wait.
No, ma'am.
-I told you to wait!
-I heard what you said.
How do you think I feel having to ask you,
''Can I go make water?''
Like I'm some child.
You ought to be ashamed.
I ain't no child, Miss Daisy.
And I ain't just a back of the neck you
Look at while you go where you got to go.
I'm a man, I'm near 70 years old,
and I know when my bladder’s full.
Now I'm going to get out of this car...
...and go over there
and do what I got to do.
I'm taking the key with me, too.
Now that's all there is to it!
Hoke!
Hoke?
You all right, Miss Daisy?
Of course I am.
Is that you, Slick? It's Boolie.
How you doing?
Congratulations on your dad's big day.
Thank you, Boolie.
Thank you. Aunt Daisy!
It's Boolie on the phone.
Hello!
Hey, Son!
Uncle Walter appreciates your call.
I don't think he can come to the phone.
Fine. How's Hoke?
What do you mean? How should he be?
Happy birthday, Uncle Walter.
I got to hang up now, Boolie.
Yeah, I'll tell him.
'Morning, Miss McClatchey.
Well, good morning to you.
Can I see him?
It's Mr. Sinclair Harris, sir.
My cousin Sinclair?
His wife.... The one that talks funny.
She's from Canton, Ohio.
She's trying to hire me.
-What?
-Yes, sir. She said:
''How they treating you
down there, Hoke?''
You know how she sounds,
Like her nose is stuffed up.
So I said, ''Fine, Mrs. Harris,
just fine, thank you.''
She said, ''Well, you Looking for a change,
you know who to call.''
I'll be damned!
I thought you ought to know about it.
I'll be goddamned.
Ain't she a mess?
Said, ''Name your own salary.''
I see. And did you?
Did I what?
-Name your own salary?
-Go away. What you think I am?
I ain't studying about going to work
for no trashy something Like her.
But she got you thinking, didn't she?
Well, sir, you might say that.
''Name your salary.''
That's exactly what she said.
Well, how does $65 a week sound?
Sounds pretty good, sir.
Course, $75 sounds better.
It sure does!
Beginning this week.
That's mighty nice of you.
I sure appreciate this. Thank you.
You ever have folks fighting over you?
No.
It sure feels good.
One dot.
Nine dot.
Two dot.
Mah-jongg.
You are the luckiest thing, Beulah!
Excuse me.
I don't know how you can Look at that.
See it a few times, you get in it.
Both your brains are fixing to evaporate.
You can bring the cake now, Hoke.
Don't make a mess with those peas.
Do I ever?
Lord, have mercy, Look at that.
Ain't she got a lot of hair?
How she get it so shiny?
Washes it in mayonnaise.
-Go on away from here, Idella!
-Yes, she did.
I read it in Life magazine.
Don't seem human, does it?
He will tear you to shreds!
l am not going into that court,
and I’m not giving in!
You are at the end of your rope.
You murdered Carlson. You'll have to pay!
Either choose the easy way out,
or you go into that courtroom...
...and let them carve you
into pathetic little bits.
You have a minute to make up your mind.
What happened?
She up to something, ain't she?
-You fixing to ruin it.
-What are you talking about?
You got the chicken too close together
and the fire is too high.
Mind your business.
It's your chicken.
Thank you, Hoke.
Now you enjoy it.
Amen.
Who is it?
'Morning, Miss Daisy.
What in the world....
I learned how to drive on ice
when I delivered milk for the dairy.
Ain't nothing to it.
Other folks are banging into each other
Like they're in the funny papers.
I figured your stove was out,
so I stopped by the Krispy Kreme.
I know you got to have coffee
in the morning.
How sweet of you, Hoke.
We ain't had any good coffee around here
since Idella passed.
I can fix her biscuits.
We both can make her fried chicken.
But nobody can make Idella's coffee.
Ain't that the truth?
Idella was lucky.
I expect she was.
Where are you going?
I'm just going to take these things off.
I don't know what you can do here today,
except keep me company.
I'll see if I can make us a fire.
Eat anything you want out of the ice box.
It will all spoil, anyway.
And wipe up what you tracked
onto my floor.
What do you think I am? A mess?
Hello.
Mama, I'll be right out...
...when I can get down my own driveway.
Stay home, Boolie. Hoke is here with me.
How'd he manage that?
He's very handy. I'm fine.
I don't need a thing in the world.
Hello? I have the wrong number.
Mama's saying loving things about Hoke.
I didn't say I Love him.
I said he was handy.
Honestly! Are you trying to irritate me
in the middle of an ice storm?
Thank you, Wellborn.
Thank you all.
I am deeply grateful to be chosen
as 1966 Man of the Year...
...by the Atlanta Business Council.
An honor I've seen bestowed
on some mighty fine fellows.
One which I never expected
would come to me.
I'm afraid that my loss up here...
...and my gain down here...
...have given me an air of competence
I don't really possess.
I will tell you that I wish my father
and grandfather could see this.
About 72 years ago, they leased
an old mill up on Decatur Road...
...with, I believe, 25 looms in operation.
They managed to grow with Atlanta.
Till now, Werthan Industries believed
that what we want is what Atlanta wants.
And this award proves that we were right.
I thank you.
Well?
What is it? What took you so long?
I couldn’t help it.
There's a big mess up yonder.
What's the matter? I might as well not go
to the temple at all!
No, ma'am, you won't get to the temple
this morning, Miss Daisy.
Why not? What's the matter with you?
Somebody has bombed the temple.
What? Bombed the temple?
That's how come we're stuck here so Long.
I don't believe it!
That's what the policeman just said.
Oh, my God. Was anybody there?
Were people hurt?
I don't know. He didn't say.
Who would do such a thing?
You know good as me, Miss Daisy,
it'll always be the same ones.
I remember one time
back down there in Macon.
Lord, I couldn’t have been more than
10 or 11 years old, I reckon.
I had this friend named Porter.
One day there his daddy was,
hanging in a tree.
Now just the day before,
we'd all been pitching horseshoes.
He was laughing and carrying on
and talking about how me and Porter...
...was going to have strong right arms,
just Like him.
Lord, there he was,
hanging up yonder in the tree.
Had his hand tied behind him.
Flies was all over him.
I tell you,
I threw up right where I was standing.
You go on and cry.
I'm not crying.
Why did you tell me that story?
Lord, I don't know, Miss Daisy.
That mess back there put me in mind of it.
Ridiculous! The temple has nothing to do
with that!
Yes, ma'am, if you say so.
We don't know what happened. Maybe
that policeman wasn't telling the truth.
Why would he go and Lie
about a thing Like that?
You never get things right!
Miss Daisy, somebody bombed
that temple and you know it!
I don't want to hear anymore about it!
-You're the boss.
-Don't talk to me!
-Where are you?
-Up here!
Hello, Mama. How are you feeling?
Not a good question
to ask somebody nearly 90!
Well, you Look fine.
It's my ageless appeal.
Miss McClatchey gave me your message.
Florine is invited, too.
Thank you.
I guess Hoke should drive us.
There'll be a crowd.
Mama, we have to talk about this.
Talk about what?
About the feasibility of all this.
I believe Martin Luther King
has done some mighty fine things.
If you don't want to go,
why don't you just say so?
I want to go!
You know how I feel about him.
Of course, but Florine....
Florine has nothing to do with it.
I still have to do business here.
I see. Werthan Bag will go out of business
if you attend the King dinner.
Not exactly. But a Lot of men
I do business with wouldn’t Like it.
They might...
...snicker a Little.
Call me Martin Luther Werthan
behind my back.
Maybe I wouldn’t hear
about certain meetings at the Club.
Old Jack Raphael at Ideal Mills, he's
a New York Jew instead of a Georgia Jew.
All the really smart ones
come from New York, don't they?
Some might throw their business to Jack
instead of old Martin Luther Werthan.
I don't know. Maybe it wouldn’t happen.
But sometimes
that's the way things work.
Anyway, if we don't use those seats,
somebody else will.
If we don't use those seats?
I'm not supposed to go, either?
You can do whatever you want.
Thanks for your permission.
Can I ask you something?
When did you get so fired up about
Martin Luther King? You weren't before.
Why, Boolie!
I've never been prejudiced in my life
and you know it.
Then why don't you ask Hoke
to go with you?
Don't be ridiculous. He wouldn’t go.
Ask him and see.
All right.
Boolie said the silliest thing the other day.
What did he say?
He was talking about Martin Luther King.
I guess you know him, don't you?
King? No, ma'am. I don't know him.
I was sure you did.
But you've heard him preach?
Yes, ma'am, same way you have,
on the TV.
I think he's wonderful.
-What you getting at?
-It's so silly.
Boolie says you wanted to go with me
to this dinner. Did you tell him that?
No, I didn't.
I didn't think so. What'd be the point?
You can hear him whenever you want.
I think it's wonderful
the way things are changing.
Now what you think I am, Miss Daisy?
What do you mean?
The invitation to this dinner...
...came in the mail a month ago.
Now, if did be you wanted me to go
with you...
...how come you wait till we in the car
on the way before you asked me?
What? All I said was
Boolie said you wanted to go.
Next time you want me to go somewhere,
you ask me regular.
You don't have to carry on so much.
Let's just Leave it alone.
Honestly!
Talk about things changing.
They ain't changed all that much.
I'll help you to the door.
Thank you, Hoke, I can help myself.
...can see that the South
has marvelous possibilities.
Yet in spite of these assets...
...segregation has placed the South...
...socially, educationally, and economically
behind the rest of the nation.
Yet there are, in the white South,
millions of people of good will...
...whose voices are yet unheard...
...whose course is yet unclear...
...and whose courageous acts
are yet unseen.
These millions are called upon...
...to gird their courage, to speak out...
...to offer leadership that is needed.
History will have to record...
...that the greatest tragedy
of this period of social transition...
...was not the vitriolic words
and the violent actions of the bad people...
...but the appalling silence
and indifference of the good people.
And our generation will have to repent...
...not only for the words and acts
of the children of darkness...
...but also for the fears and apathy
of the children of light.
'Morning, Miss Daisy.
Miss Daisy?
Hoke, is that Hoke?
It's me. You all right?
-Hoke, what did you do with my papers?
-What papers?
My papers!
I had them all corrected Last night...
...and I put them where I wouldn’t
forget them on my way to school.
What did you do with them?
What are you talking about?
The children will be disappointed
if I don't give them their homework back.
I always give it back the next day.
That's why they Like me.
You talking out your head.
Why aren't you helping me?
What do you want me to do?
Find those papers. I told you!
It's all right if you moved them.
I won't be mad.
But I've got to get to school. I'll be Late.
Who will take care of my class?
They'll be all alone. Oh, God!
I do everything wrong!
Now set down in here.
You're going to fall and hurt yourself.
I'm so sorry. It's all my fault.
I didn't do right.
It's so awful!
Ain't nothing awful
except the way you carrying on.
It's all my fault.
I can't find the papers.
The children are waiting.
There ain't nobody waiting on you.
You ain't a teacher no more.
It doesn't make any difference.
Now Listen,
there ain't nothing wrong with you!
You don't know.
Miss Daisy.
-Hello.
-Mr. Werthan, this Hoke here.
What can l do for you?
It's your mama.
What's wrong?
She's taking on something awful.
Why's today different from any other day?
No, sir. It ain't the same.
I'll be right there.
Miss Daisy, now there ain't nothing wrong
with you!
Your mind done took a turn this morning.
You'll snap back if you Let yourself.
I can't! I can't!
You're a Lucky old woman.
No! It's all a mess now,
and I can't do anything about it.
Now Look at you. You're rich,
you're well for your time....
You got folks who care about
what happens to you.
I'm being trouble.
I don't want to be trouble to anybody.
You want something to cry about,
I'll run you to the state home...
...Let you see
what's Lying around out there.
I bet there ain't one of them
carrying on the way you doing.
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
Those poor children.
You keep this up and Mr. Werthan's
going to call that doctor on you.
Just as sure as you're born, that doctor
is going to have you out in that asylum.
Now, is that the way you want it to be?
-Hoke?
-Yes.
Do you still have that Hudson?
You talking about
from when I first come here?
No, Miss Daisy.
That thing been in the junkyard now
more than 15 years.
I'm driving your next-to-Last car now.
1965 Cadillac.
It's running fine as wine, too.
You ought not to be driving anything,
the way you see.
Now, how you know how I can see
'less'n you can Look out my eyes.
-Hoke.
-Yes.
You're my best friend.
-Go on now, Miss Daisy.
-No, really.
You are.
Yes, ma'am.
-Mr. Werthan.
-Well, Hoke, good to see you!
-You didn't drive yourself here?
-No, sir. I don't drive now.
My granddaughter drove me.
My Lord, is she old enough to drive?
Michelle is around 37 years old now.
She's teaching biology
at yonder Spelman College.
-I never knew that.
-Yes, sir.
Seems mighty funny to sell the house
while Mama's still alive.
Yes, sir, I imagine it does.
Course, she hasn't been inside the door
for two years.
I know.
I suppose you don't see her too much.
No, sir, I don't.
It's hard, not driving, Mr. Werthan.
There's no bus that goes out yonder.
Course, I take a taxicab as often as I can.
I'm sure she appreciates it.
Some days she's better than others.
But, then, who ain't?
How are y'all doing?
Happy Thanksgiving, Mama!
Look who I brought!
'Morning, Miss Daisy.
You been keeping yourself busy?
She certainly has.
She goes to jewelry making.
How many times a week?
She makes all kinds of things:
pins, bracelets....
She's a regular Tiffany's.
Ain't that something?
All right, Mama?
Hoke, I thought of you the other day
on the expressway.
-I saw an Avondale milk truck.
-Is that right?
A big monster of a thing.
Must've had 16 wheels.
Go on away from here.
I wondered how you might Like
driving that thing around.
Hoke came to see me, not you.
Looks Like one of her good days.
Mama, Florine said to wish you a happy
Thanksgiving. She's in Washington.
She's a Republican National
Committeewoman now.
Good God!
Go charm the nurses!
She wants you all to herself.
You're a doodle, Mama.
Is Boolie paying you still?
Every week.
How much?
Now that's between him and me.
Highway robbery!
It sure is.
How are you?
I'm doing the best I can.
Me, too.
Well, that's about all there is to it then.
Look here.
You didn't eat your Thanksgiving pie.
Go on now.
Here, Let me help you. I got it.
Is it good?
Here comes some more.