To live... with the soul held
by a sweet memory
which always makes me cry.
From "Volver"
by Carlos Gardel and Alfredo Le Pera
El Chino's Bar
Buenos Aires, August 2001
Warming up your tools?
Making sure nothing breaks.
- How are you, Abel?
- Good.
Hey, Abelito!
Come in, Signora!
A beautiful woman like you
can never disturb us! Come in!
How are you?
Mama, I want a bridegroom
who dances the Tango,
who is manly and brave,
with his hat pulled over one eye,
and a braided cord on his trousers.
He shouldn't be stiff,
his portrait should be
like one on a medal.
Mama, I want a bridegroom
who dances Tango,
who is manly and brave.
I love my job
and I want to die singing.
I hope it happens!
- Let's begin! - Alright.
- Let's go take our places
and start singing.
The Last Applause
Avery good evening to you!
Tonight will be a real treat!
Good evening.
Thank you for letting us perform
here for you again
at "El Chino's Bar. " El Chino
is not Chinese, he's Argentinean.
But El Chino is sick,
so you won't be seeing him tonight.
He's in the hospital
and he's already doing better.
The worst is over.
Now he's watching us,
so I ask you for applause,
he is listening! Viva El Chino!
"El Chino's" is a unique place
because El Chino is unique
and this is his world.
Jorge "El Chino" García
December 1999
Here, there used to be,
just like in all of Buenos Aires,
a lot of fighting.
Punching, kicking, the whole works.
On the street, out back, everywhere.
You had to do it, too.
When you're young, you like to fight.
So you fought.
Did you record that? Good!
Where did that moron put the telephone?
It was here.
What a moron!
El Chino used to show off his room
like it was the palace of Versailles.
This is the kitchen.
The grill is back there
and this is my pad,
my bachelor pad.
Wait. I'll get the light. Should I?
You have to move or I can't.
He never denied his origins
nor the way he lived.
The dogs slept with him in his bed!
They are my maternal grandparents,
my paternal grandparents,
and that is Sacristán.
Everyone who came in said, "Beautiful!"
Not even in the Wild West
- was there anything like "El Chino's. "
- That's my father. He looks like me.
My mother and I on Mothers' Day.
Afterwards...
What do I care about that?
All my life is a yesterday
that detains me in my past,
eternal, ancient youth
that has left me afraid...
This is the real thing
like it used to be.
There's no stage, no microphones.
Here, you gotta sing or you gotta sing.
What did my hands do to her?
What have they done
to leave such pain
in my breast?
Pain of an old grove...
Tango isn't opera.
Tango is very difficult.
You have to feel it and express it.
And speak it in the right moment.
That is Tango.
Orange tree in bloom...
First one has to know suffering,
then how to love,
then how to depart, and at the end...
My name is Delfina Celia Muñoz.
I work here with my husband,
El Chino from the Pompeya quarter.
It is six months ago tomorrow,
no, today,
that my son died
of viral hepatitis.
Answer that!
He got acute hepatitis
and was taken from me.
But life goes on.
Excuse me, but...
The perfume of orange blossoms,
like empty promises of love
that escape with the wind.
Afterwards...
If you took me away from here,
from this bar, it would be
like shooting me, killing me.
It is my life.
If I had to leave here,
what could I do? I'm 70 years old.
...like a bird without sight.
Applause for Abel Frías!
I get hit over the head
and I forget immediately.
I remain tame,
I remain slow, always the same.
I'm absolutely convinced
that everyone is good and noble.
But I keep getting hit over the head,
over and over again.
I don't know if I am too sensitive;
I don't know if I am too dumb.
Always ready, always inclined
to believe in others,
to trust my friends,
to believe in love,
and in colored fish
and in universal peace.
Such good faith God has given me!
And why? They tricked me.
I'm lonelier than a mailbox on a corner,
more squeezed than a sardine...
I don't think they ever loved me
the way I really needed it. No.
They never did.
This is my bedroom.
I can show you everything I own.
These are my treasures.
My mother...
Pretty, right?
This is my favorite singer, Gardel.
I hung his picture here for inspiration.
But my little altar is the most
important of all. I tell it everything.
My mother,
all of my family that is gone,
that's why I have them here.
But what I like the most here
is my mother,
she's in this urn.
She is where she wanted to be. With me.
So I am not so alone.
I don't know if I was loved...
It's the truth!
I loved...
but I have no idea what happened.
I think I gave them too much slack.
Only me.
Let's forget it.
I don't know if I was loved,
but when I was really in love,
I was cast away. Such meanness!
I don't want to be
your "poor Cristina," no, no.
I cried, others did, too.
That's how it is.
I'll never learn.
If they cheat on me, I won't lie.
Again and again,
they pretend love and friendship,
I gave away all my love,
now my pockets are empty,
and I wear a tag:
"The stupidest in the country. "
Such good faith
God has given me and why?
That is why I sing. Every song
reflects a part of life
and sometimes they give you...
hope.
Tell me, what good
was the good faith
that God gave me?
Buona sera, if you are Italian.
Buona sera.
I speak Italian
because it's my mother tongue.
Now I can't say "help me, Mama"
any longer. So I sing Italian songs
because it's my only way
of coping with the responsibility
of having to sing in a place
where everyone sings Tango.
But everyone sings
Tangos written by the descendents
of Italian immigrants.
I think that is the reason.
If it's not, tell me.
The last lights of my village,
as I was leaving my land
are a pain that never left me.
I got up this morning,
Oh bella, ciao, ciao, ciao...
I got up this morning
and I found the invader.
Being uprooted is unnatural.
It's not natural
to leave your fatherland.
Nothing can justify it.
Nothing. It is a pain that never
goes away because it isn't natural.
And this is the flower of the Partisan
who died for liberty.
Tangos often talk about absences.
No Tangos
were written by immigrants themselves.
But by their children
and grandchildren born here.
But that 'uprootedness'
can still be felt in their music,
that means it is inherited.
Would you like to see where I sleep?
This is my bedroom.
But don't film the dirt and the mess!
Try not to.
Here I sleep and here I dream
with my eyes closed, or open.
See? My wife
and my children a few years ago.
This is my wife.
I thank her every day.
Every evening I thank her
for making me a widower.
Sometimes a woman will say to me,
"Disgraceful!
How can you thank her for that?"
Because I learned a lot. A lot.
He lives in Puente Alsina,
but he's not carrying a knife,
only a bunch of songs!
We know him as
"The Troubadour of Puente Alsina,"
Horacio Acosta!
He makes me laugh
with his comic Milonga about a wake.
I laugh
because he does it so well. This Acosta.
El Acostá, "the tall guy. "
A good show is all that counts.
What you do shouldn't come to nothing.
That's what's special about El Chino.
A fly came flying in...
and flew around indifferently...
- and landed, of all places...
- Where?
...on the dead man's nose.
Rocatagliatta, the annoying one,
more drunk than a fish,
saw the fly on his nose
and smashed it.
When he smashes the fly,
and you see how the audience
jumps back, I always tell him,
"You do that so well!"
- It's really impressive!
- Good to keep in shape, huh?
...and with his left hand, he threw
Carmona in the air... - And who else?
- The coffin!
- No!
And the cops suddenly
showed up at the gathering...
and put all the drunks
in the police van.
Garabito and Chicharrón
stole all the wine and the dead man...
What about the dead man, Acosta?
What a high voice you have, Chino!
I'm taking his place.
I'm supposed to say it and I am.
What about the dead man, Acosta?
Give her a hand,
you have to know one thing:
She only had 15 days to learn it.
- Amazing! - What happened?
- To the dead guy?
- He was arrested...
- No! That's too much!
...because a young cop
brought him in as a witness
so that he...
They didn't spoil my punch line!
Not today. Today it's going great.
Nobody knows the ending.
...could make a statement.
In January, it'll be 26 years
that I've been singing at "El Chino's. "
I love music more than anything
and most especially Tango.
There is not a single one
that couldn't be true.
That's what makes them
so difficult to sing right.
You have to feel and sing
what the author was feeling.
Because when he was writing it,
there were probably
tears running down his cheeks.
I am in a difficult situation
with my house.
It is mortgaged
and I'm about to lose it.
In a nutshell, I have a lot of problems.
It's difficult to make decisions.
Without money,
you can't make any decisions.
Without possibilities,
notjust without money.
Like I said,
I'll probably lose my home.
My problems are too big
to have any expectátions anymore.
That's the problem.
Now I want to introduce to you
the singer we've been waiting for:
Julio César, that's all I have to say.
Here he is!
This Colombina
planted in the rings of her eyes
smoke from the fire of her heart.
That Marquise
with the crazy laugh
has painted her lips
to kiss a clown.
From the balcony to the coach,
flies the nervous, thin streamer
like a picturesque broche
over the Carnival night.
El Chino's whole life was singing.
And now that he's away for a couple
of days, something is missing.
The soul of this place is missing.
El Chino doesn'tjust give us...
a job, he gives us
the chance to do what we love.
That's why this place
is irreplaceable for us.
You can hear them everywhere,
the little Carnival bells.
All together now!
But in waltz time!
Everyone join in, alright?
It goes like this...
I want to meet you,
to know where you go,
happy little mask,
calling to me as you go by.
"How are you? Do you know me?"
Adiós, adiós, adiós...
You are the mysterious woman
of my dreams.
Don't disguise your voice,
take off your mask!
Your eyes in the parade
reveal your anxiety...
- Hello, Mama.
- Already here?
- And the game?
- 0:0.
- Acatastrophe!
- It's a totally boring game.
It's perfect
for a film about a Tango singer:
"So old and still not married
because he takes care of his mother. "
But...
If I don't leave now
I'll never leave.
Like this?
This is a picture of us
when we were engaged.
- My husband... - How old is it?
- This photo is...
56 years old.
Such endurance!
- "Endurance"?
- Such endurance.
- That's what you do...
- When you're in love.
That's true love!
Do you remember
how old we were when we met?
- I was 25.
- When we met!
- 21.
- You were 21, and I was 18.
You used to
do the deliveries with your father.
You always went past our door.
- That's how it started.
- Then I brought you the milk.
Then you brought me the milk.
And one day I took you with me.
- To go on a walk.
- Right, on a walk.
And suddenly my mother appeared,
to see where we were going.
Not quite four years.
He's three years and a bit older.
But he looks old enough to be my dad!
I worked in a textile factory.
From when I was 14 till... 38.
38 or 40, more or less.
I was prepared
to look after my house,
my children and my husband,
but not to be a performer in public.
The lights...
have been put out...
And when I was about 48,
El Chino heard me here.
"How this woman sings!
Why didn't I know? She's my neighbor!"
The workers go to their toils,
like every morning,
while, talking nonsense,
a drunken Italian walks past them.
And suddenly
sounds of an orchestra can be heard.
That's how it started.
And from then we never stopped.
She has a child,
and they baptized it,
that's why they're dancing,
the trash from next door.
Encore!
That's how it was.
We never imagined
that it would all end the way it did.
La Chacarita Cemetery
November 2003
- Good day.
- I'd like some carnations.
- Carnations? - Yes.
- A dozen.
- A dozen?
Yes, a dozen.
El Chino was someone who...
He always said,
"If my son dies, I'll die with him. "
But we always thought
he wasjust saying it.
But that's what happened.
That's what happened.
I brought you the colors
of your soccer team.
El Chino is gone
and left us with
a strange feeling of being orphaned.
Because this place was our home.
There's an old saying,
"No one is irreplaceable. "
But it's not true in his case.
El Chino was irreplaceable here.
But, oh well...
I knew him and his ways so well
that I keep everything going
just like he did.
- How are you?
- Fine, and you?
Good. Tired, but good.
- Lots of work?
- Piles of work.
Delfina and I stayed, because I believe
humans know when it's their time.
El Chino felt it
and said to Delfina,
"If something happens to me,
let Omar run the place,
he knows what's up. "
When El Chino was gone,
it was over.
Everything changed.
They wanted to make something else
out of the place.
Many of us stopped going there.
I miss him and my son.
Both of them.
They left me very early.
And I had to take over the place.
Even though I had never run a business.
Now I have to.
No, no. I don't even pass by there.
I feel so impotent.
I'd like to tell them all to go to hell.
The green is calling,
the green,
the green is calling.
That's all they offer the people.
People come and there's nothing.
Nothing. Notjust that El Chino's gone,
but there's nothing else either.
That's why I think the place
will disappear eventually.
The noises are lost
to the afternoon...
The green coffee beans clothe themselves
in brown skin...
Almost everyone who worked here
left one by one.
Now I'm the only one left.
Jasmine, carnations, flowers!
- Hello!
- How're you doing, man?
Got some work? That's good. See you.
Good luck.
My life changed
because everything collapsed.
Destiny made me lose my house,
because I wanted to help people.
But I'm not complaining.
I did it with all my heart
because I wanted to.
You see how I live. I'm happy.
I'm alright. I have fun.
I yell, I do everything I can.
And until the day I die
I will never stop singing.
It's the best thing in my life.
Three Years Later
August 2006
In everything, but especially the arts,
if you have no angel,
no guardian angel...
El Chino had an angel, that's for sure.
As long as he lived,
it was always "El Chino's Bar".
And when El Chino was gone,
the angel flew away.
And the bar's time had passed.
Sadly.
- Want some Maté tea?
- Yes, please.
- Is it warm?
- I think so.
It's cold.
To warm you up.
- This'll warm my vocal cords.
- Are you going? Want some more?
- No, I'm fine - You going like that?
- No, I'll put on my coat.
- Your jacket's so thin and wrinkled.
- I'll put my coat over it.
- Yes?
- Yes.
- Do you want more Maté tea?
- No, thank you. - Alright.
He started singing when he was six.
He sang everywhere,
every birthday party, every celebration.
And he kept on with it.
He started to learn folk music.
We supported him
because he liked it so much.
He even sang at "La Boca. "
- Hurry or the tourists will be gone.
- Think so? - Get out your bandoneon.
But I think he was pretty unlucky.
I'm not saying it because he's my son,
but he sings very well.
That the world was a mess
and will always be one, that I know.
In the year 506
and in 2000 just the same.
And that there were always
thieves, Machiavellis and victims,
happy and bitter people,
originals and imitations.
But the fact that the 20th century
is a display of insolent malice,
no one can deny.
We wallow in the same dirty mud...
I am not over it.
But you can'tjust hang your head.
I don't know...
There are moments you...
when you have to be strong inside.
Otherwise...
I can't do anything else.
I have been singing my whole life.
I went to a couple bars
where I knew a singer or musician,
introduced myself to the owner
and sang some songs as a test...
I hate doing that,
but when they don't know you,
- it's the only way.
- At least you men have it easier.
I can'tjust go out at night
and see where I'll end up.
Nowadays, they even insist
that you bring an audience.
It's like
my friend Carlitos Álvarez says:
"We're the best,
but we're the worst paid. "
Ain't that the truth?
I don't know if we're the best...
Step aside!
Nobody cares if you were born honest.
It doesn't matter if one works
night and day like an ox,
if one lives off women's backs,
if one kills or heals,
or one lives outside the law.
Let's see
how generous the tourists are.
At least we got something.
It is not easy
being a singer.
Especially for those of us who
are convinced we're on the right path.
Sometimes we run out of water
right in the middle.
Everyone wants to climb the Himalayas,
but only a few make it.
Oh well...
Good day.
My name is Cristina de los Ángeles.
This is my demo-CD of Tangos.
Could you please
give it to the director?
- Thank you.
- Have a nice day.
I miss it,
that old bar.
It is such a shame,
what has become of it.
It was an escape for me, an...
I was another person there.
During the week,
I have no problem with washing,
scrubbing and cleaning,
but on the weekends I miss it.
Something is missing.
Come on! Let's go.
It's over. Even the friendship
between the singers ended.
I gave my dear friend my best homage.
Because...
When I left, I said, "I will never
set foot in the bar again. "
I did it in his honor.
I managed it on my own...
but I really
could have used a psychologist.
I became very ill.
Friends of mine died of it.
Don Walter, the Itálian,
died of a broken heart.
Cristina was very close...
to becoming ill herself.
I don't want to hear anyone say
that you forced me
out of your sweet life.
My heart cries out for a lie
hoping for your impossible call.
I don't want anyone to be able
to know how bitter and deep
my eternal loneliness is.
The hours go past
and the minute hand
grinds the nightmare
of its slow tick-tock.
In the painful shadow
of my room I must wait,
hoping for her footsteps
that may never come.
Sometimes it seems to me
that she stops
and dares not to come in.
But no one is there
and she won't be coming.
It is a ghost
that my illusion creates.
And when it vanishes,
it leaves only ashes in my heart.
Hello, Inés?
Cristina here. How are you?
Long time no see.
I wanted to invite you.
Are you busy tomorrow?
Great. Then you're not busy tomorrow.
Here. See you next week.
Is that you, Julio César?
Guess who it is!
Don't faint!
I met some young people yesterday
who play Tango.
Women who play bandoneon.
Really nice people.
I told them about us
and they invited us tomorrow...
- Finally we can meet again.
- It has been an eternity!
- You all look so young!
- Time goes backwards for us.
How are you, Julio?
So nice you could come.
And when I heard the Tangos,
I wanted to sing along.
- Am I looking pale?
- No, not pale, but a little sad.
He's going to pay today!
He's happy to pay.
It's not the Tango we know,
but at least it's back in fashion.
That's right. We're used to
certain ideas.
Would you like to sing with me again?
They invited me and
I want to pass the invitation on.
- How will we get there, Abel?
- Yes, how? - In my car.
- You have a car? No way!
- Yes. I'll drive.
- Do you have a driver's license?
- Yes, since a year ago.
- Can you turn already?
- Yes, but I can't use the reverse yet.
- No way. - Forwards, yes.
- It is magnificent!
Congratulations!
This is a real joy.
- I haven't sung with a large orchestra
in a long time. - It's a ten-piece.
- The big orchestras are dying out.
- No one can afford them.
I'm not saying anything.
Everything comes around again,
life turns like a wheel.
Haven't you seen how the young people
are wearing old-fashioned clothes?
My granddaughter wears my old petticoats
as summer dresses.
I wanted to wear my granddad's
old long johns...
With the flower pattern, please!
Turbid harbor,
where they cast their anchors,
the ships
which will stay on the piers forever.
Shadows that disappear
in the night of pain,
castaways from the world
who have lost their hearts.
Bridges and ropes where the winds howl,
coal freighters
that will never again set to sea.
Somber cemetery
of the ships that when they die,
still dream of sailing out to sea.
Fog of the Riachuelo...
- Here?
- Here. See: "El Colonial".
I continue waiting.
Fog of the Riachuelo...
- Can we just go in?
- I think so.
- Come on.
- What an old building!
...her voice never spoke my name again
by my side...
- Wonderful. Look at the lamps.
- I hear something.
I hear something.
Anchors that will never be raised,
decks of ships
whose ropes cannot be cast off...
Here they are. I told you!
Hello there. We found you!
- Hello. - These are
the three friends I told you about.
Doña Ines, a wonderful singer,
the singer Julio César,
and Abel Frías,
the guitarist for every occasion.
And I sing
for serenades, divorces,
weddings...
She never came again,
I never saw her again.
Her voice never spoke my name again
at my side,
the same voice
that had said "goodbye. "
I think we should use this chance
to sing something together.
Doña Inés can start.
Me? I'd be glad to.
- Check the key with Nicolás.
- Alright. - Have a go.
Try something.
Sure, but what?
- Do you like Gardel? - Of course!
"When you're not there"? - Good.
In what key?
Let's do it in G.
Alone on the path of my destiny,
without the protection of your glance,
I am like a bird that breaks
the chords of its song on the way.
When you're not there,
the flower has no perfume
when you leave...
Thank you.
- See you Sunday, God willing.
- Till Sunday.
With Pepe? We had 60 years.
Sixty years.
One has to accept it
because that's the way it is.
One of us had to go first.
That's that. I wasn't expecting it.
I thought he'd be around longer.
But that's how it was.
When you're not here,
my hope dies.
If you go,
my dream goes with you.
Hear my lament,
that I confide to the wind,
everything is pain,
when you're not here.
You sing beautifully! Very good!
I miss him. I miss him so much.
Every night
I lay down with the same...
...thought: "How lonely I am!"
Even though I am not really alone.
Plenty of people live here,
but in my room,
in my bed, I am alone.
Twentieth century, junk shop,
problematic and feverish!
If you don't cry, you don't get fed
and if you don't steal, you're a fool.
Go ahead!
Keep it up!
Down in hell, we will meet again.
Stop thinking, step aside!
Nobody cares if you were born honest.
It doesn't matter if one works
night and day like an ox,
if one lives off the others,
if one kills or heals,
or one lives outside the law.
- I went low.
- So we'll do it that way.
- Do you want to try going up?
- Let's see how that sounds.
Great. That's what we'll do.
How did you like the rehearsal?
I never thought I would sing with an
orchestra of such magnitude and quality.
But you have the voice for it.
So will you take me?
We're thinking it over...
- We tálked about it and...
- What?
We would like you all to sing with us.
- "La Imperial" with four singers!
- I don't need to think about it.
- True, true.
- Thank you for your trust.
- We'll have to work out a program.
- Sure.
We can'tjust improvise.
The audience deserves that respect.
And we do, too.
The musicians and the singers.
- And you, Inés?
- This is such a luxury for us.
- Do you think you can do it?
- I don't know. At my age...
- Why not? You're still young!
- Let's see if I can manage it.
I had a fulfilling life.
I started singing when I was eight.
I've sung pretty much everything...
- Can we count on you, Julio?
- Absolutely. - Cristina?
I'll tell you tomorrow.
Come on!
Yes, alright!
Let's hope... That is: I hope
that I can keep up with you.
Singing is for me...
I want to sing,
to sing till I leave this planet.
Terrible! You can't tell
if it's raining or if it's...
What weather!
Please!
A little bit is alright, but...
this is too much!
One, two, three!
It's the first time I'm late!
I am afraid
of the encounter with the past
that returns to confront my life.
I am afraid of the nights
filled with memories
that shackle my dreams.
But the travelerwho flees
sooner or later
stops his steps.
And although forgetfulness,
which destroys everything
has killed my old illusion...
We'll wait for you here.
Take as much time as you want,
we'll follow you.
- Where do you mean?
- "The mocking gaze of the stars"
- At "I keep hidden," when you...
- I keep hidden
a humble hope
that is all my heart's riches.
- Good?
- Great. We just have to coordinate it.
Yes, that's good.
But to sing Gardel is...
- difficult.
- A responsibility. I love him,
but I am afraid of disappointing him.
Let's do from "I am afraid" again.
Is the piano ready?
Sorry. Once again.
I wasn't really there.
I am afraid
of the encounter with the past...
Love for me is over now.
Or in "intensive care"!
But I'm not so worried about it.
If life has something in store for me,
it will come along.
I had two great loves.
I was crazy about the first one.
It was a poisonous love.
It didn't do me any good.
But oh well... he died.
And now I'm here and I'm in a movie!
- And you sing. - Then came a...
clandestine affair. He was married.
- Who knew about it?
- No one. Only us two.
- We used to tálk a lot!
- That must have been
pure adrenaline the whole time
when you were together.
- The kisses we gave each other...
- 700... - Don't remind me!
Stay cool, Cristina! Keep your calm.
I want to find someone!
To return
with a withered brow,
and from the snow of time,
my temples white.
To feel
that life is but a puff of wind,
that 20 years are nothing,
that the fevered look,
stumbling in the shadows
seeks you and calls your name.
To live
with the soul held
by a sweet memory
which always makes me cry.
- Very good!
- But a bit low...
Everything changes.
One changes, too.
My face has changed.
But myself, my roots
and my convictions haven't.
They haven't changed.
My Mama spoils me a lot.
Stop, stop!
Do you remember that "whinny"
you played me recently?
Really impressive!
I thought I was singing
with a serious orchestra!
- But not all musicians are serious.
- If I sing of a bird,
- will you play "cheep cheep?"
- We're not all what we seem.
Listen, you do the "whinny"
and I'll do the "airplane. "
Then we'll have everything.
All because of the length
of a horse's head.
It gives up just before the end.
And seems to say to you:
"Don't forget, brother,
you know you shouldn't bet. "
All because of a head.
Instant, violent love
for that flirtatious and cheerful woman
who swore a lie of love
with a smile on her face,
burning all my love
in a blaze.
"Because of a head" is a Tango
that unites two loves.
The love of horse races, of horses
and the love of women.
Both are very expensive,
but women give you a bit more.
They give you something else.
Horses are a bit more dangerous.
Losing by a head
all that madness.
Her kissing mouth
wipes away the sadness
and soothes the bitterness.
Look what it says:
"For Mama, Pichuco. "
- That was 30 years ago.
- 30 years? 30 years are nothing!
This one isn't so old.
It's at "El Chino's. "
- And these girls?
- Afew of the many.
- Cuca. - Really... - Susana.
She wrote me something on the back.
- All types.
- Cristina...
Dorita... So many.
So many women, but when will you marry?
Ahh... I'm still young.
I have time to find somebody.
If she forgets me,
what do I care if I lose my life
a thousand times?
Why go on living?
I met Liliana when she was 13.
I was 17, at school.
I sang at the spring festival
and I had a four-button jacket on,
like the Beatles.
She was crowned "Queen of Spring"
at 13 years of age!
She has a photo of that day
and I have one, too.
We ran into each other 30 years later
and we've been together since.
If you think
that this river used to be clean...
I went swimming here
as a kid with my mother.
We even fished here.
- I've never been here.
- You weren't even born.
- It was really great.
- It's really nice over there.
The changing cabins were there.
You got a token
and you could get changed in them.
- Times were different.
- I'm hungry, Julio,
- want to have a sausage?
- A sausage? Alright, let's go.
Are you paying?
- No! You're the hungry one! - How long
have you lived with your mother?
- Since... '85.
- '85
And you want to
leave your mom all alone?
She'll have to live alone.
My time is also running out.
I'll visit her every day.
Not like my brother
who comes every couple of months.
If I don't move out now, then when?
I'm 58 already.
For your fame,
for your looks,
you're the most infamous gangster
of the underworld.
You're the bravest of the brave,
you are "Ventarrón" himself.
Who could be your equal,
you with your wild Tango moves
to the murmur of the bandoneons,
if the chance ever offered itself?
Now you are no longer
the "Ventarrón" of days gone by.
You're worth nothing to your friends,
and to the coward you're a poor soul.
And when you hear a Tango,
proud and rebellious,
you remember that past,
the glorious pride of "Ventarrón. "
- What great records!
- You see.
- So many!
- They're a couple of years old.
- Are these shellac?
- They're shellac.
- Really?
- So you can see now
what era I come from.
Today a promise, tomorrow a betrayal...
No, that goes like this...
Today an oath, tomorrow betrayal,
student loves
are blossoms for but one day.
Did your voice change over the years?
Of course. Sure it changed.
I had to lower my tone.
- You had a very high voice.
- Oh yes.
When I started singing "Malena"
at "El Chino's," they all stared at me,
because I began the song
with a long, sustained note.
I sang...
Malena...
sings the Tango like no other,
and puts her heart into every verse.
Her voice
is a scent to the suburban weeds...
So you sang 25 years at "El Chino's. "
How was it for you to stop singing?
That was your life?
Yes, we miss it.
And when the weekend comes
and I am at home,
I look out the window to see
if people and cars are at the bar,
but no one comes.
I think it's really a pity.
All I really had there
was friendship and...
the chance to indulge my vices.
Because singing is like a vice.
- It's so cold! - How are you?
- Fine. I'm going to warm up.
- Good idea.
- See you later.
A chorus of whistles in the corner,
the whole place filled with card games.
The drama of the pale neighbor woman,
who never went out again
to watch the train.
And so I remember the nights,
in the Tango Quarter,
with the carts that came into the yard,
and the moon squelching in the mud
and in the distance,
the voice of the bandoneon.
Come to the window bars,
you are the mistress of my soul,
my captive moon,
who kisses me and then leaves...
I have returned again,
my cow herd is on its way,
musician mule drivers help me arrive.
I had to stop
because of a stubborn bull,
here in Calicanto,
on the willow covered banks.
Your love is a star
with chords like a guitar,
a light
that illuminates my darkness...
Come to the window bars,
you are the mistress of my soul...
I think we should do a concert together.
We just have to find a day
where we don't have otherjobs.
"I work a lot!" Stop it!
- You are talking like a singer!
- Let'sjust sing together!
I'll call my agent
and find out when I have a free day.
Give me his number and I'll call mine
- and our agents can figure it out.
- Well, my offer stands...
Yes...
- We'll find a date.
Would you all
like to perform in "El Chino's" again?
When I hear the words,
"Perform in El Chino again"...
It's like someone
is stabbing my heart with a knife.
Sometimes when I drive down
Beazley Street, I think,
"How long I played there!
18 years!"
I would go to China
or any place else,
but to "El Chino's"... no!
Come. Slow down.
Take it easy.
Slow down, Popy!
Or you'll hurt my hands.
- Good morning. How are you, Eva?
- Good morning.
My bread, please. The usual.
Alright.
- How are you?
- I'll pay you tomorrow.
- Fine.
- Or I won't have any more coins.
I should get used to the idea
that the time has come to retire,
but I don't want to stop yet.
I feel I can still do it.
- It must be here.
- Here it is, "El Chino's. "
- Shall we go in?
- Go on. - Go on in.
"National music and culture"
- Good day.
- May we come in?
- Please do.
- Is this "El Chino's?"
- Yes, come in.
We are a Tango orchestra,
the "Orquesta Imperial. "
We're preparing something
and that's why...
we're here.
- Which one was El Chino?
- Him in the middle. The big picture.
- We have a surprise for you.
- How nice!
Nice for you, 'cause you like surprises,
but the tension is killing me!
Look where they've brought us!
You know, you only learn to
appreciate the small things very late.
But they are
what you look for at the end.
What do you look for?
The love of your friends,
the warmth of your home, the smell
of your things...
That's what life's about.
Not about being dazzled.
Day by day you say farewell
to something without noticing it.
To return
with a withered brow,
and from the snow of time,
my temples white.
To feel
that life is but a puff of wind,
that 20 years are nothing,
that the fevered look,
stumbling in the shadows
seeks you and calls your name.
To live
with the soul held
by a sweet memory
which always makes me cry.
I don't want to hear anyone say
that you forced me
out of your sweet life.
My heart cries out for a lie
hoping for your impossible call.
I don't want anyone to be able to know
how bitter and deep
my eternal loneliness is.
The hours go past
and the minute hand
grinds the nightmare
of its slow tick-tock.
It is very satisfying
to see when you make people happy.
They want to hear a Tango from you,
and then you sing it to them.
You enjoy that they are happy
with what you do.
But, if I ever see that people only clap
out of a sense of duty, I will give up.
In the painful shadow
of my room I must wait,
hoping for her footsteps
that may never come.
Sometimes it seems to me
that she stops
and dares not to come in.
But no one is there
and she won't be coming.
It is a ghost
that my illusion creates.
And when it vanishes,
it leaves only
ashes in my heart.
Whilst the serene moon
spreads in its silver light
like a suffering sob,
you can hear the song.
The sweet, heartfelt song
that the whole quarter listened to
when silence ruled
in the old house.
It was a girl from the suburbs,
so they say,
the flower of her quarter,
whom the singer loved.
For her alone, he sang of his love
beneath her window.
But another love for that woman
grew in the heart
of the most notorious villain,
and a street lantern saw
how, in a duel,
in its weak light,
the two of them died.
Sometimes I think now,
"Damn! Why is this happening now?
Why didn't it
happen to me 30 years ago?"
But it was God's will.
That was my life.
I won't change anything.
That is why, a howl in the night
arises from the calm silence,
becoming this song, like a broche
of that past love.
In her sadness,
the beautiful girl
opened herwings as far as she could
and with her virtue and grace
flew up to heaven...
Look, I'm trembling!
Thank you!
You remind me how it was
25 years ago. No more.
That's how long ago I started here.
And it was easier and harder.
Easier, because we were like a family
and it's harder now
because we had to start over.
But it is easier too,
because we used to
sing standing on a block of wood
without a mike and with a single guitar.
Now we have luxury accompaniment.
This is a luxury.
May God grant them the success
they deserve. They really deserve it.
A real luxury!
That the world was a mess
and will always be one, that I know.
In the year 506
and in 2000 just the same.
And that there were always
thieves, Machiavellis and victims,
happy and bitter people,
originals and imitations.
But the fact that the 20th century
is a display of insolent malice,
no one can deny.
We live in a big mess
and wallow in the same dirty mud...
Jorge "El Chino" García,
died in August 2001,
six months after his only son.
Their coffins lie a few meters apart
at La Chacarita cemetery.
Walter Barberis died in 2001,
a few months after El Chino.
His sons are still dedicated to Tango.
Horacio Acostá died in 2005,
shortly after losing his house.
He leaves behind two adult daughters
and an 11 year old son.
Omar Lauría died in May, 2006.
Delfina Celia Muñoz
took care of the bar alone
and died in March, 2007.
Abel Frías has retired
and lives with his wife and two dogs.
He almost never plays guitar in public.
Julio César Fernán has been living
with his girlfriend Liliana since 2006.
He still sings in bars and restaurants.
His mother Rosa moved into a home
and died a year later, in November 2007.
Inés Arce still lives in the house
where she lived with her husband.
She sings at parties and in restaurants.
Cristina de los Ángeles
lives alone in Buenos Aires.
She still earns her living by singing.
"El Chino's" was closed in 2007
and completely remodeled. Today
it is a restaurant with a Tango show.