Come on, come on!
Not too fast!
Careful, the stairs are slippery.
Are you Batman or Superman?
- Are you okay?
- Yeah!
Wait!
You can start searching.
Find anything, Max?
Nothing.
I think I found it!
Max is getting warm!
- The dogs ran away!
- Call them!
Bijou! Pretzel!
Let's open the envelope.
You didn't catch me!
So... what's written inside?
- Nothing. It's weird.
- Invisible ink!
Daisy got it right.
Pierre, give me your lighter.
They figured it out.
Look, it's the island.
They find it.
There's the bridge.
I know where it is!
Come on, let's find the treasure.
See you later.
See you, can we go there?
Where were you?
I rang the bell 10 minutes ago!
We didn't hear.
- You were playing by the pond.
- No.
We told you
it's dangerous for the kids!
Don't worry.
You're totally irresponsible!
- Which wrapping paper?
- This one.
I found this.
Thanks. Do you have any scotch tape?
Yes.
I hate champagne.
Just toast with us.
A drop then.
That's enough, thanks.
It's your birthday.
At my age, birthdays don't count.
A rare occasion to come together.
A good chance.
It's true,
never get to see you all.
Especially Adrienne.
Me? New York isn't next door
and my job ties me down.
Jeramie lives further away than you
but they come every summer.
We follow you in the press.
A friend of mine sent me
an article from Japan.
It was incomprehensible!
I'm working for Takashimaya
department stores,
designing a line of accessories,
both simple and classical.
It's tough and I'm behind.
To you, on your...
No. Stop it.
We can say it!
On your 75th birthday!
Say whatever you want.
Cheers.
The present!
This is from the whole family.
It's nice,
but it wasn't worth the trouble.
Open it before complaining.
What is it?
Look. It's a phone.
There are three phones.
A base and two handsets.
But I don't need three phones.
For your room, for downstairs
and for the studio
or the yard.
So you don't have to run around.
I don't mind running around.
And my phone works fine.
It's too complicated.
I chose a really easy one,
with big buttons.
The manual's multilingual.
No need to memorize it.
Well, thank you...
It's very nice.
You'll have to explain it to me.
- And set it up before you leave.
- Don't worry.
We thought
of something practical too.
Of course it's not very original...
The mohair blanket.
The present for old people!
Perfect for long winter nights
in front of the fire.
And Saturday night TV.
I was just kidding.
It's very nice.
It's pretty and above all, useful.
Thanks again.
Let's sit down to lunch.
Wait. I'll take it.
Look how it suits me.
- What do you think?
- Gorgeous!
Not a real present.
Then I think I know.
Not a surprise either.
The American edition?
They just finished it.
Hot off the press.
Nice, isn't it?
I'm glad they
used the painting we chose.
The lay-out is beautiful.
You can make out the studio.
I expected it next month.
They sent the proofs, but just the text.
Did they hope you'd correct the English?
I couldn't have.
I wanted to correct some references
from the French edition.
The French edition is excellent.
Not the index!
You nagged them to the last minute.
You can't be fussy enough.
Let me see.
Salad?
A little.
Your great-uncle
would have been happy.
You always said
he didn't care about honors.
A nice book,
30 years after his death, in America.
It shows that posterity cares.
Thanks to you.
It's true.
It's the fruit of your work.
You can be proud.
What matters now
is the retrospective.
Have they set the dates?
Yes... July in San Francisco,
November in Chicago,
January in Vienna.
Paris hasn't been decided yet.
Early next year.
Are you going?
San Francisco for sure,
for the opening.
- We'll try to come.
- Us too.
I hope so!
We'll be there.
The children too?
Your wine-drinking grandkids?
Will they be in San Francisco?
Look at this picture.
It wasn't in the French edition.
It's here.
It was taken exactly where we are.
Look! He's in the middle.
How funny! What year is it?
Late 60s, I'd say.
Fifties.
Sixties.
Exactly the same table.
- In the same place.
- Let me see.
It's true.
Why change its place?
It's perfect right here.
Who's he?
Let me think...
A friend of Paul's,
a cybernetic sculptor.
He was a big deal.
He's fallen into oblivion.
That's his wife.
Eloise, the snifters!
I moved them.
They were always here!
It wasn't very practical.
I'll get them.
Don't worry.
Let me wipe them off.
- They're fine.
- It'll take a second.
It'll be fine. Sylvie, Pierre!
Take it easy.
This is Grandma's house.
Come see the two Corots
I told you about.
Who's Corot?
A 19th century painter.
He himself gave them
to our ancestor.
What for?
No idea. He was a doctor.
He must have done him a favor.
There's that one too.
One day they'll be yours
and your cousins'.
You'll pass them on
to your kids.
Like them?
They're okay
but not what I like most.
Yeah, it's another era.
What's the name again?
"Puma". Puma sneakers.
Why do they need
to be made in China?
It costs less.
We have five factories there.
I'm in charge of
technical supervision.
I spend my life in airports.
Air China isn't that reliable,
but it's great. The future.
The future is making cheap sneakers
by employing cheap labor?
It's nothing new
and nothing to be proud of. Sorry.
Think whatever you want.
World growth depends on it.
You benefit from it too.
Converse.
Same thing.
And you call those shoes?
Ask Fredaric.
He's the family economist.
So?
America benefits the most.
Angela,
don't you get bored in Shanghai?
With three kids, time flies by.
I help out
with the Christian community.
They need volunteers.
So much poverty. I do what I can.
Can I help?
I'm not that bad off yet.
Just take the phone and the book.
I'll put them in the office.
Get me an ice cube too.
Sure thing!
Be good and don't forget.
I love having you,
but these reunions exhaust me.
You go out of your way.
Not at all. Eloise does everything.
I'm old.
That's what it boils down to.
You're fine.
I'm not saying the contrary.
It's just that at seventy-five,
I have to think of what comes next.
Meaning?
What will happen after me.
We still have time.
No... Since you're the eldest
and the only one in France,
you'll manage the estate.
Change the subject.
We have to talk about this.
You're never around, always busy.
You're here now.
I have some things to tell you.
First, this is a desk
by Louis Majorelle.
The chair too, but you know that.
You've told me 1000 times.
It's one of a kind.
The Musae d'Orsay wants it.
Same for the armoire
by Josef Hoffman.
In any case,
there are 3 of you.
It'll be divided by three.
We won't touch a thing.
Don't tell me.
Your collection will stay intact.
I've taken care
of preserving Paul's memory.
Because they're my memories,
it's my life.
My youth. I've done what I can.
After me, it's another story.
Ours.
No. You have your life.
No need to become
keepers of his tomb.
We'll do it for you.
I'll be gone. I don't care!
It's all in here.
This is the list
of the most important pieces.
Their certificates of origin,
their approximate values.
They're old appraisals.
You'll have them redone.
And here are the notebooks
of Paul Berthier.
Hardly anyone knows about them.
Notes, lots of notes...
I lent them out once,
for an exhibition in Oxford.
They all go together.
Try not to separate them.
It's what Paul requested in his will.
Come see something
in the living room.
I forgot the decorative panels
by Odilon Redon.
This one and the one in the studio.
But be careful.
You can't tell but they've been
eaten away by the humidity.
It has to be restored.
You'll take care of it.
This display case
is also by Majorelle.
It's not at all my cup of tea,
but it's worth something.
I don't care what's worth what.
I'm not an expert or a dealer.
It will all be yours.
But not to sell!
Yes, to sell!
They're museum pieces.
They're not meant to rot
in a house closed most of the year.
When you're gone
the kids will be grown.
They love this house.
We'll come often!
It's their childhoods they love.
But when they're adults,
they'll have better to do than deal
with bric-a-brac from another era.
In here are the pieces
of the Degas plaster.
The one you boys broke
when you were kids.
That was a major drama.
It is salvageable?
No, I don't think so.
It's sad but that's life.
This is the last sketch
your great-uncle did.
A view of the garden
from this window.
His chair was there.
At the end he wouldn't move.
I remember. He could hardly speak.
That thing in his throat stank.
Fortunately Eloise took care of him.
He used to scare me.
This one...
I want it to stay in the family,
with you.
In any case,
you're the only one concerned.
Jeramie has his business in China.
As for Adrienne...
she's always on the move.
She never has time for anything.
And you?
How's your work going?
I published a book.
You won't care.
Really?
Based on my university class.
University?
I've been teaching for two years.
You told me. It rings a bell.
It's created quite a stir.
Paul Vernon got involved.
Paul Vernon?
The one on the radio?
That's him.
He's eloquent, smart
and has a very good radio voice.
He said my book is full
of unfounded hypotheses.
I'll tell you.
You never read the last one.
It's by my bed. I'll read it.
It'll just bore you.
Wait, I forgot.
That vase by Antonin Daum.
We had the pair. One disappeared.
You've told me several times.
I'm sure Eloise broke it
but she won't admit it.
Even by itself
it's worth quite a lot.
My mother annoyed me.
Why?
She just pretends
that she cares what I do.
I don't think economy is her thing.
Not to hurt you,
but it's not mine either.
Come on, dogs!
She pushed me into it.
I thought your father did.
My father,
God rest his soul, and her.
He was worried about your future.
It's what I wanted.
Why did she want to see you?
To talk about her death.
In those terms?
No, about the collections,
my uncle's sketches,
the house afterwards...
She talked about her death.
Like I said.
I think she looks great. Glowing.
But she's 75.
So? She can still live 10, 15 years.
Women live long.
What would happen
if she died tomorrow?
You mean for the house?
Yes.
Nothing. We'd leave it as it is.
Are you sure?
Fredaric and Adrienne live overseas.
Why would they keep
They're attached to it.
I hope so. I'm not so sure.
They come less and less.
If she's not here...
What will that change?
She knows the question will arise.
She's more lucid than you.
Go...
Stop it.
So she mentioned the Daum vase.
As usual. It's an obsession.
When she's not well,
she rehashes that.
She's convinced that I broke it.
It's true that it disappeared
years ago.
I don't care. I found it ugly.
I prefer this one.
You think she's not well?
She's depressed.
She can spend a whole day
without speaking.
She has memory lapses.
She can forget what she just said.
She brought up the inheritance.
It's her only concern.
She wants you to tend
to Paul Berthier's oeuvre.
She says the opposite,
not to burden me.
Do you remember him?
Hardly at all.
He died in '72. How old were you?
I was 10.
I have a few vague memories.
Each visit with him was ceremonious.
He was a wonderful man.
The house was alive then.
It still is.
When you're all here.
Twice a year.
Can I have some paper towel?
Max spilled yogurt on the couch.
- OK, wait a second.
- Thanks.
Give me a hand.
Take out the cake.
If Mom weren't here,
would you still stay?
Tend to the house?
If you keep it.
We will, for the children.
I'd totally forgotten about this.
What is it? Christofle?
Is was Paul's.
It came from his family.
It's like the imprint of a leaf.
It's stunning.
I'd forgotten but...
I dreamt about it one night.
I hid it under my sweater.
I took it away
and ended up in a forest.
It was raining and it turned back
into a plant,
like a lily pad. With roots.
I panicked.
Fortunately I woke up.
The tea set I took it out for you.
It's too small for a large family.
I can't remember whether
it's Georg Jensen or Michelsen.
Let me see.
In any case it's Danish.
It's Georg Jensen.
They did this kind of work,
hammered silver.
I saw you took this out too.
It's less delicate.
You can see the difference.
It inspired my final project
at art school.
I designed
exactly the same thing, or almost,
with flowers on top.
I did well,
but it was pure plagiarism.
I already told you.
The tray and the tea set
will be yours.
That's not what I meant.
They're not objects
that correspond to your lifestyle.
What lifestyle?
You prefer contemporary,
like what you design.
If a piece works, it works.
You're mistaken. Modern or antique,
beauty is beauty. You notice it.
In general you prefer objects
not weighed down by the past.
True.
And I can't see you
using a silver tea service.
True too.
Paul bought this when he
was showing in Copenhagen
in the early sixties.
I went with him.
It didn't go well.
He didn't sell a thing.
The press was bad.
A real disaster.
Sylvie! Pierre!
I keep calling you!
Enough, we're leaving now.
- Go on, kiss your grandmother.
- Come on, let's hurry.
Put this in the back seat.
It's fragile.
Get in the car.
Hurry or we'll hit traffic.
It's already late.
We still have to pack
and close up the apartment.
The plane's at 1 p.m.
You said you'd come.
We have a guest room.
Not in the summer.
It must be unbearably hot.
And I'm too old
for such a long trip.
You're coming to San Francisco
for the show.
You know how nervous
I've been about that!
No, it'll be wonderful.
I know the museum. It's great!
I know, I know... Will you come?
Of course I will.
We'll all be there with you.
See you in September!
Bye.
So long, kids!
Thanks take me by.
Take easy...
Drop me at Place Clichy.
Wherever you want!
Don't forgot apples.
Shall I turn on the light?
Thank you, no.
I'm fine like this.
The kids forgot
the basket of cherries.
Their parents were distracted.
Thinking about their trip back.
Fredaric thought you were gloomy.
Yes. I spoke to him about my death.
It seems normal to.
They have lives of their own.
Heir concerns aren't mine.
A lot of things
will be leaving with me.
Memories,
secrets,
stories that interest
no one anymore.
But... there's the residue.
There are objects.
I don't want it to weigh on them.
It's what Paul would have wanted.
Shall I prepare something
for dinner?
No, thank you. I'm tired.
I'll go to bed early.
There's a traffic jam
and I cannot find the parking lot.
They have visitor's parking lot.
Everyone arrived but you.
No problem.
So he hates it?
Not at all. He invited you, right?
Here we are!
Hello, Amalie. Fredaric!
Do you know Paul Vernon?
Shut off your cell.
Fredaric Marly,
to resume your argument
and to push it to its limits:
Economy is a huge sham,
a superstition
like a primitive fetish-object.
And economists are the high priests
of a modern religion
as hollow as any other.
That's about it.
Still, if we read
your book carefully,
it seems that according to
your infinite relativism,
you undermine
your own affirmations.
No, I say that because economy
is the opposite of a science,
any attempt to control it,
no matter how well-intentioned,
is often capable
of totally backfiring.
That's my point.
But you're an economist.
So you consider your own work vain.
I was awful.
Not at all.
I thought you did a great job.
It's technical. Bores people stiff.
It's fascinating!
I disagree.
People tune out after a minute.
Writing this book
has just brought me trouble.
You're wrong. It's well-liked.
No, I'm just lucid.
Stores all over
want you for book-signings.
I'll call you.
Tell me for the book signings.
Okay. No problem.
Bye.
My condolences.
Thank you. I appreciate
your having come so quickly.
It's my job.
Your mother
was very much liked in our village.
I know.
She called me last week
about the hunters in the forest.
The wild boars
keep breaking the fence.
I took care of it.
With an electric fence.
We'll do the same.
I prepared the papers.
You have to fill in
the number of the plot.
Come on...
I took out a map of the cemetery.
It's small. There's not much space.
We'll expand next year.
This area is free.
Plots H4, H5 and H6.
It's surprising how much
the village has changed.
There are a lot of new companies.
Their employees buy locally.
For the peace and quiet, the nature.
And they're close to Paris.
50 minutes from Gare du Nord.
A train every half hour.
Watch out.
There's a hole there.
We had a death last week.
It's those plots.
Afterwards we'll have to expand.
That one? Near the family crypt?
There, by that rusty cross,
are three unmarked tombstones.
We'll clean them up.
Over there...
I want to buy the newspaper.
Why?
There's an obituary,
which extracted from Paul's will.
It pissed me off that
I don't want them to publish it.
You said she wrote down what
she wanted to say on the diary's cover?
Yes.
I'll leave the pictures to you,
and there's nothing left
from my place.
But through you, it can go on beyond me.
I think it's good,
it's her wish for the lifetime.
It's a curse.
Of what I'm doing in Japan.
This is a prototype.
Very nice.
You want to see?
It's not finished yet.
This is the saucer.
We start fabrication
in a couple of weeks.
Help yourselves. There's more.
Can you get us some?
Of course. I'll give you a set.
When they come in.
I was shocked by Hélène's death.
It was so sudden.
I can't get used to the fact
that she's gone.
She was drained after San Francisco.
Yeah, but it was
incredibly satisfying for her.
She seemed 15 years younger.
She was glowing.
Her conference on Paul's
everyday life freaked me out.
It was totally indecent!
There were things I never knew.
Me too. I was stunned.
Everyone was.
She never spoke so freely
in front of us.
But... you think she had
a relationship
with her uncle?
Not at all.
What?
It's not clear.
I'm not so sure.
There was something,
but a real relationship? No!
Think what you want.
As always!
Our untouchable mother.
- There was great affection.
- Why always...
Whenever she looked
at a painting of Paul's,
she got immersed in it.
Because she loved him!
- Of course she did, but it wasn't...
- It was obvious.
It was pretty explicit.
To me. Unsettling.
- There's more to love.
- More than what to love?
You could see it.
Every painting brought him near.
Do you mean
a sexual relationship?
- Why are you so upset?
- I'm not. That's not the point.
- The truth is out!
- She never said it. Never.
A lot goes unspoken in this family,
so now I feel relieved.
She tired herself out.
She did too much,
always running around.
Above all she achieved something
with the show and lost interest
I think it started much earlier.
She had enough.
She felt diminished and hated it.
Like at her last birthday.
Remember?
She rambled on about the estate.
There was quite a turn-out.
More than I'd have thought.
It was a nice ceremony. Simple.
Not too sentimental.
As she'd have wanted it.
The village church
was a good idea.
I'm glad she got the roof fixed!
It was caving in.
We'd all have died!
With the money she left,
the priest will change the boiler
and fix the cemetery wall.
It's a ruin.
I liked that priest.
He spoke about her well.
What are you doing?
Going out?
To meet Pierre.
Is that bad?
Of course not. Go on!
Dad wants us here.
No, you should get out.
Here, I brought you this.
No TV today.
I never watch TV.
Give it to your dad.
He needs it.
This is for Pierre.
No PC today.
Stick it there.
We'll never get him off the Net.
We can try.
Your design?
Brand new.
Cool!
Go on, before he comes.
You'll get nabbed.
See you later.
Bye.
Lisa? What do I do with this?
Jeramie...
can you get the other quiche?
What's that?
Can I help?
Is that one with bacon?
I think it's a quiche e la quiche.
I guess we should get down
to practical matters...
You're all leaving.
I'll be here
and I'll have some issues
to address.
I've thought it over
from my perspective.
I'm sure there's a point
on which we all agree:
To keep Paul Berthier's memory
and the house alive
with its objects and furniture,
its soul, so we can pass it on
to our children.
Afterwards, it'll be up to them.
We won't be around.
The paintings too?
Of course.
He Corots, the Redon panels.
It would be so sad to lose them.
Don't you think?
Sure.
We can use the house
to meet up on vacations.
If you have any.
It'll need work.
It's falling to pieces.
Eloise can stay.
She'll look after the house.
I asked her. She agreed.
Should I set the table?
I know what you're saying.
I can empathize, for Mom...
and Paul Berthier,
who I never knew.
Or can barely remember.
But I understand.
But for us it's going to be
a little more complicated.
I wanted to bring it up
since we're all here.
Angela agrees with me.
It's just that they offered
to renew my contract.
I hesitated, but I won't find
a job like that in Europe.
The company's growth is in Asia.
The best potential is
Obviously this means
a long-term commitment.
Five years.
I'll be transferred to Peking.
So we'll have to move there.
The winters are freezing cold.
We told the kids
we'd rent a summer house in Bali.
We've looked. There's great stuff.
It's dirt cheap compared to France.
You'll come visit.
- Of course we will.
- Sure...
Because... we won't have the opportunity
to come to Europe.
At least not for the next few years.
We'll see then.
The kids won't miss it here?
The kids?
You know, we speak French at home.
But they're far removed
from the country and culture.
Their school is in English.
Like kids their age,
they're into America.
Next term we're sending Pearl
to San Francisco.
Yes.
So obviously, for us,
both in terms of the present
and the future,
the house doesn't
really come into play.
I mean, we won't be able
to benefit from it.
And we'll have expenses.
We need to buy in Peking.
The company helps
but I'll have to put in more.
With the Olympics,
real estate has skyrocketed.
I understand.
I didn't realize,
but I understand.
This is just our situation,
but we'll let the majority
Of course.
I'll get the roast.
Can I have the cutting board?
With the knife.
- Here it is.
- Over there.
You want a plate?
This is fine.
I guess it's my turn to speak.
Not easy.
I had something to say too.
And I thought I had a scoop!
Thanks, Jeramie.
You stole the show from me.
Sorry.
More wine.
James and I have known each other
for almost ten years now.
I forgot to tell you.
He had to get back to work.
It's true
you don't know him that well.
He's always on his computer.
We met him in San Francisco.
He spent time with Hélène.
She liked him a lot.
We're getting married.
Next March.
It'll be a really small thing.
We haven't decided
on here or the States.
- Stop it!
- What?
My first experience was a disaster
but there's no...
We never said "disaster".
- I didn't.
- Neither do I.
We're happy for you.
We just didn't expect this.
Don't rub it in!
Congratulations.
This means that a lot of things
will change for us.
First because
we both live in New York.
I have my agency
with most of my clients and he...
He's artistic director
of an internet magazine.
He's from Denver, right?
Yes, we spend summers there.
I hear it's nice.
I'd love to go hiking
with you some time in Colorado.
In the end,
I won't make it
more than once a year to France.
Maybe once in a while...
So... I don't want to take sides
or cast the decisive vote,
but that's where I'm at.
I won't benefit from the house.
But over the years...
it no longer means much to me.
France neither.
So you vote to sell.
Yes, sure. I vote to sell.
You too, Jeramie?
Yes.
You're just being diplomatic.
You could say that.
I wouldn't vote against you.
We're not voting against you either.
I gave my point of view.
I want us to agree
and decide what's best for everyone.
Want some?
Just a drop.
Wine?
- No, thanls.
- Some more?
Sure. It's very good.
Thanks.
- Some more?
- Yes.
Let's make a decision.
It's obvious we're selling.
Since I'm the only one
living in Paris,
I'll have to deal
with the practical stuff.
Obviously I'll keep you posted...
We'll consult on major decisions.
There's a whole slew
of furniture, paintings, books...
We should see if it's worth
selling it all off at auction.
I know someone who can help...
There are some things I'd like
for sentimental reasons.
As for the rest,
I don't know what to do.
The problem will be the estate tax.
We should try to keep the Corots.
We can't cut them in three.
They're what's most valuable.
If Jeramie needs money,
they should be sold first.
- That's my cup.
- Sorry.
Probably best to organize
one big auction.
We can do a catalogue.
"The Paul Berthier Collection".
Pictures, well laid-out,
of what we like most.
To have a trace.
And you know,
I'm more used to this than Fredaric.
I can help. He doesn't know much.
He'll make mistakes...
I'll be stuck in China.
If I can help, I will.
But the time difference...
We'll manage.
Fredaric?
You're crying?
Don't be ridiculous.
Sorry.
Okay! Everyone's here.
Mr. Lambert will see you shortly.
Nice going.
I couldn't find a spot.
There's a parking lot.
No problem.
Mr. Lambert is on the phone.
Sorry for the wait.
Please, take a seat.
There are enough chairs.
It's all pretty clear. It would have
been more so, if your mother
had taken certain measures
to prepare for her passing.
I told her to see a lawyer
but she wouldn't hear of it.
Normal superstition.
The problem is,
you may be taxed to the max.
I looked at the list.
It seems that the bulk
of the estate is here.
The paintings, the furniture...
I'm no expert but some of this
seems very valuable.
The paintings alone.
Especially the Corots.
His value on the international market
is hard to call.
And... his subject matter is austere.
In any case,
you'll have to get it appraised.
The best way to lessen the estate tax,
which will be very
is to donate to the State.
The Musae d'Orsay is interested,
in principle.
Hélène said so.
The Majorelle desk...
The Joseph Hoffman armoire too.
They're important pieces.
They come up rarely.
They won't let them go.
And we know the curator of
the department of Decorative Arts.
Mom's friend.
It should work out.
Very well, then.
He'll help present your case.
The museum must then get clearance
from the tax department.
There are some sketches
by Paul Berthier, all his notebooks.
We could sell them
in the United States.
It's good to get
international recognition.
I thought I might help.
Yes, if you get an export permit.
Otherwise I think you've
all agreed to sell the house?
Yes, we discussed it.
Too much upkeep.
And we don't really need it.
I know a good realtor.
He says he can sell it.
He's selling our place in Paris.
Mr. Rosen.
You've told him?
We've discussed it for a while.
Informally.
What does he say?
It's not his specialty,
but he asked around.
It'll sell fast, and well.
He's confident.
You wasted no time.
I don't get it.
It was a given.
You counted on it.
What was your plan?
I had no plan. I love the house.
I thought we all did.
I wasn't doing the math.
That's unfair.
I like the house too.
I have a job
that takes unexpected turns.
Three kids.
I have tough choices to make.
Sorry, I do math.
Can you talk about this later?
So you have Mr. Rosen's number?
Of course.
At the bottom.
Thank you.
Just a second. I'm coming.
I have to go. I'll stop by the hotel.
My flight's at 3.
I'll be back in 10 days.
I'll be gone.
So I'll see you when I see you.
Tell me for Pearl.
We'll talk it over.
I'll take her on vacation.
Just tell me.
Nothing doing.
Always on the move.
Want to get a drink?
Sure.
There?
That's fine.
She got that from Mom.
What?
Never staying put.
Always wanting to be elsewhere.
She's running from something.
Not us, I hope.
Now that you mention it.
I'm sure...
What do you want?
Coffee.
Hellow.
- Can we have two coffees?
- Yes.
If you don't mind. Mom was the same.
Devoted to her uncle because
she hated Dad's radiator
She loved him.
But she looked down on him.
The day after he died
she took on her maiden name.
Berthier sounds better
than Mrs. "Radiator" Marly.
That was questionable
but at times Dad was a bit much.
You're wrong.
Rough, but more sensitive than her.
He paid the bills,
was sneered at and kept quiet.
Because... he felt inferior.
She suffocated him with her uncle.
Paul Berthier was a great artist.
Yeah, I don't know.
Some stuff is good, others less.
You're wrong.
It's all great. Really.
You know,
Thanks.
You knoe what? Don't be angry with me.
It was difficult moving to China.
I thought it was temporary.
To make some quick money.
Now it's your life.
Mine and that of my kids.
You won't come back.
No, I don't think so.
Mom knew it.
She felt it.
She told me. I wouldn't listen.
You know the only thing I regret?
The two Corots.
Why not keep them?
And buy you out?
It's beyond my means.
I need the money.
You're not angry?
No.
Are you sure?
And Eloise?
She'll get the house in order.
Then she'll retire.
As far as I understand,
her relatives
have a nice place in the south.
She'll live with them.
Good. Glad to hear it.
Strange to imagine
the house being sold.
Yeah.
With other people in it...
other routines...
another way of living.
Eloise gone.
Yes. Eloise gone.
- Fine.
- That; s it.
See you around.
Were you able to follow?
It was fine.
I lost sight of you for a second.
You have the key, right?
No.
I gave it to you for the padlock.
No, you didn't.
Sorry.
I'll shut off the alarm.
Remember the code?
Yes.
I'll hold onto the key.
This way, please.
Here's the vase I told you about.
By Daum. It's signed here.
It was one of a pair.
The sketchbooks are this way...
We have to go out
to get to the studio.
Come see the Corots.
Please. And the Redon panels.
Just one.
The other's being restored.
It really needed it.
Here they are.
I don't know them.
Done in the area?
I think so. My mother said
that's where the supermarket is
We passed it
we left L'lsle Adam.
- I'll go first.
- After you...
Mom listed everything here.
Very well-organized.
These are the sketchbooks.
If you want to look.
I saw some of them
at the Oxford show.
But it was far from complete.
What do you plan to do?
I'd like to sell them
in New York.
I know it won't be easy.
Which is why
they should stay together.
I'm sorry. It's unsettling.
First time back
since Hélène died.
We left it intact.
Yes, I can see.
As she did,
ever since Paul died.
Everything about him was sacred,
sometimes annoyingly so.
She really loved him.
You mean she was fond of him?
She was Paul's last great passion.
His last great passion. Mom.
Because of the family
they had to keep it a secret.
You were kids.
You wouldn't have understood.
I saw them together often.
It was very moving.
Your mother was truly happy
back then.
#Call Fredaric
to set up the phone#
Majorelle didn't make
many display cases.
Yours is the last one to be found
in a private collection.
The key is in the office.
Here's the Majorelle desk.
We'll see it better
once it's cleared off.
The museum has wanted it
for a while.
I think she left the key here.
I'm a bit confused.
Where is the Hoffman armoire?
Right behind you.
Paul Berthier showed it to me
when he bought it.
He was very proud.
He had a good eye.
No one cared about
Viennese modernism then.
It was frowned upon.
I took the hands.
- You mind?
- Not at all.
They have no value.
Besides sentimental.
I'll show you the porcelain.
There's more but...
Mom gave this to me. I'll keep it.
Theodore Haviland,
designed by Suzanne Lalique.
Thanks, I know it by heart.
Full set?
Is it a full set?
Of course.
Are you keeping it too?
No way. Definitely not.
I'm taking this. Here it is.
You didn't mention these.
They were always around.
I never noticed.
Monogramed H&Co.
They're by Felix Bracquemond.
He did very little glasswork
in the 1880s.
They're very nice.
Modern for the time.
Where did you find these?
What?
They're Bracquemond vases!
They were in a closet.
Not Mom's favorites.
She never mentioned them.
It wasn't her taste
but Paul Berthier
appreciated Bracquemond.
The impressionistic vases
may also be his.
Where are they?
On the chimney.
The pseudo-Japanese things...
Have a look
and tell me what you think.
I don't know Bracquemond.
There was a show in Limoges
a few years ago.
The vases
can only strengthen our case.
You think it'll work?
It should.
Hélène and I
often discussed this donation.
What did she say?
That it was up to you
all to decide, not her.
I don't want to be insistent
with Adrienne but...
I'm skeptical about
the export permit for the notebooks.
Such an important ensemble
shouldn't leave the country.
Or be broken up.
She won't be breaking it up.
She's deceiving herself.
She's considering Christie's
in New York.
That's what she said.
They'll advise her
to sell them by the page.
You have the key to the cabinet.
Damn, I took it
and left it in my pocket.
Nothing doing,
she used this as her broom closet.
Look. Rust remover! What's this?
That's Paul's last sketch.
The view from here.
See?
Mom wanted you to have it.
I know.
And look here. The pieces
of the Degas plaster I mentioned.
Can I have a look?
Of course.
It's in terrible condition!
Can you help me carry the painting?
I'm coming.
We'll lay it against the wall.
Careful...
I heard you were coming.
Flowers, how nice.
Your mom hated rooms without flowers.
Empty vases were like death to her.
Asters. They were her favorites.
It's the season.
You took a taxi?
My nephew has a cab. He drove me.
He wouldn't come in. He's outside.
This packing up is very disturbing.
For me too.
Yes, I can imagine.
For the family it must be sadder.
I wanted to say...
I'm really sorry.
I didn't want to sell.
But... it's impossible.
I told you before.
Dividing things among us
wasn't easy.
Your mom suspected it.
That Jeramie and Adrienne
wouldn't come back to France.
She spoke about it.
What did she say?
That after she died,
the house would have to be sold.
You know she left you some money?
It's the lawyer
who will give it to you.
He'll get in touch with you.
Call and I'll explain
how you should declare it.
It's stupid paperwork
but you can't push it off.
I want you to keep something of my mom.
A souvenir...
one of her belongings.
Thanks, but I'd be embarrassed.
Don't be. It's the least we can do.
Okay then.
There's a vase
with big green bubbles.
I can keep putting flowers in it
and think of her.
What's that?
A vase. Fredaric gave it to me.
He said to choose anything.
I couldn't take advantage.
I took something ordinary.
What would I do
with something valuable?
I agree. It was the right thing to do.
Mr. Marly, follow me.
It's no big deal.
We gave her a scare.
We'll run a few checks
and let her go. Sit down.
Thanks.
But it's serious.
I'm shocked. I had no idea.
She's serious. A good student.
The store manager
spotted her a while ago.
These girls
then sell the clothes at school.
Have you noticed anything?
Last night we saw an exhibition.
Contemporary art, very difficult.
She was interested.
Has she been spending
more than usual?
Anything beyond her means?
I don't know. Maybe. I can't tell.
I'll ask my wife.
A friend of hers got away
and is still unidentified.
She has lots of... friends...
From the gym. They come and go.
I'm not often home.
My work often takes me overseas...
And to make matters worse,
we found this in her bag.
I won't prosecute for 3 grams.
Too much paperwork.
We're lucky it's not crack.
But if it happens again,
I'll be less understanding.
She doesn't have a record.
She's a good student.
Am I making myself clear?
Fredaric Marly.
Is this a bad time?
Have you heard anything?
Sorry! I thought it was earlier.
The meeting was pushed off.
I'm on my way there now.
As we speak. I'll call you afterwards.
Okay?
I promise.
Bye.
Did you call me a cab?
Hello, sir.
Good day, my friend.
Ladies and gentlemen...
We'll now be turning
to the Berthier bequest.
Mr. Waldemar
is going to tell us about it.
It's a remarkably interesting collection
of Art Nouveau
including these wonderful panels
by Odilon Redon.
These pieces have interested
the Musae d'Orsay for years.
Especially the Majorelle desk,
which you know.
Helene Berthier
once lent it to us for a show.
We're also interested
in this display case by the same
There are three others
but they're all unfortunately
out of the country.
We also have this vase
by Félix Bracquemond
and these two others
from the Auteuil atelier.
And obviously the two
decorative panels by Odilon Redon.
You each have the list
in front of you.
Why so few pieces by Paul Berthier?
The family doesn't have many at all
and they decided to keep them.
I heard that Adrienne Marly
is selling Berthier's notebooks
at Christie's.
They'll be ripped to shreds.
Something has to be done.
Excuse me, but I spoke with her
recently about this.
That possibility
seems to have been discarded.
On a personal level,
if you'll allow me, sir,
I must voice serious objections.
Concerning Art Nouveau furniture,
it's always the same thing.
We're told
how exceptionally rare it is
and it always ends up
locked in a storage room.
People aren't ready for it.
Stealing and smoking. Great!
I didn't rat on Aurore.
That would have been.
It's the first time.
Yeah, right.
Sorry.
Okay, it's not.
And honest too!
You smoke pot too.
I don't get caught!
More experience.
No, more careful!
So I'll be more careful.
Start by putting an end
to this crap!
I got it. The cops lectured me
for two hours, thanks.
Anything else to tell me?
Like what?
Let's continue.
Usually when there's
shoplifting plus drugs,
there's also a guy.
If there's a guy,
tell me before the cops do.
Sort of.
Sort of a guy?
Yes.
And sort of fooling around?
Sort of.
Sort of more?
We're careful.
You're careful.
Totally careful.
Excellent. Now I feel reassured.
So who is this totally careful guy?
None of your business.
Okay. You don't have to answer.
It's your right.
But it is my business.
You don't know him.
Is he from school?
No.
Let me guess. You met at the gym.
We can never have a serious talk.
Go on, answer.
If you get pulled over, no big deal.
We'll go back to the Police station.
Yeah, great! Slam the door!
How did it go with the committee?
So these things interest you now?
Normal. It's all you talk about.
I got your sister out of jail.
Still, couldn't you find out?
I had no time.
So call now.
It's too late to call the curator.
Don't you care what she did?
I know. Her friend called.
To say what?
To flush some weed
down the toilet.
Did you?
Sure. It could have been bad!
For you too, as her legal.
This building contains
our restoration studios.
Over there is cabinet-making,
ironworks there...
and sculpture here.
- Are we interrupting?
- No, come in.
- Nice to see you.
Now here's an interesting piece.
We received it as a donation.
The work Bruno is doing on it
is really amazing.
It's new to me too.
You really have rescued it.
I honestly
didn't think it possible.
Almost over.
We've done the whole place.
We're in Furniture
but I'm losing my group.
Let's see a movie.
Choose something.
I can meet you wherever.
I won't be long.
Strange seeing it here.
I don't know what to think.
Me neither.
It's nicely displayed.
Who designed that lamp?
What's-his-name. No idea.
Doesn't it seem caged?
No. A lot of people benefit.
Benefit? They walk pass by.
They pass and look.
It's history. For everyone.
Do those vases have a history?
They mean something
with flowers, in a living room.
In natural light. Otherwise
they're disenchanted.
Same goes for paintings then.
Of course. Remember Antonio Bernardi?
Yes.
We visited a private collection
in Switzerland.
In Lugano. I couldn't come.
This financier kept all his paintings
in a modern apartment
with metal shutters
and alarms everywhere.
He was so proud to show it to us.
Antonio saw one of the paintings
and he went pale.
His ex-wife's portrait.
- Francesca.
- Yes.
No news of her?
She died. Long ago. Cancer.
For Antonio, she was in prison.
He wanted to haul it away.
Look!
What?
Oh yeah.
I forgot to tell you.
It's valuable.
There's another one. I gave it to Eloise.
I loved her Christmas card.
It made me cry.
It moved me too.
Did you answer her?
I forgot.
You promised you would.
Come on... let's go.
We shouldn't have sold the Corots.
Forget the Corots!
We couldn't care less!
Stop mulling it over.
It's exhausting!
You'd have bought them out?
Why not?
With what money?
I'd have managed. Taken a loan.
And the house?
Why not?
You know it was impossible.
Thank you.
Anyway, it's over now.
I sign the sales agreement next week.
The kids want to throw a party
there with friends.
Let them have fun.
We still own it for a month.
Good. They'd have been upset.
Are they spending the weekend?
I don't know.
I think that's what they said.
They'd better behave.
Why?
Tell me if you need something.
I will.
We'll be in Spain all summer.
Muriel told me.
We'll be back in September.
Have fun.
You can always call.
I won't bother you.
You have Muriel's cell?
I have.
Got a light?
Every thing ok?
Thanks, it's heavy.
We can drop this all here.
I'll show you the bedrooms.
First floor there's a bedroom.
Bathroom on the left,
toilet on the right.
What are you doing?
For the fire.
- Where was the wood?
- Out back.
It's the neighbor's.
You've taken a ton.
- What about the music?
- Coming along.
Is there a problem?
You want to try?
You do it!
Take this.
OK?
Where's Richard?
I saw him in the studio.
Thanks.
- Is Richard around?
- He just left.
He went to the pond.
Thanks.
Hey guys, I brought beer.
What's up, guys? Want to share that?
Are you okay?
Let's change the music.
My grandma used to take me here.
I'd help her pick fruit.
She'd tell me stories.
What kind of stories?
How she did the same thing
with her uncle.
There's a painting of her
as a child picking cherries.
From this angle. No...
That way, because
the house is in the background.
It wasn't hidden by trees yet.
Where's the painting?
A collector has it in Lyon.
We ate at his place once.
She also said that one day
I'd bring my children here.
When I have kids.
What's wrong?
Are you crying?
My grandmother's dead.
The house has been sold.
Sylvie! Richard!
We're waiting!
I don't want them to find us.
We have to climb the wall.