The wind’s too strong!
- Awful weather.
- The letters must shine.
Some wind you have in this village!
The women here
live longer than the men.
Except our poor mother...
She got lucky.
Don’t say that, Raimunda.
Mother died in father’s arms.
It’s how she would have wanted it.
She wanted to die in a fire?
I think it was a good death.
They were asleep, didn’t notice at all.
What difference does that make?
That’s not a way to speak.
Hello, Augistina.
Bye, Augustina.
Good day, Manola.
Mom, what else should I bring?
That’s all.
Now, she’s an eyeful.
Augustina!
This is Paula, right? Wonderful girl!
Let me kiss her.
Ah, something’s wrong here.
She stole her father’s eyes.
How are you?
- Not like before.
My lot is impossible
to keep clean.
It’s a nightmare.
- Well. it looks great.
I feel such peace
when I’m taking care of my mound.
I often come here alone,
I sit down and forget all worry.
We have to go and see aunt Paula before we leave.
Come by and visit me, too!
Of course.
Wait, how’s Paco doing?
Fine, he stayed in Madrid—too much work.
Mother, is it true that aunt Augustina
comes to look after her own grave?
Yes, that’s how it’s done around here.
You buy yourself a lot and maintain it.
What a nutcase.
That’s how it’s done.
I’ll drive?
- Yes, yes.
Aunt Paula?
Who is it?
Raimunda.
Let’s be quick.
I don’t want to stay the night.
Put a smile on for your aunt.
Okay.
The house smells as awful as ever.
Aunt Paula, how are you?
My, you look thin! Are you on a diet?
Ever since I turned 14.
Who are these people?
What do you mean who?
Solia and my Paula.
Paula looks just like me.
Let’s go to the dining room.
Sure, come on in.
Solia looks so much older…
Can I turn it off?
- Turn it off, I’m not watching.
Fires are a terrible thing.
So, what brings you here?
I don’t know. Maybe we can talk.
No.
- Let’s have breakfast then.
Look in the cupboard.
My rheumatism is killing me.
I found doughnuts,
just like mother’s.
How was the cemetery?
Mom would have been pleased.
Did you clean it well?
Of course.
She likes it very clean.
If she could do it herself, she would
but of course she can’t.
Yes, too bad she can’t.
Auntie, don’t you ever get lonely
here in this big house?
You’d be better off in a home.
They’ll take care of you.
I like it here.
Can I use the bathroom?
Go.
Still, living alone is no good.
I’m worried about you.
How do you manage with food?
Augustina brings me bread.
If I need anything else from the store
I just call them.
Don’t worry.
So pretty.
Look what your aunt has made.
She even inscribed your name.
Are we leaving soon?
We are.
Aunt Paula, we should go.
I have a bout of rheumatism again.
Don’t get up.
This can’t go on.
I’m still worried, next time
I’m taking you with me.
Yes, yes, next time.
If there is one.
Of course there will be.
Take care of yourself.
You, too.
Of course.
Auntie, I love you so much.
Are we stopping at Augustina’s?
- Yes.
Come on in!
So, how did your aunt seem to you?
Bad.
Terrible.
She’s so stubborn. I can’t imagine
how she manages by herself.
She manages. No other choice.
Every day, I bring her bread.
She won’t starve, at least.
Let’s go out in the yard.
- I’m sad.
She talks about our mother.
As if she’s alive.
Yes, that’s what she does.
Come, sit down, let’s talk.
I’ll give you some money
to take good care of her.
No need to give me anything.
It’s my pleasure.
I’d take her with me
but she won’t let me.
I don’t know what to do with her.
We’ll think of something.
Every day when I go to the store
I knock on her window
and I stay until I see her.
Don’t worry, she’s in good hands.
You can’t imagine how grateful I am.
I just hope... someone takes care
of my own mother this way...
wherever she is.
See that?
The only hippie in the village.
Come see the plastic necklaces.
They’re beautiful.
They may be plastic
but they’re top quality!
They remind me of my mother.
- You’re such a good daughter.
Any news of her?
- None.
It’s like she vanished.
What about your sister?
Regina? She’s in Madrid,
reaping awards and accolades.
Mom, I ran out of minutes.
So much the better, we need
a break from your telephone.
Use mine.
- Please.
In that case, you can’t.
What was I saying?
Regina, she’s on every television show.
You can rent an apartment in Madrid
for the price of a ticket.
She was meant to be a singer.
Do you remember... when you were 14...
They took you to an audition
for young talents.
Really?
You never told me that.
Past is past. Anyway,
it was because of Augustina's sister.
Didn’t you ever wish you were with her
in show business?
Not really.
She would have liked that.
She would flip out.
Want some?
No, thank you.
Homegrown and home-made.
No, no.
We have to go, really.
- Yes.
Did you tell the police
about your mother’s disappearance?
No. Regina thinks
it won’t do any good.
Many times she appealed on TV
to people who may have information.
TV is one thing,
the police is another.
What do I know.
It’s not the first time
your mother disappears.
Yes, but never for that long.
It’s been three and a half years.
Don’t lose hope, and take care of yourself,
you look tired.
Look at the pretty blossoms.
It’ll bear a lot of fruit.
Too bad I don’t have any appetite.
Must be the cigarettes.
It’s thanks to cigarettes
that I eat at all.
Her eyes are just like her father’s.
Cigarettes stimulate appetite
and improve your mood.
Drive safe.
You won’t believe what I saw
at my aunt’s house.
What?
An exercise bike.
That’s absurd.
She got an exercise bike
for her treatment.
The old hag has completely lost it.
I don’t like it when you talk
that way about her.
Mom, she didn't even recognize us.
It’s the wind. The damned wind
makes people crazy.
Mm, very tasty.
I can’t believe
she can still make these.
Hello, Regina.
Are you off to work?
What can you do.
Can you give her a ride?
Where to?
The city. The closer to downtown,
the better.
Hop on.
- Thanks.
Later.
Hi, dad.
- Hey there.
What’s new?
How was it?
Did you have fun?
At the cemetery?
You must be kidding!
Are you having fun now?
What?
Put your feet down.
Bring me another beer.
Are you drunk?
Get me another beer!
Please.
Paco, don’t you think you’ve had
enough? You’re working tomorrow.
I rest tomorrow, and the day after.
- What?
They fired me.
Wait a minute.
Goddamn it!
Then look for another job
or are you just resting from now on?
I’ll look, let me
finish watching the game.
Say goodbye to the TV.
If we’re poor,
might as well live like the poor.
Paula, get off the phone.
Dinner’s here, if you want to eat.
Are you mad at me?
- No.
I’m worried about my aunt.
She’s worse than ever.
She couldn’t recognize Solia, her own niece.
How can anyone live like that?
- She can.
Stop it, Paco.
What’s with you?
I’m just tired,
and I have to be up early tomorrow.
I can do it myself.
Don’t be a nuisance.
Don’t call me that.
- I was kidding.
What are you doing here?
Waiting for you.
Why?
I tried to call you a million times to buy bread.
You’re soaking wet.
How long did you wait?
I don’t know. Not long.
Where were you?
Out with your girlfriends?
No.
I didn’t go anywhere.
Then why didn’t you pick up?
What’s the matter with you?
Something’s wrong.
What is it, tell me!
Is it your father?
He...
Where is he?
In the kitchen.
What happened?
I was in the kitchen... with my back to him...
he came in and grabbed me...
He was drunk.
I fought back... I asked him what he was doing.
He kept telling me he wasn’t my father.
I fought back...
but he kept coming...
he tried to hug me.
Then he took his pants off, he said
there’s nothing wrong with that...
because he’s not my father.
I opened a drawer
and took a knife...
just to scare him off...
to make him leave me alone.
He wasn’t scared...
Said I wouldn’t do it
and jumped me.
What are we going to do, mom?
I don’t know.
You should change, you’ll catch a cold.
Paula, remember!
I killed him.
You saw nothing
because you were out.
It’s important that you remember.
Hush.
Who can that be?
- I don’t know, go away.
Raimunda, it’s me, Emilio.
I’ll be right there.
What is it?
Sorry I’m bothering you
this late.
Thing is, tomorrow
I’m going to Barcelona, and I want
to leave you the restaurant key
if someone wants to see it.
No problem, but you know
I’m not home all day.
Paco is home, right?
Paco?
He found a new job.
It’s his first day tomorrow.
What’s this? Are you hurt?
- It’s just a scratch.
I remembered I’ll be home most of the day
now that Paco has a job.
Give me the key.
Here, it’s my brother’s phone number
and this is my cell.
You’re leaving tomorrow?
- Early morning.
Just out of curiosity, how much
do you want for the restaurant? I really like it.
It’s a pity
you don’t like the owner that much.
For Christ’s sake, Emilio.
5 mil. asking price
but we can negotiate.
I understand. Good bye,
we’ll miss you.
I’ll miss you more.
Good luck.
- Thanks.
Emilio is leaving?
- Yes.
Go to your room, Paula.
- I want to be with you.
I’ll need your help later.
Don’t pick up.
It’s one of your girlfriends.
Pick up and tell her
you can’t talk right now. It’s late.
I can’t talk right now.
- What? It’s aunt Solia.
Get your mother on the phone.
- Mom, it’s aunt Solia.
Tell her I’m busy.
She’s busy right now.
- Give her the phone, it’s urgent.
Mom, you have to take this.
Solia, I have so much laundry...
Augustina called.
Aunt Paula died.
When?
- Just now.
Aunt Paula died.
I swear, the whole time
I was thinking of how to take her.
And now, she died all alone.
- Don’t cry, honey.
Augustina said not to worry.
She’ll take care of everything
until we get there.
Before she died, aunt Paula
picked a color for her grave
and paid for everything.
It’s unreal,
the way she arranged everything,
so rational to the very last.
I can’t make it
to her funeral.
As much as I hate to say it.
I’m very busy.
- What? How can you say that?
It’s true, I can’t make it.
You have to go alone.
- Alone?
You know that I get panic attacks
when I see dead people.
You don’t have to see her. I’ll ask
Augustina to take care of everything.
And if they ask me about you?
Tell them I just had surgery.
Think of something.
Listen, I’ll visit soon,
just not right now.
I don’t understand you, Raimunda.
Aunt Paula loved you so much.
I loved her, too.
Solia, one day I’ll explain.
You’ll be shocked.
- I’m shocked already.
Calm down, Solia. Take a Valium.
I’ll take one, too.
And just go tomorrow.
Okay?
- Okay.
The door.
Wait here, don’t come with me.
I hope nothing has changed
since I worked here.
Stop! Don’t come near!
Sorry.
What do you want?
I wanted to see
if the restaurant was open.
We’re closed.
Why? Can you help me?
We’re shooting a film nearby
and the crew needs a place to eat.
Do you know of any other place around?
How many of you?
25... 30 people.
Lend me a hand.
I can manage that, no problem.
Really?
Lunch for 30.
When should I expect you?
- We’re done at 15:30, and we need...
16:00 sound good?
- Okay.
Terrific.
How much are you paying?
300 euro.
Okay.
Sorry I yelled at you.
You just scared me.
No problem. See you at 16:00.
Thank you.
You’re welcome. Bye.
- See you.
No problem. It’s already 10:00.
Please, can I have
2 more kilos.
All right.
- How much are the potatoes?
4 kilos for 1,60 euro.
I’ll take 8.
- Okay.
Hi, Katrina.
- Hello, Raimunda.
Where to?
- I’m cooking lunch for 30 people.
Can you lend me 100?
Sorry, I’m broke, too.
Just got out of acupuncture.
They turned me into a hedgehog.
Please, I’ll pay it back tomorrow.
- Cost me 10,80...
Thank you so much.
I’ll bring it over later today.
- Thanks.
I’ll have to go on a diet.
- Won’t hurt you any.
Hi, Ines.
So you’re back from your village.
Yes, since last night.
How are you?
Did you happen to bring
any sausages or blood pudding?
Sure, how did you know?
My blood pudding is finger-licking fresh.
I need 1,5 kilos.
- That much?
I’m cooking for 30.
- Who’s visiting?
Long story, tell you later.
Give me credit, I’ll pay tomorrow?
Okay, no problem.
- Thanks.
Wait, do you have anything sweet?
Of course. Doughnuts.
They’re to die for.
With cholesterol that high,
you shouldn’t be eating those.
It’s my only weakness.
I brought three boxes.
Don’t eat all of them.
- What should I do, give them away?
Sell them to me, you’ll make a profit.
Can I at least try them?
Have a few, but not too much.
Deliver them to my place?
Okay, see you soon.
- See you.
Bye.
- Bye, sweetie.
Anybody else want pork-chops?
What about you?
Just a bit more?
Augustina?
Is that you, Augustina?
Soledat, daughter.
Solie, I have to talk to you.
Solie.
All right.
It’s okay, calm down.
Where is she?
- Upstairs, in my mother’s room.
Better this way, I brought her here
to be close to the body.
Thank you, Augustina.
Let’s go to the next room.
Good evening.
I spoke with your sister, poor thing,
just out of surgery.
Yes, just now.
Calm down, you don’t have to
see the body.
My condolences.
Such a pity.
Santa’s daughter.
Please, let her catch her breath,
she’s tired from the journey.
Come here, Solie. Calm down
It happened during the night.
I had finished dinner and was
watching TV
then I heard a knock on the door.
I thought I’d imagined it,
but then I heard it again.
"Who is it?" I asked.
And then I heard a voice say:
"Augustina".
I went out on the street,
nobody in sight.
But I wasn’t afraid.
I looked at your aunt’s house.
The front door was open.
That’s odd, I thought.
So I went over...
called your aunt but no answer.
Of course, she couldn’t have
answered, bless her soul.
I went into the bedroom and found her.
She was just lying there,
small as a bird.
Her spirit called you.
Hers or that of another woman.
- Who else?
I don’t know, I didn’t see her.
Someone or something called
to bring me news of her death...
and opened the front door for me.
Let’s go to the kitchen.
You must be starving.
- Yes.
I haven’t had a bite
since yesterday morning.
I knew it.
Look, you scored a celery.
- That should be enough.
What were the women talking about?
Just shooting the breeze,
you know how it is here.
They were talking about my mother.
Yes, they say they saw her.
They say she came back
to take care of your aunt.
Has she visited you?
No, what about you?
- Me, neither.
But things like that do happen.
- I don’t know.
My grandmother was visited
by my grandfather’s ghost.
May he rest in peace.
Go on, eat.
She was terrified at first.
But then she asked him
why he had come back.
The deal was, she hadn’t kept
a promise she had made.
So she kept it— she took the whole
village to the cemetery.
He was appeased and she didn’t
see him any more.
Here.
I haven’t told you this before.
Do you want to go to your aunt’s
place to look around,
maybe take something to remember her by?
- No, thanks.
Maybe later, with Raimunda.
- Tell her everything went well.
The whole village came to her funeral.
I’ll tell her by all means.
She’d hate to have missed it.
Go on, get going.
Solia, open up.
Open up.
It’s your mother.
My mother is dead.
You must be her ghost.
Call me whatever you like,
just get me out of here.
I’m in the trunk.
Of course, mom, anything for you.
Soledat, daughter.
Don’t be afraid.
I am your mother.
Don’t you want to hug me?
Help me out.
Aunt’s suitcase?
- Yes.
What’s in them?
- Clothes, and some of her valuables.
Good thing I managed to hide them
before the neighbors got here.
Everyone except Augustina was scoping,
but I had managed to clean up.
Augustina deserves a present.
She did more for Paula
than your sister did.
A true hero,
she even managed the funeral.
Thanks for coming.
I’m deathly tired.
Are you staying the night here?
- Of course, where else?
My god. No wonder you were scared!
Do you still have the beauty parlor?
- Yes, I do.
We can adapt this room. Tomorrow,
give me a haircut and dye my hair.
Okay.
- I’ll need clothes.
I don’t intend to just stay in here.
Nobody knows me here.
Back where I was I couldn’t even
stick my nose out.
Can you imagine?
Are you staying long?
Can’t wait to get rid of me?
- Not at all! Just asking.
I’ll stay as long as God wills it.
If you’re tired of me, just tell me.
You’re divorced, it’s better for you
to live with your mother.
Unless there’s another man...
No, mom, I’m alone.
As usual.
Not anymore.
Answer the phone.
Are you back yet?
- Yes, I am.
I couldn’t find you.
I just spoke with Augustina.
Yes, everything went great.
The whole village came.
The whole day I thought of you.
I wanted badly to be there.
300, right?
And for the drinks?
- Drinks are on the house.
Same time tomorrow?
Everyone loved it.
Glad to hear it.
Just one thing, if the portions were larger
it would have been perfect.
No problem. Tomorrow I’ll feed you so much
you won’t be able to walk.
Great. See you tomorrow, then.
- See you.
Solie, I’m sorry.
- Did you start in a restaurant?
Yes, Emilio left me his.
Now, that’s news!
- It’s not just that.
Paco left us.
That’s why I couldn’t
make it to the funeral.
You called in the middle of an argument.
I knew that something bad was happening.
Did he beat you?
- No, Paco never laid a hand on me.
He just left.
Forever.
He’ll be back, you’ll see.
I don’t think so.
- Why?
Call it intuition.
All right, then. Kisses.
To you, too.
- See you soon.
You know, neither of us
has had any luck with men.
Raimunda and I failed,
but not you.
What about me?
Father adored you.
Raimunda said you’re lucky
you died in the arms of your lover.
Raimunda is a good egg,
but her tongue can be evil.
I turned a blind eye to your father
and he took advantage.
He cheated on me till the very end.
What are you saying?
- It’s true.
I kept quiet, didn’t want you to know.
Enough about this, let the bygones
be bygones.
Will his ghost return?
- I hope not.
What about your husband?
- My husband?
Can he come back?
- I don’t think so.
No word in two years.
- You’re better off.
It’s just the two of us.
How much did you pay for this? 10?
- 10,80.
I’ll give you 3 euro more.
And I’ll pay you for 4 boxes
instead of three.
Thank you.
- So they won’t say I’ve used you.
Can you help me with the fridge.
I just finished eating.
- I need to bring it downstairs.
Go ahead, tilt it towards you.
Yep, that’s right. You got it.
Now, watch the stairs, no rush.
Careful! That’s good.
Left. Terrific!
Can it fit through the elevator door?
- This side first.
Watch out! Okay.
- My god, it’s like an elephant.
Now we can call the elevator.
Kitchen’s this way.
The room keeps cool throughout the day.
What about this freezer?
- Not working.
So, this is your restaurant?
- At least while you’re shooting.
You can count on me.
I can help you make the dessert.
And I can wait on the tables.
I don’t know if we’ll be open tonight,
but I appreciate the thought.
Mom?
Do you need me to do anything?
- I need a haircut.
I mean something you wanted
while you were alive,
that doesn’t let you rest in peace.
When you die, a lot of what you did
is left unfinished.
And a lot of what you finished
was done wrong.
I just don’t know if anything can be fixed.
And if it can,
is it my business to fix it?
Who knows.
My clients will come any minute now.
What are we going to do?
- We’ll serve them. I’ll help.
I can’t introduce you as my mother.
Everyone knows I’m an orphan.
Then tell them I’m a foreigner.
Foreigner? From where?
The Dominican Republic.
- No, that won’t work.
Too many Dominicans around,
they know the accent.
Chinese then.
Madrid is full of Chinese.
Mom, you make a poor Chinese woman.
We need something exotic.
That we don’t have any of.
Russian.
You think I look more Russian
than Chinese?
Yes, Russians look just like us.
Just keep quiet, whatever you hear.
And pretend you don’t understand any of it.
Let me show you how we do things.
Here we do haircuts and dyeing,
and here’s where we wash.
If the client is tall,
don’t use a pillow.
If she’s short, you use it.
This carpet’s here so you won’t slip.
Here’s where you hang the showerhead.
I used to hang it down below
but I got backaches.
Yes, I get those, too.
Shampoos have a built-in doser.
Have a seat, mom.
That’s good.
Don’t use more than one towel per client.
They just get in the way.
- That’s right.
Then press on the hair with one hand, and done.
You’re so organized.
Proud of you, daughter.
Hello.
- Good day.
Hi.
- Hello.
She’s Russian, doesn’t speak Spanish.
Poor thing.
She was out begging, I took pity.
She reminds me of my mother.
Solia, don’t take in Russians
They’re all Mafioso’s.
You have a kind heart.
People use you.
You want it lighter?
Wash hair. Yes?
She was a hairdresser back home.
How do you communicate?
- With gestures.
She’s a fast learner,
soon she’ll speak enough Spanish.
So many Russians around,
I’m not suprised.
So you’re Russian.
- Ruski.
Russia, water not cold, not hot.
Hello there.
- What’s up?
Got a day off tomorrow.
Then so do we.
We’ll be done next week
and we want to celebrate.
What would you like,
dinner or a party?
Party sounds better.
Could you reserve the balcony for us?
No problem.
Don’t look at me like that,
I’m blushing.
I’ll stop if you do.
Go get a drink,
I have more work to do.
Since she came back
she’s sounded strange over the phone.
If she asks you about Paco,
you know nothing.
The less she knows, the better.
Hello.
- Hi there.
Anybody there?
- I don’t think so.
I have to use the restroom.
- Why?
I need to pee.
The pipes are clogged.
I’m waiting for the plumber.
I’ll pour in water myself.
I really need to go, for heaven’s sake.
Hello.
What’s with you.
- Not in the mood.
Let me give you a haircut.
- I don’t want any.
You have split ends.
- Okay, but just a trim.
Listen...
Is your father back yet?
- No.
He’s gone forever.
What a story.
I just don’t understand him.
Did anyone die in here?
Or your mother.
- What?
She’s so pushy.
When we were growing up.
There weren’t any restrooms.
We went in the chicken pen.
Even then, I had to wait for her
She could spend hours among the hens.
Raimunda.
What’s this dress doing here?
- It’s mother’s.
I know.
And that smell.
What smell?
- Same as in the toilet.
Mom’s smell. Don’t you remember
how she farted all day long.
Yes, I remember.
You couldn’t breathe.
Remember?
When we had guests...
a barrel of laughs!
Why did you bring these here?
Don’t complain to me about nightmares.
Dead people’s clothes are to be given away.
Aunt Paula’s suitcase.
The old doll.
What’s this?
Jewelry?
What were you going to do with it?
Nothing.
- Nothing?
As in keep it to yourself?
- Raimunda, don’t say that.
I didn’t bring the suitcase.
Then who did?
When I came back from the funeral
it was waiting for me here.
What?
What kind of nonsense is that?
You think I’ll buy that?
You’ve no conscience.
Raimunda, don’t leave this way.
We need a new fridge.
Why don’t you repair the old one?
It’s too far gone.
Its motor’s still running.
I told you not to go in there.
I saw the door was open
and came in to get a hammer.
Did someone else go in there, you think?
- I don’t think so.
Mom, you said
you got rid of the body.
I haven’t had the time.
Do you think I enjoy
keeping a dead body around?
Paula, get ready.
They’ll be here in half an hour.
Paula?
What is it?
You haven’t even changed yet.
I’m not in a party mood.
Me neither, but this is our job.
So get up, lazybones.
You need help?
What is it?
I can’t get it out of my head.
He’s too close, in that storage room.
You’ll drive me crazy, too,
with such thoughts.
Mom, I can’t help thinking it.
I killed my father.
Paco was not your father.
Stop lying to me.
I know you just want to make me
feel better.
It’s true.
Paco was not your real father.
He took us in.
So he was telling the truth.
- Yes.
But that doesn’t excuse him.
I promise, Paula, I’ll tell you
everything, but not now.
Go on, get dressed.
We don’t have much time.
Who is my father, then?
A man from the village.
- Do I know him?
I promise to tell you everything.
Later.
Okay?
Okay, remember you promised.
Two Mohitos.
- Two Mohitos. And for you?
Two more.
Yes, lemon makes them tastier.
Here you go.
- Thanks.
Mm, delicious.
You sure know how to make them.
Our cleavages are more delicious.
Enough work, let’s have some fun
We’re off now.
What counts for me is for the clients
to have fun and be happy.
More Mohitos?
Bend down, they’ll see you.
I’d love to see Raimunda
and my grand-daughter.
The other day I just glimpsed her leg.
- And you saw what happened?
That’s her restaurant.
Looks like business is good.
She deserves that.
Poor thing, works so hard.
Keep your head down or they’ll see you.
- Who’ll see me?
What are you doing here?
I’m glad to see you.
I brought aunt Paula’s things.
Didn’t know you had a party.
That’s the film crew’s party.
I cooked for them a whole week.
Come on in.
I never thought of stealing
aunt Paula’s things.
I know. I just got carried away.
You know me. I speak without thinking.
Hi, auntie.
- Hello.
Anything to drink?
- No, thank you.
You remember?
- Of course I do.
It’s been years since I last heard you sing.
I’ve never heard her.
Really?
- Never.
Would you like to?
- Of course.
Okay.
I can’t believe it.
Quiet, they’re about to sing.
Good evening.
I would like to thank the film crew
for letting us feed them.
From the bottom of my heart.
My gift to you is a song.
I’m a bit rusty
so don’t be too critical.
She learned that song from your grandmother,
for the audition.
”Auto Friends,” can I help you?
I’m calling about the ad,
I’d like to rent a bus.
Sure, how big and for how long?
The normal size,
for a day.
Yes?
- Can I speak to Raimunda?
Speaking.
I was given this number to schedule
a tour of the restaurant.
They gave me your name.
My name’s Carlos.
Pity you didn’t call earlier.
Someone else took over the restaurant.
Mr. Emilio didn’t tell me anything about that.
He must have had his reasons.
How can I get in touch with
whoever’s in charge?
She’s not around today.
Best to call Emilio and ask him.
Thank you. Good bye.
- Bye.
Hello?
- Emilio, hi. It’s Raimunda.
Raiminda, nice to hear your voice.
Did a man call about the restaurant?
Yes, but he sounded fishy,
said he wants to use it
as a laundry.
A laundry?
- You know, for dirty money…
from drugs or prostitution.
I told him it’s okay, go ahead.
How could you say that?
Okay, Emilio, I’ve been
meaning to call you.
I know it’s wrong but,
I kept the restaurant for myself.
I’m sorry.
You? You kept it for yourself?
I should have told you earlier.
I’m extremely disappointed.
Sorry.
- I don’t understand, how did this happen?
Thing is, this filming crew showed up
and I was desperate.
I had no money, Paco left me.
Paco left you?
- Yes.
We got into a big fight.
I don’t think I’ll see him again.
He left the same day
you left for Barcelona.
How are you doing?
It’s bad.
Trying to get my life back on track.
I see.
What should I do now?
Tell me how much rent I owe you
for the month and I’ll send it.
Just give me a couple of days.
Yes?
- Raimunda?
Yes, who is it?
- It’s Augustina.
I’m in Madrid, I’d like to see you.
What luck, I can’t today.
I’m running errands.
Tomorrow?
Tomorrow’s busy, too.
The whole week’s busy.
Too bad, I’m in the hospital.
What happened?
Cancer. Doctors say
it’s not looking good.
I need to see you.
Which hospital are you in?
I’ll come today.
The central one.
God bless you for this, Raimunda.
You go alone, I’m running late.
Hi, auntie.
- What are you doing here?
Solie.
- Is this your mother I hear?
Solie, come out.
What?
- I’m leaving you Paula.
Wait! I’ve work to do.
Going to the hospital.
To see Augustina. She has cancer.
That’s terrible news.
Paulina will bring you auntie’s handbag.
Keep it.
I’ll try to be back soon.
Say hi to Augustina.
Tell her to keep her chin up.
Will do.
Can I come in now?
Yes, sweetie, come on in.
How are you, dear?
I knew that there was something
wrong with me.
Don’t lose hope.
These flowers are beautiful.
You didn’t need to do this.
Raimunda.
Do me a favor.
Just name it.
Close the door.
Grab a chair.
I don’t have much time left.
But before I go I need to know
what happened to my mother.
What can I do?
You can tell me
if she’s alive or dead.
How would I know?
Ask your mother.
My mother?
She’s dead.
She is. But she visited aunt Paula
to take care of her.
The whole village knows.
If she visits, ask her about my mother.
That’s all I want from you.
But that’s crazy.
Have you seen her?
Not me.
She never came to you?
I think she avoided me.
But I heard her talk to your aunt
many times.
Okay, I’ll ask her if I see her
but I doubt it will happen.
I really have to go now.
I won’t ask you for anything else.
You owe me, remember.
I have to go, a lot of work to do.
Stay a bit longer, your sister
wanted to talk to you.
Some other time,
I really have to go.
It’s about TV.
She wanted to give you some tapes.
From that audition you went to together as kids.
Call her, please.
She’s expecting you to call.
Tell my sister I don’t even like TV.
Me, neither. I’ll tell her.
Don’t forget what I asked.
Your Russian friend seems to like TV.
For someone who doesn’t understand
a word, she’s really into it.
I’m pretty sure
they put something inside those TV sets.
I can’t take my eyes off.
It gets worse every day.
I just can’t stop. It’s like a drug.
I stayed up all night, too,
to watch a horror flick.
Of course, after all those screams...
Do you like the doll?
Just like the ones in the horror flicks.
It’s very old. Your mother played with it
when she was carrying you.
Why didn’t the two of you live together?
We had no money.
Your father went to work in Venezuela
and left your mother with your aunt Paula.
I stayed with your aunt Solia.
What did your mother tell you?
- Nothing.
She doesn’t like talking about it.
How is she now?
- Better.
But still unbearable at times.
Yes, she’s got a very strong personality.
How did you two get along?
She was my favorite as a child,
but when she grew up...
she began to drift away from me...
for no particular reason,
until we were little more than strangers.
Your mother didn’t like me.
It’s terrible when a daughter
doesn’t love her own mother.
Now that you two are alone together
you must love her all the more.
Make sure she can feel it.
Why did you come back, Grandma?
I was lonely.
Good day.
- Hello.
I’d like 25 feet of scotch tape
and some packing paper.
How much tape?
- 4 or 5 rolls.
Ah, okay.
5 rolls of tape...
add one more pickaxe and one more shovel.
Sure.
Okay, thanks a lot.
- Thank you for shopping.
How are you, Raimunda?
She’s lost it completely.
Who, Augustina?
Completely nuts.
- Hi, mom.
What happened to you?
- Nothing.
Bring me a glass of water, will you.
Could she stay with you tonight?
Sure, but where should I put her?
Anywhere.
Paco’s coming over today.
We need to talk in private.
Sure.
You’re staying here tonight.
Okay, I’m off.
Long night ahead of me.
Hello.
- How are you?
I need your help tonight.
Can it wait till tomorrow?
No. But I’ll pay you
like a regular customer.
No way, I’ll give you a discount.
I didn’t know you were seeing someone.
- Whatever gave you that idea?
Okay. How can I help?
First we need to load up some furniture.
I'll explain on the way.
Furniture?
- I’ll explain later.
We can’t do it alone.
- Let me get the neighbor to help us.
Put on something comfortable.
I’ll wait outside.
What should I put on?
- Something more comfy.
Careful. Just like that.
- Don’t drop it. Be careful.
Come on. Push.
One, two, three, lift!
One more time.
One, two, three.
Almost broke my back.
- That’s all. We’re done.
Thank God!
- That’s how you do it.
Where are we going?
- Hooker River.
Where’s that?
- About 100 miles away.
100 miles?
That’ll take the whole night.
I told you I’ll pay you.
For my company?
- And for helping me dig a hole
and bury the fridge in it...
no questions asked.
Wait, I’m happy that you trust me
but you could at least tell me,
for heaven’s sake.
I got enough problems as it is.
No ID papers,
no job, no home,
and now thins.
I’m asking you, how much do you want?
- Okay.
Okay, I want the night shift.
- What night shift?
In your restaurant, I’ll serve
the drinks and get all the tips.
But you supply the drinks.
- Partners.
No word about this to anyone.
- Of course. I’m your accomplice now.
I haven’t killed anyone,
in case you're wondering.
I don’t want to know.
I wasn’t going to tell you.
Move aside. Let me do it.
Push.
Goodness me!
I can’t do it any more.
I need a break.
What are you doing here, Augustina?
Can we talk?
- I’m busy right now.
Okay, come here.
How are you?
- Same old.
Did you learn anything?
- About what?
About what I asked you.
I thought you were pulling my leg.
I’d better sit down.
Raimunda, have some sympathy for me.
I’ll do anything for you
within the bounds of reason.
I just want to know if my mother is alive.
Augustina, your illness has addled
your brains. I know it’s hard,
but you can’t bother people
with your problems.
My life’s complicated enough.
My mother disappeared the same day
your parents died in the fire.
Isn’t that a strange coincidence?
Not really. You said it yourself,
your mother left that morning
and it wasn’t her first time.
Your grandmother raised you
because your mother was away all the time.
Why am I telling you this?
My mother left that morning
to meet your father.
That can’t be true.
Nobody saw her.
She wanted to be discreet.
They had an affair, Raimunda.
That’s a lie.
My mother loved my father,
she would never allow it.
That’s why she left him
to live with aunt Paula.
She stayed with my aunt
because she was sick.
not because she ran away.
She would never let it happen.
So she lived in two houses.
How would you know?
You never lived together,
didn’t keep in touch for years.
I heard them say you passed each other
on the street, like strangers.
I heard them say lots of things.
I once overheard your mother
and mine arguing.
Your mother said that she can’t
keep letting your father in,
she couldn’t do it anymore,
and that she didn’t care
about winning him over,
because your father only hurt
those who loved him.
What are you trying to do, Augustina?
To make you realize
your parents and my mother
are connected somehow.
Why didn’t you turn to the police?
They ask too many questions.
Best not to parade your own skeletons.
That’s why I’m staying away from TV,
even though my sister insists.
Because this is up to you
and me to sort out together.
I have to go back to work.
Think about what I said.
How’s Paco doing?
Who?
He’s fine.
We should have warned auntie
about our visit.
Why, she’s home.
Mom, you don’t understand.
- What?
It’s not polite to visit
without calling first,
even if she is your sister.
Who told you that?
Your aunt Solia?
That’s just basic manners.
You and your aunt are going to
kill me with your basic manners.
How vulgar!
What brings you here, Raimunda?
What’s up your tail?
- Don’t scream, I’ll go deaf.
I’m already deaf.
As a bat. We came to see you.
And I need a haircut.
Why didn’t you call? I have a client.
- I’m in no rush.
Also, we need to talk.
About what?
- Our aunt’s house.
Can I watch some TV?
- Yes, go ahead.
We need to decide what to do
and start on the paperwork.
Grandma?
- Here.
Hide. My mom’s here
- I heard.
Solie, where’s the Russian woman?
What Russian woman?
- My assistant.
I was talking religion to her,
she was washing my head, then she was gone.
She must be sensitive.
I shouldn’t’ve mentioned religion.
She probably stepped out.
- My hair’s halfway done.
I’ll finish it. Poor thing
is claustrophobic. She needs open air.
Some assistant you have.
How much are you paying her?
Nothing, she’s staying with me.
I gave her some of mom’s clothes.
I don’t approve of this,
taking in complete strangers.
We’ve been saying that.
She’s too nice, people use her.
How did it go with Paco?
He came for his clothes.
I think he lives with someone else.
I don’t care.
Why didn’t you tell me about this Russian woman?
I don’t know, must’ve slipped my mind.
Look here, it’s Augustina.
Good evening, Augustina.
- Evening.
Your sister told us your mother
never married, is that true?
Yes.
She was a hippie.
This is Augustina.
My mother believed in free love
so she never married.
The day she disappeared
a friend of hers died, right?
That’s right.
- What did she die of?
There was a fire. They’re common
in our village because of the hot wind.
She refers to Alcanfor de las Infantas.
Statistics say there are
many insanity cases there.
Do you think your mother suffered, Augustina?
I mean, from some mental disorder…
I don’t think so. Whenever she got ill,
she just left.
That’s a hippie for you.
Then one day she left
and never came back?
Yes, over four years ago.
That friend who died in a fire,
tell us more about her.
What about her?
Tell us about the woman
who died in the fire.
There’s a rumor going around...
I don’t believe rumors.
Tell us what you told us earlier.
About her and her husband,
about their connection
to your mother’s disappearance.
You said that?
I’d rather not talk about it.
Isn’t that what you came for?
Isn’t it?
- It is.
But I changed my mind.
What’s the matter with you?
Lost your nerve?
Augustina wanted to tell you
something else as well.
She wants you to know
she’s got a terminal illness.
Cancer.
No need to be shy,
you’re among friends.
Let’s support her
with our applause.
Augustina has a dream.
She wants to be treated in Houston.
But in order to live that dream
you have to tell us everything in detail.
Augustina came to the restaurant.
She did?
She thinks we see our mother’s ghost,
wants us to ask her about her own mother.
She says her mother had an affair
with our father.
Did you know about this?
No.
Okay... Mother told me,
after...
After what?
- After she learned.
Solie, look at me.
Is there something I should know?
If I tell you...
you won’t believe me
and you’ll probably scream.
I promise not to scream.
Mother’s ghost is visiting.
Who?
- Have a seat.
She was with aunt Paula until her death.
She told Augustina about it
and opened the front door.
She left money for Augustina,
to buy bread.
You did that?
- Yes.
Who told you that, Augustina?
See, you don’t believe me.
Solie, Augustina is whacked in the head.
Remember, you yourself were amazed
that aunt Paula could manage alone
in her condition?
Remember!
I remember.
What are you driving at?
Auntie was not alone.
Who do you think made those doughnuts
and brought auntie’s belongings?
The dolls, too,
before the neighbors got to them?
Do you understand now?
Do you?
Have you seen her?- Yes.
Is she the Russian woman?
Yes.
Where is she?
In there.
Mother.
What are you doing here?
I thought you were dead.
I came back to ask for your forgiveness.
I knew nothing about it, daughter.
I swear I had no idea.
Daughter.
Sweet daughter of mine.
The worst is over.
She didn’t reject me.
Or did she?
- No, she didn’t.
Is it true you came back
to ask her forgiveness?
Yes, and to see you.
Will you explain one day?
- I will.
I hope you’ll understand
and forgive me as well.
I have to talk to her.
Let’s go back.
Now?
- Yes.
I used to dream about this.
- Me, too.
I don’t know where to begin.
You’re not a ghost, right?
You just never died.
No, I never died.
But even if I had, I would return
to ask for forgiveness.
How could I not see it?
They say love is blind.
- Yes.
I learned on the day of the fire.
Is it true you left father?
- Yes.
I couldn’t stand his affairs.
You called the night before the fire
to talk to your aunt.
You didn’t ask about me,
as usual.
I got angry...
I told your aunt bad things about you.
She defended you...
she told me everything...
about your father raping you...
and that your daughter Paula,
your daughter...
is also your sister.
I couldn’t believe it.
How could such a nightmare unfold
before my eyes without knowing it?
I understood then,
your silence,
your coldness.
I understood why
your father had to flee to Venezuela.
He was never one to
take responsibility.
I understood why you and Paco
left for Madrid
and wanted nothing to do with me.
I thought you had to know
what had happened.
I understand.
You have no idea how mad I was
when I found out.
I went looking for him,
to gauge his eyes out.
I found him asleep, in the arms
of Augustina’s mother.
They didn’t hear me coming...
so I set the house on fire.
It was a windy day, within seconds
the fire swallowed them.
They never even woke up.
So the remains in your grave
are Augustina’s mother?
Yes.
I roamed the countryside for a few days,
as in a long dream.
I wanted to go to the police,
turn myself in.
But before that I had to see your aunt.
She was not well.
Not well at all.
When she saw me,
she didn’t even blink.
She lived in the past, she thought
we had never separated.
Your tragedy took away
her last bits of sanity.
I couldn’t leave her...
so I stayed...
until her dying day.
The people in the village
think you’re a ghost.
It suited me well.
Better to be a ghost
than have to face the truth.
I thought there had to be
an investigation.
I thought they’ll arrest me
and...
punish me somehow.
Although I swear I’ve led a life without sin.
It’s true.
We’re almost there,
no need to arrive in daylight.
Let’s stop here then,
there’s a meadow.
I haven’t been there for years.
It’s dry now.
- How do you know?
From the news.
There’s draught all over Spain.
We often picnicked here.
Remember, Raimunda?
I do.
Used to be so green then.
I told you it’ll be dry.
Let’s have a snack.
- I’m not hungry.
I could have a doughnut.
- Me, too.
This was your father’s favorite spot.
You mean Paco?
Yes, him.
He really missed this place.
So you buried him here.
Come out quick while there’s no-one around.
If only Paula could see us.
All together.
She would have been so happy.
Yes, she would.
Did you always have such big jugs?
As far back as I can remember.
I remember them smaller.
Did you do anything to them?
- What could I have done?
Okay, then.
Grandma, was it you
that used the exercise bike?
Yes, it was.
Every single day. It works wonders
for blood pressure.
How did aunt Paula take that?
She couldn't stop laughing.
I'll go hide.
That must be aunt Paula.
- Stop it, Solie.
I’ll go see who it is.
Hide mom’s utencils.
Who is it?
- It’s me, Augustina.
We’re having dinner, just arrived.
Sorry to interrupt.
Come in, don’t just stand there.
- Thank you.
Good evening.
- Good evening.
Have a seat.
- Thank you.
I came to say I’m sorry
about that TV show appearance.
Ah, the interview.
It didn’t come out right.
I know. I’m not looking for an excuse,
but they offered to take me
to a hospital in Houston
where they can treat that kind of cancer.
But I’d rather die with a clean conscience,
not ashamed to look you in the eye.
Mom, I’ll be upstairs.
- Yes, okay.
Have something to eat.
- No, thank you.
You’re selling the house, I heard.
- We are.
At least, we thought we were,
but there are so many memories...
I don’t really know what to do.
Well, I’ll get going.
- Why so soon?
Stay with us.
- No, I have to go.
A nurse will stop by
to do my injection.
The doctors in Madrid showed me
how to do it myself,
but I could never learn.
Your sister has no excuses
for not being here with you.
Don’t remind me of her.
After what happened on TV
she won’t talk to me. She’s pissed.
Not as much as I am with her.
You have plenty of reasons.
- I look at you...
and I’m truly envious.
Irene.
I’m so glad to see you.
- Me, too.
I heard about you and here I am.
It must get lonely.
It does.
If only aunt Paula was here.
I’m here now,
to take care of you.
Did you leave the door open?
- Yes, let me close it.
I already did.
Did the nurse come already?
- No, she will tomorrow.
You’ll be in pain
if you miss today’s.
Do you have the medicine, syringes?
- Yes, they gave them to me.
All right, I’ll do it then.
I was born in this bed.
My mother slept here.
Your sister Paula and I
slept on that one.
I know Augustina
and I’m grateful to you.
We have to talk, Irene.
Anything you wish.
Just don’t tell anyone
that I’ve returned.
Don’t worry, I won’t.
Thank you for not mentioning me
on television.
It’s none of their business,
it’s just between the two of us.
Of course.
Nobody’s business but ours.
Hey, beautiful. Give your father
a kiss, Magdalene.
Did I ever tell you the story of Pinocchio?
The boy that told lies
and his nose would grow bigger.
He lied to his father,
the puppet-maker.
It’s me, mom.
Open up.
Raimunda, what are you doing here?
- I wanted to see you.
Are you going to stay here?
Yes.
Till the very end.
Augustina is not doing well.
After what I did to her mother,
I could at least be there for her now.
Mom, I’ve so much to tell you.
About Paco.
Something awful happened.
- You’ll tell me later.
We’ll see each other every day.
Yes.
I need you so much.
I’ve always needed you.
Don’t say such things, Raimunda.
My eyes are watering.
Ghosts are not supposed to cry.