taken from the book "TheAvengers ofTragic Patagonia"
ofOsvaldo Bayer.
For narrative reasons' some ofthe facts'
names and ranks han been altered.
Buenos Aires' January 1923
REBELLION IN PATAGONIA
Son of a bitch!
Río Gallegos' 3 years before
Things have to be said without
mincing words' comrades.
Hotel owners are all
a bunch of exploiters.
Yes! Despicable exploiters!
The waiters and kitchen
staff of Hotel Argentino...
work from 6 in the morning
through to midnight.
And for that they pay us
a miserable 80 pesos!
And anyone who dares to look
askance at it' is fired...
and isn't able to get work
in any other hotel.
There are two alternatives' comrades:
Either die of hunger
or kowtow to them.
We have to fuel the fire' comrades!
There's no chance ofwinning here:
I demand that the Federation...
calls a strike in the hotels.
Because otherwise' we'll
do justice with our own hands...
and not an exploiter will be left
with a head in all of Río Gallegos.
Starting with my boss'
the bloodsucker Carballeira.
One moment' comrades!
Wait a moment.
Permission to speak.
Go on.
You're right"
but we must be disciplined.
If hotels have to be burnt'
we'll burn them'
but it must be by a
majority resolution.
Because there are two fundamental
words that shouldn't be forgotten...
in union anarchy:
Discipline and Organization.
Comrade Graña.
Comrades' the time has come
for plain speaking.
The issues about...
organization and discipline
you've been listening to'
leave out human values.
Speak plainly' then.
OK' but say once and for all.
Do you agree with
the hotel strike? Yes or no?
Comrade Secretary General'
you're restricting me
in my turn to speak.
You're right' comrade.
But be concrete' please.
I'm being asked for
definitions here'
but I'm replying
that before a strike...
it's preferable to know
where the individual's going.
Whatthe revolution is for.
Well said Kropotkin
that revolutions...
Comrade Graña' we'll discuss
that in the ideology lessons.
Right now we're dealing
with the hotel staff strike.
Begging your pardon.
Comrade Danielewski
reports now.
Comrades' I have to
denounce the Hotel España...
which pays Chilean workers
halfwages...
justfor being Chilean.
We cab drivers...
inform the Federation
of our solidarity...
with the strike' by not driving
a single passenger...
to the hotels! Not one!
- Strike!
- Yes' Strike!
I want to tell you' that I've come
from Puerto Santa Cruz...
to bring you the solidarity
ofthe stevedores'
- ... waiters and wagoners.
- Well done' comrade!
And to inform you that if
you declare a strike'
we will also stop work in
the hotels of Puerto Santa Cruz.
Long live the comrades
of Santa Cruz! Hurrah!
- Long live anarchy!
- Hurrah!
Comrades... Comrades...
Comrades'
Patagonian exploiters...
value men less than
mules or packhorses'
since today one worker
is replaced by another...
without any cost.
- Well said.
- Very well said.
We're workers from
all parts ofthe world.
Isn'tthat so' German?
Eh' Poles?
And you' Chilean comrades.
And we are here'
united by solidarity.
Today that solidarity is called:
Support forthe comrades
hotel workers.
I ask' then...
for us to vote for the strike
for an indeterminate time'
until we win.
I would say' my friend'
what we need now...
is a bit of organization.
Nearly all the landowners
are with us.
That's good. I'm glad..
For ifthe workers unite...
No' no' no.
Athrust is needed.
Someone directing.
Who directs and knows
how to defend our interests.
What do you think' my friend?
We need a manager
for our organization.
Finding one in Río Gallegos
will be hard.
No' no.
We've already found him.
And he's very near.
Here' atthis table.
You' Méndez Garzón.
But' sirs' are you forgetting that I'm
the Governor ofthe territory?
Whatwould they say in BuenosAires?
Imagine'
Governor of Santa Cruz
and Manager ofthe Rural Society.
Don't you think there's
an incompatibility?
Do you think so?
From both jobs you will have
a better perspective.
What's more'
think of yourfuture.
Public office
is very unstable.
You're a Conservative'
the National Government is Radical.
Gentlemen' I would like to thank you
for your presence in my house.
Thank you' Carballeira' we are
in solidarity with the only hotel...
- ... which managed to scorn the strike.
- Thank you.
And how did you achieve it?
Well' quite simply'
with people of goodwill'
with responsible workers.
Out! Out! Scabs! Blacklegs!
I'll kick your arse!
Look what you've done! Look!
- Look at that pan!
- Get out!
- Out!
- Let me be' comrade.
- I have seven kids.
- That's nonsense.
Leave everything'
we'll help you.
Come on! Be off! Out!
See' German'
that's what I'm lacking.
Awoman.
A companion.
Of bourgeois upbringing'
as Graña would say.
But you won't deny
that a good pair...
Awoman!
To love. To love her well.
Damn it' how nice!
One thing' orthe other.
Come on' old man'
Because I had one'
I know what I'm saying.
First itwas ideas...
and love.
Then when the kids came...
and jail.
Lookwhat I gave her, poor thing.
My times in jail...
and the kids going hungry.
- Did you leave them in Germany?
- Yes.
With the promise to bring them
over soon to enjoy the freedom'
ofjustice!
You certainly chose well.
Even in the uttermost corner
there's egoism' exploitation.
You thought you were coming
to paradise?
Look' I'll join you in the fight
until we win'
and then' go to live with my own ones
in earthly paradise'
far away from men.
And where's that?
Listen' I'm only telling itto you.
Among forests and mountains'
by Lago Argentino.
- Blood sucker!
- Criminal!
- Bastard!
- Exploiter!
Comrades' make way!
- Bloodsucker' slave-driver.
- Exploiter.
Gentlemen... Gentlemen' I'm here
on the advice ofthe Judge...
to settle this dispute.
A legitimate weapon
ofthe workers.
- Yes' yes' apologize.
- Notto us.
The ones you should apologize
to are the workers...
you fired.
The comrades.
What's more' they must be paid
the wages owing up to today.
And deposit in the Workers' Society
1'500 pesos as a fine' sir.
1'500?
As a fine?
Yes. For legal damages.
For the cost of organizing
the boycott against you'
printing offlyers
and moral damages.
The staffwages.
- Good!
- Well done' comrade!
- 1'500 pesos!
- Bravo!
- Good!
chlldren ofthe people
chaln oppress you
and that Injustlce
cannotcontlnue.
Ifyourexlstence
Is a world oftroubles,
I'd soonerdle
than slavery.
Those bourgeols,
so selflsh,
who thus desplse
Humanlty.
They shallbe sweptaway
by anarchlsts
to the strldentshout offreedom.
Red flag,
sufferno more,
exploitatlon
mustsuccumb.
Rlse up, loyalpeople,
to the shout ofsoclalrevolutlon.
Dlgnlty,
Is not to be asked,
only unity
can demand It.
Ourshlelds
you shallnot smash.
clumsy bourgeols,
get back! Get back!
Comrades. Comrades
Comrades' with this money...
we'll be able to buy
one ofthe most-prized weapons...
of unionist anarchy.
- A printing press!
- Very good!
A printing press to clarify things
for our rural comrades...
and so thatthe ignominy
of exploitation is ended.
Comrades.
don't think that ranch owners
will be convinced by words.
We know it' comrade.
We know that the landowners
are very strong and powerful.
But we also know thatwe have
the fundamental weapon...
to overcome them.
The strike!
- Long live the strike!
- Hurrah!
Silence' comrades.
Comrades'
to carry to the final victory...
the black banner of anarchy...
and the red of unionism'
we must start from the bottom.
Comrades' we must affiliate
al the rural workers...
to our federation.
Here.
Look' Mr. Soto'
I don't understand anything
of politics' but I do try to...
help the rural workers'
you can count on me.
I expected no less.
You know that I earn my pesos
with my fleet ofwagons.
But I've always been
on the side ofthe underlings.
More than once I've been thrashed
for demanding fair wages.
That isn'tforgotten.
And when one has to fight' I fight'
that's why I'm called "Facón Grande".
You are a very well-respected man'
that's why we're asking you to go
affiliating the rural workers for us.
Certainly. Leave it to me.
Lookfriends'
do you know whatthis is?
Here the abuses ofthe
bad bosses are denounced.
And you know what you have to do'
join the federation...
and supportthe workers' society
which defends you.
Yes' man' which defends you.
From the bosses
and from the police too.
And from that bastard
of a governor we have.
Come on' we mustn't be afraid.
In this city we have
a nest of rats.
Rats who wantto destroy
nationality'
nationhood' ownership.
But my friend' don't be scared
by those crazy anarchists.
They're nothing more than a bunch of
mouthy simpleton Spanish immigrants.
Simpletons? The Russian Revolution
was made by simpletons like them.
Remember Lenin himself has to
get rid of 20 thousand anarchists.
Go on.
Imagine' sir, if Lenin
had killed them all'
whatwould we have to do?
Read. Read the terms carefully.
They don't acknowledge nationhood'
frontiers' or anything.
Now they're preparing a tribute
to a man who was executed in Spain.
Now that's a provocation.
I will not permit excess.
Take care' Governor' I'm warning you
that I'll report...
any breach ofthe Law.
Your Honor'
don'tthink you'll intimidate me
with your relationship with Yrigoyen.
I too have my friends'
and in more powerful places
than the Presidential Palace.
Sir, excuse me but
you may not go in.
Do you know what you're doing?
You are lacking respect
for my position as Judge!
But' sir' it's an order
from the governor.
What governor! Bullshit!
Tell that gentleman to go
and govern the Rural Society.
Gentlemen' I'm here in person
to advise you of the court's ruling:
The ceremony is permitted'
because it does not break
any constitutional...
or legal regulations of the Republic.
Inspector' arrest them all.
And confiscate the Unionist leaflets'
newspapers and books.
Come on!
Get a move on!
The party's over!
Those of us who were not caught have
decided to go to a general strike.
Clearly' we have to
paralyze the ports.
And the countryside.
Hello.
Comrade Soto has told us
we should turn to you.
That's right.
You three' go to Clark's descent.
You two to' make for
La Esperanza.
And us?
Over by El Cifre.
For the strike.
- Good afternoon.
Please' gentlemen.
Gentlemen' it is essential
that urgent measures are taken.
Nearly all the estancias
in the territory...
are paralyzed by the strike.
It can't be that for the sake of
those foreign anarchists...
we are all in danger of ruin.
Excuse me' gentlemen. Atelegram
from BuenosAires' Mr. Governor.
Excuse me' gentlemen.
- Yes.
Traders sort outtheir problems
and then sell more'
whereas for us
the shearing is held up'
- and the price of wool drops.
- Precisely.
Gentlemen'
PresidentYrigoyen orders the
immediate release of the detained
and the opening
ofthe Workers' Society.
These Radicals
don't know whatthey're doing.
They thinkthat by being lenient
they'll stop them.
They're dreamers!
We've been setfree thanks to
the rural worker comrades.
Now we must fight for them.
We must achieve the first
rural workers' agreement.
So they don't carry on
living like animals!
...and itwill be presented
to the owners.
I'll read it to you.
"List of conditions:
First.
Bunks are abolished.
Second.
In each house for workers...
there shall be a washbasin to... to...
...to wash themselves.
Third. Lighting shall be
provided by the owner.
One packet of candles per month
for each worker.
Fourth. Each estancia
shall have a first aid kit...
with instructions in Spanish
and not in English.
Fifth. Minimum wage for sheep hands'
horse hands and herdsmen'
100 pesos. It's fair,
notwhat's paid at present.
Sixth. To encourage
the increase ofthe population...
preference will be given to workers
with families and with children.
Not as at presentwhere only
single men are contracted.
Seventh. Landowners
must recognize...
as the only organization
representing the workers...
the General Workers' Federation
of Río Gallegos'
a member ofthe FORA."
That's all.
Mr. Manager, sir, we'd like
you to reply to the gentlemen.
The Rural Society will not enter
into dealings with an organization...
led by foreigners.
On no account.
Neitherwill we discuss the
running of our estancias.
That is our business
and ours alone.
So'
the rural strike will continue
as far as its ultimate consequences.
Let's go.
Firstly' gentlemen'
we wantto put your minds at rest.
Although we are far away'
our interests are here.
And in Chile' of course.
We are in full
agreementwith you.
In BuenosAires we have undertaken
extremely important dealings.
And I say extremely important
because there is' as intermediary...
the President ofthe Republic.
On the other hand there are
the Armour and Swift meat exporters.
Putting pressure on through
North American Embassy?
Exactly.
Waiter, please.
But' gentlemen' the most urgent
problem is that we have to start...
with the shearing and the workers
are still on strike.
My dear friend' don'tforget that
we have a few little sheep.
In BuenosAires theAssociation of
Free Workers has been constituted'
and they're sending us the first
batch of a hundred collaborators.
Strike-breakers!
- Scabs! Blacklegs!
- Let's go!
No. Don't shoot to kill' man.
Self defense.
We gotthem scared!
InspectorMlchelll' you are to
take 10 gendarmes out there...
and brlng me those
crlmlnals underarrest.
The gendarmes!
They'll shitthemselves!
Shoot damn you!
So you're one of those
who beats rural workers' are you?
Forwhich land owner do you work?
They've killed Gracián!
Michelli' the son of a bitch!
And he fled.
You're not going to escape so easily.
That's how to give it
to all these dogs.
Not like that' comrade'
he was injured.
Go and heal him' if you can.
This is going from bad to worse'
five gendarmes dead.
You have to go and see
what's happening.
While the judge tells us one thing'
the governor says another.
Santa Cruz is a
bag full of cats!
The problem is serious.
There are many interests at stake.
There's even pressure from abroad.
I understand' Minister, but'
I'd like to have
more precise orders.
You spoke with the President.
Yes' but he limited himself to saying:
"Go' Lieutenant Colonel
and do your duty. "
Not a word more' my friend'
go and do your duty.
Mlnlster, slr, I must
tell YourExcellency
thatI've found here
that those responslble...
for the chaotlc sltuatlon
In the terrltoryofSanta cruz...
are the authorities themselves.
And thatthe police
can be classified...
as appalling.
The rural worker is exploited
in the most primitive manner.
He is paid with checks or vouchers'
which he has to exchange...
in the shops or stores ofthe
same companies that employ them.
Without exaggerating' I must say...
that after having
worked for a year'
he leaves as poor as when he started.
This' Minister, is one of
the origins of the strikes...
of a revolutionary nature'
and the cause of hatred
towards society.
- Does it seem reasonable' Soto?
- Yes' sir,
butwe can't make any decision...
until Facón Grande
returns from El Deseado.
Tomorrow' no?
Whatwe cannot accept' sir,
is handing over our weapons.
Butwhy not' Schultz?
Tell me why.
How can we be expected to hand in
our weapons? It's preposterous!
But most of them have
been stolen from the estancias.
Confiscated' Your Honor.
Confiscated.
I think it's enough
that we hand over the hostages...
and call off the strike.
Appreciate the importance'
gentlemen.
Itwould be the first agreement
for rural workers in Patagonia.
Sir, we will abide by
our comrades' decision.
The assembly Is soverelgn.
45 days of strike' we've won'
and now they want to exchange
our weapons for a piece of paper.
Florentino Cuello.
You're not going to tell me' sir,
that these are all the weapons?
Don't you worry'
Lieutenant Colonel
Sixty-eight and El Toscano' they'll
go shooting guanaco in the mountains.
They're not good honest working folk.
Alright' friends'
the party's over.
Now you have the agreement
you wanted'
now' getto work.
- Traitors!
- Madam!
Colonel...
I beg you' Lieutenant Colonel' sirs'
accept our apologies and...
forgive the lady.
The thing is we're all very hurt...
by the outcome of your negotiations.
You've handed over the triumph
to the bandits.
You don't know what you're saying'
Mr. Novas.
You must understand' those of us
who work' who live here'
- ... we have the authority to speak.
- That's not disputed!
Maybe not yourself'
but the others'
those from Buenos Aires'
who don't know the provinces'
why don'tthey come and struggle here'
in June' with 30 degrees below zero...
and 2 meters of snow?
I beg you to calm down'
remember there are also landowners...
who live in London and don't know
Patagonia even on the map.
Understand this' Lieutenant Colonel'
they've killed gendarmes'
they've setfire to estancias and you
reward them giving them an agreement.
- You leave and this will explode.
- No.
Ifthe landowners fulfill
their part of the agreement'
peace will be definite.
In any case' gentlemen'
I've done no more than
carry outthe orders
ofthe President.
Good night.
No' comrade'
no alcohol in here.
- It's justto counteract the fat.
- I beg you.
Alcohol only serves
to turn people brutish.
It's a weapon ofthe bourgeoisie.
Have a cup oftea.
You must be kidding' friend.
To hell with gringo habits.
Eating mutton with a cup of tea?!
Comrades' the bourgeois
reaction has begun.
That bloodsucker Fernández
has thrown me out ofthe store'
for being an agitator.
And they've left these comrade waiters
of the café "LaArmonía" withoutjobs.
I assume responsibility
for declaring as from now
the boycott of Fernández...
and "La Armonía":
- Ready to go?
- Yes' sir.
Look.
- Friend.
Old Felix' that's all we needed.
I've been replaced
as Governor.
But that's absurd!
And' Commander Zavala's
reports.
There you have it' that's
the peacemaking he's left us.
This will never be sorted out.
Yes it will'
in BuenosAires.
Look here' Felix' as soon as
the new Governor arrives'
I'm going to the capital.
Where are you golng
wlth parcels and llsts?
ThatI see you
In such a hurry.
To the congress
ofthe anarchlsts...
to speak
and be understood.
Explaln,
one moment' ifyou wlll,
anarchlst'
whatdoes Itmean?
The Immense
common front ofworkers,
who clalm
the rlght to llve.
The worker
who tolls and sweats,
tellme, how come
he can be badly off?
Because the mule
whlch eats straw'
carrles the graln
foranotheranlmal.
It's strange,
butI don't understand,
whatdoesyou
new alluslon mean?
That the same
thlng Is happenlng...
to the worker
with hls output.
That the same
thlng Is happenlng...
to the worker
with hls output.
That the same
thlng Is happenlng...
to the worker
with hls output.
And' Mr. Méndez'
when will you be traveling?
Nextweek'
on the "Asturiano".
Bring the food.
Bring the food!
Serve the table!
Gentlemen' the food is ready'
but not one of us
is going to lift a finger.
There is someone seated here who
has been boycotted for exploiting'
and you will not be served until
that bloodsucker Fernández...
- ... leaves.
- But' what are you saying?
- Butthis is outrageous.
- There was more!
- Sit down.
- You' take a hand in the matter.
This is an insult
to the nation...
and to the ladies present here.
Nothing. Nothing! You can stamp with
rage' we aren't lifting a finger.
Either the bloodsucker goes
or we don't serve!
Gentlemen! Gentlemen' calm down!
What's the problem?
We'll serve ourselves.
- How's it going' comrade?
- Good to see you.
Well' and how are
things going at Paso Ibañez?
Very bad' Mr. Font' sir. Very bad.
They're forcing us
to get nasty.
It's the same in Las Heras.
They're saying the same everywhere:
"Forgive us' Mr. Font'
but we can't pay the raise. "
It's the order from BuenosAires'
from Gallegos' from La Mercantil.
- I don't know what.
- Damn it'
they've tricked us
with the piece of paper.
That's how it is.
For the moment'
in Puerto Santa Cruz...
it's been decided to stop
the shearing of the eyes.
Comrades'
I'm deeply grateful to you...
for the post of General
Secretary of the Federation'
with which you have just honored me.
With the roads now passable'
the news is beginning to arrive.
The landowners
are not fulfilling the agreement.
Comrades
have to go round the countryside...
and warn
the ruralworkers...
so thatnext summer
they flnd us ready and wllllng...
to face a flght that cannot
be putoffany longer.
- And' German?
- Everything's ready.
- Let's go.
Afew minutes of your patience.
There is some news.
The Chilean Embassy is
very concerned aboutthis matter.
Anotherfavorable fact.
The English representative...
warned the Chancery
that another strike...
would damage
British interests.
Very good' we're not alone.
What's more' he hinted
that in the Falklands'
there are two warships
ready for any emergency.
These Radicals are beginning
to have problems. Port stoppages'
strikes in La Forestal'
internal conflicts in the party'
and as an added extra' the coming
presidential elections.
I don'tthink the government wants to
complicate things with a new conflict.
Gentlemen' you may go in.
Stop!
Comrades' in Gallegos
they've unmasked.
Politicians and exploiters
all mixed up in it.
They've started stirring it up.
- Any arrested?
- Arrested?
All ofthem!
Comrades' take as delegated
the order for a general strike...
to each of the estancias
where you work.
We'll respond
to the owners' provocation...
with the orders
of the organized workers.
Strike!
And form one single
great column of protest.
All the columns of strikers
must meet at Lago Argentino.
OK' mister' you're facing
the Red Council which will make...
the Socialist Revolution
in Patagonia.
El Toscano' yours truly'
my comrade' No. 68' from Ushuaia'
Frank Cross' cowboy from Arizona'
José Barría' Chilean'
but not Chilote [as an insult]'
and Zacarías Caro'
Patagonian by adoption.
OK' mister, go handing over
all the weapons you have'
money' jewels...
The Red Council greets
the striking comrades.
Go on!
You're nothing but bandits!
Scantfavor you're doing
to the workers' cause.
The strike has been called to
free the detained comrades.
And for the landowners
to comply with the agreement.
And that's all!
Alright.
But stirring things.
Any gendarme that's found...
And all the cash
to buy weapons.
Join us!
Not one of you lot has
anything to do with the strike.
This is a genuine
workers' movement!
When the strike ends
the Workers' Federation...
will pay you for the damages
and the provisions.
Now you have to come
with us as a hostage.
They'll wipe out the lot of you
Let's go.
The situation' Lieutenant Colonel'
is much more serious...
than you realized.
The territory is overrun
by bandits.
They kill land owners'
rape their women.
They say they're going to raise
the red flag in the Plaza de Mayo.
The President
has decided that you...
shall command the troops once again.
Zavala' you well know the high esteem
in which PresidentYrigoyen holds you.
Your responsibility
now is greater.
We run the risk
of losing the Patagonia.
Think of Chile.
Lieutenant Colonel' we have
to finish once and for all...
with these anarchists.
Take them to the room.
Lieutenant Colonel' sir'
I'm going to settle the troops.
Go on then.
You arrive and I leave.
I've been called to Buenos Aires.
- Indeed!
- No problem.
- You'll get it all sorted.
- Yes' definitively.
See here' the workers
trust you.
The workers have let me down.
Farewell' sir,
have a good trip.
The Spaniard Outerello is at
Puerto Santa Cruz and Paso Ibáñez.
In the north' José Font'
alias Facón Grande'
in control of the Puerto Deseado
to Las Heras railway line.
In the foothills of the Andes'
the leader Soto.
And somewhere about'
the famous Red Council.
LieutenantArrieta' take a truck'
fifteen soldiers'
go out in search ofthe Red Council
and on a mission to harass...
the Spaniard Soto.
CaptainArzeno' the big group
will begin operations...
clearing up the center
and north of the area.
Excuse me' Lieutenant
Colonel' sir?
According to the information gathered'
each column of strikers...
is four or five times
bigger than our troops.
Captain Arzeno' we can't
make an academic war here.
The orders we have
are perfectly clear,
to utterly destroy the uprising.
Death sentence"
Anyone who resists
will be executed.
Without batting an eyelid!
We have to stain
the Patagonia with blood.
May no one feel weak...
and may everyone
fulfil his duty.
Any questions?
Good.
Lieutenant Colonel' sir'
The gentlemen Matthews and Saunders
have asked to accompany us.
They could act as guides.
That's fine.
Very good sir.
Only this way can this land
continue being Argentina.
Thank you. Good afternoon.
Lieutenant Colonel' sir.
Avery hard campaign
awaits us.
May I give the troops
some time off?
Only until 10 p. m.
Tomorrow we rise at 5 a. m.
Excuse me' Lieutenant Colonel' sir.
Mayer' take time off.
I'm told there are very
pretty girls here.
Thank you' Lieutenant Colonel' sir.
- Mayer.
- Sir.
Are you of German
descent or...?
German' Lieutenant Colonel' sir.
A good race' Mayer. Good race.
- Viel Vergnugen.
- Danke schön' Herr Obertsleutnant.
Kneel down.
Kneel down!
Order fire.
- Aim!
- Fire!
The army! Soldiers!
Don't shoot!
Don't shoot' it's Zavala!
Bring a sheet.
Flag to discuss peace terms.
Order a cease fire.
We want to tell you...
Take your hat off when
you speak to me' eh?
We don'twantto have
a confrontation with the army.
All we are asking is that
our detained comrades are freed...
and the rural agreement obeyed.
I am here in person
so thatthere can be no doubt...
regarding my position'
unconditional surrender...
or the death penalty
for all who resist.
We were hoping you had come
to see thatthe agreementwas obeyed...
- ... which you yourself signed.
- and you lot didn't obey.
- The landowners...
- The owners and all of you lot.
All! Look' don'ttalk to me
about agreements.
This is all that matters.
Good. With regard to your demand'
we must consult
with the ranch delegates.
Wait a moment.
Sirs' we are atwar.
We must act swiftly.
We have to rescue the hostages and
save the blood of our soldiers.
And ifwhen these criminals
come we receive them with gunfire?
The leaders dead' the Chilean
scum will surrender immediately.
If you give the order,
Lieutenant Colonel' sir...
But Colonel...
What are you doing?
They'll kill us all.
There are many strikers
out there.
And I...
I have a family'
three children.
I have six children.
Do you realize' Captain?
Civilians can't be brought in
to deal with these things.
It has been decided...
It has been decided
to call an assembly.
As from now' we will
free the hostages...
to show them that
we have nothing against you lot...
and the only thing we ask
is justice.
I said unconditional surrender.
You have 2 hours to decide.
And remember,
my hand will not tremble.
They won't surrender,
all the worse for them.
And so?
The surrender will be accepted only
when freedom is given...
to the strikers and you
assure us of fulfillment...
ofthe rural agreement.
Who is he?
The owner of La Barrancosa.
Why did you kill him?
- Itwas the soldiers.
- You are the murderers'
because you provoked this situation.
Captain' four shots.
What' Lieutenant Colonel' sir?
Fire him four shots!
- Come on...
- Sergeant!
Come on' Commander' don'tjoke.
You four' seize him.
You lot' seize the rest.
No! No' no! Let me go!
Zavala! Zavala! No! Please!
Zavala' no' please!
Let me go! Let me go! Zavala!
Zavala' please!
- Zavala' please!
- Aim!
- Fire!
- Zavala' please! No!
"Lieutenant Colonel Zavala disembarked
at Gallegos on his way to Deseado. "
Just as well.
The Commander is a guarantee.
- Hurrah for the strike' damn it!
- Hurrah!
Down with the exploiters!
Stop this all of you!
I didn't know there were
so many thieves amongst you!
Drop everything and get out!
Come on' friend...
Get out' I said!
Alcohol is our
worst enemy.
Damn them' they're like priests.
Here you have him Facón'
quite tame.
Do you remember when
he put you in the stocks?
Goddamn son of a bitch!
I can still feel
the lashes you gave me.
No' leave him!
He's alone and unarmed.
Remove his badges' he doesn't
deserve them' for bad police.
And now let him go.
It's notthe done thing to
kick a man when he's down.
Look out! They're gendarmes.
Ready!
It's not the police' it's the army.
Lower your weapons!
Take aim.
Fire!
Withdraw!
All back to the camp!
Mr. friend Martense'
how's business?
So-so.
With passengers?
No' I'm with my comrade'
on Federation business.
Get out of here! Right now!
They're shooting
all the Federates!
- Butwho's shooting?
- Well who do you think?
Your beloved Zavala.
Butwhere? Who?
Who? Well Ramón's already
taken care of.
- Outerello?
- The same. As you hear it.
And in Cañadón León'
he's left them scattered.
About a hundred are left dead.
Indeed' they make you dig your grave'
they can't be bothered even with that.
And when the ground Is hard
they make a plle ofyou,
they sprlnkle itwith petrol
and then setllght to It.
Dead when attempting
to flee: 13.
Excuse me' Lieutenant Colonel' sir?
I need to tell you something.
Isn't it too much punishment
for what these men have done?
Do you think I
enjoy shooting?
There's not other remedy here.
There are too few of us
to dominate them.
In this empty wilderness'
the only way is being hard handed.
Last night we took 400 prisoners.
Do you thinkwe're able to keep watch
day and night over so many rebels?
We're running the risk now
of losing Patagonia.
Think of Chile' Captain.
Think of Chile.
They must be scabs' blacklegs.
We'll stop them.
Come on!
It's Facón Grande' that's all.
Get ready.
Ready!
- Get ready.
- Ready!
Ready!
Quickly!
Aim!
- Aim!
Stop!
- Fire!
Attack!
Attack. Come on.
Come on! Come on' forward!
Stand up to them!
- To the ground.
- To the ground!
Fire!
Attack!
Keep firing' damn it!
Cover him! Cover him!
Stop! Stop firing!
Damn it.
Itwas Zavala.
We made him back down.
We made a heck of a mistake.
You're going to worry now?
Let's celebrate!
You're already drunk
again' friend.
Don't do thatto me.
Come' Mr. Font' sir' the telegraph.
Facón Grande is receiving.
Put this.
Friend José Font'
Edward Matthews
offers himself as a mediator.
Please travel to Jaramillo.
Guarantee offered.
Commander Zavala...
...open to positive solutions.
OK' tell him that I've
already set off for there and...
thank the gringo Matthews.
Facón' give yourself up!
I'm here to discuss peace terms
with Commander Zavala.
Who wantto talk to me?
Arrest him' for murdering
Argentine soldiers.
That's treason!
If you're a man
I'll fight you with my hands tied!
Take him away!
I'm Facón Grande's second in command.
I'm here to make a pact.
Get down. Come on!
Get down!
Wait a minute'
I'm the Gaucho Cuello'
delegate of the Fede...
...ofthe Workers' Federation.
You take care ofthe other one.
Take them away.
Come on. Walk!
Come on!
Get up. Get him up.
Come on' walk.
Walk! Come on!
Come on' look sharp. Justthere.
Justthere.
Get ready.
Aim!
You don't kill a gaucho like that!
Fire!
Load.
Come on.
Lieutenant Colonel' sir' we good
men have organized ourselves
as a white guard and we're here
to offer you our support
That's fine.
You may join the column.
We wantto tell you thatthe
Rural Society is to put your name...
forward as military governor
of Santa Cruz.
Gentlemen' I'm not guided
by any personal ambition.
I'm doing my duty'
as I understand I must.
Excuse me' Lieutenant Colonel' sir.
The Red Council.
So you lot wanted to implant
socialism in Patagonia.
A good catch' Chief.
A photo for the BuenosAires
newspapers.
So the readers find out
what these strikers are like.
Letthem see the armbands clearly.
That's it.
I think' friend Zavala' that it
would be best to leave these alive'
so that public opinion finds out
what the Patagonian reds are like.
Very good'
friend Méndez Garzón.
We'll place them at the disposal
of the Judge.
Ready' now!
As I feared. When they attacked us
as a mob I understood it all.
Antonio' all that's left to us
is to fight' confrontthem.
Fight? With these men?
Most ofthem don't even know
how to use a weapon.
They must be taught!
Listen' German'
the comrades are already looking
at us askance' you know?
They have to be spoken to' prepared.
For two and a half months now
we've been out in the countryside.
Sleeping out in the open
most ofthe time.
Eating whatever there is.
We don't even have tobacco left
Antonio' that's struggling.
You have to be organized.
You Spaniards'
you talk a lot...
but you're not organized' no discipline.
How many weapons are there?
Some fifty rifles
and about a hundred revolvers.
Ammunition?
There'd be ten shots per gun.
Enough to hold out.
And when they're all gone?
We'll fight them with knives.
Take aim.
Lower your weapons!
Unload!
Load. Unload.
Good' comrade' and?
What are we waiting for?
Tonight's assembly.
No' my people want
the assembly right now.
That's no problem.
They're more aroused.
Also' ifthere's no shearing'
we'll be spending a hard winter.
We'll do whatthe majority decides.
Because' what this is about here'
comrades'
is making humanity
understand'
that everything can be achieved
through reason and freedom.
Anarchist ideas
are the only ones...
Shut up' big mouth!
No' comrade. That's against
our principles offreedom.
To interrupt a speech
is to cut freedom.
These big mouths talk and talk
but we have the troops on top of us.
For they mustbe made to understand,
thatweapons are products...
of stupidity
and irrationality.
Alright' but cut it out' comrade.
We're wasting time.
Everyone here knows thatZavala
is camped at Río Perro.
Right here!
So' we have to decide right now
whatwe're going to do.
Like what are we going to do' comrade?
Resist! Resistwith the weapons!
Or maybe you don't know that the murderer
Zavala has killed Ramón Outerello...
and dozens of comrades
at Cañadón León?
But where do you get that from?
What' did you see it yourself perhaps?
I didn't see it. Butthe person
who told me deserves to be believed.
Ah! You didn't see it'
you were told' then!
He wouldn't have seen them'
but we did see...
how they attacked us without warning
and we lost nine comrades there.
I think we mustn't
expect mercy'
neither am I prepared to ask it.
Comrade' you've limited me here
with my turn to speak.
No' comrade' stop him.
Now it's up to us to talk
to the Chilean rural workers.
We don't want any
kind of problems...
with the authorities.
The only thing we do want is
to be allowed to work in peace.
That we're treated properly
and paid as we deserve.
That's why we think...
thatwe ought to go and talk
with the military to lift this strike.
Comrades. Comrades!
The only way to win
is to fight.
Fightto the last man!
Only one possibility is leftfor us'
to resist!
To defend this estancia
with trenches...
and turn back
those who attack us!
I propose we carry on
with out tactics'
occupy ranches
and take hostages.
And when the army arrives'
disappear.
Hide ourselves in the woods'
in the mountain region'
until they have to
come to terms with us.
Because withoutthe workers
the estancias can't function!
No' comrade' if we split up
they'll go catching us one by one.
We must resist
all together, here.
But comrade'
ifthe army can't
beat us with 100 armed men...
they'll send 200' or 1 '000.
And us? What are we going to
fight againstZavala with? Ah?
With our bare hands? No' we have to
agree terms' arrive at an arrangement.
Is itthat perhaps we didn't do
it in the last strike?
Comrades' we can't
throw out ofthe window...
all the sacrifices
we've made.
You want us to talk
to the army? So be it!
We'll electtwo comrades
to have an interview with Zavala...
and ask for conditions.
Excuse me' Lieutenant Colonel' sir,
two strikers
askto be received.
Show them in.
Go in.
Excuse us.
Apologies for interrupting your meal.
What do you want?
We represent
the Workers' Federation.
We've come to talk
as equals'
about the conditions for an agreement.
As equals.
- What nationality are you?
- Spanish.
- And the other?
- Polish.
And you two rebelling foreigners'
want to impose conditions on me?
But' conditions forwhat?
Sons of bitches!
Conditions for what?
Sergeant!
Come out. Come on' come on!
Captain'
go up to the column.
A sargeant and a white flag.
Go and askthem for
unconditional surrender.
Yes' sir' Lieutenant Colonel.
You've all seen
how insolently they behave.
I'm not going to letthem
raise their heads.
Especially Soto.
ThatAntonio Soto'
who's filled them with those ideas.
And we'll have done
with all this for good and all.
Ready. Aim.
Brothers' throw down those guns'
embrace the cause...
- ... ofthe libertarian ideal.
- Fire!
Aren't you the leaders
of the Workers' Federation?
Yes' sir.
Orderfrom Lieutenant Colonel Zavala.
Unconditional surrender.
Hand over of hostages'
horses and weapons.
Otherwise we shall not
hesitate to proceed.
Didn't Lieutenant Colonel Zavala
receive our delegation?
No delegation
will be received.
That is the last offer.
We won't decide
without consulting the Assembly.
As you like.
You have 2 hours.
Don't accept. They'll shoot you all'
not a single one will be left alive.
Comrades' don't trust
Zavala' don't surrender.
You're laborers' you're workers!
Comrades' carry on with the strike!
To triumph definitively so as to
form a new society...
where there are no poor or rich'
where there are no weapons'
where there is happiness and respect
for human beings!
Let's get going.
...tire ourselves out like beasts.
We must make
the trenches now.
Let's return to the camp.
And I'm saying it plainly and clearly
so there's no doubt left:
The only way to win
is with weapons!
Comrades' I move that we
surrender ourselves unconditionally.
I didn't expectthis end.
I didn't expect it.
Come on' German'
there's nothing leftto do here.
NoAntonio' I'm staying.
I respect the decision
ofthe majority.
But it's suicide!
They'll shoot you first!
I've always complied with
the decision of my comrades'
even ifthey were mistaken.
Today they've chosen death.
I too respect it'
but I'm not meat
to be thrown to the dogs.
If it's to fight' I'll stay'
butthe comrades
don'twantto fight.
I do.
I'll carry on fighting.
Come on' German'
very near here is that paradise
you were seeking so much.
Where'sAntonio Soto?
Damn it!
Draw out your gun.
Where'sAntonio Soto?
Stop' you bastards'
it's me' Soto!
Lieutenant Colonel' sir'
that's the Chilean
who proposed the surrender.
Good.
This is the German' Shultz.
So you're
the great revolutionary.
Put him to one side.
Let's see' the ranch delegates'
on step forward!
One step forward
the ranch delegates!
It seems there are no delegates' eh?
Did they all die?
It's OK' they'll appear soon enough.
Find out about Soto.
Lieutenant Colonel' sir, maybe notthat one.
He's the only mechanic in the area'
we might need him.
Leave him.
So you've got new clothes.
Can you tell me
where you gotthem?
Captain' undress them
and tie them to the fence.
Letthem spend the night naked!
I now have the report'
Lleutenant colonel, slr.
Soto and three others are
fleelng by horse to chlle.
Send outLleutenantArrleta
wlth ten men,
and bring him back alive or dead.
- What's your name?
- Esperidión González' sir.
Now you go straight
to your boss's place...
And from now on'
if he orders you to be a dog'
you get down on all fours
and you bark.
- Is that understood?
- Alright' sir.
And whoever lets the candle go out
I'll blow the lid off his brains!
OK?
Yes?
Aren't you sleeping' Lt. Col. sir?
The condemned are already
in the shearing shed.
Each with a candle
to make it easier to guard them.
Very good.
For tomorrow'
Does the order stands or...?
Yes' Captain' yes!
The order stands!
Or do you want me to let
them all go free?
It's not about
pardoning or punishing here'
it's about putting an end
to these rebels.
You prefer to kill a hundred leaders
rather than some day...
a thousand innocents dying.
They may say I was
a bloodthirsty military'
butthey'll never say
I was a disobedient one.
- Not in the European war...
- Come on.
Ready.
Aim.
Fire!
Laborers, reduced from 120
to 80 pesos a month.
Wagon drlvers, from 130 to 90 pesos
Sheep hands, from 140 to 100 pesos.
Ranch cooks'
from 160 to 120 pesos.
Herders' per day'
from 25 to 12 pesos.
These wages replace
those from the previous agreement...
which is
definitively annulled.
The memory of your action
in Patagonia...
will remain in the memory
of its inhabitants'
as a lesson on what inspired
men are capable of...
in the fulfillment of their duty
and in the greatness ofthe nation.
Very good!
Friends.
Forhe's ajolly good fellow!
And so say all ofus!
Hip-hip! Hurrah!