THE DIE IS CAST
Wait!
Wait, no!
Give yourself another chance.
No, my Life's a wreck. I want
to put an end to this.
Don't think Like that. Lt
could all change by tomorrow.
- Wait!
- No.
I’m a jinx. Lt's a karma L
can't put up with any more.
Wait, no!
You're meant to be alive.
Or it would have gone off.
Lt didn't go off
because I’m a jinx.
because you're Lucky.
Life always gives you a chance.
That's why you're alive.
I’m a jinx. That's why the shot
didn't even fire.
Lt's a sign!
Lt's a sign, don't you see?
You have to stay alive,
it's a chance.
You have nothing to Lose.
Maybe everything will
change tomorrow.
I’m an actor. Today is an
important day for me.
I was going to do
something important...
but if I can't help you,
it won't mean a thing.
I just need 10 minutes.
10 minutes, have a
coffee with me.
There's a Little bar near here.
Come on, put the gun down.
Put the gun down.
Please.
That's it.
I'll stay here. You come over here.
One step at a time.
Come on.
You've got your Life ahead of you.
There's a step that
only you can take.
He was bound to die, anyway.
What guilt? Stop messing around.
You don't understand. Don't
Laugh. I almost had him.
He'd changed his mind, I’d given
him reasons to stay alive.
Not enough for him to
notice the truck, Felipe.
Stop messing around!
Me standing there saying,
"You've got your Life ahead of you"
"Come on, step forward. "
And so he did. He's
probably thanking you by now.
The Last thing that guy saw
was my stupid face.
Come on, Let's go.
Please.
Give me your hand.
Lt is moist.
Lt knows not yet age nor sorrow.
Warm.
Warm and moist.
An excellent hand.
An honest hand.
Really?
You may say it,
for I gave my heart with this hand.
Lt is a Liberal hand.
In other times, hands gave
away hearts.
Today in the modern age
thou ask not for hearts;...
hands are enough.
I don't understand.
- Come. Fulfill thy promise.
- Which promise?
- To speak with Cassio.
- Cassio.
A heavy catarrh
means a storm is brewing.
- Give me your handkerchief.
- Here it is.
Give me the one I gave you.
- I haven't got it.
- You have Lost it!
Answer me!
You haven't got it!
My faithful friend Lago
obtained it from Cassio.
Take that away, asshole!
You fucking prick!
- What's your problem?
- What's your problem?!
What are you doing with
that handkerchief on stage?
Don't you know that colour
is jinxed in the theatre?
- Lt's a disgrace, Carlos!
- What does the text say?
Lt clearly says a mottled,
strawberry handkerchief.
- What did you give him?
- A mottled, strawberry one.
We gave you a strawberry
handkerchief. What's that?
- You gave me this one.
- Take that away!
Why would we give you that
if it's a banned colour?
Everyone knows that.
Have you seen any "amarelo"
anywhere in the theatre.
- I didn't know.
- You didn't know?
I knew, but I didn't think
you thought it was a big deal.
Not a big deal?
Are you stupid?
- A Little respect, please.
- Calm down, Maribel.
Don't start with me!
Lt's not my fault.
Don't you see what's going on here?
Can you feel the energy?
I feel bad! I feel bad!
I can't breathe in here!
That colour is a disaster.
I don't want any part of it.
- On or off stage! Get it?!
- Yes.
I don't understand why you
didn't get a black guy...
instead of this idiot all
painted black, getting me dirty.
Saying "A warm hand", "a moist
hand", and dirtying everything.
- Please just...
- No, Listen here.
I won't go on! Not until Ursula
comes, cleans up this mess...
and say, "it's all right"!
No Carlos! I won't go on!
- I’m Leaving!
- Maribel.
- I can't!
- Lt's the police.
Lt's the police.
For me?
Hello?
Yes, that's me.
What is it dear?
What is it?
My brother's been run over
by a truck!
Jinx!
You and your fucking handkerchief!
- These actors...
- Hello.
Excuse me.
Early this morning, here,
Pedro Lazábal was run over.
He was the brother of
the actress, Maribel Lazábal.
The driver said he couldn't stop in
time, as the man appeared suddenly
on the road giving onto the
Costanera Sur.
The driver is with us...
This is Marcos, the assistant
director from the theatre.
We've put things back
a few days because of Maribel...
and the director has decided
to replace you.
Look, I don't believe
in these things...
we all think
it was a coincidence...
and all this jinx business
is very unfair.
Your pay for the rehearsals
will be in the bank tomorrow.
The crew all send their best.
Bye.
You fucker.
Four no-shows, and seven Late
arrivals in the Last six weeks.
Lt's not my fault the
car alarm keeps you awake.
A chief administrator can't
set the example you do.
You Leave me no choice.
You’ll get your wages and
your redundancy payment.
Well, part of it. We’ll pay
you the rest of it...
in merchandise.
That's the way things are.
The Lads from the warehouse
will bring it over to your house.
Good Luck.
- That's it.
- What about the boxes?
They said "no boxes".
- Hello.
- Sorry I’m Late.
- No, it's all right.
I’ve only been here an hour
and 10 minutes.
- I said I’m sorry, period.
- Don't get offended.
I forgive you, period.
- See what you're Like?
- What I’m Like?
I wait an hour and 10 minutes,
I don't ask why you're Late...
I have to forgive you, and
"period" as you say...
- and you even get offended.
- I’m not here to fight.
- We've already fought enough.
- Fine, I’m sorry, you're right.
I wanted to say that I want
to do whatever it takes...
to make things better,
to make this work.
- Guillermo?
- Yes.
I’m seeing someone else.
What do you mean?
Who?
- Someone, period.
- Period, my ass!
- Who are you seeing?
- You don't know him.
Thanks for seeing someone
I don't know! Thank-you!
Who is he?
What's his name?
- Alfonzo.
- Alfonso?
- Alfonzo. Ls he a Bourbon?
- Cut it out.
Who is Alfonzo?
- He's my boss. - You're cheating
on me with your boss?
I’m not cheating on you.
I want to be happy...
- and I’m not with you, period.
- Sorry then.
You and Alfonzo,
and the Royal Family.
- Don't be childish.
- I’m not childish.
How Long have you been
fucking me over?
I’ve been with him for two
weeks, since we split.
I came to say that it's over.
Whatever happens, I don't want us
back together, period.
I have to go now.
Take care.
In the extermination camps
large warehouses were filled...
with huge piles of
the prisoners' shoes...
Months?
Weeks.
Hello.
Dad, sorry I haven't been
to see you, I had a tough week.
What's up, Dad?
Felipe. This is your old man.
I talked to Guille and I have to
see you both together.
Guillermo's coming at 10 o'clock.
I'd like you to be there.
It's important.
Please do come.
Hello.
Thanks for coming, son.
Please, sit down.
- Felipe, I know that you and L...
- It's alright...
Let me say something.
I made a Lot of mistakes...
and you were very small
when I became a widower.
I thought putting you in
boarding school in Buenos Aires...
- closer to your grandmother...
- Lt's all right Dad...
I know the story of my Life.
But I wanted to admit that
I made a terrible mistake.
In front of your...
I don't Like to say, half-brother.
In front of your brother.
I haven't Long Left.
- What have you got?
- An orange in my head...
that's growing fast.
I'd Like to talk to the doctor,
see what he has to say.
There's nothing he can do.
I asked you to come because
I wanted to tell you a story...
that I’ve never told anyone.
In the forties, I was a kid. And
one night, with some friends...
we went to the theater
for the first time.
I was a kid of the times...
I had nothing to do with
the world of show-business.
That night, I was dazzled
by a girl called...
Lina Delponte.
I had never seen
something like that.
Lina Delponte.
Beautiful.
On my way out of the theatre,
I saw a sign that said...
"Help wanted for
administrative duties. "
So the next day I applied...
and I was lucky,
and they gave me the job.
I watched her night after night.
Couldn't get her off my mind.
I was crazy about her.
I dreamed about her.
Two months Later I got
a job as an accountant...
in a company in Rio Gallegos.
So I Left my job in the theatre,
for a better future...
or so I thought.
Because that night,
something happened...
that could have changed
my destiny.
Lt was my Last night in the
theatre and in Buenos Aires.
Suddenly, the door opened...
and she appeared.
I couldn't believe it.
Lina Delponte!
Without a word...
she sat on my lap...
and stated to kiss me in a way...
She took out a Little jar,
with some white powder inside.
And all of a sudden she says:
"D'you wanna try?"
I didn't know what to say,
and asked: What's it Like?
"What's it Like?", she said.
You’ll see 25 watt Lamps, as if
they were 60 watt Lamps!
I can't put it into words.
That night...
Life opened up a whole new road
for me, that I didn't take.
Because when I told her that
I was Leaving the next day...
she said, "What a shame.
"Cause if you stayed...
we could be together.
But if you go, it will
be impossible. "
How would my life have been
with Lina Delponte?
Boys. I’d Like to stay awake
the few nights I have Left...
so I can go through
my entire repertoire...
before I get on the train.
Can you get me some cocaine?
Ls it a Lot to ask?
He's mad, man. Cocaine.
I can't believe it.
I agree, it's madness.
But we have to do it.
Then you both have
an orange in your head.
I’m an actor, man. That's
all I want in Life.
I’d Like to be known for
the forty plays I’ve done...
not for going to jail
as a dealer for geriatrics.
That's what he asked us for.
He was clear about it.
What are you going to do
when they call you tomorrow...
and tell you: "Your father's
on the roof saying...
he's Spiderman,
and doesn't want to come down. "
- That's not it.
- Then what is it?
He must be scared to even close
his eyes. Don't you see?
Lt's a memory he has
from those days.
How do you know what goes
through a person's mind...
when they tell him he has
weeks to Live?
He isn't reacting to that.
He has an orange in his head...
- that won't Let him think.
- He's still Lucid.
And Doctor Sosa said so too.
And I know him well.
I know you do.
Do what you think is best.
No. You were there
and you heard him.
Don't you come preaching to me.
He's your father and he's
dying. That's how it is.
And for the record, I have
to tell you something:
Lf you're so resentful
you’ll miss your Last chance.
- Chance for what?
- To tie up Loose ends with him.
- By buying him coke.
- By doing whatever he wants.
I don't care if it's coke,
mustard, or whatever.
Lt's what he asked for,
so I'll get it for him.
But I need your help.
You must know someone.
Lt's been such a Long time.
Just right now.
I'll make a phone call.
I can't promise anything.
- Call me tomorrow.
- Thanks, Feli.
- What about you?
- Me what?
How are you doing?
Your Life. Your career...
Great.
And you?
Great too.
What the fuck...?
I just picked it up from the
mechanic... fuck!
What did those guys do?
You’ll have to take
another one, buddy.
What do you think?
I’m delighted!
- How are you?
- Felipe!
- Fine. Well, Like shit.
Buddy, don't Let all this
mess with your head.
I know you. Lt's stupid.
You're a talented guy.
And there's no way I think
you're a jinx, buddy.
And I won't Let any asshole
talk about you badly.
I’d just put them straight.
Right away.
They talk about me?
I came here to ask you
a couple of things.
One is the phone number of
that fortune teller...
Alda. She’ll help you, sure.
Great, buddy.
And the other thing...
and that's why I wanted to
see you in person...
I need to buy cocaine,
just a couple of grams...
- Lt's for my brother.
- I didn't know you had one.
He's a half-brother...
Lt's part of something
I have to do.
I'll get whatever you want,
but I don't think...
- Lt's not that...
- Lt won't help you...
I don't want it to help me.
I’m totally fine...
You just told me you
were Like shit.
They're two different things.
I feel Like shit, it's true...
but the cocaine's not for
my brother...
Lt's actually for my old man,
he's in an old folks' home.
Don't make it harder for me.
Lf you don't believe it's for
my brother...
I won't believe,
that you don't think I’m a jinx.
- I want to think it isn't that way,
is it? - No. Lt isn't.
I don't think you're a jinx.
Actually, you brought me Luck.
- How come?
- Your part.
They gave it to me.
There's nothing here about
the bad Luck you say you have.
You aren't predestined.
Lt's strange.
Lt's as if someone else’s bad
Luck was stuck to you.
- That could be it.
- What? Do you know who it is?
- Yes. Lt was a coincidence.
- There are no coincidences.
Bring him along and I'll put
an end to this in no time.
I can't. He's dead.
- Can you help me anyway?
- We’ll give it a try.
First go where I tell you
and buy: a kilo of salt...
a rosary, preferably white,
one quartz stone...
two candles,
one white, one red...
two liters of full-fat milk,
bay leaves...
and a rue plant,
in a clay pot.
Draw a circle with the salt
about meters in diameter...
and take your clothes off.
You can
stay in your underwear.
Put seven bay leaves
around the salt circle...
but without breaking it.
Light the candles...
and put the plant inside the
circle, with a piece of paper...
where you write, "I, Felipe Nugal,
ask my superior beings...
to end this bad luck that
doesn't belong to me. "
Bury the paper
in the plant pot...
put the rosary around the pot...
and pray with your eyes closed.
Are you catholic?
When I was a kid.
Not so much these days.
OK. Then take a teaspoon
of mistletoe oil.
Mind you; it tastes awful.
Then, pour the milk all over
yourself inside the circle.
Wait for it to dry and
shower with white soap...
the kind for washing clothes.
It's important that you concentrate
on the water cleansing you.
Then put the quartz stone on
to keep draining off the energy...
throughout the night. Get
into bed and go to sleep.
And everything will be great.
- Hello.
- Hi, I’m here for the audition.
- Lamadrid...
- What's your problem?
- What?
- Nothing.
Do you think I didn't see you
whispering to these two...
touching your balls,
touching your tit...
do you think I’m an idiot?!
I’ve already ruined your day.
The power has begun.
Maybe if I touch you
you’ll blow up.
See me touching you?
Why are you so scared?
You don't need me to
have bad Luck.
Have you Looked in the mirror?
Beside you, Bob Sponge would Look
Like Miss Venezuela.
- Stop it, man!
- You stop me!
What right do you have
to do this to me?
To make a big deal out of
something you heard...
that was a coincidence.
You're an asshole.
I’m not a jinx. Get
that into your head.
Excuse me. The director
has taken ill...
and can't go on with the auditions.
We’ll call you when we're
ready to go on. Thank you.
I'm Clara, leave your message.
Hello Clara, this is Guillermo.
I just wanted to say I miss you...
and see how you were.
That's all.
Kisses.
Bye.
- Hello.
- How are you?
Sorry.
My friend hooked me up with
a guy who’ll meet us at the bar.
He's in a blue shirt.
I'll talk to him...
but I'll pass it on to you.
I don't want to have that on me.
- Fine. I'll take it.
- Ok.
- Are you staying or coming?
- I'll go with you.
- Felipe?
- What?
- Thanks a Lot. Really.
- Great.
- Will you bring him this tomorrow?
- I can't tomorrow.
- You bring it to him.
- The day after.
OK. The day after.
- Bye.
- Shall we have a drink?
- What?
- Let's have a drink.
We haven't seen each other
in ages, we should talk.
- Lt's not a good idea.
- Why not?
Mostly because I’m tired.
I’d prefer to go home.
- Do you still Live in San Telmo?
- Yes, San Telmo.
I'll give you a Lift.
Lt's on the way.
- I’d prefer to walk.
- You said you were tired.
- I need the air.
- I can't Leave you here.
There's no one around.
I'll give you a Lift.
We can go in the car.
Give me the money.
Come on, the money.
- Here, here, here...
- What's wrong?
What's wrong? Come on.
Give it over.
- I haven't got anything.
- Give me the money.
What's your problem?
Do you want me to kill you?
- I haven't got any more!
- Do you want me to kill you?
- Coke! I have Coke!
- Coke? Do you have any weed?
- How's he going to have weed?
- I gave you everything.
- Bang, bang, bang!
- Wait! In the boot!
- I was going to sell them.
- Yeah, yeah.
Come on, you fucker!
Fucking hell!
I wanted to spare you this.
This or whatever...
well, fuck you.
What's wrong with you?
Are we going to have a drink?
Lt's not a good idea.
I told you quite clearly:
Lt's not a good idea!
" I'll give you a Lift. "
- No, I’d prefer to walk!
- What's wrong with you?
- Do you want to know?
- Yes.
My Life is a...
Everything I touch rots.
My path is fatal. Someone is
sowing evil for me to harvest.
What? I don't understand
a fucking thing!
I’m a jinx!
A jinx! A tainted person who brings
bad Luck to those around him.
I gave you so many chances to
Let me walk away!
You passed them all up!
Lf you had Listened, none of
this would have happened!
But no! You don't get it!
You aren't a jinx.
You know what you are?
Someone who thinks they're the
centre of everything that happens
- in everyone else’s Lives.
- No, I’m a jinx.
Lt's all been black for me
for ages now!
I’m a jinx, man.
Do you really think you're a jinx?
Yeah, I really do.
So why did you get me
to carry the cocaine?
What?
Lf you really think
you're a jinx...
why did you get me to carry
the cocaine?
I wanted to Leave.
You wouldn’t Let me go!
But nothing ever
happens to the jinx.
The bad Luck goes to
the other people...
so if you really think you're
a jinx why didn't you come alone?
So on top of being a jinx,
you're an asshole too.
Don't start twisting things around,
you prick.
I didn't want to do this
from the start.
I only did it so no one
would bust my balls.
I didn't want to do
this stupid thing.
And be thankful I gave it to
you. The guy calmed down...
when he saw the coke. Otherwise
he would have killed us both.
So now you're not a jinx!
Now you've saved my Life!
- Don't twist things around!
- I’m not!
Do you know what saved our Lives?
The shoes I put in the boot!
So for once in your fucking Life,
be thankful to someone...
for keeping you safe and sound!
Fuck me!
- Why were those shoes there?
- What?
Why where those shoes there?
I heard you.
You were going to sell them.
That they were worth 6000!
- So?
- What are you up to?
- Are you stealing?
- Don't be an idiot!
I’ve been working in a shoe
factory for seven years!
I worked in a bakery
for five years...
and I don't have a boot
full of doughnuts!
- What were they doing there?
- Because after seven years...
they fired me and paid my
redundancy in shoes...
and I was going to sell them!
That's why!
You aren't a jinx!
You're self-centered...
and you think everything
revolves around you!
And the sad thing is,
you don't even see it!
And be thankful I put
the shoes there...
or you'd be getting your ass
kicked in a wasteland...
beside the highway somewhere!
Why don't you get your
ass kicked and Let me sleep?!
- Shut the fuck up!
- I'll call the police!
Why didn't you call them
when they were robbing us?!
Take it easy, Felipe!
- Come on.
- Leave me alone.
Jonahs?
Yes, I’ve met Loads.
There's a Lot in
your Line of work.
But what are you
Looking for exactly?
I have to prepare
a character who's a jinx...
and as you know everyone,
I thought you could help me...
to meet one, to talk a Little,
study him closely.
There's a guy whom L
haven't seen for ages.
He was an administrator
in the theatre.
What was his name?
I called him Coco so as
not to use his name...
but just in case, I give
the Left one a touch.
And is it possible to find him?
I went to his house once.
He Lived in Devoto.
Do you remember where?
When you Leave the station,
the dome is on the right.
On the other side, diagonally
across, there's an old house.
The guy lived there.
Tell him I sent you.
- Ls Coco there?
- Who is asking?
Felipe NugaL.
Tell him Pepe sent me.
You're preparing to play a jinx?
- And you want me to give
you the details? - Yes.
You want me to tell you what it's
Like to Live...
pointed out by a bunch of idiots...
who call themselves artists?
Ls that what you want?
I'll tell you.
It’ll be 100 in advance.
What's wrong?
When you go to a specialist,
doesn't he charge you?
Well, I’m an expert in my field.
Lt's up front or piss off.
I was very busy scratching
my balls before you arrived.
I don't think I have enough.
I have 45.
As a favour to Pepe.
What do you want to know?
- How did it start?
The day I started work
at the theatre...
a series of events began,
silly Little things.
A Light exploded,
and burned the curtain.
The next day, when they
were changing it...
one of the technicians
had a heart attack.
Luckily, he recovered.
But there was an actor...
an asshole, that started
going around saying...
that I was a jinx.
That's how it started.
Someone points you out,
the rumour goes around...
then everyone is saying it,
and you're finished.
But did you feel guilty
when the bad things happened?
Well, it gets into your head.
But things Like that
happen everywhere!
Yes, but when it got
into your head...
did you try to do anything
to stop being a jinx.
I wasn't one!
They made me into one.
The fucked up thing isn't
if you are or aren't a jinx.
Lt's the way they make a
reputation for you.
Then you have to Leave
all the circles you moved in.
And if your family depends
on that, what happens?
They ruin your Life, don't they?
But I screwed them, buddy.
- Do you want to know how?
- Yes.
I made a List of everyone
who touched themselves...
when I walked past,
and I started to call them up.
Hi, Cacho, how are you?
Lt's Humberto, from the theatre...
the jinx that has everyone
touching themselves...
every time I walk by.
Do you remember me?
That's great.
Because I remember you.
I’m always thinking of you.
And I was calling to say...
I hope you have a good week,
without any problems.
I'll be calling you forever.
Every Sunday to say good Luck...
every birthday to wish
you many more...
every opening you have,
to say: "break a Leg".
I’m always going to call you
to wish you the best.
Bye. Until next Sunday.
That's how I started.
One by one.
They were shitting themselves.
Actors, you know.
After 3 weeks of phone calls,
I went up to each one of them...
and said, "Lf you don't want
me to call every Sunday...
for the rest of your Life,
take down this account number...
and put in 100 pesos every month,
which is the minimum...
for having ruined my Life
by humiliating me...
and closing all the doors
to the job I Loved doing...
you son of a bitch.
- And? - I make 4000 a month,
without moving a finger.
Now, everyone who fucked me,
is working for me.
But you didn't come here to
prepare a character.
Why are you here?
Because...
I’m a jinx too.
And I’d Like to know what
to do to make it stop.
What do you expect from me?
Diet tips?
So you're a jinx.
Fuck me.
Two colleagues, face to face.
So you really are a jinx.
Yes, I’m terrible, buddy.
There aren't many of us,
and I understand you...
because you end up constantly
questioning yourself.
Everyone Leaves you.
I just have my mother Left.
Take this. How am L
going to charge you?
I think I'll raise
the installments next month.
Prices have gone up so much.
And I always wanted a Mercedes.
I’m saving for a used one.
Those fuckers screwed me
so much...
I’m going to make them all
pay for the Mercedes.
- Do you want to know more
about this? - Yes.
The guys get together once
a week. Why don't you come?
What guys?
- "Skinny thing. "
- Nice to meet you.
- "Magic Hands. "
- Hello.
- "José Wiggy. "
- Nice to meet you.
- This is "the Sergeant".
- And "Little Ears".
- Hi.
I once shook hands with a
former president, at an event...
and the next day,
inflation began to rise.
Don't remind us!
Welcome pal!
Here you’ll
feel supported, Loved...
and even proud
of your condition...
because this is an
iron-strong brotherhood.
- Isn’t that right, Wiggy.
- Of course it is! Welcome pal!
I’d Like to make a toast
to the memory of our hero.
No, no!
Please...
You know he was Like a
father to us.
What's wrong, man?
After everything that "Christ"
went through!
Or are we going to forget him too?
His name deserves to be spoken,
even if only now and then.
- Remember what happened Last time.
- He's right...
Lf you all won't drink
to him, then I will.
To the memory of
my dear friend, comrade...
and the founder of this
wonderful brotherhood.
He taught us to walk
with dignity and pride.
To the memory of our dear
Elbio Di NapoLi.
I told you!
I told you, asshole!
Don't say his name!
Idiot!
BOOKS
In my essay on luck...
I claim that mankind is divided
into two main groups.
Those with good
luck and those with bad luck.
We pass from one group to another
without realizing it...
not even being aware of it...
until luck, good or bad,
touches us clearly.
These shifts happen
all the time...
because the system tends
towards equilibrium.
For every lucky person,
there is an unlucky person...
and vice-versa.
Just as electrons jump
from atom to atom...
while searching for
a nucleus to orbit...
people are also shifting from
one group to the other.
Let us take an example.
We are in an airport,
anywhere in the world.
Mr. A misses his family badly,
and arrives at the airport...
wishing to travel immediately,
so as to see them.
He gets the last seat
on the flight.
Mr. A now finds himself
in the lucky group...
being able to now
satisfy his desire.
Mr. B, just like Mr. A, wants
to travel to the same place...
as he has been offered a highly
lucrative business opportunity.
He thus also finds himself
in the lucky group.
But he must arrive today
or the chance will be lost.
Mr. B arrives just after Mr. A.
Unable to get a seat on the flight
and on the point of losing
his business opportunity...
Mr. B leaves the lucky group
to move into the unlucky group...
as the system balances itself.
Mr. B's only chance is the stand-by
list he put his name on...
in the hope
of getting the flight.
About to board, Mr. A begins
to feel sharp stomach pains...
due to the rush with which
he ate his sandwich of ham...
cheese, peppers,
guacamole, egg and mayonnaise.
Mr. B's luck has changed again.
He will soon find out...
he has moved from the unlucky group
to the lucky one once more...
as Mr. A's condition is so
severe, that he is unable...
to leave the toilet in time
to catch his flight...
finding himself once more
in the unlucky group.
Mr. B is delighted.
He will now be able to seal
his million dollar deal.
In the take-off,
a fire in the engine...
causes a fatal accident.
Mr. B, who had been
in the lucky group...
is now once again
among the unlucky...
for he has not only lost
his business deal...
but also his life,
in the accident.
Meanwhile, Mr. A,
still seriously ill...
moves from having bad luck at
having lost his flight...
to having good luck again,
having remained alive...
although, unaware of the events,
he continues to curse his luck.
This is a crude example,
with tragic consequences...
but this is how things
happen all the time...
regardless of the scale
of the events...
and mostly, we don't even
realize what is happening.
Those whose Lives are
invariably dominated...
by good or bad Luck are
considered to be extreme cases.
An extreme person identifies
himself...
with one group or the other.
If I am unlucky and believe
myself to be so...
I tend be more and more so.
One example is someone we
associate with bad Luck...
whom we avoid even naming,
Labeling him as a jinx.
This condition can be
innate or hereditary.
This is called,
"extreme inheritance. "
For example: Lf an extreme
person dies, the inheritance...
may pass on to anyone, but
the most susceptible people...
are those who share an emotional
bond with the subject when he dies.
- Can one voluntarily change from
one group to the other? - Yes.
Lf the individual manages to
invert the polarity...
of his electrical charge.
See illustration.
Human electrical
polarity converter.
An electrical charge can
alter our frequency...
and induce a shift from
one group to another.
Laurencio?
- Guillermo.
- Nice to meet you.
I understand the
"master" bit.
I wanted you to explain
the "magic" involved.
- So you got the bug then...
- Yes. - Why?
I want to Learn to dance tango.
And why today and not Last year
or in two months' time?
Actually, I want to Learn
the tango to get a woman.
I Like it better now.
I went to a club. She was waiting
for me to ask her to dance...
but I didn't because
I can't dance tango.
I ended up just
standing there.
Tell me.
Do you force or flow?
Do you make things happen
or just go with the flow?
I just know I have
to Learn the tango.
I don't know her,
I don't know who she is...
but if I don't Learn how,
I won't do anything.
I think it's already happened.
You and her are already together,
or you will never be.
Do you follow me?
I dance all day every Sunday.
I’m in here all day.
I have no idea what goes on in the
world outside. I don't know.
At night, I watch the replay of
the football game on TV.
But for me, it's as if
it were a Live broadcast.
So I get happy,
get sad, get excited...
and when the ball goes up
in the air, well, it's a goal.
However, the ball will Land where
it has to, and nowhere else.
Why?
Because it has already happened.
But since I’m unaware of that,
I think it's happening at the time.
Time is difficult to understand.
I think we fool ourselves thinking
Life is a Live event.
But I think it's actually a replay.
That woman and you are
already together...
or you won't ever be together.
Now you have to Learn to dance
a Little and go find out.
There's the magic.
Technically, it's about
openings and changes.
Dancing tango is Like walking
with a woman stuck to your chest.
Hold her. Hold her, go on.
Put your arm around her waist.
Take a step. Move away.
No, don't Look down.
Always keep your head up.
That's it. You did that by
yourself!
You're already correcting yourself.
That's a good start.
You flow Guille!
Very good!
Felipe...
Guillermo.
I had an idea for the old man.
We can bring him a placebo.
I know.
We’ll give him some
baking powder or something...
and tell him it's cocaine.
No, he won't be able to tell
the difference.
He won't notice, trust me.
OK, I'll do it, but
both of us should go.
Fine.
Good bye.
- I’m sorry, I slept in.
- Lt's all right.
Know what?
I’m sorry about the scene
I made the other night.
I’m sorry about the one I made.
L...
Do you really think you're a jinx?
No, I was a bit out of it
the other day.
Lf you want, we could go
for a drink sometime.
- Lt's been such a Long time.
- Yes.
- I saw you Last year.
- Where?
- I went to see you in the theatre.
- Really?
- You were doing Shakespeare.
- A Midsummer Night's Dream.
- You were brilliant.
- Thanks.
Hello...
- How are you feeling?
- Fine.
Tell me. Ls it day or night?
Lt's daytime, Dad.
Do you know if the board
confirmed the figures?
Yes, they did.
Dad, we got what you wanted.
Do you remember?
That thing, to make the Little 25
watt Lights Look Like 60 watts?
Oh yes! The Little Lights...
What Little Lights...?
With all these crocodiles...
running here and there...
Little Lights...?
I want to speak to my
brothers. My brothers...
You don't have any brothers, Dad.
I have two.
Felipe and Guillermo.
I Love them so much.
Guillermo always comes to
visit me, he's so good...
Felipe... Felipe’s kind of
angry with me...
He's very sensitive.
He's an artist.
He has to be Looked after.
He's a great artist.
Look after him please.
Look after him for me.
My Little brother.
I Love him so much.
Hello, Dad.
How are you?
I know you can't answer me.
I was thinking about that
story the other day.
Maybe it would have been better
to have stayed with the dancer.
You wouldn’t have ended up
a widower when Mum died...
and you would have avoided
that mad woman...
that walked out on you
and Guillermo.
You might have had a happier Life.
At Least happier
than the one you had.
I have some nice memories of those
few years we spent together.
You were always so serious.
I think you were bored
to death back then.
The other day you said
I was an artist.
That I was very sensitive
and needed Looking after.
"My Little brother", you said.
Look what we had to go through
to finally say these things.
You don't know what's
happening to me.
I could have really used your help.
So much Lost time.
I want to admit my mistakes too.
I want to say sorry.
I want to say I Love you.
I Love you very much.
- Excuse me?
- What is it, ma'am?
- What is it?
I’ve come to say hello
to my husband.
OK...
If I told you what just happened,
you'd Lose all respect for me.
I'll sum it up for you.
I Love you very much.
Get the guy in the next room
to tell you the rest.
Lt Looks Like he’ll be
on the same train as you.
How many girlfriends
have you had Guillermo?
Three.
- And what were they Like?
- All different.
- Are you sure?
- Yes.
I think they're always
the same in the end.
We always do the same things
over and over.
Lt's very difficult to avoid
repeating yourself.
You can change the shape
but the pattern is always the same.
Lf you become aware of repetitions,
you can stand aside...
and Let the ball roll past.
Then you have a better chance
of beginning to find...
what is right for you.
Lt's the same with women.
"Repetition" is the opposite
of "evolution".
To evolve, you have to Learn.
- Did you ever have to Learn
something to get a woman? - No.
Lt Looks Like Life has chosen
tango for your evolution.
Buy a good pair of shoes
and you’ll notice the difference.
- Thank you.
- Bye.
Hi, Felipe. It's Alfredo.
I hope it all went well with the
fortune teller and the other thing
There's
an audition for a film...
and they're only looking
for a few people.
I can't go. We have
an extra rehearsal.
So I'm passing it on to you.
All my best, buddy.
- Who is it?
- I’m here for the audition.
Come in.
Hello.
Yes.
Yes, I’m on my way.
- Ma'am.
- Yes, dear.
Hello, Victor, sweetheart.
Do you remember me?
I’m Lina Delponte.
Hello, this is a message
for Mr. Felipe Nugal...
from Europa Films.
We'd like him to get in touch...
to organize an interview. The
number is 47216594. Thank you.
I think we're ready
to go see what happens.
- Do you think so?
- Yes, why not.
You know how to hold her
and then, just walk with her.
That's all you need.
Women don't want some guy
with fancy dance moves.
They want a guy
who can hold them.
Go to the club
and ask her to dance.
Then you’ll know if the ball
is in the back of the net...
or if it went wide.
- Can you hear it?
- What?
Listen to it, because
it will be the Last time.
Come and help me!
We have to take advantage
of this unique situation.
My wife has taken the kids
to her mother's in Chascomús.
- We're alone!
- But wait! Wait!
Where are you taking me?
She didn't want to.
"Are you mad?", she said...
She didn't want to... But
you want to end this too...
I can get it for a grand,
and it’ll be over!
I don't understand any of this
and I have to go!
You can go afterwards,
come to my place first!
A grand! I paid for it!
What a moment!
This is a great moment.
I’ve been waiting for this
for two weeks.
Lt's so beautiful...
- Ls that a real bazooka?
- Thank the Lord.
Lt's a good-Luck-night for some
and a bad-Luck-night for others.
- No, you're mad.
- We're both mad...
if we think it's fair to keep
Letting those bastards interrupt...
our sleep.
Now's the time to sort
this problem out.
The world belongs to whoever
takes the bull by the horns.
- When was the Last time you slept?
- Months ago.
You are going to sleep tonight.
Let's do it now,
or I'll chicken out too.
Do you know how to use it?
I got it from an ex-army guy,
he wrote me down the instructions.
He said it was easy.
And if soldiers all over the world
use them, it can't be so hard.
Take out to use.
Open rear end.
Extend tube.
Load explosives
into the tube.
Read it for me.
Hold the bottom half
of the tube...
and Line up the target
with the upper end.
Come here.
Come here!
- Are there any people around?
- No, there's no-one.
Now you’ll get it,
you son of a bitch!
Guille.
- Hi.
I missed you a Lot.
Guillermo, Alfonzo didn't
mean anything. Lt's over.
I think if we want to,
we can fix things up.
Why don't we start
over again, period.
Hello. I’m here
for an interview with...
- You're Felipe.
- Yes.
I recognized you from
the audition tapes.
I’m Marcia... Mark's assistant.
Follow me.
- Hi, I’m Mark Johnson.
- Felipe NugaL.
Have you been doing this for Long?
Quite a while.
I’m not well-known.
I haven't done television.
Lots of theatre work.
You had a great audition.
The film is a co-production
between the USA and France.
Lt's a fairly ambitious project.
And the script...
Lt's one of the best scripts
I’ve ever read.
Felipe...
Are you working in theatre?
Or doing anything that would
stop you traveling?
- No, I was doing Othello but...
- That's great!
- You're ready to sign then!
- Yes.
The idea is to film in
Locations around Europe...
and the actors are Robert
Redford, Gerard Depardieu...
Uma Thurman, Winona Ryder,
Jack Nicholson...
And you.
Lf you want to, of course.
Jack Nicholson. Well...
Take this and start reading.
Your character is Juan.
Mark, Jack Nicholson
is on line 4.
It's true.
Luck changes all the time.
Every decision we take, every
intention behind each action...
is a magical movement
in the universe.
A twist of fate that
places us in one group...
or in the other.
What's important is
what each of us does...
to find our own destiny.
Jack Nicholson says hello.
The old sea dog!
Subpack por Snoop...
Ripeados por Rekcah2002
www.clan-sudamerica.com.ar