It's late.
I'll just finish this reel...
- Shall I close it?
- Yes.
THE THREE WISHES
If the shuttle was included,
why did you say no?
Are you tired?
So why did you stay up so long?
It's very nice.
Yes, better than I'd expected.
Actually, I love it.
Breakfast from 7 to 10,
lunch from 12 to 2.
Walking tour 3 p.m.,
City tour 10, 12, 2 o'clock...
Tea 5 to 7, dinner 8 to 11.
Hurry up with that stuff
or we'll miss lunch.
Excuse me.
- Thank you.
- Thanks.
- Fancy a walk?
- OK, let's go.
Hats, wraparounds,
hats... Hello there.
- How are things?
- Fine.
Hats, wraparounds, would you like
to see anything?
- Yes, this one?
- Yes, certainly.
- Thank you.
- Not at all.
It's lovely...
And this one?
That really suits you, madam.
Will you take it?
You ought to know...
that I don't make love
to older women.
It's a joke...
That really suits you, madam.
Will you take it?
That's enough.
If I decide to commit suicide,
it'll be on a beach at night...
or during the day, I don't know.
During the day...
I'd lie down in the sun, face up,
nice and quiet...
But a woman would appear
to rescue you...
I don't think so...
Enough.
Will you shut up?
Stop it, Victoria...
- Stop it!
- What's up, Pablo? What's wrong?
- I'm feeling dizzy.
- Ah, yes?
Yes.
Well, just say:
"Vicky, I'm feeling dizzy",
but don't shout at me...
Have you gone crazy?
Answer me, Pablo, have you gone mad?
Pablo...
Agustina, how are you?
Are you well?
I'm really pleased.
Yes...
Very well...
Alright...
No, mum's at the coast and...
I'm looking at some paintings
somewhere...
Yes, of course, certainly...
Look, I'll call you back
in a while, OK?
A big kiss to you,
a big kiss.
I love you too.
Bye.
Ana?
Hello.
What are you doing here?
- Cigarette?
- No, thanks.
So... what are you doing here?
I'm spending a few days meditating...
In fact...
I left my husband yesterday.
I was married for almost ten years.
And after giving it lots of thought
I made the decision...
and here I am...
You separated yesterday?
Yes.
But why?
I don't know.
We need to stop and think...
sometimes.
Like when you wake up one morning
and something's bugging you...
and that something is your partner.
That's when you need
to stop and think...
The tide's coming in,
shall we move back?
A friend once said something
very wise.
She compared Diego, her partner,
to Nacho,
a guy she'd met somewhere...
We shouldn't compare, but in this
case it's valid...
She said:
- Diego's fallen asleep in the armchair.
- Here?
Yes... She thought:
That idiot Diego's
fallen asleep in the armchair again.
But then Nacho falls asleep in the
same armchair,
and she thinks: How cute Nacho looks
asleep in the armchair...
That's how it is.
Perhaps your friend was a bore and
the guys just fell asleep.
No. I'm not saying it's always
the way but...
some partners are for life
but others aren't.
We just need to realize in time.
Well, perhaps you realized in time.
I don't know. I'm not sure...
- No?
- No...
- Are you married?
- Yes.
Actually my wife will be waiting
for me in the hotel.
Really? Go back, then.
She must be worried.
I don't think so...
- No?
- No...
- Have you got kids?
- No.
- Sorry, I was curious.
- That's fine. I didn't want kids.
Why?
Because...
I'll tell you in a minute.
Do you know what?
I left my phone in the bar
where I had lunch...
It's near here. Can I ask you
to watch my stuff,
- and I'll be back in five minutes...
- I'll go with you.
There's no need. I'll leave my bag
with you and I'll be right back.
- I want to go with you.
- I'll leave my things here.
- And if you don't come back?
- I'll be back.
I'm coming with you.
It's not like I didn't want kids.
At first I just wanted to enjoy
being with my partner.
Then I started working hard...
and couldn't find the right time.
Then when I stopped
looking for excuses,
I realized I couldn't imagine Juan
as the father of my kids.
It's strange because I reckon
he'd be an excellent father,
but I just didn't want
kids with him.
And in that process
you went through,
did you imagine any particular
father for your children?
- No.
- No?
But I should start trying
to imagine it,
because I don't have so many years
left for existential matters...
You do... four, five...
- And you?
- What?
Have you got kids?
One daughter...
How odd.
I could never see you as a father.
- What's he playing?
- I don't know...
Shall we go?
So why could you never see me
as a father?
I don't know.
- How old is she?
- Six.
Agustina's her name. She's staying
with her grandparents...
Are you happy with your wife?
Am I happy with my wife?
- I don't know.
- No?
No, no.
We've been together for a long time,
and have many things in common...
But I don't know...
When I wake up in the morning and
see her beside me in bed,
I'm neither happy nor sad...
You haven't answered my question.
Do you think there is a
precise moment in time...
when you can say:
From now on...
I don't love that woman and I don't
enjoy doing what I used to with her.
I don't think so.
I don't mean a precise moment
of infidelity.
No, it's a bit like what
you were just saying.
Life follows its course,
and one day you realize...
that what you liked
about the woman you loved,
are the things that most annoy you
or bother you...
Shall we go on?
It's a little like what happens
with your eyesight.
It hasn't happened to me but people
say that one day you begin...
to lose your eyesight, right?
They say that happens
at a precise moment in time.
You go to a restaurant,
they give you a menu,
but you have to move it around
in order to see it properly, right?
If somebody could tell you when...
I'm serious. What's so funny?
It's...
I'm laughing because I've just
remembered something daft,
- shall I tell you?
- OK.
Not long ago my ex started wearing
glasses but couldn't accept it.
So I could be sitting at home
reading or something,
and I'd hear in the background:
"Where the hell did I leave my glasses?"
It was his sort of stock phrase...
I'll be there soon... honest.
Go on, I interrupted you.
What were you saying?
Where was I?
Oh, yes.
We all think that at one magical
moment you'll fall in love,
and you'll want to spend all
your life with that person.
What I wanted to know was:
Is there also an exact moment...
when that stops for ever?
It's as if...
the relationship crashes,
or you crash...
Like a crash... let me think
about that...
Alright, a crash,
but my question is:
Do you crash one day and find that
everything bugs you about them,
or do you crash the day you realize
there are many things that bug you?
- It's very complicated.
- It is.
This is it.
- Will you wait?
- Of course.
I'll be right back.
That's lucky.
You weren't very hopeful.
I was...
OK, where were we?
According to you we were
busy crashing.
You could also ask yourself,
not only if it's a process or if
there's a moment of rupture,
but you could also ask...
if you were ever really happy
with that person,
or if life simply brought
you together. Don't you think?
- Yes, that's different, isn't it?
- Yes...
but doesn't it scare you
to think it?
I don't know... I don't know...
The fact is I don't stop
to think very often.
I don't have the time...
Life is what happens and
I get carried along...
At times I feel very tired...
You're in a bad way...
- Shall we go?
- Yes.
I'd imagined so many chance meetings
with you,
but never like this.
How then?
With you swearing a lot at me?
Yes, a lot.
This is a short cut...
- I dreamt about you several times...
- Oh, yes?
Yes, several...
In one particular dream...
shall I tell you?
Go on.
I was trying to contact you
by phone,
and as I dialed your number
the phone disintegrated.
And there was an elderly woman
helping me,
by bringing the missing keys
I needed to dial your number.
But I still couldn't contact you...
It's amazing what happens in dreams,
like when you dream about
somebody who's dead,
but it's so real that you wake up
thinking they're still alive.
I used to dream about you too.
They were sort of weird
recurring dreams,
but they always ended in the
same maze with glass walls,
and I'd try to touch you or
cry out to you,
but my voice wouldn't come.
- I'm going for a swim.
- It's cold.
No, it's not.
I'll come with you then.
OK.
- You're still the same...
- Don't you believe it.
After you fucked things up for me,
I changed... a lot...
- So that's for me?
- Yes.
Stop it, put me down...
- Didn't you want a swim?
- You go in first.
- Are you sure?
- Yes.
- Lf I freeze it's your fault.
- Alright.
Go on in.
- You're so beautiful...
- And 12 years older.
You're much more beautiful
now, really...
You have a magical quality, unreal.
Because I'm like an apparition
here on the beach.
No, I mean it.
You have an expression I'd never seen
before. I love looking at you...
Whenever I thought of you
I used to spit poison.
- Ana?
- What?
- I have to go.
I have to go. I love being here with you
but I have to go, really.
- But we can meet tomorrow.
- No, don't bother.
- No, we can meet.
- It's OK, no problem. Don't worry.
- Pablo, go away, it's alright.
- Listen...
- Listen, listen...
- Just go.
- Everything's OK, Pablo. No problem.
- Listen.
I want to see you tomorrow, please.
Here on the beach at five o'clock?
- Yes?
- Yes.
Tomorrow at five, here?
I'll be waiting.
I ordered a bottle
of well chilled white wine,
but you brought a bottle which was
practically warm. So listen to me,
bring me a very cold bottle with a
bucket of ice, if you'd be so kind?
- Yes.
- Thank you very much.
Haven't you seen all the tables she has
to wait on? It's not her fault.
It's not my fault though, is it?
You don't drink white wine anyway
so keep out of this.
So you could have ordered
something for both of us.
Victoria, did I or didn't I ask you
what you wanted to drink?
Yes, you asked me but you'd
already ordered the white wine.
What's up with you? You went crazy on
the beach, you were rude to me,
and you get upset because I'm drinking
white wine. What's wrong?
You were the one
who got angry and left the beach.
You insulted me.
- Lower your voice.
- You insulted me, Victoria.
My wife thinks I can't have white wine
so forget it. What do you want?
Nothing, nothing at all.
The white's fine, leave it.
Take it away...
Leave it... leave it.
Did you have to tell the waitress
what bothers me and what doesn't?
Look, if I have to go through all that,
we'd be here for hours, Victoria.
I'm going to bed.
Congratulations.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you very much.
- Thanks.
That's very kind.
Hello?
Hello, love. How are you?
Thank you so much.
You're up very late.
Go on, off to bed with you.
Yes, darling, we'll talk tomorrow...
Go on then. No, don't put her on.
Me too, darling. A big kiss.
Hello? Thank you very much.
Are you coping OK with Agus?
Yes, lovely...
Great...
It's lovely, it really is.
Yes, lots of love. Bye.
Blow...
Happy birthday, Victoria.
Hang on...
Let me close the door...
- I don't know if I can walk.
- Yes, you can.
We'll just go over to the bed.
We'll be thrown out.
- What's this?
- Balloons, did you bring them?
- No.
- No? Champagne.
- Hang on.
- They're lovely!
- Give me another one.
- No, here, give it to me.
Cheers, happy birthday
and may you be very happy.
I haven't got an ashtray.
- Want some?
- Yeah...
- Are you sure?
- Very.
This is for me.
- Want some?
- No, no more.
- Want a little?
- I don't want any more.
Have some with me.
I want some more.
Pass me your glass
Stop it.
- Let's drink to that!
- To life!
- To life as single girls!
- What?
I'd die if I wasn't able to be with a
guy just once a week.
Is that why you raped your ex?
You're great! You really make me feel
much better.
I had a date the other day,
but the guy stood me up.
I was looking gorgeous when Carlos
turned up to leave the kids.
Well, we put them to bed
and things took their course...
Give me that...
And again...
You did quite well even at forty...
really well.
Stop it!
Stop it! What are you doing?
One, two, three, four, up!
One, two, three, four, both arms!
One, two, three, four, to the side!
One, two, three, four, and turn!
One, two, three, four.
You knew we'd lost each other...
- Victoria, I'm talking to you.
- I'm listening, Pablo.
You knew we'd lost each other,
so why didn't you answer the phone?
- We hadn't lost each other.
- We'd lost each other.
I stopped to look at some stuff and when
I got to the corner you'd gone.
And you knew we had to return
the bikes, didn't you?
I came to the hotel to return mine
and thought you'd do the same.
But you should have been
more alert, Victoria.
Alright, I'm sorry.
I thought you'd forgotten the time
once again.
That's Julián coming in over there.
- I thought he'd look different.
- Really? What like?
I don't know, just different.
Are you going to say hello?
I don't think so...
Vicky!
Hello, Julián!
I can't believe it...
You haven't changed a bit.
No! I've changed.
Time passes and isn't very kind...
- Are you talking about me?
- Not at all.
- You're not very kind.
- No, you look good.
- It's been ages!
- Hasn't it!
Let me introduce my husband.
Pablo, Julián. Julián, Pablo.
- Hello, pleased to meet you.
- How do you do?
- Congratulations on the lovely hotel.
- Yes, it's beautiful.
- Are you having a good time?
- Great.
- Did you see the show last night?
- Yes.
Yes, it was lovely.
Are you staying for the release of
balloons on the beach tonight?
- No, we have to be at the port at 10.
- What a shame! It's great!
- Really?
- Yes...
- What are you drinking? Coffee?
- Yes.
Let me invite you to try some vodkas.
It's our speciality.
- No, no, that's fine.
- I'll be right back!
- Hadn't you decided not to say hello?
- He said hello to me.
Drinking vodka at this time in the
afternoon is absurd.
- So what do you want me to do?
- Keep it short because I want to go.
A few months ago, Alejandra Méndez
told me you'd opened this hotel.
- Do you remember Alejandra?
- Yes, she was here for a few days.
So when Pablo invited me to Colonia
and I saw the hotel leaflet,
- I guessed it was yours.
- Sorry, when did you arrive?
- Yesterday?
- Yesterday.
Yesterday? And you were
going to leave without saying hello?
No, I didn't want to bother you...
If I happened to see you, fine...
So, if you happened to see me...
Thanks.
Pablo, start with this cherry-flavoured
one. It's not too strong.
Vicky, this one's made from wheat,
it's smoother.
And this one's for me.
Do you live here?
My house is three blocks away, but I
spend most of the day in the hotel.
Except Mondays, which is my day off.
I escape from the world
and go fishing all day.
Wonderful!
- Do you like fishing?
- No, I don't actually...
Tell me about yourself. How's life
treated you? How's the singing?
- No. Totally forgotten.
- I don't believe it, Vicky.
You were going to be
the famous one in the class.
- No, I took up design...
- Good!
Actually she copies designs
from old films.
I get my inspiration from old films.
- Do you have a brand name?
- No, not yet.
- Look, I designed this T-shirt.
- Really? What is it? Let's see.
- Do you like it?
- I love it.
- And what went wrong here?
- You're wicked, Vicky.
You used to have beautiful curls.
- Well, I'll be 40 in a few months.
- Yes, you were one of the youngest.
Right... And your birthday's...
don't tell me...
- 9th March.
- The 10th. You were close.
That's today, Vicky...
But Miss Fernández Carrizo...
Happy birthday! What an honour
that you're celebrating it here!
Thanks. Fernández Carrizo?
I'd forgotten I used to be Carrizo.
I'm only Fernández now.
I can recite the whole register:
Agostini, Belardi, Cáceres,
Caseros, Cohen, Epstein,
Fernández Carrizo...
Let's drink to that...
Pablo, Vicky.
- Many happy returns.
- Thanks.
- Matienzo 2571.
- No, that's too much.
- I can't believe you remember that.
- As if I could forget.
We used to have all our parties
at her place...
Your parents were angels. I don't know
what they're like as in-laws...
- I can't complain.
- Do they still have that house?
No, they sold it. It was demolished
a few years ago,
and they built a hideous tower block
with a swimming pool.
- What a shame! How old was it?
- It must've been built in 1920...
Pablo, sorry, you can't smoke here.
You're not angry, are you?
No, not at all. Come on.
I remember the patio, the lights,
the ombú tree...
By that ombú I told
Adriana Barrios I loved her,
on your 13th or 14th.
Then we had the 5th year party to raise
money for the Bariloche trip.
How could I forget?
"Invite your mates and get them
to invite their mates..."
And as a result, they burnt
the armchairs with cigarettes,
and stole my dad's CD collection.
- No, did CDs exist then?
- No, I suppose they were cassettes.
Well, they stole some sort of music.
I got into deep shit!
- Victoria, I'm going out for a smoke.
- No, let's go.
No, stay and talk. I'll have a smoke
and I'll be back, OK?
- How long have you been married?
- Eight years.
Eight years?
- And you?
- What?
- Are you in a relationship?
- Yes.
- Yes? Tell me more...
- No, one question each.
- No.
- Yes, let's see.
- Is it true you no longer sing?
- It's true.
And... is eight years a long time?
That was two questions.
It's my turn.
Hold it.
Leave your hand right there.
This is Vicky's hand.
Her whole being is reflected there,
her intelligence, her character,
her strength and weakness...
Let go.
Your coffee's getting cold.
Do you want it?
No, thanks.
What was that film where Juliette
Binoche played with a sugar lump?
I don't know.
Yes, a film in which she was married
to a musician,
and they crashed the car into a tree...
- And she was left completely alone.
- I don't remember.
- But you really liked it.
- You don't remember.
- I'm telling you I don't remember.
Why didn't you take up cinema
if you're so fond of films...
instead of copying trash all your life?
Do you know what, Pablo?
I'm a little tired.
- Sorry, I didn't mean that.
- No...
- Please don't leave.
- No, I want to go back to the hotel.
- Stay.
- Leave me alone, let me go.
- Let's go to the bullring.
- No.
- You wanted to go.
- No, I want to go back, I want a bath,
to pack... and to have
some peace and quiet...
- I want to be alone for a while.
- No, listen, let's do this...
Go to the room, have a bath,
get changed... look at me,
and we meet at the bullring
in an hour.
Alright?
Hey, forgive me, please.
Do you forgive me?
Sorry.
You know what, Pablo?
I don't understand you.
You wanted to meet,
so I came and waited.
- I know, sorry.
- Honestly...
I'm sorry.
Shall we go back to the beach?
Yeah?
I'd rather have a coffee.
What was your first night
of freedom like?
- Very good.
- Good?
Yes, very good.
A party in the hotel, music, booze...
- Men, sex?
- No, if only...
A night to remember. Right?
What I will always remember will be
my first afternoon of freedom.
Me too.
Do you miss him?
No, I don't think so.
Perhaps I miss being with someone...
Last night when I went down
to the party in the hotel alone,
it was weird, neither good nor bad...
Any regrets?
Hello. I'll have an orange
and peach shake, please.
- Didn't you want a coffee?
- They make good shakes here.
Coffee for me.
Regrets?
No. It was very hard,
I felt something here...
that grew and grew every day.
- Poor guy, if he could hear you now...
- No...
He's very sweet.
I was the one who couldn't cope...
I know the feeling.
Why, is your wife sweet too?
Yes.
Does that make you jealous?
I don't like my ex-partners
falling in love with other women.
Your ex-partners?
Now that's interesting.
- Do you have many?
- Are you jealous?
Very.
- So?
- What?
- Many or a few?
- What difference does it make?
None. I’m just curious.
A few...
After you walked out, or left me...
- or what shall we say?
- No problem.
Don't tell me
if you don't want to no.
- Alright, I won't.
- No problem.
- You know something?
- What?
- You're dying to tell me.
- You're dying to know.
Thanks.
No, I'll have it, thank you.
It was hard for me
to go steady with a guy.
It was as if in each relationship
I wanted to get one back on you.
Do you know who I went out with
soon after you left me?
No, who with?
With Santiago.
- Are you serious? With Santiago?
- Yes.
Well, well...
Bastard.
He never said a word about it.
I was very depressed.
What happened?
Nothing. After two months I'd had
enough. He was very stupid.
I did it to spite you,
but you never found out, so...
- He wasn't that stupid...
- He was a bore.
Waiter, here's the money...
If you're in a hurry and have to go,
just go.
I want to go back to the beach
for a little air...
Shall we go?
This is a sort of déjà vu.
How did you meet your ex?
He was a teacher at the university.
Did you continue at the faculty...
Yes, I graduated, won awards...
You missed out
on a very famous publicist.
Really?
No, not famous, but I'm doing OK...
can't complain...
You didn't think I'd go on, did you?
Quite honestly...
- No.
- I guessed...
And you?
I remember the party
your dad threw when you graduated...
You do? Me too.
Poor guy, he had great hopes.
He'd already imagined what and where
my first building would be,
- how many floors it'd have...
- And...?
- I never practiced
- No?
No, no, no.
The problem with my dad came then...
and I had to take charge of the factory,
at first I thought it wouldn't be
for long but...
I'm still there...
I never thanked you
for coming over that day.
I didn't do it for you...
- Were you already seeing Santiago?
- No.
Amazing, isn't it?
After those months with Santiago...
I heard nothing more of you, as if the
earth had swallowed you up.
Amazing because in two years
I didn't move or change my number...
Well, in the street, a cinema...
Don't you find there are people you
always meet and others never?
Yeah, it happens.
There are people
I never want to meet...
and I see them all the time...
There's a supplier at the factory...
Watch it!
Hang on...
Do you still argue with people?
Why do you ask?
You used to be... how can I say...
temperamental...
Over time the defects get better or
worse. They're never the same.
- Your answer?
- What do you think?
I don't think. I'm asking you.
So I was temperamental?
And what were you like?
Gorgeous.
And what about now?
What do you think?
I used to like you, a lot,
but now I really like you...
- You owe me something from yesterday.
- What?
- You left me swimming by myself.
- And that's why you won't kiss me?
Let's go for a dip?
Are you coming for a swim?
- No, let's stay here...
- Come on...
No, let's stay here... please...
- Why, do you have to leave?
- No, but let's stay here...
Come for a swim.
Coming?
No, you go, I'll wait here, OK?
Are you alright?
You're OK, aren't you?
Are you alone?
Victoria!
We shouldn't have come.
I think it was very important for us...
Otherwise it would have taken us much
longer to make a decision.
You're the one who's making it.
More tea?
Ten, nine, eight,
seven, six, five, four,
three, two, one...
Go!
Subtitle Ripped and Corrected by PANGI
www.clan-sudamerica.net