Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
THE HOLY GIRL
Look,
look at the extreme vileness
that is singing like this
to you today.
What is it, Lord,
you want of me?
Give me wealth
or poverty.
Give consolation...
Who is it?
... or despair.
Grant me hell
or grant me heaven...
The woman at the photocopy store.
... radiant sun,
for I have given in to you,
for I have given in to you.
She's short of air.
She doesn't know how to breathe.
It's bad for
the blood supply to the brain.
Corridor number 11.
Listen carefully.
Dr. Gutiérrez,
Dr. Vesalio, Dr. Olaz? Bal
and Dr. Jano, please follow me
along here to your left.
Everyone else,
follow the maid.
- Doctor, this is your corridor.
- Of course.
Is it the one behind?
No, it's this pipe here.
Put on your shoes!
But nothing's happening.
Dr. Jano,
this way, please.
We did some renovations,
but that was a while ago.
You can
listen to music on this.
Hello, how are you?
I'll leave you the numbers
of the taxi service
for going into the center,
You're there in 15 minutes.
Massages, until 7:00,
8:00 or 9:00,
the masseuse is there.
But you can also go later.
Carlitos, my old friend!
- How are you?
- Fine, and you?
I'll see you later.
No, I told Dr. Vesalio
that you were sleeping
in this room.
In the other bed, of course.
I didn't know...
- You left this downstairs.
- Thank you, girls.
And forgive me.
They're the girls from Theriaca,
from the lab.
Girls! Just a second.
It's some perfume.
Your room will be free tomorrow.
The important thing is always
to be alert for God's call.
God calls us
and that is a vocation.
He calls us to save
and to be saved.
And that is the only meaning
our existence should have.
What do I have to do?
What is my role in the Divine Plan?
Is it this? Is it that?
What matters is to be
alert for the call
and not lose hope.
- What's that?
- It's coming from the street.
But what is the call like?
Is it something
you'll recognize?
Like a voice in the night?
But I get really scared
at night
and if I feel that
a voice is calling me
I'll think it's the Devil.
- Don't be silly.
- And the fear of God?
That something
completely different.
You can't confuse
ugliness with beauty,
or happiness with horror.
What if He asks me
to kill someone,
like He did with Abraham?
I'd think it was the Devil.
Don't compare yourself
to people in the Bible.
Before you go, we must
organize the photocopies.
Who's going to make them?
The photocopies...
- You've got the material?
- And the money.
I didn't bring any material
but I heard a story
that explains about a vocation.
It's a bit horrific.
- Is it short?
- No, it's quite long.
Why is it horrific?
Yesterday she was kissing a man
much older than her.
The same one as before,
with the hairy knuckles.
She couldn't breathe.
- He had his tongue down her throat.
- Girls, I have to go.
Really.
She never kissed
the other guy like that.
And he kept groping her.
She was shaking,
like she had epilepsy.
What can I have?
Anything tasty left?
- An escalope with something light?
- A salad?
A fried egg.
Go on.
It's a craving.
Manuel rang.
They're expecting twins.
He told me to tell you.
Twins...
Are they boys?
How could he know
if they're boys?
She isn't even
two months pregnant.
It's too early to tell,
Helenita.
Here, Florinda,
take this and check it.
My hair is so dry.
You shouldn't use
the hotel shampoo too often.
It's terrible.
It's all we can get
with the budget we have.
What should I do?
Do I call
and congratulate him?
Or should I wait
until he tells me himself?
Mirta...
What should I do?
Do I call and congratulate him
or wait for him to tell me?
He asked me to tell you,
so he knows that you know.
Don't get involved
in my affairs.
I'll eat something and go.
This room is freezing.
It's like a grave.
Don't say that,
you're scaring me.
You're freezing.
Don't say that.
Did you know you're going
to have twin stepbrothers?
Amalia...
- Are you listening?
- Don't say "stepbrothers", mom.
Who told you?
Your dad told Mirta.
Did you know?
See what he's like?
I'm always the last to hear.
There'll be a lot
of interesting lectures,
and several seminars.
Who's that?
One of the speakers.
The hotel is full of doctors.
They're attending
a very long congress.
Their hair will be
completely frizzled.
Don't use the hotel shampoo.
- 34?
- What?
I didn't say anything.
Lord, have mercy on us.
Christ, have mercy on us.
Christ, hear us.
Christ, hear us. Heavenly Father,
have mercy on us.
God the Son,
redeemer of the world.
Holy Mary, pray for us.
Holy Mother of God.
Virgin of Virgins,
Mother of the Divine Grace.
Mother most pure, Mother
most chaste, Mother without fault,
Mother most kind,
Mother most admirable,
Mother most wise,
Mother of the Creator,
Virgin most powerful,
Virgin most merciful,
Virgin most faithful,
Mirror of Justice,
Throne of eternal wisdom,
Cause of our joy,
Spiritual vessel,
Vessel of grace,
Vessel of true devotion,
Mystical Rose, Tower of David,
Tower of Ivory...
Gate of heaven,
Star of the morning,
Health of the sick,
Refuge of sinners,
Comfort of the afflicted.
Queen of the Angels,
Queen of the Patriarchs,
Queen of the Prophets,
Queen of the Apostles...
Why must you memorize that?
Is there nothing more useful to do?
Amalia?
I'm talking to you.
Amalia!
Don't shout.
I learned it because I like it.
Lamb of God, who takes away
the sins of the world, forgive us.
Don't speak to me like that!
Good evening, Dr. Jano.
See you tomorrow.
Would you like a book of Spanish
ballads? They're really long.
"A-hunting goes the master,
as he always does,
the hounds are weary...
The hounds are weary..."
What time is it?
Aren't you wiped out?
Mom!
What are you doing?
My key...
I can't find my key.
I can't get into my room.
Go and brush your teeth.
Why are you up so late?
I was watching a beautiful film.
I can't sleep anyway.
I can't believe Manuel didn't
tell me about the twins.
I can't believe it.
- Why don't you ask Mirta for a key?
- No, no.
Why not sleep in Amalia's room?
No, I'll lie down here
with you and Amalia.
I'd prefer that.
Look at the time.
If I tell Mirta,
she'll scream at me for hours.
Don't let her. I'm sick
of her interfering in my life.
Move over.
Oh, Lord, she's awake!
Sleep.
What a beautiful child!
Just like her mother.
That child, Helena,
is a blessing.
Hello?
Excuse me.
It's a friend.
An excellent idea. We need
a good close for the congress.
I had to share
with a colleague last night.
I'll call you at noon.
Love to the kids.
- Do you know Jano?
- Yes, we've met already.
How are you doing, doctor?
Cuesta wants me
to do a dramatization
to close the congress,
about the doctor-patient
relationship. I love the idea.
I'm going to show the difficulties
of interpretation,
what a good examination entails.
We may have to do
a few hearing tests.
It would have to be a case
that's very well documented
with studies,
and we could contrast it
with the patient's statements.
Yes, of course.
I forgot my shaving cream.
Jano, I'll have to steal yours.
- Well, I must be going...
- No, hang on.
Let's settle this.
It's a great idea.
I saw it done at a congress.
It's very didactic.
What we must find
is a patient
with an interesting problem.
- Thank you.
- I'll come by later.
Look at the time.
My Lady and Mother,
I offer myself to you,
I consecrate to you today
my eyes, my ears, my tongue,
my heart, my whole being,
for I am all yours.
Keep me and protect me
as your own. Amen.
Now!
Two red dots.
They have a yellow rim
and are slightly separated.
Some green lines.
Like rays?
Yes, they gradually disappear.
Things look different.
White seems much whiter.
Do you think a vocation
can be to save
just one person?
It's not much, is it?
Not at all.
It's perfect.
Your hair is so shiny!
Don't cut it.
Do we fit?
Your son?
What a coincidence!
The same school...
I met your kids
at the party for Felipe's kids.
When is it?
They'll pick us up
after the lecture.
Will you give me that?
I have to move Dr. Jano's things.
Hello!
Grandma...
What are you doing here?
Did you see grandma?
- She went to some kind of group.
- A prayer group.
- Did she say when she'd be back?
- In a while.
I've got the photocopies.
But did she say when?
Well, I'm off.
When grandma comes,
tell her that...
I don't want
pre-marital relations.
When will grandma be back?
She's coming later.
No, don't talk to me.
A complete examination
of the upper respiratory tract,
a good rhinoscopy,
a good laryngoscopy.
A proper study means that,
in a good interview,
and generally this is
what's hardest for us,
a good interview
will allow us to identify
all the symptoms and situations
that lead to a diagnosis,
and this should be done
at least twice,
that is, before and after
any medical treatment
or surgical treatment.
Well, that's everything.
Doctor, how was it?
Interesting, a bit long.
The lab people are here.
I have to speak to the director.
You know him quite well,
you can introduce me.
This is Dr. Jano. He and I studied
together. Do you remember?
- No. Hello.
- My sister Helena.
My pleasure.
Yes, I want to hear your lecture.
It should be very interesting.
The relationship
between doctor and patient...
No, that's Dr. Vesalio.
Mine is about
a case of Meniere.
I'll go along anyway,
because I like to attend
all the congresses we organize,
as a listener,
provided there are
no slides of operations.
No, it's mostly statistics.
We're all wiped out
and Sonia broke her shoe.
Weren't you a diver?
Yes.
I was a diver, years ago...
We don't have a cold pool anymore.
It was too expensive.
Now we just have the thermal pool.
But it's no use.
You've got a call.
- Who is it?
- Don Manuel's wife.
- What Manuel?
- Don Manuel.
- Your ex-husband.
- Tell her I'm busy.
- Very well.
One night,
a man was driving a truck
and before he crossed a bridge
a woman appeared,
desperately asking for help.
The woman came up to his window
and said,
"There's been an accident,
a car has fallen into the ditch.
Two people are dead
but there's a baby alive.
Please, call the firemen.
We must save the baby."
The firemen arrived,
they pulled the car out of the ditch
and turned it over.
Look, that's the bridge.
They found a couple
who were dead
but the woman was holding
a baby who was alive.
And the truck driver realized
that it was the same woman
who had asked him for help.
I think it's here.
What's this?
A hand!
Girls, a hand! A hand!
Jose, come on!
Girls, there's a hand!
Amalia, this way!
Jose, come on!
Don't leave me here!
Jose, over here!
Where are you?
Jose, wait for me!
Enemy, I'll not go with you.
I'm going with God.
Girls, those are shots!
Go away, enemy.
I'll not go with you...
Last night I was talking
to one of the doctors.
Very pleasant.
That's him.
You've got a call.
Your ex-husband's wife.
Don't say that.
Tell her I'm not here.
Don't put it through.
Does she want me
to congratulate her?
Just do it,
and get it over with.
I won't, because
no one told me personally.
Maybe she wants to tell you.
Yes,
that she's expecting twins.
Did you meet Dr. Jano?
He's married.
It's impossible
to talk to you, Mirta.
Mom,
some day I'll poison you.
You'll never get a job
as a chef afterwards.
I'm not a cook, mom,
I'm a physiotherapist.
Dry your eye.
And then I saw the Lord who was
cradling an enemy of mine
who was dead
and for whom I had prayed.
He said to me,
"Here is our son.
Who do you love more,
me or our son?"
I answered that I loved
our son more,
that is, I'd rather suffer
in this world to save a soul
than be in heaven
with our Lord."
How's that?
I don't understand it.
- What book is it from?
- It's a photocopy.
But who wrote it?
M. D. V.
17th Century.
Girls,
when you bring material
you must know the source.
Now, read it again.
"One day I was dressed
as Divine Charity
and then I saw the Lord
who was cradling
an enemy of mine
who was dead
and for whom I had prayed.
He said to me,
"Here is our son.
Who do you love more,
me or our son?"
I answered that I loved
our son more,
that is, I'd rather suffer
in this world to save a soul
than be in Heaven
with our Lord."
She'd rather save a man
than be with God, I think.
We'll never make any headway
if you don't collaborate.
We've discussed vocations
for two weeks and got nowhere.
But isn't the Divine Plan
the plan for salvation?
This woman says she'd do
anything to save someone.
You must be willing
to do anything,
even if it scares you,
even if you have to lie.
- Can you lie?
- Apparently.
The mother saved her child
in the accident.
I don't want to hear
that accident story again,
is that clear?
She was talking about my story,
not the accident.
I meant the accident.
Isn't being a mother
a vocation?
There is a lot of material
that can help us think
about our role in God's plan
and help us to be prepared
for the call.
Don't listen to her.
She just wants tongue kisses.
Since she's been
with that guy...
I bet they've had
pre-marital relations.
If you ask her she'll deny it,
but I don't think she can...
Page 177.
"In our lives, there are
also mysterious callings,
more or less clear,
more or less urgent,
that come directly from God
and show each person
his role in the Christian community.
All means are good
in God's hands
for calling us."
That's clear.
God sends us signs,
that's what matters.
They say we look alike.
Who says that?
Dr. Jano?
Jano looks like dad,
before he got sick, don't you think?
He's an attractive man,
isn't he?
He said he was here a few times
as a student.
I should have
kept up my studies.
Why didn't I do that?
Did I give them up
when I got married?
No, long before.
Look at your hands.
A surgeon's hands.
You've got no spots
or anything.
We must stop the kids
running up and down the corridor.
Mirta is worn out.
She's difficult.
Poor Mirta.
She's in a bad way.
Excuse me,
may I spray this?
Who's that?
I don't know, she must be new.
She's pretty.
You have to understand that
this is all Mirta has got.
This is her life.
Because you've got
Amalia,
and I...
You've got me, and Amalia,
and your own children too.
Of course.
I need my children to help me.
When the Chilean woman
took my kids, it really hurt me.
I know that.
You should call your kids,
at least on their birthdays.
What I'm saying is that Mirta,
good or bad,
is a help,
even if it's just so that I can
lie down here for a while
when I don't feel well.
I'm not saying she isn't.
That's invaluable.
Goodbye.
I'll see you tonight.
Thank you.
I was sent some marinated pigeon.
Do you like it?
I certainly do.
Why don't you dine at my table?
You can meet my daughter.
- I don't think you know her.
- No, I don't.
I've been divorced
for several years.
I didn't know.
See you later.
Do it very neatly.
Very neatly,
above the lines.
If it's too faint to read,
look at the book.
- Do it carefully.
- All right!
That maid is filthy!
Do you know
she leaves the laundry sink
full of hairs?
Why do you let her
wash her hair in the sink?
What's the sign, Jose?
What sign are we waiting for?
The other day, she was brushing
her teeth at the kitchen sink.
You have to tell me
things like that.
I can't do everything
in the house!
Did you say anything?
She said you don't let her use
our bathroom.
She's got such a nerve!
They're incredible.
Jose, I think I've got a mission.
How do you know?
Did you get a sign?
Oh, my God!
He's dead,
those are reflex movements.
We have to call an ambulance.
My head is splitting.
Mom,
a man was saved
by a miracle today.
He fell from the second floor
into Josefina's patio
and he wasn't killed.
That's terrible!
- A workman?
- No, a neighbor.
It's all the same.
It's terrible.
It was a miracle he survived.
I don't know what to wear.
What time is it?
Let's see.
I've still got time.
Well, my pretty little girl.
Josefina is going to cut her hair
and donate it to the V irgin's wig.
How awful.
That's her grandma's idea.
There's pigeon for supper
and I told Dr. Jano
to join us for dinner.
Tidy yourself up a bit.
Dr. Jano?
Don't breathe,
you'll get an allergy.
I didn't know what to say,
so I said yes.
But I don't like you
hanging around that hotel all day.
I don't know
why Helena doesn't realize
that her daughter
needs a house, a home.
You can't rear...
Helena was reared in an hotel,
it seems normal to her.
We must have
Turkish blood in the family,
we all like smoking
and Turkish baths.
May I have the shampoo?
And at the same time
she's very kind.
She sent us this box.
Mom, the shampoo!
Here,
leave some in the bath tub.
It's a specialty,
a branch of medicine.
But I forget how it happened.
Maybe because
my mother sang.
Well, my mother loved to sing
and I'd go with her to the doctor
because she'd get hoarse,
very often.
Freddy, I'm ready.
Shall we start?
He's a photographer.
But it didn't arouse
my curiosity at the time.
My daughter sings.
Go and play.
Isn't she having dinner?
No, she'd arranged
to meet a friend.
I thought you were an actress.
Excuse me.
What?
I thought you were an actress.
Helena!
Shall we have a photo taken
with the doctors?
Everyone close together.
Another one.
And smile!
That's it.
Very good.
No...
Oh, yes.
No, I'm not an actresss.
Freddy told us
that you
used to put on plays in the hotel
when you were kids.
I don't know why
I saw you as an actress.
Maybe because of
Esther Williams.
A wonderful swimmer,
but as an actress...
No, we used to put on plays
with the staff.
Everyone used to look at you
in the pool.
I guess
there weren't many girls
who dived from 30 feet
in those days.
- Does your ear hurt?
- No.
The hotel was always a bit remote.
It wasn't easy.
- There were no drama classes.
- It's bothering you.
No, it might be water.
At times, especially in this ear,
I get a kind of whistling,
mostly at night.
Do you fall asleep with the TV on,
or listening to music?
Dr. Vesalio, you'll make her dizzy.
One more time!
So, do you fall asleep with
the TV on, or listening to music?
Yes, I often fall asleep
watching TV.
That can cause sounds
inside your ear,
but if you take a mouthful of air
or move these joints,
they sometimes stop.
It must be because
of all the diving.
Our coach was deaf,
but from birth.
What kind of sound?
Like a whistling
or like a badly-tuned radio.
They seem like distant voices
if the frequencies are low.
Generally speaking,
most people hear things.
What does the patient hear?
How does he hear?
That's what my work is.
Do you hear those sounds
at night,
and when you watch TV
do they stop?
They usually show
the films I like at night.
With the hours I work
I could easily have been an actress.
The Doctors' Union
has got theater workshops.
Some doctors take part
in the plays they put on.
That's wonderful!
You too?
Yes, once.
- Really? What part did you play?
- A doctor.
I didn't have
to rehearse a lot.
I'm taking the kids
to put vinegar on them.
Come along.
What are you doing in there?
Get out!
Kids, go to the kitchen with Mirta.
Come on.
Hello, how are you?
Sit down.
- No.
- Please.
They're organizing
an outing for tonight.
Dr. Vesalio is tipsy already.
I don't think he'll last.
Did you see how the water
cooling system has improved?
- How are you, Helena?
- Very well, doctor.
Your colleagues are happy.
- Are they bothering you?
- No, not at all.
Are you dining in the hotel
or going out with your friends?
No, I'm dining here.
A glass...
Thank you.
- Want some?
- No, thanks.
Doctor...
What about
the patient-doctor relationship,
the dramatization?
They're trying to find
a hospital patient.
It would be a good end
to the congress.
Yes, but it has to be
an interesting pathology.
What about
some kind of acufens?
Possibly.
Why not?
"A woman of the world
was driving very fast
with her friends one night.
She crashed
and saw them burn to death
without being able
to save them.
She walked for four days
until she collapsed from thirst,
wanting to die.
Then she heard
a voice saying to her,
"Rest now, sleep,
tomorrow you will be the fountain
that will ease thirst."
The woman returned to the city,
gave up her life of comfort
and devoted herself
to tending the poor."
Well, Jose.
What do you think?
It's horrible, she made it up.
Is it so hard
to make photocopies?
- Did you write it?
- No.
You have
to photocopy texts from books.
It isn't so hard.
I can understand the bit
about the woman's vocation,
but the people
who were killed...
Don't you have a vocation yet?
Amalia's got one!
Do you have a vocation?
What was their vocation?
Because they died
and that helped the woman
find her vocation.
She finds hers and is saved.
What about them?
They were born
to burn to death.
Girls, this isn't
getting us anywhere.
I have to go.
Helena...
- Could I have a word with you?
- Of course.
Very nice.
Look,
Dr. Vesalio has an idea
that may interest you.
We'd like you to participate
in the closure.
What is it?
We want to act out
a visit to the doctor.
It wouldn't be very much,
just a short scene,
but we'd do it properly,
set up a surgery...
Don Manuel's wife
is on the phone.
- No.
- She's insisting.
No!
I won't speak to her.
Doesn't she realize?
I was trying to persuade her
to take part in the scene, but...
At first, I thought it was
a stupid idea too,
but I saw it at an international
congress and it's amazing.
It was a singer
who had a problem
with volume and tone
because of some
botched-up surgery.
How can we interpret correctly
what the patient wants to tell us?
- Well...
- It isn't so easy.
Let's not keep on.
But it's very interesting.
She was a well-known singer.
What was her name?
A real beauty!
As far as that goes,
the doctor did have a good eye.
Hello, doctor!
Have you seen this?
It's fantastic.
He's not playing anything.
I was leaving.
Dr. Jano!
How are you?
This morning I saw one of
the lab girls coming out of a room,
one of the rep girls, I think.
This is a congress,
not a casino.
And it isn't the first time
this week.
This is a medical congress.
We're only asking
for a week of decent behavior.
It isn't that much.
Give me wealth
or poverty.
Give consolation or despair.
Grant me hell
or grant me heaven,
sweet life,
radiant sun,
for I have given in to you,
I have given in.
This way, please.
How is it going?
Mr. Hoffer,
Mrs. Helena Tiscornia.
We're going do a cubicle trial.
If you'd be so kind...
Can you hear me?
Can you hear my voice?
Good.
Dog.
White.
Quote.
Knot.
Kiss.
Hiss.
- Tail.
Defy.
- Ship.
Nice.
Rice.
Mule.
Mass.
- Niche.
- Handy.
- Bothers.
- Mothers.
What do you think?
Can you plug the gadget
into the piped music system?
What kind of plug is it?
Look, it's plugged into
the electric organ.
- Is that called an organ?
- No.
It's in behind.
What do you think?
Now, try it out.
Don't follow me!
Here.
Here, take a taxi,
and don't come back to the hotel.
You're filling your eyes
with microbes.
Did he touch you in the hotel?
I know what I have to do.
Hello.
We have to tell someone.
We could ask Inés.
- I bet she'll know what to do.
- You promised...
You promised you wouldn't
tell anyone if I told you.
We don't have to tell anyone.
It's my business.
It's my mission, I know that.
Don't cry anymore.
I promise I won't tell anyone.
Not a single word.
Give me a kiss.
Will I get the photo?
What are you doing?
Photocopies for grandma.
What is it, the stigmata?
No, the suffering
of the Passion.
Those photocopies.
I need them,
I'll come and get them today.
- At grandma's house?
- Yes.
Ciao.
For a few words, doctor!
But they weren't legible.
It isn't the first malpractice case
over handwriting.
This is lawyers' doings.
Putting a doctor on trial
for his handwriting!
I saw the prescription.
It wasn't terrible, but you couldn't
read the dosage clearly.
It's possible.
You can't smoke in here, mom.
You know very well
where you should be now.
I left it all ready.
You just have to cut and serve.
Dry your eye.
My hands are covered with oil.
I come in,
I sit down,
we shake hands...
I come in,
we shake hands,
and I sit down.
And then, well, doctor...
I think that you...
Don't worry.
Just answer the questions
spontaneously,
as we've been doing.
Of course, you're right.
Well...
Finish your coffee, Jano.
I'd like to know what you think...
I don't know what to wear.
You'll think it's stupid,
but I can't decide.
I'm going to be on a stage,
even if it is only a platform.
They're all lovely.
This one?
That one would do.
And this one?
Yes...
I'll put it on
and we'll go over it all again.
It doesn't suit me.
Thanks for the coffee.
Hello?
I'll put her on.
Maria Callas, for you.
You only turn up at meal times.
This isn't an hotel.
Excuse me, Amalia.
It's a family home.
There's a big difference
and you don't see that.
Mom,
Amalia lives in an hotel.
What did I ask you to do today?
Try asking me for the car later.
No more car!
We can't practice here.
My brothers have all got lice.
That's the other idiot!
Make me look like a skinflint.
Until I'm gone,
you won't know...
- What did she say?
- You've got whooping cough.
I don't have whooping cough.
You do,
because if I spin you round
you get whooping cough.
No, try it.
Try it!
...do what you want.
And I hope you're not
like the Correa brothers.
They didn't stop
until they destroyed their mother.
And look where they are.
Where are they?
One is divorced.
The other is in Spain
on a two-year scholarship.
You see?
The other one out of the country.
Juan Pablo,
don't you want to take
elocution class with Inés?
Inés isn't a speech therapist,
she's a loony.
She can give me classes
in my room.
- Good morning.
- Hello.
Good morning, doctor.
How are you doing?
Atilio...
Well, Freddy,
where are the baths?
Hugo...
Yes?
- Do you remember Dr. Jano?
- No.
To be honest, I don't.
My daughter Amalia,
Dr. Jano, Dr. Cuesta...
Say hello.
What were you doing?
Are you purifying the mud?
This is ready.
Fifteen minutes in the mud,
then a shower
and a lie-down.
Dr. Jano!
It seems
they're looking for you.
Dr. Jano, you have a call.
You can take it in the booth.
Hello?
Yes, thank you.
Hello, how are you?
What about the kids?
Kind of so-so.
I've been away a long time.
Put her on.
Hello, sweetheart.
Yes.
No, there's no cold pool.
No, the diving board is gone.
I told your mother I didn't know
if it was worth you coming.
No, it isn't that.
I don't like you
traveling at night.
There she is.
Hello, Jose.
How are things?
Fine.
Pour her coffee.
- Have you got a temperature?
- Yes, she has.
The photos!
Exactly.
What's wrong?
There's some problem between
one of the girls and a doctor.
I'm not surprised.
Freddy, if you please...
There's Jano.
Is that him?
How are you?
We've got the photos.
Doctor...
There's a little problem.
Dr. Vesalio is withdrawing
from the congress.
He left me these papers
to give to you.
They're the tests
they did on Helena,
so that you or Dr. Cuesta can do
the representation, the closure.
What?
That boy is so intelligent but...
He went out last night
with one of the rep girls
and he just got back
twenty minutes ago.
The lab has replaced the girl,
they fired her.
Dr. Vesalio made a scene.
He says he's leaving.
It's one way to ruin a career.
My career?
No, no, his career.
He's an expert in his field
but easily tempted.
He does this at all the congresses,
he can't resist.
Who?
Dr. Vesalio.
Why don't you tell him to stay?
He'll listen to you.
But I hardly know him.
As you were sharing a room
I thought you were friends.
No, that was just for one night,
the hotel had a problem.
Excuse me.
He's odd.
Very odd.
Going off like that,
so suddenly,
without a word to me
and with the representation
in a few days.
He got me into this mess
and now he disappears.
There are a thousand questions...
What do I care?
I know what I've got.
It won't change my life.
Just the opposite.
I'm going crazy, always thinking
about that noise in my ear.
- The family is coming.
- Oh, mom!
Why "Oh, mom"?
Dry that eye!
That man has a family.
That torments him.
He's not a bastard.
He obviously has
a sentimental conflict.
You know, I think that too.
Poor man.
Stay by me,
I still have caresses
that you don't know.
I don't think
I can open my eyes.
Open them.
Look at me.
I'm asking for the stigmata.
I can see you a bit
when you move,
but I'm going to stay like this.
All right.
Open them now.
One, two, three...
Now!
If my words,
trembling with love,
don't waken any passion
in your mind...
It's amazing
how quickly I can learn.
I've got the gift of learning.
Open your eyes.
The guy who groped you
isn't that old.
What's his name?
Open your eyes, idiot.
You opened your mouth!
No, you stuck your tongue in.
Stay by me,
I still have caresses
that you don't know
of all of me.
And I'll invent
some new ones for you
so that you'll stay with me.
Take this off, it's burning!
You have to give it time
to work.
Have you noticed that
Dr. Jano is a bit withdrawn?
Why not go to his room,
kind of casually,
and see what's wrong with him?
- I can't go out like this.
- I'll comb it for you.
I look like I've got more hair,
don't I?
I'm worried.
I have to do that performance
and I'm really going off the idea.
You should
devote all your time to that.
- Mirta can't do everything.
- I'm here, aren't I?
That's why I'm telling you.
Go on.
- Freddy...
- Hello, doctor, how are you?
Fine.
Come in.
- Is the room comfortable?
- Yes.
My family are coming,
I've reserved a room for the kids.
It's been years
since I saw your wife.
I'd just had my youngest son
at the time.
Right.
Your kids must be big now.
Yes.
Well, I must be going.
- What did he say?
- Fine, fine.
He's fine.
I'm going to call Chile.
I'd like the kids to come
and help me with the hotel.
Mirta is very good, I know,
but family is family.
Mirta is almost family.
I know that.
Look at the time.
What's the time in Chile?
Have you got the number?
It must be really late.
How old are they now?
They must be pretty grown up.
Know what?
I'll call the Carrera Hotel,
my friend Francisco,
so he can tell me the time.
Have you got
the Chilean's number?
Hello.
Mr. Francisco Gutiérrez,
please.
Hello, Francisco.
This is Freddy from Argentina.
Yes, a very long time...
How many years?
Listen,
what time is it there?
What time?
It can't be.
Hello?
Were you cut off?
No, but the poor guy
would have talked for hours.
I'm going
to call the kids anyway.
They'll understand
it's an emergency.
- Is this my address book?
- No, it's mine.
It's all the same.
Do you remember
my wedding suit?
You couldn't pay
for that today.
The Chilean.
With that voice!
We should call a doctor.
Would you like something to eat?
Yes, thanks,
but nothing reheated.
Then try another hotel.
I'm sorry about the time,
but I didn't want just anyone.
Dr. Vesalio left in the end.
What a pity,
such a jolly man.
Sit up.
Does your throat hurt?
Open your mouth.
What about that food?
Stick out your tongue.
Take a deep breath.
Sometimes, when you're asleep,
you stop breathing for a few seconds.
You could suffocate.
She's all right,
it's just a chill.
Come and sleep with me,
darling.
Fifty.
Fifty-five.
Sixty.
Sixty-five.
- What's wrong?
- A bee stung me.
Seventy.
Seventy-five.
Dad, look!
It's incredible!
Eighty-five.
- Are you sure?
- Yes, I am.
It's a long time.
You need a haircut.
Five.
Wait, start over again.
Don't talk to me.
Don't talk to me!
Mom!
My God!
What did you do to grandma?
Something horrible happened.
I was telling Juli? N about it.
He's the only one
who listens to me.
It's horrible.
A doctor at the congress
interfered with Amalia.
My God, that's awful!
What happened?
Juli? N,
get dressed and get out.
The doctor is a friend
of her mother.
I didn't know what to do,
he told me to tell you.
Of course.
- Did Amalia tell her mother?
- No, she didn't dare.
See what I mean?
- We have to tell Helena.
- No, mom.
Please.
I'll tell Amalia to tell her,
please.
Jose, we're going home.
Sweetheart,
fold this.
Is the representation
starting at 6:00?
Stop that!
A bit later,
at 6:15 or 6:30.
Is there dinner afterwards?
Yes, there's dinner.
Don't pour shampoo
on the bees!
This is the hive.
They're getting away, hurry!
Hand me my purse, please.
Quick, they're outside!
I'll take the kids for a walk.
- I'll keep a front seat for you.
- Yes, do that.
Come on, kids.
They're getting out
the other side.
I'm going to tell your mother
everything.
I wanted to tell you something.
You're a good man.
Did I hit you?
Come in.
I feel the same.
It's madness.
We should be going.
Good evening.
We have to talk to Helena.
It's urgent.
I'm very sorry!
She's at the closure
of the congress.
You can wait in the hall.
I'm going to find Amalia.
Don't come back
until I've spoken to her mother.
Josefina!
Get rid of that long face.
You're helping her.
Remember.
Elevator!
- Mirta.
- Yes?
I must speak urgently to Helena
about a very serious situation
that has occurred
here in the hotel.
Stop that!
What's wrong?
Go and see what it is.
Stop that.
Right, I would ask you all
to please take your seats,
and if we could have
some silence
we'll get ourselves organized.
Doctors,
if we can all take our seats...
You can sit there.
I think there's going
to be a scandal.
They're going to report a doctor
who interfered
with the girl from the hotel.
You know the one?
The girl at the pool,
with brown hair.
Dr. Jano, if you'd come round
this way, please.
As you all know,
today,
to close this congress,
we are going to present
a public consultation.
So I would ask for
a big round of applause for Helena
who is going to participate
as our patient.
The first part
of this representation
is an interview
with Dr. Jano.
Doctor...
- Your tie.
- It's fine without a tie.
Dr. Jano,
we're waiting for you.
Jose!
When did you get here?
What are you doing?
Are you allowed in now?
You want me to come in?
Are you allowed?
The water is so warm.
You notice that smell?
Yes.
Orange blossom.
I'll always take care of you,
because you have
no brothers or sisters.
I'm your sister.
Next year,
I'll have twin brothers.
I mean, sisters.
Hello, hello.
Did you hear?
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org