Goodbye, Roberto.
See you, Luisito.
Hit him!
He'll knock him.
- Good hook.
- A southpaw.
Do you box?
Yes, sort of.
I was a
middleweight Walter Junior.
Another beer
and a glass for the boy.
Thanks.
I also was left-handed.
Let me see.
Come on.
Come on, shoot.
Thanks, pal.
Good, good...
I didn't cover you.
- I don't know you.
- I'm from Paraná.
What brought you this way?
They told me...
...there is work here.
This place is dead.
I was fired from the factory
a few years ago.
I'm going back to work.
See you.
Still here?
I don't know anybody here.
You said you are from Paraná.
I live near Paraná
in the countryside.
I can offer you something
for a few weeks.
You'll only get room and board.
- Do you have a family?
- Yes, but they live...
...across the river.
Okay?
Alright?
He'll sleep in the barn
and he'll help with the harvest.
- What was your name?
- Félix.
Hey, kiddo!
She's my wife.
You don't have to train today.
Have a drink.
Thanks.
The stew was good today.
Coming, Popeye.
Popeye!
You don't have to.
Mercedes!
Cut it out!
Listen, the highway is closed.
Many trucks stopped.
Next they'll stop the train.
You have to carry a gun nowadays.
It's the only way.
One of these nights
I'll take you to town.
Here's the vegetable garden.
You'll have to pick them.
Little by little.
And there's the orchard.
The ingredients are important
for sauces and jams.
It's not a hard job.
My family always did it,
and lived well.
But things have changed.
I never liked this.
Bring all the fruit here.
She'll tell you what to do.
She's in charge of this.
She likes it...
...but with the baby
she can't do it alone.
Bye!
These are juicy.
And these are dry.
We just picked these...
...peaches.
When they are nice and yellow,
they are ready to pick.
This is Roberto's father.
Here we boil.
This is for the sauce.
Here we do the grinding.
The seasonings.
See?
These recipes...
...with such neat handwriting...
...were written
by my father-in-law.
These recipes are ancient.
They all wrote here.
His parents brought them
from abroad.
"Preparation...
...for peach jam. "
"Pick ripe peaches. "
I learned this from the old man,
Roberto's father.
He learned from his mother.
It's written here: Granny.
You should've seen...
...how patient he was
in teaching me.
I'm not from here.
Here are the baskets.
Mercedes, come to bed!
Come here!
Here's what you asked me for.
Thanks.
So, is everything OK?
Come here, leave that.
Show me that.
Come on.
My boy, my Chango!
One day I'll make a champ
out of you!
We'll go in a minute.
Get out of here!
I told you a thousand times!
I don't want the dog
in the house!
Let's go, Félix.
Here.
Sleep boy.
Sleep boy... Sleep boy...
The sun...
Sleep boy.
The sun is no longer warming you.
The moon watches over
your sleep.
Sleep boy.
Tomorrow you'll run...
...in the fields.
Sleep boy.
Look at all these colours!
The red tomato...
This is nice.
This is orange.
Look at the orange, Chango.
Look.
How do you see things,
Changuito?
Yellow!
There's a bug
that can change colours.
My grandma showed it to me.
It turned blue, then red...
...and then yellow.
Weird bug.
Goddammit! Don't fuck around
with me, bitch!
Things grow easily here.
Over there...
Anyway, we lost the house there.
I came over here...
...and then they all left.
What about your mum and dad?
I don't know. I never met them.
Do you have any brothers?
No.
A girlfriend...
- Someone?
- No.
You're alone?
I had a grandmother.
She died?
Yes.
It's getting cold.
Fuck this rain!
I had to run.
My work will get fucked up.
I'll have to start over.
And then I get paid shit.
What am I going to do?
Good.
Better than the old man's.
No.
Yes, it is.
The old man
didn't see much at the end...
...and used too much sugar.
- No.
- Don't be stubborn.
I know my father's cooking.
Try it.
Tomorrow you'll run...
...in the fields.
Sleep boy.
Let's sit down to eat.
The sun is no longer warming you.
Sleep boy.
The moon watches over
your sleep.
Come on...
...show me some punches.
Come on, Félix.
Come on!
Shit, come on!
Hit!
Look at me dancing like a fool...
Goodbye.
Félix, I brought you cigarettes.
Thanks.
Tomato! Peach!
Jam, lady!
Tomato, sir.
Here, that's it.
Listen, Chango.
This is very important.
Remember they day your mother
handed you over to me?
When you grabbed my hand?
I knew very well
what you meant by that.
I know you need me.
But don't worry.
I won't leave you alone.
You'll never be alone again.
Got it?
- Want some mate?
- No, thanks.
Have another one.
Let's go home.
It's still early.
When I say something,
you listen!
Am I clear?
Where do you think you're going?
You'll do as I say!
- How are you today?
- Fine.
Have some mate.
Have a biscuit.
It's good.
Bring jam.
Excuse me.
Is everything here?
Hand me that.
You take the bike.
I'll go with this.
Excuse me.
- Can I heat up some water?
- Go ahead.
Thanks.
Fucking dog!
I told you, bitch!
You fucking bitch!
Who do you think you are?
She left.
Mercedes left.
I looked for her everywhere.
I'll find her.
Leave me alone...
Nobody saw her leave town.
Not by bus...
...not by train...
...not even on foot.
What's up, Chango?
Goddammit!
Are you OK, Roberto?
Easy!
Easy, Roberto.
Stop! Stop!
It's me, Félix! It's me!
Stop crying, goddammit!
Stop crying!
I can't take it anymore!
Stop crying,
I just can't take it!
Please, stop crying!
Stop crying!
I can't take it!
I couldn't sleep a wink last night.
I couldn't sleep at all.
I just can't take it anymore.
Look at all these bubbles.
Look how they float.
- It's hot.
- Yes.
The boy crapped again.
All the time.
Shall I get you cigarettes?
Thanks.
BLESSED ALL THE CHILDREN
Hello. A ham sandwich.
- White bread?
- Yes.
- To eat here or to go?
- I'll take it.
Two pesos.
Thanks.
Good morning.
A beer.
What's wrong with the baby?
Why is he crying?
What's up, pal?
Why are you crying?
Hello.
He is so cute.
Let's show him to the baby.
Hello.
Do you like it?
Thanks.
Freeze, right there.
Give me what you have.
Don't try to be smart.
Hand over all you have!
Is that all?
Nothing else?
Don't be smart. Stay put.
Come on, I don't have all day.
Move the bed away from the wall.
Do you want some?
It's free.
Finish it or give it to the kid.
OK, let's go.
- Bye, Cadillac!
- See you around.
Later.
Sit down.
Do you know of any job?
Is it yours?
Yes.
A little change...
Some change...
Thanks.
Hello.
Give me a croissant.
How are you?
When you fight
you look as if you were dancing.
- Get the hell out of here!
- Calm down.
How do you get
those puppets out?
Just put a coin in and see, idiot!
I don't even have
enough for beer.
- Selling something?
- No.
What about that bag?
I'm sleeping in the park.
Sometimes, I do odd jobs.
Little jobs.
Small stuff.
It's easy. People get scared
and give you everything.
If you're interested...
...you can come with me.
I mean, both of you.
What do you say?
They call me Cadillac.
Cadillac.
"Los Fabulosos Cadillacs".
Don't you know the band?
No.
The cops don't fuck with us.
Let's go.
Come in.
Nati, I want you
to meet someone.
Félix, Nati, my sister.
And him...
His son, Chango.
He's so cute.
Hello, baby.
I'll be back in a while.
Look at this pretty doll.
You're not a girl
but it doesn't matter.
Look.
That's where you get off...
I'm making spaghetti,
do you want some?
I'm not hungry. Thanks.
There's enough,
only Dany and I eat here.
- Look, I got paid with this.
- Wow! Great!
For a job today.
Apparently it's new,
but if it isn't... it's still good!
This is what they paid you with?
It's great!
- Do you want something?
- An ice cream.
Let's go.
We're not going to Japan.
We're doing a job right here.
It sounds good.
The stereo.
I'll give you your share later.
They said to take bus 148.
I didn't know this place.
It's crowded.
Where are you from?
Paraná.
Your son was born there?
Yes, that's right.
Lady?
- Juárez and Lambaré is that way?
- No, that way.
Thanks.
We were going the wrong way.
Lady, do you have the time?
- Twenty to ten.
- Thanks.
We're on time.
You don't always get
a cool stereo like today.
But every now and then
I get a good job.
Here it is.
Green... Renault.
Just follow me.
I don't care if it's
used or stolen.
As long as it sounds good.
Once, we stole some speakers...
...from a nightclub.
Still got them.
Let's go!
You bastard!
Stop!
Let me go!
- Stop!
- Bastard!
- Let me go!
- Come here!
Come here!
Ripeados por Tylerg|
Visita: www.clan-sudamerica.com.ar