Good.
Very good.
Claudia...
Why don't you wait a bit longer?
I've already been waiting for a week...
and it doesn't seem
I'm late for my period.
Are you scared?
No.
Here's your prescription,
with the near and far corrections.
Very well.
Now you'll be able
to readthe menu.
- Doctor...
- Tell Branquini that...
- You want me to?
- Yes, give him his eye drops.
It's yourfirst time here.
I'll have to register you.
Really?
Name?
Juan...
Desouza.
Age?
46.
- Occupation?
- Lawyer.
Marital status?
Married.
Phone number?
47321...
Diagnosis:
Farsightedness and nearsightedness.
0.25
I have to go on.
Choose some nice frames...
and I'll pick them tomorrow.
Thanks a lot.
You're welcome.
I have to go on.
Hello...
- Please, eat something.
- No, no.
Eat some, come on.
Hello.
- How are you, Lidia?
- Just fine.
Hi, dad.
- How are you feeling?
- Fine.
- What happened?
- Nothing.
- Nothing? You fell down, right?
- Yes...
Why?
You have to ask Lidia
when you want to move around the house.
- Not Lidia, please...
- Yes, Lidia.
When you go to the bathroom,
you go with Lidia.
When you need to have your diapers
changed, you ask her. That's her job.
Okay.
Here it goes...
Keep your eyes closed.
I can't come tomorrow...
I have to leave town.
I'll manage.
- Not that way!
- Okay, hold it.
I wash and you rinse, okay?
- Will you let herbathe you?
- Yes.
Will you really let Lidia bathe you?
No, I've already had a bathtoday.
- But that's what Lidia is here for...
- Give me.
Here I come, wait...
or it will get in youreyes.
Don't open your eyes,
here you have this.
Come on, rinse.
Okay.
Move back, dad.
Be careful.
Easy does it... there you go.
A bit more. That's it.
Rinse a bit more.
Enough.
You have such nice hair.
Should I bring your pajamas?
The blue ones.
The blue ones are too small.
I want the blue ones.
Okay.
Hello...
Mister...
But that's none of my business.
Yeah. But you call her...
She'll listen to you.
Yes, dear...
Yes, I'm busy right now...
Thanks.
I'll call you back. I'm busy now.
I can't talk.
Yes.
Yes... later on.
Excuse me, it was my wife.
...and the property
was foreclosed, right?
Yes, there was this huge debt.
But it has been paid. All of it.
Here you have the papers.
And I've included...
myfees and expenses as well.
- Do I discuss it with you?
- No, with my boss.
So, it's a farm...
- with a house.
- Yes, Emilio's house.
The poor man could no longerwork.
But we let him stay anyway.
Poorman...
- Are there people in the house?
- No.
Let me explain.
An elderly couple owned the house.
Really nice people
but with no children.
And one day she died...
in March, April.
And he just fell to pieces.
He died two orthree months later.
They found him in his bed
afterten days.
Imagine that...
Anyway,
the house isn't worth much.
The important thing is the land.
It's 35 soy quintals, outside of town.
Emilio, happy birthday!
Yours forever, Mabel.
Here you have
the plans ofthe house.
Take them with you.
Great.
When you're done,
I'll treat youto lunch.
Okay, Desouza?
Unfortunately, I have to go.
- Can't even stay forlunch?
- I really have to go.
Last call,
bus to Buenos Aires,
leavingfrom plafform 4.
Last call.
To Buenos Aires,
we're leavingnow!
- Good morning.
- Morning.
- May I help you?
- I'd like a room.
Do you have a reservation?
No.
How many people?
- Just me.
- Let me see.
Name and last name?
Emilio...
Branelli.
- Nationality?
- Argentinean.
- Age?
- 45.
- Marital status?
- Married.
- Occupation?
- Architect.
ID number?
15...
584...
1... 31.
- Where from?
- Buenos Aires.
Buenos Aires.
Let me see...
Great.
Follow me.
I'll show youthe room.
This is room 18.
- I like this one.
- Great.
Come with me,
I'll check you in.
Here's the remote control
and you already have yourkey.
- We charge a day in advance.
- No problem.
What brings you here?
Is it work?
Yes, I'm a doctor.
That's just great...
Here's yourchange.
Let's check you in, Doctor.
Name?
Manuel...
Salazar.
Salazarwith a "z".
Occupation?
I know! Doctor.
- Nationality?
- Argentinean.
- Age?
- 45.
- Where from?
- The Capital.
Marital status?
Single.
ID, please.
- Don't you rememberthe number?
- Of course I do!
12...
584...
181...
Verywell, Dr. Salazar.
Anything you need, I'm here.
That's very kind of you.
Thanks.
Hi, Claudia, this is me.
I can't make it tonight.
I'm staying here.
I'll explain it later.
I'll call you back.
But things are fine, I'm fine.
Love you, bye.
Manuel Salazar-R.I.P.
You left life tooson.
Your wife, daughter, parents and
brothers will always remember you...
as the righteous man you were.
Deceased: Manuel Salazar
Very well.
It's 17 pesos.
Fine, thank you.
A glass, mister?
Still around, Desouza?
What are you up to?
Just taking a walk.
But... didn't you have to leave?
Come on, I'll give you a ride.
Where are we going?
For a drink.
I'll show you around.
- The bathroom?
- The bathroom? In the back.
Overthere.
I'll wait foryou inside.
- Hi there, Mr. Notary!
- How is it going, Huguito?
What's up?
Hello...
- I was just resting, excuse me.
- Don't you worry...
I'm almost done.
- Did you buy anything?
- Yes, a shirt.
How nice.
This colorlooks really good on you.
Should I clean this one?
Yes, please. Thanks.
Excuse me.
Deceased: Manuel Salazar.
- Excuse me...
- What is it?
I need a glass of water.
- You're Roberto, right?
- No.
I'm sorry.
I mistook you for somebody else.
No problem.
- Are you from Buenos Aires?
- Yes.
Manuel had a good friend
in BuenosAires.
Yes, but it's not me.
- Thanks a lot.
- You're welcome.
- I'm Fontana. Nice to meet you.
- Nice to meet youtoo.
- My pleasure.
- Likewise.
I'm Manuel's godfather.
What's yourname?
Your name...
Lucio Morales.
Were you a close friend ofManuel's?
Not that close.
- Would you excuse me, please.
- Sure.
Lucio...
Lucio.
Just Lucio?
Don't you have a middle name?
No.
I like Lucio.
But I like Luciano better.
I love the name Luciano.
What are yourkid's names?
How do you know I have children?
I don't, but at yourage
most men have kids...
Besides, you can tell...
Rocío and Martín.
Do they look like you?
Yeah.
They must be very cute...
Yeah... they're very cute.
Are you divorced?
No, you're not.
When I have a child,
I'll name him Luciano.
Are you staying on?
Yes.
We could meet tomorrow...
- Yes.
- I get home at 8.
At 8 here?
Okay, at 8 then.
Bye.
- I'll stay in bed.
- Sure.
Doctor Salazar!
Open the door, please!
It's an emergency!
Doctor Salazar!
Doctor!
It's an emergency!
- What is it?
- Open up, please.
Please, excuse me.
I know you were resting...
but the woman in room 11
is dying on me.
I don't know what's wrong.
She's really sick.
Please, come, you're a doctor!
Can you help me?
- Call an ambulance.
- I did already.
They told me they'd come in
10 minutes but they're not here yet.
Please, doctor, come with me.
- I'll be right out.
- Hurry up.
Doctor, it's in here.
Come, please.
Try calling the ambulance again.
Ma'am...
Ma'am!
What?
Who is it?
My name isJuan, ma'am.
My God!
Give her oxygen.
Can you hearme, ma'am?
Can you hearme?
- The next bus to BuenosAires?
- There's one at quarterto...
- Are there any seats left?
- Yes. One ticket?
One.
- Round trip?
- One way.
It's 27 pesos.
Cash orcredit?
- Charge it.
- Okay.
An ID, please.
Here you go, have a nice trip.
The grey bus, platform 5.
Where were you?
Working.
Claudia is pregnant.
We're going to have a child.
Does yourmotherknow?
Not yet.
You want to tell her?
No.
I don't want to see her.
Should we take abath?
Hold it.
There we go...
Sit here.
- Wait, wait...
- Letme do it
So...
Will it bea boy or agirl?
Idon't know.
Maybe agirl.
Or maybe a boy.
Lift your leg.
Your leg, dad.
And now the other...
Now sit over here.
Great.
- Fine.
- Alittle bitmore.
Letme sit
The water is way too hot.
Why the rush?
I'm not in a hurry.
- Are you ina hurry?
- No.
- Then?
- Fine.
Letmedo it.
There wego.
- Slowly...
- Yes, yes...
Subs. riped by bluciano for
www.clan-sudamerica.com.ar