Blockade! Blockade!
Are you hot, baby?
Today they do a blockade!
They could've
warned beforehand.
Foreigners come in
and see such a scene.
I'm not against
them protesting.
But they can go do
it somewhere else.
Only a car per minute
can go by...
and they said the flight
schedule won't change.
We'll have to go back home.
No, I'll never go back.
I'm not going back.
I'll walk.
It's not good for you, Nilda.
I'm not going to die.
Awalk will do us good.
Specially for you, so you
can slim that tummy.
- What about the car?
- She'll stay with the baby.
Don't leave me alone in
this mess with the baby.
Don't worry, the police is here.
They'll take care
of any problem.
Bye, honey. Take care
of the baby.
Give him something to eat
so he won't cry. Bye, honey.
I want to wear my glasses.
It's so hot.
Come on, Lito.
Let's go, Contreras.
We'll never get there.
Careful!
How can it be?
DON'TCLOSE THE FACTORY
Blockade, damn it!
- How does this affect you?
- What?
How does this blockade
affect you?
We have to take a plane.
My wife is sick.
If every factory that closes
they're going to do this
the government
will have to intervene.
Thank you.
Don't forget to cut the
power on the weekends.
And pop in Sunday noon.
Lito, he knows it by heart.
He'll do it.
- Nilda.
- What, honey?
- How do you feel?
- Fine. Fine.
You asked me 5 minutes ago.
You go first.
Go wrap the bags
with plastic.
- What for?
- Security.
They've got a lock.
- Go do it.
- Where is it?
I don't know.
Somewhere.
- I'll go with you.
- No, you stay with me.
I'm sick.
He can do it on his own.
I wanted to say something
regarding the factory.
Me too. Don't worry...
I'll be fine if you
don't do anything.
Sit down.
If during all this time
it went well with Lito
that means the factory
can go on by itself.
You'll be in charge
of the factory.
So please be responsible.
You, yourfamily, and all of
us live thanks to the factory.
Don't worry,
everything will go fine.
Don't look so sad.
I'm young, I've got lots
of things to do still.
I don't plan on moving yet.
Go find Lito. They might
even wrap his head.
- Everything OK?
- Yes, fine.
- How much is it?
- $48.
$48?
- $6 each.
- $48 pesos?
- $48 dollars.
- What?
Prices are in dollars.
$48 dollars?
What a rip off.
I hope everything's fine.
And come back soon.
Everything will be all right.
You know what you have to do.
- You do know.
- Yes, Nilda. Don't worry.
- Don't forget the small chamber.
- Yes.
And rememberthat you have
the cameras in that bag.
Anah? Wants you to film
the plane on the inside.
I'll explain again. You film
with the red button and...
You told me a thousand times.
Come on, Lito.
Forget the camera.
Nilda, your coat.
Your bag.
Bye. Bye.
Akiss to the family.
Send my love to yourwife.
And take care.
Carefull with the chamber.
- Have a good trip.
- Bye, bye.
Good luck with everything
you have to do.
Thanks. Bye.
Good luck. Have a good trip.
- It's almost set up.
- Wait a second.
Let me see, Lito.
Wait, wait.
You can't go out
any old way.
Hold on a second.
I'll go see the guys.
Hey, get ready overthere.
You look like a football team.
Ok. Roll it.
That's it.
OK. Take it easy.
We're at the door
of our factory.
And if you may escort me,
here we go.
THROUGH YOUR EYES
I'd say these machines aren't
found anywhere in the world.
They're fantastic.
And we're... wait.
Tell them to work!
We owe lots of money
and they're just sitting there.
Do something!
You get a rag.
And you pretend to oil
that machine.
Let's continue.
And here we are at
the heart of ourfactory.
This machine, as you see,
"Societ? Well, it's French.
Is from 1925.
Get a close-up.
From 1925.
My grandfather's grandfather brought
this machine. Come on, Nilda.
Then we have these two
enormous condensers that...
- Lito, this is no good.
- Why?
They're old. It won't
give a good impression.
- I want to show all we can.
- I don't like it.
- What is it, Lito?
- This won't go.
She's right.
Now I want to introduce you
to our star machine: The Rolicube.
The Rolicube which I invented
in 1983.
You have money to buy a camera
but none for salaries.
Through this computer,
we can immediately see...
the control of the three
cold storage chambers.
- Lito, two don't work.
- Why don't you shut up?
I'm trying to sell here.
Just shut up.
Come here.
Give me the camera.
Here. Careful.
Excuse me.
Go on and sit down.
Here we have Mr. Contreras
controlling the plant.
Don't smile.
- What do I do?
- Nothing.
This is the last stage
of our ice production.
As you can see here...
every hour we produce
50 bags of 15 kg each.
They're packaged ain'tight
and sent to Expeditions.
Later they're prepared to be
distributed among the customers.
As you can see this is
the invention of 1983...
for which I want to
make a toast with you now.
Cheers.
Excuse me, you can't
film here. House rules.
- Please turn it off.
- Of course.
You should've protested.
What?
- You can film.
- No, I respect rules.
- Diabetic?
- No, my wife is.
Sorry, but my grandmother
was diabetic.
We're going to get some
tests in the States...
because she has to have
a kidney transplant.
She wants to do
it in New York.
She'd stay and live there too.
You plan to move?
No. I said she'd like
to live there.
Me? BuenosAires
and Gardel.
Good.
Put that away.
Chicken or pasta?
Pasta.
Chicken, please.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Not so much.
It's bad for you.
Just to give it some flavor.
Here.
- You want everyone to know?
- Test yourself, please.
Eat it, honey.
Gershwin Hotel.
What's he saying?
He doesn't speak a word.
Give me some paper.
$48 pesos forthat
crappy plastic?
Oh, my God, please,
take it down.
Gershwin...
Just like it sounds.
S- H...
- What is "Double U".
- W. Gershwin.
- Gershwin...
- Hotel.
- Hotel?
Driver.
What?
Does he understand anything?
At last.
Rememberthe mess we went
through for our visas?
Anyone can get one.
Then they say this country
isn't tolerant.
I'm so tired.
Come on! Come on, Lito.
You can see later.
Yourwife's tough.
Let me know and we can
push her off the roof. Joking.
- Are you Argentine?
- Yes.
- Peru.
- You're Peruvian?
No, but they call me Peru.
See you.
I'll wreck it.
I love that if Americans
are into details.
The brush has
a red handle
Tiles matching the curtain.
How embarrassing
at the freeshop today.
Why did they reject our card?
I thought the Gershwin Hotel
it's named afterthe jazz musician.
I picked it.
Since it was called "Gershwin"...
I thought there'd be music,
a concert.
Apiano in the lobby.
Did you see one?
After all, we are in N.Y.
Right on 5th Avenue.
Don't touch the fridge
It's waytoo expensive.
Did you call the bank? You pay
with the card for everything here.
Lito, turn that down.
I can't find the button.
Sorry, I didn't know
you spoke Spanish.
I could've ordered in English.
Here's a...
With cream.
Fortwo.
- Lito, I ordered dinner!
- What?
I ordered dinner.
Don't you want
to measure it first?
Get me the NPH first. I should've
applied it 5 hours ago.
It was 7 hours ago, there's
a two hour difference.
And you didn't want
to do it on the plane.
Stop worrying.
You're going to make
me more sick.
I ordered food:
Steak with salad
a fruit salad and
dessert for you.
Adessert for me
that you're going to eat.
You ate everything
on the plane and now this.
- It not good for you.
- Lito, dej? Est? Bien.
- What is it?
- Nothing.
It always happens.
It'll go away soon.
Go on.
Lito...
What is it?
I'm going to the bathroom.
I don't feel well.
I'm OK...
I can't see, Lito.
- What is it, Nilda?
- I can't see anything.
Go get an ambulance.
Hurry, I'm blind.
Please, my wife has high
blood pressure. An ambulance.
Peru, please! Call an ambulance,
my wife's sick.
Get me my robe.
The silk one.
Don't talk.
Please, don't talk.
- You have my make-up?
- I've got everything.
- I can't see.
- Easy, easy.
- Is my brush here?
- Yes, it's there.
Please, don't talk.
Tell them, Lito, that
I'm Ok. This is temporary.
You don't need
to come with me.
I know you don't like
to be in an ambulance.
I don't know what
I did wrong.
We didn't eat anything.
Well, we did...
The salty peanuts,
the Coke.
- Are you here?
- I'm here.
You had the chicken.
I only had noodles
with cream.
Because I say so!
And don't say the truth!
No, I've been discharged.
What? Aparty at my house?
Don't you dare!
It's my house and I want
it just like I left it!
Excuse me.
I heard you speak Spanish,
and English as well.
- That's my job.
- I don't speak a word.
I teach English. I've got
my cards in the room.
My wife speaks English.
We're leaving soon anyway.
I wanted to make
a call and I don't how.
- You're Argentine, right?
- Yes.
I noticed because of
your shoes. Number?
- 42.
- Phone number.
47...
The operation went fine.
You can see her at 10.
She's just scolding me.
She's still sedated, on diuretics
and she has a cateter.
Her kidneys are not working well
so we'll to have to do a dialysis.
Please, no, not dialysis.
We came here
to get a transplant.
The transplant will have to be
done later. The dialysis can't wait.
If you have a insurance. How do
you expect to pay for everything?
I have an insurance
from Argentina...
but I don't think
it'll cover us here.
I'll pay with my credit card.
We'll transfer yourwife to dialysis
and then you'll take care of everything
with administration later.
Good luck.
Argentina.
Looks like they cut it last night.
It's all flooded.
I knew they'd cut the power.
First they send you a
telegram warning you...
and then they cut it.
Seems like they enjoy it.
They're the ones with
the hole in the middle.
They melt in a second.
Plus some idiot cut it
off last night.
Isn't there automatic payment?
The bank won't give any
more credit...
We've been in red
for a century.
Good thing Lito went to N.Y.
If he see this he'll die.
In this heat. We could sell
the entire production in a day.
They'd be begging for more.
Everthought of a generator?
Chiche can get you one.
With the gas price?
How could we afford it?
He can get you the gas too.
Does Chiche have an oil
duct in his garden?
He has a friend that sucks gas
from parked cars with a hose.
Chiche says someone steals it,
but I bet he does it.
- How long would he take?
- El Chiche would take...
- What is it?
- Phone, from N.Y.
Hello. Lito?
Hello, Contreras.
How are you?
How are things overthere?
How's Nilda?
Fine. She already had her
tests done. We'll leave soon.
How are things overthere?
Fine.
It was more expensive than
we thought, so send money.
How much?
All you can.
I'll need a few days to collect
money from some clients.
If you have any problems,
talk to Rodriguez Ford.
- The bank manager?
- Yes.
Is it hot?
It's cooler now. But we're
running out of ice.
The temperature may go up...
Hello?
Hello? Lito?
Lito!
Should I call Chiche?
Go ahead. But I don't
want any stolen gas.
Is he going to steal it?
Hello.
I look awful.
You're fine.
How are you?
I'd feel better if
you didn't lie to me.
She's saying I can't
wear any make-up...
and I'm telling her
that I sleep with it on.
She's right, you just
got out of surgery.
Yes, but I'm pretty good.
And you look well.
- Could you make the call?
- Yes, thank you.
Good. Yourwife?
Excuse me.
Get me my make-up.
The red one.
Here.
There's a lighter and
a darker one.
I want the darker one.
Here.
Is it OKhere?
Excuse me.
Sorry to butt in.
I had the same problem.
I always wore make-up.
So I had this done.
Permanent make-up.
Want to see it?
Sorry!
Show him.
Look at it.
Well?
Lmpressive.
Tell me more,
so I can imagine it.
It's like a tatoo.
You can wash yourface
and it won't smear.
You can even take a shower
and you're always made up.
Sara Santamarina.
I have to sit in that?
- If you want to learn English...
- I know English.
He told me. Good luck,
nice to meet you.
Likewise. Thank you.
Lito, call the doctor.
- What for?
- I want permanent make-up.
You didn't even see her.
I can imagine.
Call the doctor.
Let's make a deal.
You can have it done
if you go to dialysis.
OK. I'll have the make-up
done first, then the dialysis.
The doctorwill decide.
Besides, he was to do
dialysis tomorrow.
What's he doing?
What's he playing?
Oh, God! He's drilling
a hole in my head!
It's the boys playing
across the street.
Please...
I'm going to ask for a bed
so I can lie next to you.
No, Lito.
Please, don't, Lito. What for?
You're right.
You don't need
to come tomorrow.
I'm having dialysis
in the morning.
Come in the afternoon.
Don't forget the camera.
I want you to film everything.
Everything.
I can't sit here all day
in the hospital.
I'm going to get an operation and
you won't have to go back to Bs. As.
What's the matter, Lito?
There's still some tape left.
- But we only have this cassette.
- Buy another one.
I want to film everything
to show the girls.
When I tell you to tape,
tape everything.
The streets, the stores,
parks, clothes, everything.
You can tell me and
then I can tell the girls.
I'll be your eyes.
What eyes?
Now go to the hotel,
take a hot bath
sleep all night. In the
morning, have breakfast
and get dressed.
Put on yourturquoise sweater.
It matches your eyes.
Your grey pants. I don't
know if we brought them.
And your jacket, it's cold.
And don't forget to bring
me my cologne and my bag.
Everything's on the dresser
in the room.
Won't forget anything?
- Good night. Get some rest.
- Go on, hurry.
I...
Manhattan Gershwin Hotel
River...
Acab in the river?
Oh, a boat.
Manhattan.
Thank you.
See you tomorrow.
Good evening.
Hi, Gramps.
- How's yourwife?
- Better.
It's so cold.
Have a drink.
No, I quit 20 years ago.
Once I get to see some good
football and not this crap...
with the stick and the ball.
I need a favor.
I need to get some
tape forthe camera.
Maybe you could come
with me, since you speak...
I could pay you.
I know a place where
they sell them cheap.
- Tomorrow?
- What time?
In the morning. 8?
Will it be this cold?
Colder.
Nilda?
I don't speak spanish.
Here's my office.
The rooms are in the back.
This is the living room.
- You sleep here?
- It's the best.
If I get bored,
I take off.
Put this on, it's cold.
Come on, Lito!
Where are you going?
There's a lot to choose from.
Hurry up.
I have to be back at 12.
Come on.
Do you study English?
You learn by force.
When I got here, I didn't
understand a word.
Theytalked to me in English
and I couldn't get it.
It was so hard to understand.
And they started calling me Per?
Lito, give me some money.
Aren't you going to eat
your hamburger?
And the fries?
I can't digest fried food.
Come on. Your wife's sick,
not you. Eat something.
You like it, don't you?
Get off here, Gramps.
Don't get lost. It's two blocks away.
How much?
Shitty town.
Nilda?
She's in dialysis.
Nice to meet you.
I don't understand.
Nilda...
Died.
Do you have friends?
They send me to tell you that you have
a message from Contreras Gonzalez.
- Thank you.
- Wait.
How's yourwife?
Fine.
How do you call
BuenosAires from here?
Let me help you.
And it's so hard
to find a job.
If you fall off the train,
you can't catch it again.
Don't worry, Peti. Don't be silly.
Everything will turn out fine.
But you know me.
I always see
the glass half empty.
Looks like they found Chiche.
Did you hear him? Chiche is
coming forthe generator.
He's in the hospital.
His stomach burst.
You know what he was doing?
He used to go with
a hose and a drum...
and he stole gas from
the cars parked outside
He was getting away with it.
And this time he went to Recoleta.
It's full of security guards
in that neighborhood
and there are cops there too.
One of them followed him.
He put the hose in his mouth
and started sucking...
and one of the guards caught him.
He got scared and swallowed gas.
And when he tried to run,
they shot him.
I told him that
the Chiche was stealing.
Chiche's an idiot.
No, he isn't.
Cool it.
He almost lost his life
because of the factory.
We're just down here
taking water out.
You complain all the time
and Lito's in N.Y.
The phone's ringing.
You go, it's all dark.
Contreras, Lito.
Lito, how's Nilda?
Fine.
I'm about to leave the hotel.
We have some problems.
When are you sending
me the draft?
We still need the signature
from the bank manager.
Is Nilda there?
I'd like to say hello.
Hello, Lito?
He hung up.
Do you mind if I take
the towels, Gramps?
I have to leave the hotel with
the bags and go to the hospital.
How much would you charge me?
That's no charge, Gramps.
Why don't you go
pay to save time?
- Pay?
- You can't leave without paying.
I don't understand.
Please call Peru.
Peru.
He says your card's been
rejected. You have to pay cash.
It's been rejected?
That's impossible.
I reserved two days
from Buenos Aires.
You have to pay forthree
days plus the phone calls.
Tell him that in two days
I'll get a draft in dollars.
He says you have to pay for
your stay or he'll call the cops.
- Is he calling me a thief?
- No, a South American.
Tell him I've always paid.
That I've always been responsible.
That I don't owe a penny.
Wait for me outside.
Call the police, Sting,
and the whole fucking squad!
Have a little compassion!
No wonder you're
in the rut you are!
Run, Gramps!
I made you lose your job.
No problem, Lito.
I've got other jobs.
Yeah, you shouldn't have only one.
Ahouse, a wife, a job.
That's no good.
You have to move. You shouldn't
settle down anywhere.
Orthey grab you
by the balls.
If you don't believe me,
look at yourself.
- What?
- Forget it.
I'll take you to the hospital,
you pay me
and I'll take off. OK?
Listen. I need you
one more day.
I'll pay you.
Come on. We just ran off
because you had no money.
Just one more day.
Please.
Money's no problem
I have a lot.
Is there a problem, Gramps?
Please explain to her
that I want them...
to permanently make
her face up.
Money's no object.
What did she say?
That the idea of permanent
make-up is to enjoy it in life.
That doesn't matter.
Permanent make-up.
She can make her up lightly.
No. No.
The permanent job.
I promised her.
It was herwish.
Sara...
Yes, Sara Santamarina.
It's hard to get understood.
- Why didn't you tell me?
- I'm going to make a call.
Sara.
I don't know if you
remember me.
It's Julio Litoracci.
Nice to talk to you.
Listen, I'd like to talk
to you in person.
Just the two of us.
Without Nilda.
Yes, I have the address.
What time?
Lito!
Problems.
See you laterthen.
Thank you very much.
What is it?
$24.291 dollars.
$24.291 dollars?
I already paid $2.000.
Here I have $3.200.
And the day aftertomorrow
I get a draft from Argentina.
Listen.
If the make-up is so important,
pay for it and keep $200.
Meanwhile we can wait
forthe moneyfrom Bs. As.
We can sell these.
You have to pay with something.
We can make some cash with
the jewelry plus the money...
You know her?
No. She was stealing.
Some guys started hitting her
and cut her head open.
I brought her
to the hospital.
Is she coming too?
You want to go back?
- What's that?
- Agreat meat store.
LooksArgentine.
It is. Come on.
Come on, Gramps.
Good morning, Argentina!
How are you, man?
Fine. How are you?
This is a friend of mine, Lito.
Chango.
Lito had a problem and
we need some help.
Martita.
How are you, Martita?
I've been waiting for
my orderfor 2 hours.
My van broke down.
I didn't forget.
But you remembered to put
the musician outside.
He's a tradition.
- Did you remember my gizzard?
- Don't insult me.
My van broke down.
Here's your order.
I added some extras.
They're delicious.
Martita, should I put
it on yourtab?
Obvio, Chango.
"Obvio, Chango."
- Did your van break down?
- No, I just forgot.
Theythink I can make
a living making sausages.
What do you need?
Interesting.
- Is there more?
- Like always.
I'm with a Russian girl that
can get me a few things.
You believe her?
She's alone
and out of money.
We can try.
Plus you need some bait
to get to the Russians.
- You have more of this?
- Yeah.
- Where?
- In the batmobile.
Go get it.
- What was your name?
- Lito.
Go through that door
and come around the back.
- Here?
- Yes.
The mate's good.
Nilda says you should have
3 mates in the morning...
and 3 in the afternoon, and
you have no stomach problems.
Wait a minute.
Put it here.
So Nilda's yourwife?
She was.
- I'm sorry, I didn't know.
- That's why we came.
Lito needs some cash to pay
the hospital bill.
How much does he need?
- $20.000
- What?
Let's see what you have.
With that shitty music,
no one will come in.
Are you Argentine or what? You
only sell me soap and towels.
Is this your family?
Yes, my wife.
She died two days before our
first grandchild was born.
She's here in the cemetery.
Wait yourturn.
What about the Russian girl?
I met her on the river.
On a cab.
Let's do this.
I'll give you a hand,
and you can help me too.
I still have
some merchandise left.
I used to sell them on
the street.
But after 9- 11 things changed
and no one wants this.
But they're tough. Talk to her
and see what you can do.
Here. This is forthe jewelry.
But if you give me a hand
with this, there's more.
- Ready.
- Ready?
- You have a place to stay?
- My batmobile.
You're kidding, Peru.
I'd take you home, Lito,
but with 3 grandchildren...
there's no place to breathe.
- Is this far?
- Let's see.
No.
I'm Lito Litoracci.
I'd like to see Sara Santamarina.
Lito!
What a surprise!
I'm glad you came.
Welcome! Come in.
Excuse me.
You take care of her.
First, his name is Ricardo.
Second, he understands
everything I say...
and like you, he doesn't
want to speak Spanish.
Sorry, Lito. Come in.
Just a minute.
Please, sit down.
I'm about to finish my class.
Excuse me. Let's continue.
What were we saying, Paco?
Acomplete sentence.
Very good.
Everybody.
Again.
- Have some.
- I don't drink alcohol.
The best coffee in the world.
Puerto Rican coffee.
The coffee the Pope used to drink.
And this is aged rum.
- Since I don't drink alcohol...
- You can't reject my rum.
OK.
What were you saying?
With Nilda, we spoke about
the permanent make-up.
Since she saw yours.
That's why I came.
You want to see my
permanent make-up?
Let's begin with the brows.
Then the lips.
First this side.
It's my best side.
Do I look all right?
Perfect.
I can't believe you're
doing all this for Nilda.
Whatever Nilda says,
it's an order.
Some women have all the luck.
I'm so glad you're
staying for dinner.
Your company makes
me feel so good.
I'm going to make a dish
specially for you.
It gets cold in New York.
And I make ice.
I feel it most
in my hands.
Don't you have gloves?
I haven't had time
to buy any.
I have a pain'to give you.
But it's so cold out,
you can sleep over.
I have a spare room
you can use.
And underneath,
as you may see
there's a knife that cuts the ice
which falls into the tray...
and then the cubes are
bagged for distribution.
So you sell ice cubes.
Aspecial kind, because
there are manytypes.
I make round ones with
a hole in the middle.
- Did you like the food?
- Very much.
I hope you're not hungry.
I only cook for myself.
Not for your daughter?
- She eats with herfather.
- I wish I knew where he was.
She says that eating here
depresses her.
It's the best meal I've
had in New York.
Thank you.
See? That's the last stage
of the production.
This is the ice we
can produce...
and which we want
to export.
That way we can create more
jobs, more production
and get a better result
for the country.
We can export to many countries.
We have our eyes set on China.
There are over 1 billion
inhabitants.
There aren't enough cows
in Argentina...
to feed the Chinese
people one day.
That's whywe decided to offer
our actions to everybody.
You, for example, could
buy actions.
Lito...
- Do you like coco pudding?
- Yes.
Lito...
Is it OK?
If it has a wrinkle,
I can't sleep.
Thanks.
Thanks for cheering up my meal.
I haven't had the in a while.
- Nilda used to like to cook.
- She doesn't cook any more?
No.
Some women don't know
what they have.
Good night.
Lito.
You're going to scare me
to death. You disappeared.
You don't have to worry.
If you hire me,
I worry about you.
Did you sleep here?
She says they're finishing
the cosmetic surgery.
No, no.
I taped Sara Santamarina's
face so they could copy it.
You can see her, Lito.
Go on.
- I can't do it.
- Neither can I.
- I'll pay you.
- No, Lito.
- Here.
- Money doesn't matter.
Don't do this to me.
He speaks Spanish.
Hello. Take a seat.
Nilda, with God.
Here you are.
I have to go.
She says you have to sign
some papers and wait a while.
I'm going with the Russian girl
to sell Chango's stuff.
Come on, Gramps.
Four eyes see more than two.
Sleep well last night, Gramps?
- How did you guys sleep?
- Fine. Why?
- Since the car's small.
- You find ways.
You came directly
to the hospital?
We slept and came
directly here.
Why the questions? You want
to know if I fed her?
I'm just asking.
I'm not yourfather and
I don't want to be.
You're adults and you
know what to do.
We're adults and you
sound like a child.
- Why are you angry?
- I'm not.
You aren't?
Why the face?
Hey!
Somebody's there.
What are they doing?
It's Chango's box.
Damn you, asshole!
They took everything!
Son of a bitch!
What a son of a bitch!
She's a bitch!
Damn you, old man!
I was ripped off
because of you!
What a damn bitch.
Was I screwed!
You can tell me and
then I can tell the girls.
I'll be your eyes.
What eyes?
Now go to the hotel,
take a hot bath,
sleep all night. In the
morning, have breakfast,
and get dressed.
Put on yourturquoise sweater.
It matches your eyes.
Your grey pants. I don't
know if we brought them.
And your jacket, it's cold.
You want to go home
and take a shower?
What can I do?
Let the factory fall apart?
How are you, Chiche?
It hurts when I yawn,
but I'm OK.
What do you want?
Don't tell me you
want your salary.
What are you doing?
That's Lito's office.
Get out of there.
Take yourfeet off.
What do you want?
This isn't handled
so easily.
You're not doing so well,
Contreras.
We haven't been
paid in 2 months.
Next month...
Looks like we won't get
paid next month either.
So what? You're
going on strike?
When Lito gets back,
you talk to him.
We've talked it over and
we'll decide in a meeting.
- Hello.
- Contreras?
It's Lito.
How are things overthere?
Listen, I only have
a couple of coins.
You know when
you're coming back?
The draft didn't get here.
Send me some money.
I'm on it.
How's Nilda?
Nilda... She died.
She died?
What do you mean?
It can't be.
I'll explain later. Please send
me some money, I'm stranded.
Things aren't well here.
We're doing what we can,
but there's no money.
- Put a mortgage on the house.
- We already did.
Send me something, please.
Hello?
Polaco told me Peru
would screw me. And he did.
And he screwed you too.
What about yourwife, Lito?
She's in the morgue.
The nurse, Greta, told me
if there was someone...
Orthey'll send herto
the university and...
Don't worry about the money.
You can pay me back
some other day.
I'll accept it, and I'll
pay you back for sure.
It's not that.
What else can
I help you with?
Is that truck yours?
This is crazy.
What if the police stops us?
What do we say?
Want to see her?
- I don't know how to thank you.
- It's nothing.
It's OK. Come on, let's go.
God be with you.
Staywith God.
Where?
The second door, Lito.
That one, open it.
Lito, you want to say something?
Nilda...
You're in New York...
where you wanted to be.