Paris, Two Thousand Ten.
Faced with rampant crime in certain
suburbs, or barrios,
the government authorized
the construction of an isolation wall
around cities classified as high risk.
Come on! Let’s go! I'm starving.
They ain't ready yet.
OK. They're ready.
Help yourself. Go on.
I must have an effect on you fags, huh?
I step outtake my car,
and you're already hot to trot.
We don't want no shit here, K Two.
Whaddya talking about.
It's just a friendly visit that's all it is.
Sniff... Smells good here too
Merguez?
Delicious!
Want some?
So... is your boss around?
We ain't seen him today.
That's okay. I don't mind waiting.
C'mon relax. Go on, search me.
I ain't armed clean as a choir boy.
Look, we don't want no shit.
You better go back.
What's with you guys?
We can't communicate
for once we're together,
and y'get all nervous and shy.
So get movin', will ya?
We don't feel like talkin'
The boss ain't here.
We told ya. If you want,
we'll tell him you were.
That's really nice of you
Anyone got a piece of paper?
I'll leave him a number.
No, I'll write it on the wall.
Won't get lost that way.
Nothing on the wall.
Oh I forgot. This is Mister Clean's
apartment building.
Real fancy guy your boss is, huh?
Yeah, it hurts you to see a building
still standing in this shithouse of a city.
I think it's great.
It makes the city more lively.
So, where do I write the number?
Gimme your hand.
Gimme your hand,
I said. If I was gonna cut you,
I'd a done it a long time ago.
Look at him, armed to the teeth,
and he's scared of a pen.
Don't worry man about it.
I'm not gonna press hard.
Why do you wanna see Leito?
He's got some stuff I want.
Things that belong to me.
There you go.
Now, you got a good reason not to wash.
Now that was a nice friendly visit.
Why don't we shake on it, huh?
What's your name?
Tarik.
Tarik, let's shake.
That's better. Don't be afraid.
This is worth a picture.
I wish I had my camera.
Right guys? Smile, come on.
It's okay. They're with me.
So you feel like talkin' all of a sudden,
but it's too late.
You go up the stairs.
I'll take the elevator
For once, it's not broken.
Call downstairs, the elevator's coming.
You could do it yourself, you know.
Tarik, who's comin' up?
Tarik!
Fuckin' thing never works right.
Hey move it, we got visitors.
Look, if I don't watch the end,
I won't be able to follow tomorrow.
Tarik, would you say somethin'?
Tarik!
- Tarik.
- The picture's gone. Hurry, fix the antenna!
Hey, I ain't your nigger.
You do it man.
Tarik, will you answer me!
You're too worked up man.
It's probably the food being delivered.
That's bullshit. Since when do
they deliver an hour early, huh?
You're such a pessimist.
Leito's apartment,
you wouldn't know the number huh?
It's fourteen.
Thanks.
Son of a bitch!
There ain't no numbers on the doors!
Get 'em all opened!
I'm lookin' for Leito.
It's not here, I swear!
Then tell me where it is, asshole!
Down the hall and left.
He got his name on the door.
You're coming with me.
I don't trust signs.
Go right...
left...
the third door.
What're ya tryin' to do, get me killed?
Alive, remember?
Taha wants him alive.
Move over...
On three, huh?
One... two...
Catch the bastard!
Get it open!
Come on!
The roof, hurry!
The stupid fuck!
There he is!
Stop me if I'm wrong.
You get ripped off twenty kilos of power.
At nine, you know who did it,
and you go to get it back.
How many were ya?
Ten, twelve.
Ten, twelve huh?
And about noon, seven of you come
back empty-handed.
Anything else?
Well, we coulda iced the guy,
but you wanted him alive so...
That's fantastic.
Before long, it'll be my fault.
That's not what I wanted to say.
He's like... a...
like a bar of soap, he's...
Oh, is that so?
Well, yeah.
Let's see, fifty a gram, twenty kilos.
Don't bother counting. It's a million,
in euros.
That's very expensive soap, huh?
So, which one of you
has a suggestion for me
so he doesn't slip away again?
Me! Me, I uhh I got an idea.
K Two, that's great. Go on.
Well, since it was Leito
who dumped all the dope,
then he's gotta give us the cash for it.
That's just common sense.
I asked you for an idea.
Wait, hold on!
Go on.
His sister Lola.
Leito's sister works at the supermarket.
If we've got her,
he won't stay in hiding for long.
That's what I call an idea.
Go and get her.
We'll be right out.
Come on, the boss wants to see you.
The boss is waiting, I said.
You heard, so get off your ass...
He never comes in on Tuesdays.
I'm not talkin' about that scumbag.
I mean my boss and yours Taha.
Taha can go fuck himself.
Let's me go!
Let's me go.
What the fuck is wrong
with everyone today?
Hey K Two, is she my birthday present?
I'd love a piece of her.
She looks just my size!
Watch your hands.
Hey, we gotta search her. Huh?
We already did. She's clean.
C'mon, share the wealth.
Leave us her panties.
When I come back, I'll bite your balls off!
I got other plans for you mouth.
You'll like it a lot more.
That's for openers, slimeball!
Hands off her I said. She's for Taha.
And you cut that shit out, okay?
It's me.
K Two is here.
I know your face. Show me the girl.
Okay, bring her up here.
Make sure he knows we got his sister.
Spread the news.
I wish I could see the cocksucker
when they tell him what happened.
You're lookin' at him now,
you son of a bitch.
Why don't I cut you now
and that'll be the end of it.
Cut me and there's a pack of wild dogs
that're gonna be out a master,
and that might not be too cool.
What're you after?
You see Taha, that's the difference
between us two.
You never know what's in my head,
but I know all the shit going on in yours.
I'm always a step ahead
because I know what you're thinking.
Hold it, K Two. It's okay.
Stay nice and calm.
We're just talkin'.
Yeah, just talkin'.
Look, tell me what the fuck you want.
Stop busting my balls
and let's get this over with.
Two things.
Yeah, go on.
Y'leave my building alone. No dealing
for five hundred meters around it.
Yeah okay. What else?
That's easy. Your life for my sister's.
I let you go.
I walk out with her, and if none
of your guys move, we got a deal.
Y'know, you shoulda gone into business.
Yes or no?
Okay, it's a deal.
I got your word?
She ain't enough?
Give the order.
K two, let her go.
You heard me. Wait downstairs.
K Two, will ya stop your fuckin' thinking
and do what I'm tellin' ya to do?
Get down now
or you'll never get up again!
Look, I kept my word.
She's free, so now let go of me.
Patience, Taha.
Y'think you're gonna get outta here
in one piece?
Y'think every here is your buddy huh?
Listen,
I got a deal with this guy, okay?
I said that he and his sister could go.
And so make sure nobody moves,
and everything'll be cool.
Hey you...
Open your mouth.
Chew it, pig! C'mon, eat me!
She's my kinda girl.
You can't have her. Go on.
Move it!
Let's go!
Okay, let's go.
Clear the way. C'mon, move it.
This way. Faster.
Hey, get rid of this fuckin' thing.
Hurry. Move it.
Go on! Go on, move!
Stop your vehicle. Stop your vehicle.
Okay, hold it. We brought you a customer.
We want the inspector.
Make way for us. We're comin' in.
Son of a bitch.
Hey, can't you settle your scores
someplace else,
'cause we're closing up here.
It's Taha. Taha Ben Mamoud.
Doesn't the name mean
something to you?
I know him, but I told you we're closing up
by order of the government.
So if you can't show me some proof,
I can't do anything.
Five kilos of heroin taken from off
his desk, with two wit nesses.
How's that?
There are too many of them outside.
We're outnumbered.
Okay okay, since you insist,
but first your weapons.
Hand 'em over, and you men,
keep your eye on Taha.
Oh, poor na? Ve Leito.
I'll bet you really think it's gonna
change something, don't you?
Maybe not much,
but you gotta start somewhere.
Now we're gonna eliminate
the paperwork, okay?
You go into the cell, and you go pick up
your dope and clear out.
Don't that for Chrissake!
If you let him go,
it'll be worse than before.
It won't be worse 'cause we're getting out.
When the shit falls, we'll be far away.
You won't be here,
but it's still gonna go on,
and you're the ones
who're supposed to stop it.
I'll bet that you still believe that.
The barbed wire
and the walls, did you forget that?
They're gonna put a lid on it
and blow it all up.
That's what they'll do to make
the shit disappear.
As for you, be grateful you're here
'cause there are some guys outside ready
to make dead meat out of you.
Why the hell are you still here?
Like you said, there are a lotta guys
out there all ready to do what I tell'em to.
Stop that shit, Taha. You're free.
Y'got your dope.
What the hell more do y'want?
The girl.
No! No!
Now get out.
No!
I'm warning you, touch me and you'll...
Lola! Lola!
Don't worry. I'll take good care of her.
Gentlemen, it's always a pleasure
to do business with you.
So long.
No, no!
Take her to my office, tie her up,
and give her two grams.
That'll calm her down.
Okay, okay, let's get back to work now.
I didn't have any choice, kid.
I've been in this area for fifteen years.
I'm retired as of tonight,
and I'd like to take advantage of it.
It was her or me. I'm sorry.
You shoulda chose my sister.
You're already dead.
Six Months Later
Digame Pedro,
what you got against my car?
My name's not Pedro.
Who gives a fuck your name's not Pedro?
I'm talkin' about my car, cojone.
What if I crashed your head in every time
I wanted you to keep quiet?
Hey, it's only a car.
No, it's not only a car.
It's my car, maricon.
I just had it overhauled,
and it cost a fortune.
So I suggest you show
some fucking respect for my car
or you'll find yourself under the wheels.
Comprende?
Forget it Carlos.
He didn't do it on purpose.
C'mon, what the fuck's the matter
with that guy, huh?
I'm sick of these kids
who don't respect anything.
Anybody can close a door
without slamming it.
It's okay, he's gonna take good care
of your car from now on. Right Pedro?
My name's not Pedro.
What's more, the door's got a squeak.
The garage takes a fortune
and gives me back the car
with a squeaky fucking door!
I'll get rid of the squeaking, Carlos.
I promise you.
We gotta recruit better, Benito.
It's getting bad.
Remind me to talk to Frank.
Okay.
I'm tired of getting
all these Portuguese guys.
Sawdust in the head. Campesinos.
I'll talk to Frank about it. Don't worry.
I want men with an education, damn it.
Hire good prospects as soon as
they get outta school.
Guys who wanna use their brains instead
of hanging out all day.
Benito, there are six million unemployed
in this fuckin' country.
Two or three shouldn't be
so fuckin' hard to find.
Yeah, Frank'll get us
some good men, that's for sure.
Well, what're ya standin' there for?
Very good.
Place your bets.
Twenty seven.
You won't forget me Carlos?
No problem Mr. Keijman.
End of the week, as usual, huh?
Hijo de puta.
He's got balls that asshole, huh?
Remindin' me about his kickback
with all the money he owes us.
People got no education nowadays, Benito.
Get downstairs!
Hola. Que tal?
Everything okay, Sammy?
No, things are pretty terrible.
Oh yeah? What's wrong now?
Everyone you see is a cop.
One there, and two there.
They've already spent an hour
choosing a can of corn.
They're perverts.
Perverts? What're they doing
in the food section?
Nada. They're just waiting for two AM
when the hookers use
the coffee machine there. See?
You got here at one ten,
and outside,
look what's happening now.
What's that?
Perverts, and I don't think they're gonna
spend hours looking for corn.
Anything else suspicious?
Yeah, most of our regular players
didn't show up tonight,
and it just happens to be the day
we transfer our money.
Yeah, and so you're saying...
...that a real big transfer
can be very tempting.
All you have to do is put the cops
onto the deal,
and you get ten percent
of the money with no risk.
How d'you know that anyway?
'Cause I've already been offered it.
You must've been tempted.
How can you be sure it was a real cop
who approached you?
You're pretty clever, huh?
It's the only way to stay alive.
That's for sure.
You went to school, right?
Economics.
Bachelor's degree.
Yeah, I was right. Y'see the difference?
So somebody's tryin' to rob us, huh?
And rob us big time.
Didn't I tell you that that Pedro guy
was pretty fuckin' weird?
Hijo de puta.
His name wasn't Pedro.
Who cares what his name was?
I ain't puttin' up any monument huh?
Okay, grab all the money and let's go.
No one's goin' anywhere.
Sacks down, hands up, huh?
Benito, what're ya doing?
I'm not Benito anymore.
The name's Damien.
First Attack Division Carlos Montoya.
You're under arrest, you hear?
Benito, you've gotta...
You have the right to remain silent.
Whatever you say
can be used against you.
Any threatening gesture or false movement
will be considered as a refusal
to cooperate thus putting my agents
in a position of self defense. Clear?
What does all that shit mean?
It means one false move,
and I paint the place red, Capito?
Yeah yeah. And how do ya think
you're gonna get outta here in one piece?
We're gonna stick around here some more.
Sammy, you and your friends clear out.
Why the hell did ya let them go?
Because you're the big one.
Chameleon in place. Are you guys all set?
We are Chameleon. Here it comes.
What do we do now?
What are you asking me for?
You went to school.
C'mon, enough of that.
What's goin' on?
You okay? Nothing broken?
No no, I'm okay.
Glad to hear it.
Chameleon to carrier. The delivery's ready.
Commencing operation.
Okay, c'mon out of there Sir, please.
What now Einstein?
Step on it. It's getting hot over here.
The wire damn it.
Hey, you better send me
some ammo and quick.
They didn't take the money.
Go on, shut the door.
Go on, they're waiting for you.
What a great sense of timing you guys go.
Okay guys, go go go go. Come on!
This way. This way please, everyone.
- Just keep moving. C'mon.
- Come on, come on man. Easy does it.
Good job.
Captain.
You're the fuckin' biggest son of a bitch
I ever met, you scumbag!
That's the first compliment I've had all day.
When I think I trusted you like a brother.
A brother?
You mean like washing your car
for six months before giving me a real job?
Oh, that door of yours,
the one that squeaks?
It doesn't squeak anymore.
It's Captain Tomasso, Colonel.
Thank you. Show him in.
Hello Damien.
I'd have much preferred simply
to congratulate you for last night's operation.
Unfortunately however,
we have a real emergency. Sit down.
I'd rather stand if it's okay with you.
As you like.
You know Mr. Kruger,
the Secretary of State for Defense,
and Mr. Corsini, his assistant.
They need a man of courage
for an extremely delicate mission.
Mr. Kruger, I'll let you explain the situation.
It happened yesterday. In the afternoon,
we were transferring material
in an armored vehicle
when we had
what you might call a little incident.
No no no no no no!
I don't want your dirty sponge.
It'll scratch the windows.
Shit!
One day, I'll get 'em for that.
The good news is that the vehicle
had a lot of tracers in it,
so we know exactly where it's located,
and we're asking you to get it back.
Where is it?
What's inside of the truck?
What is this shit anyway.
An experimental scatter type bomb,
sometimes known as a clean bomb.
It's a prototype based
on neutron technology.
Medium range, about eight kilometers.
The waves are of short duration
and are absorbed very fast.
The risk of polluting the atmosphere
is close toi zero.
You're worried they'll move the bomb.
Is that it? It wouldn't be so clean
in the center of town, would it?
Yes, and that's one
of our primary concerns.
What's more, the bomb is equipped
with a timing mechanism set
for twenty four hours.
Unfortunately, it was triggered accidentally,
and that was exactly an hour ago.
Y'mean that in twenty three hours, it'll...
It'll explode.
- K TWO.
- Yeah?
Y'got twenty four hours to sell this mother.
Can't be done. Too short.
Captain,
we're not asking for your advice on this.
We're trying to explain
your mission to you.
Colonel, you know the way I function.
I study the terrain for weeks and weeks.
Then it takes me months to infiltrate.
Damien, there are
two million people there,
and maybe half are the scum
of the earth,
but the other half are entitled
to our assistance.
So you're gonna change how you operate,
unless you don't care anymore
about saving innocent people.
But accepting a mission
that's a lost cause is totally crazy.
You want me to defuse a bomb
in the worst barrio,
Where I've never even been.
Couldn't be more attractive.
As far as the site goes,
we've found you a local guide.
Plus I've gotta work with someone.
He's a young man who was born there,
and he knows the barrio like a book,
so he'll save a lot of precious time.
And the guy, did you force him to do it,
or is he a volunteer?
He doesn't know yet. We're counting
on you to convince him.
Leito,
transfer.
Where to?
Shut up.
Prisoner 712, in the van.
Let me go! Let me go, godammit!
Come on, get up!
Prisoner 713 in the van.
Fuck, he bit me, the asshole!
You okay?
Never better.
The fucker thought I'd let him kick
the shit outta me without doin' anything.
I'm gettin' outta here.
You think playing around with the lock
is really gonna open the door?
You say that because y'don't know
who I am yet. The name's Phantoman.
And Phantoman doesn't plan spending
eight years locked up.
What'd they get you for?
I blew away five guys,
buy they weren't the right ones.
The guy I wanted got away.
What'd ya want him for?
He murdered my father
and my two brothers.
And it hurts to know
this guy is still breathing.
So soon as I'm outta here I head
for Barrio Thirteen
and finish the bastard off for good.
Does he live there?
Yeah, and he's gonna die there.
What's the guy's name?
Taha. Y'know him?
You're not missing much.
I made the big mistake of trying to do
some business with the guy.
He lives in a kind of hangar
with an army protecting him.
And he struts around the place.
Him and his human vegetable.
What human vegetable?
A junky. He keeps her on a leash
like a dog or something.
I never was anyone so doped up.
Lola's her name, I think
I'll be back in two minutes flat.
Hey, there's a space here in front.
Can I drop you somewhere?
Barrio Thirteen'll be fine.
You got it.
Damien.
Leito.
Okay, they've left the prison.
The plan's going according to schedule.
Are they still together?
Yes, they're in the front of the van.
It shouldn't be hard to spot them.
Excellent. Congratulations Colonel.
I wouldn't claim victory so quickly.
It's much easier to get out of prison than
it is to enter Barrio Thirteen.
And that is when we'll see how good
a guide your Leito is,
Because without him,
Damien's going to be out of luck.
Your captain can take care of himself.
I'm gonna need your help
because I don't know the way.
Any idea how we can sneak in discreetly?
Yeah. Go straight.
Hey, cut that shit out. What're ya doing?
I won't lose you this way.
Take those fucking things off me!
You wanna get inside?
Yeah.
Then from now on asshole,
I'm Phantoman,
and you're gonna do whatever I want.
Now floor it, huh?
What do I do now?
Go on, straight ahead.
Okay, turn right, now.
Turn right I said!
Hey, I heard you the first time,
but the wheel won't turn.
Okay, stop the car.
The brakes are gone too!
Then stop it against another car,
but go easy.
I didn't say to smash the car.
Okay sorry, I did the best I could,
but no one's stopping you
from getting a new driver.
Now let me go, huh?
What's wrong?
You should feel at home, man.
What're you talkin' about?
You're a cop,
and a cop who thinks
I'm an idiot doesn't live long.
C'mon Leito, let me go, y'hear?
This is where you wanted me to take you.
Okay, so you're here.
Now take out your police manual
and look at the page
that says, "I'm up shit's creek"
Leito, I'm not a cop for Chrissakes.
It's true. Let me go damn it.
It's thanks to me you’re out of jail.
Yeah, I wonder why you did that.
Somebody needed me to be set free.
But whatever the deal, count me out.
Even if it's to save your sister?
She doesn't need anyone
except her brother.
Fuck!
Hey, y'know that's my car
that you just fuckin' wrecked.
Sorry man. I broke outta jail an hour ago.
This piece of shit didn't have any brakes.
I was coming here for a little shelter.
For shelter?
You got bad directions man,
'cause this ain't no Monaco. It's Baghdad.
Tell 'em to calm down.
Cool it. Easy.
Sorry about your car,
but in exchange take mine.
How's that for a deal?
Well, did you sell the bomb or not?
It ain't about that, Taha.
It's Leito.
Leito?
He broke out an hour ago.
Won't be long before he starts bangin'
the door down.
Hey, wake up.
Your brother's on his way to rescue you.
Be careful.
Okay.
First of all, how'd you know I was a cop?
The way you move.
Nobody around her moves
or fights like that. It looks too clean.
When you come from the street,
you got one thing more.
Oh yeah, what?
Hate.
Right. Sorry to disappoint you,
hate wasn't part of my education like you.
They taught me Liberty,
equality, fraternity.
Water, gas, electricity.
You don't give a shit about laws,
do you, wise ass?
Sure I do, but I want 'em to be
the same for everybody.
But they are, and I'm here to make sure
that they're obeyed.
No no, you're just a pitbull
who bites for his master.
Yeah, when laws aren't obeyed,
that's what I do.
This is where I was born.
It was already pretty bad news.
Then they built a wall around us
when I was eighteen years old.
Did I do anything wrong to rate
that punishment?
No, I respected every fucking law
to the letter.
And I didn't quit school
in ninth grade to sell crack.
It's because they closed the school down.
The only thing I ever did wrong
was getting born here.
And what the hell
is burning people's cars gonna change?
You know any other way
for us to get heard?
Not immediately, no.
Want me to tell you what's goin' on,
and why I sprung you?
For a good cause I imagine. Am I right?
Yeah, for a good cause.
There's a bomb here
in this goddamn armpit of a barrio
and if I don't defuse it in two hours,
Barrio Thirteen's population will be zero.
So if I think the way you do,
I could say to myself,
"What the fuck do I care
if two million losers get snuffed?"
But no, there's always an asshole
who's willing to fight for the idea that
laws are made for everybody.
And now, you help me locate that bomb
or you protect your own precious
ass like all the bourgeois you criticize!
There's really a bomb around here?
I don't even wanna know
why it turned up here.
Who's got it, Taha?
That's right.
He's got your sister and my bomb.
That's two good reason to work together.
If you're lying again,
you're dead, man, huh?
Deal.
So what's your plan?
Tell me exactly what Taha's place is like.
I'll figure out how to sneak in.
I find the bomb, and once it's defused,
we go after your sister.
- While I do nothing.
- No,
you've gotta create a diversion.
Taha's gonna make you his priority.
That way, I'm sure not to be disturbed.
Y'think it'll work?
Y'got a telephone?
Yeah.
Hand it over.
- That's not Phantoman, it's James Bond.
- Okay, okay.
Yeah?
It's Leito.
How did you get my number?
You can buy anything in jail.
I heard you were out.
I'm over at the factory.
Hey wait, who're you calling?
Well, what do ya want?
Listen, I'm with a cop
who's got a deal for you.
I'll send K Two to get you.
What're you outta your fuckin' mind?
The plan was to sneak in for Chrissakes,
not to advertise that we're coming.
Discreet, man,
oblique, meaning never in their face,
playing it cooler than cool.
Forget your police manual, will ya?
You're in Barrio Thirteen here.
It's different here,
and I know Taha by heart.
Trust me, it's our only play.
So what's your plan, huh?
We fight his two hundred goons
and the winner's whoever's not dead?
No, no one's gonna die.
There's only one thing that works with Taha,
and if we use it, it'll give us time.
What's that?
His curiosity.
Who's this cop he's talkin' about?
What is this?
Whenever I ask a question, I get a mmm...
Hell of a vocabulary.
Okay, find out everything about the guy.
I mean everything.
And I want him here, not at the morgue.
I'll be right back.
Count me out. Too risky.
You're dead if you go it alone.
I've always worked alone,
and I'm still around so fuck off.
Ciao.
I know Taha's place like the back of
my hand all the exits,
even one I dug out myself.
Good, I'm happy for you.
I hope you didn't hurt your hands.
I know where the bomb is.
You'll never find it without me.
A couple of minutes ago you didn't know
there was a bomb.
What is this bullshit?
Taha's got a safety vault for valuable
things, and I know how to get in.
How'd ya know he put it in there?
Where's he gonna put it,
in the kitchen?
Okay, here's the deal.
I set you free, and you shut up
and do what I say. Okay?
No, I've got another deal.
You keep it shut and you pray
my sister is alive, and then you behave.
I'll get your bomb.
Now uncuff me before we're in deep
shit up to our necks.
Deal.
Is this guy the cop?
What a sense of deduction,
K Two. I'm impressed.
That's very funny. If Taha doesn't finish
you off, the pleasure'll be all mine.
C'mon, let's go.
Follow us, and no bullshit.
We're the nervous kind.
Guard duty isn't for sleeping!
Sorry, but I dozed off.
- Where is he?
- In the back.
Did you feed him?
He eats all the time.
I got some work for you,
so you can stretch your legs a bit.
They could wipe out the city
with all this shit.
That's the van that transported the bomb.
At least you're sure it's here.
Stay here. I'll pick you up on the way out.
Very funny.
Seems you got a new pal, a fuckin' cop.
He's no pal of mine.
He's the only one who can defuse
the bomb you stole yesterday.
The only one?
At countdown zero, everything goes
for eight kilometers.
And you of course have come to save us.
There's a code that'll stop the timer
and will save two million people or more.
The state sends us a brave cop to save us
from a nasty bomb that without
our pal here, is gonna go boom.
Great
story.
Thanks, Superman,
but let me be honest with you.
Y'see, we weren't planning on hanging
on to your bomb.
So, you want it back?
Yeah.
How much?
Taha, if I don't punch in the code
in an hour, the bomb will...
I know, it'll explode. So what?
It's no concern of mine,
as long as it's not where I live.
But if you don't want it to blow up
where you live,
well, like they say,
you better Cough up a little dough.
It'll kill millions of innocent...
But they shoulda thought of that before
when they made it, for example, huh?
So, how much?
A million... euros.
I have a million on my right for openers.
Do I hear a higher offer? K2?
Two million. I have a two million bid
on my left so,
who'll double that?
Here.
Nice bid, four million.
Four million, four million on my right.
Have you decided on a limit?
When y'think our lives aren't worth
the price, tell me, and I'll stop bidding.
Ten...
ten million on my left.
Good, now things are getting
a little lively.
Well, Blues Brothers?
Ten million.
There's only one of its kind.
Y'want it or not?
Well, since you've got no more
to fork up ten million's the price.
Ten million going once...
ten million going twice...
Twenty!
A handsome bid,
in the eleventh hour too.
K Two?
No, that's good. He can have it.
Twenty million.
Wrap it up.
Twenty million victims
that's about ten euros a head,
the price of a couple of burgers.
Cash or what?
Forget cash.
I couldn't ever get to the bank
and then bring the money back here.
The bomb would explode before.
Djamel,
give 'em our account number
in the Bahamas.
First, let me see the bomb.
That's funny.
I was sure you were gonna ask me that.
Help yourself.
Your bomb didn't have a launcher.
Lucky I always keep
some equipment around here.
We found a Russian
launcher we sort of modified.
Your baby's ready to go.
As for the direction, I decided to point it.
I'll let you guess.
Y'satisfied? You've seen your bomb.
Now, make the transfer.
You see, Leito,
I learned something from you.
Now it's me who's one step ahead.
Find me Kruger. It's urgent.
zulu zulu fox delta charlie.
How much has to be transferred?
Twenty million euros.
Are you sure the bomb is there?
It's in front of me. I can even read
the 48 minutes left on the screen.
Captain, we don't have that kind of budget.
You've got to manage otherwise. I'm sorry.
Okay, I'm waiting.
They're making the deposit.
Okay, thank you Colonel.
It's done. Twenty million euros
are in your account.
Now let me start on the bomb.
Our deal's not quite finished.
Djamel, call the Bahamas
and make sure the money's arrived.
That's what I'm doing.
The bank doesn't open
for another half an hour.
Let's hope it opens on time.
If you two don't mind,
go wait in the next room.
Get over there.
On your knees. Face the wall,
hands behind your head.
Yoyo, watch these two
until you hear from me.
What do we do now?
Hey, don't forget we did what you wanted.
If we'd have played it cool,
we wouldn't be here.
Yeah, and if your buddies
had paid the transfer,
we'd already be outta here.
Already dead, you mean.
You don't suppose
Taha would've let us out of here?
We'll never know,
since your pals refused to pay up.
Now at least you know
how much your life is worth.
Come on, To them,
I'm not worth anything at all.
Damien,
there's something not right
about this whole thing.
Like what?
Something. I dunno what.
They lose a bomb like we lose our keys.
They want to get it back,
but they won't pay.
Look, when it comes to blackmail,
they're very peculiar.
Hey super cop,
what're you, defending them?
No, but there are values, real values.
The ones I thought you defended too.
How much time we got?
37 minutes.
It wouldn't hurt to have an idea.
Yeah, it wouldn't, huh?
I think I got one.
Well?
Remember the tunnel I told you about?
The one that you dug?
That's right.
It starts in the toilet,
to the left of the elevator.
And Yoyo of course
is gonna let piss together.
No, but if we think up a good reason
to go and see Taha,
he'll take us to the elevator, huh?
Okay, and once we're at the elevator?
We improvise.
I've heard better plans, y'know.
Got another one?
No.
Then move it.
Get down right now.
We gotta see Taha. It's super urgent.
It is, huh?
Well for now,
you're gonna super get down
and super keep your mouth shut.
Got that?
You must be a super dickhead.
What's your name again?
What the fuck do you care?
It's for Taha. When he asks me whose
fault it was that he lost 20 million euros,
I don't wanna get the name wrong.
Listen, if you're fuckin' with me,
we're gonna have to snuff you.
Deal.
You three come with me.
The rest of you, cover us.
I wish I knew what we were doing.
Stay loose and just let it happen.
Get ready to go.
Now!
It's down there.
That's your way out.
Through the bowl? Great!
Jesus, you shoulda been a cop.
They'd've loved you.
Follow me.
What's goin' on down there?
What's happening?
Why don't y'answer when I call you?
We were in a tunnel.
I would like to know what the fuck
you're talkin' about.
Well, it was because
of those two assholes.
They got away through the tunnel.
We tried to catch up with them,
but then the walky talky...
Hold on a second.
Repeat that once more.
Leito and the cop, they...
Djamel,
what about the transfer?
We got problems, Taha.
He was bluffing?
Yeah.
I shoulda known!
You can't trust a cop. Never!
Even with a gun to his head.
But he'll pay for this, the bastard.
I'm gonna detonate their bomb.
Taha Taha,
I think you had better sit back down.
They used the Bahama account number
to move in on all of our numbered
bank accounts,
and they cleaned them all out.
What's that? All our...
Bahamas, Ryad,
Karachi, all of them, even London.
Nothing zero.
But how's that possible?
If I ever learn that I'll be king of the world.
In the meantime,
this dumb little accountant
is going back home.
Excuse me.
Hey Taha, if you're broke, then
how the fuck y'gonna pay us this week?
I got cash in the safe downstairs,
and no one's about to rip that off.
K Two, your piece. Hand it over.
K Two, give it tome, huh!
You are a bunch of fucking shitheads!
What do we do now, K Two?
First, we better find Leito and that cop.
Okay, move out everyone.
We better separate!
Outta the way! Move!
Police!
How long before the bomb goes off?
Ten minutes.
And you're sure you can defuse it?
Yeah. What's more, I'm the only one.
Well, you go and stop it, and...
and Leito stays with us.
No, I need him. He comes with me.
No can do.
Okay, Leito and me will stay here,
and you defuse the bomb.
How's that. You better go.
You got nine minutes.
Okay, you both go,
and I'll wait for you down below.
You gotta come down sooner or later, huh?
If I do the job, I'll bet even
you'll be glad to see a cop's face.
What the hell is that?
A present from Taha.
Let me handle this. I love presents.
Hey Mongol, y'ready now for me
to teach you a thing or two?
Go on.
Nice going. Where'd you learn that?
In a cookbook or a fishing manual.
I don't remember.
It's all over Lola. It's all over.
No. Sorry but it's far from over.
Fuck this man, I can't get through!
Okay, got it.
Hey, don't worry. He's an expert with cuffs.
He'll get 'em off in no time at all.
Hello.
Captain Tomasso. I'm in front of the bomb.
I need the code.
Where are you now?
In front of the bomb
with three minutes thirty left.
Gimme the code and we'll talk later.
Where are you? The exact spot.
On the roof of a building in Barrio 13.
Y'want a weather report as well?
Good work Tomasso.
We're all very proud of you.
Thanks, but time's running out.
9293...
929 what?
Three... seven zero nine B thirteen.
Seven zero nine B thirteen.
I'll call you back if I'm still alive.
B thirteen? Like Barrio Thirteen?
Yeah.
Doesn't it seem strange
that the bomb's code is Barrio 13?
9293, the two zones we're in.
Just coincidence.
Damien, wait. Hold on.
If the bomb wasn't scheduled
to come here,
why the hell does it have
the same numbers as this barrio?
Look, whatever it is, I gotta stop it, huh?
Damien, listen. What if it's the reverse?
Come on, the reverse of what?
You detonate the bomb
with your code instead.
Why send me then if they wanted
the fucking thing
to explode in the first place?
Explain that.
So it blows up right where they want
the center of Barrio 13.
Gimme the exact spot
was what your boss asked,
and you said Barrio 13.
Yeah, but that's a security measure.
It's a trap, Damien, I'm sure.
Get off my back and let me work.
I already saved your life once,
so trust me.
I'm a military officer with a mission.
That's what I do.
I'm sorry.
Cut this shit out Leito. In one minute
we're all gonna...
Open your eyes, Damien.
Nobody gives a shit about this barrio.
Twenty years
and they can't solve the problem.
They built a wall around us.
Now they're gonna clean it out for good.
How come there are no civil servants
here. No post office or school,
and just by chance,
the police station was shut down.
But the bomb was stolen, Leito.
They didn't make that up.
Oh yeah? The van was attacked
by some bad guys, right?
It was, yeah.
That's the story they told you, huh?
Yeah.
Then tell me why just before,
when we saw the van, it was intact.
Where were the signs of an explosion
or of a smashed in door?
Maybe it was a different one.
It was the same and you know damn well.
And once they were sure the bomb was
on the inside of Barrio 13,
and that it wasn't going anywhere,
they got their best pit-bull to set it in motion.
And you really accomplished that mission.
You stopped Taha from dumping it,
so it's all for us.
It can't be possible Leito.
Y'don't kill two million people
'cause you can't solve their problems.
No? They murdered six million because
none of them was blond with blue eyes.
Sorry Leito.
Sorry.
Don't do this, Lola!
I prefer dying for my brother's dumb ideas
than for yours.
It's over.
This time, it's really over.
No, it's not over.
You see? I said that even
you would be glad to see my face.
Y'got five minutes to leave here.
How about a souvenir?
Yeah, be my guest.
Thank you.
Nothing yet.
Jesus! It's well over an hour
that we've been waiting!
And if by tonight nothing happens,
then what?
I've no idea Corsini. For Chrissakes,
it's supposed to explode and that's that!
What's that?
Sounds like a fight.
Go and have a look.
There. Mission accomplished.
Well, not quite.
At the last minute,
we couldn't remember the code.
We both tried, huh?
But it's my fault, totally.
It was me who forgot my numbers.
- You remembered yours, right?
- Oh yeah.
Hey, he's incredible.
We made an absolutely fantastic team,
you know.
And without Leito, I'd be dead now.
Okay, let's have it.
Like the two zone numbers?
Yeah.
That's wild huh?
A coincidence.
Now we got seven zero nine.
Easy to remember. That's today's s date.
Seven zero nine
September 7th. End of summer vacation.
Practical huh?
A bomb explodes on the day
you know everyone's around for sure,
and you get rid of all the scum in one shot.
If I'm mistaken, stop me.
Now then, the code...
I think that I've got the rest of the code:
B 13,
like Barrio 13.
How could I have forgot?
Why don't I give you the honor of finishing?
Are you telling me you plan on blowing up
this bomb here in Paris?
I'm sorry, but I thought the code
was to defuse the bomb.
You mean that if I punch it,
it'll do the opposite?
Stop playing the fool Tomasso.
You know perfectly well...
No I don't. Explain it to me.
I wanna know what...
Barrio 13 is uncontrollable.
It costs a fortune to the state,
the taxpayers are worried... worried,
frightened
and fed up paying for such scum!
So we clean it out?
With a bomb I guess, huh?
Yes, it's not very democratic,
but it solves all the problems.
Except one,
yours, Sir.
No, I beg of you, please...
Look, why don't we clean up everything?
You want us all killed.
You should've thought of that first,
when you built it.
No!
Y'really thought
I was gonna go through with it. Why?
For revenge? No. You don't always need
violence to solve problems.
There are ways much more democratic.
Look out the window, and smile.
Is the sound okay?
What are you plotting, Tomasso?
I'm doing my job Sir.
You know my job, don't you?
I see that laws are obeyed
obeyed by everyone.
I make sure that no one forgets that.
That's my job. No more, no less.
Now, if you still don't understand
you can see it all on network TV.
Barrio 13 is uncontrollable.
It costs a fortune to the state,
and the taxpayers are worried
worried, frightened
and fed up paying for such scum!
So we clean it out?
With a bomb I guess, huh?
Yes.
It's not very democratic,
but it solves all the problem.
Barrio 13 is uncontrollable.
It costs a fortune to the state,
and the taxpayers are worried
worried, frightened
and fed up paying for such scum!
So we clean it out?
With a bomb I guess, huh?
Yes. It's not very democratic,
but it solves all the problems.
Except one, yours.
You sure you don't wanna stay
on this side?
With the reward you'll get,
you can buy a real nice place.
I got a nice place.
Besides, this is where I live.
I was born here.
Now all I want is to live here in peace?
But you're gonna, Leito.
They're gonna be demolishing
the wall next week.
The police, the post office
and the schools all open next month.
You know it's thanks to you all of that.
You brother, are the greatest.
I've been saying that for years.
C'mon, will you smile?
You look so down.
I hope things don't get messed up
on the way,
and that they keep their promises.
Hey, these things aren't words.
They were voted on,
and government
decrees have to be applied. It's the law.
And there's always an asshole like me
around to see that laws are obeyed.
Take care of yourself.
You make it sound as
if I live in the barrio like you.
Your neighborhood's
more dangerous than mine.
I'm not so sure.
Come and see us.
Can't promise I...
He'll come. Yeah.
Hello.
Thank you.
Go on.