More than
six thousand soldiers,
And the same in Police...
Banned air traffic.
Snipers on the roof.
Secret agents.
Politicians.
We had the idea of
flying a spy plane
above the congress...
to see what would happen
to see how long it would be
before they shot it down.
Well, here we are now,
and nobody dares...
- What number have you got?
- 36.
There's two 26's.
- Boys?
- Yes a boy.
I'll get it to you
as quickly as possible.
She's in debt...
Nowadays she lives on mate.
Who's she in debt to?
From today's government.
That's why they live like that.
You can see it now.
Last year
there were no boats...
in February.
Today there are.
He's saying the system's on
course again so that's positive
Now the debt must be paid.
Now, who is to blame for...
the last 100yrs
in Argentina?
Psychologists say the IMF
are like analysts.
It's an act, but for us it's
the central analytical part.
DEBT
lmagine the world: Instead
of having 6 Billion people,
it is a town of
a 1000 inhabitants.
In that world there are 506 men...
and 494 women.
Do you know what's the most
spoken language in the world?
It's Mandarin... 144 people
in 1000 speak Chinese.
60 speak Hindu, 56 English.
53 speak Spanish.
In that town of 1000 people,
there are 6 Argentines.
And 3 of them live below
the poverty line
1 out of those 3 has some
degree of malnutrition.
One third of that world,
330 people, have anemia.
More than 10 %, 130 people,
have chronic malnutrition.
Half of the town of a 1000,
500 people,
live with less
than $2 a day
and 200 with less than $1.
The 200 richest people
have 86 % of the wealth
and the 200 poorest,
only 1 % .
In reality, the world has
6 Billion inhabitants.
It'd be good to give
these numbers a second thought.
But talking about
billions of people.
What I wanted to do...
and I spent 6 years trying...
was to open the program showing
what television was like.
In the end,
6 years later, I showed
the workings I wanted.
The idea of seeing studios...
walking through corridors
showing all about television
clerks, chorus girls,
kids from a reality show,
corrupt politicians, cooks
a magician screwing a girl...
Then we could say: This is it,
what you see is television.
It was in vain,
a week later...
what we thought we'd captured,
surprised us again.
What did you eat today?
Because we saw you there.
Omelette.
- And last night?
- Nothing.
- Do they feed you at school?
- No.
CHILDREN THAT FAINT OF HUNGER
- Are you sad?
- Yes.
Why! What's the matter? Tell me.
We didn't eat yesterday,
we didn't have the money.
- How old are you?
- Eight.
What'll you do when
you grow up?
Nothing.
It's simple and atrocious
and terrible to see.
I've never seen anything like it,
either in life or on TV
And the worst is, I found out...
the girl was called Barbara
like my daughter, Barbara,
who may be viewing the program
in another part of town.
That's how I met Barbara Flores.
THE GIRL THAT FAINTED OF HUNGER,
SHE NOW HAS MALNUTRITION.
TUCUMÁN: THE GIRL THAT FAINTED
IS AGAIN UNDERNOURISHED.
After that interview,
Barbarita became a symbol.
And she and her mum started
going round the studios.
From then on...
nothing could be controlled.
Barbarita, in the media circus.
Have we done the right thing?
She was on the cover
of "Gente"
"Personality of the year",
I don't know if it was worth it.
After the interview, campaigns
to send food to Tucumán began.
I was touched by their pain,
that really touched me!
Everything we are,
feel and dream...
goes through our brain.
It's our fastest
growing organ...
It rapidly develops the shape
it has in adulthood.
It takes an incredible
amount of energy.
Can we compare the brain
of a child with a machine?
A byte is the minimum unit
of information in a computer.
It's a dot,
a letter, a character.
1 billion bytes make a Gigabyte,
the unit for storing memory.
A computer like this
has between 4 and 5 Gigabytes...
of memory capacity.
This means about 1800 books
of 300 pages each.
You know how many Gigabytes
that boy has in comparison?
500,000. He can store 227 million
books of 300 pages each.
During the first few months
of growth...
the brain creates
100 billion neurons...
which will create 100 trillion
possible connections between them.
In the 3rd. Week of life,
embryos develop...
250.000 cells per minute
that give the shape of what will
be the spine and the brain.
By week 7, the neurons begin
to multiply at an incredible rate,
and will continue after birth
depending on supplied nutrients,
to connect with the largest
possible amount of neurons.
In its 1st few months, a baby's
brain is almost complete.
It's now the body...
that begins to grow.
The brain normally consumes
half the sugar in the blood,
a quarter of the nutrients and
a fifth of the oxygen consumed.
And a huge amount of proteins,
almost 2 mg per minute,
and 84 different minerals.
But if all these nutrients
didn't exist,
the development of the brain
would be different.
The growth of the neurons...
and their connection
would be less...
and therefore would
reduce fat tissue,
destroying vital muscles
and organs.
You see, the brain destroys
the body in order to feed itself.
Malnutrition in this case will
kill in between 8 to 12 weeks.
And he's wearing glasses
He's got to have a beard
Give it to me...
like this... look...
The eyes and beard
are like this.
Mine have been undernourished.
Now, thank God,
they're better...
because I struggle a lot.
Have they been undernourished?
No, No! Under weight. I've a boy
of eight and a girl of nine.
Have you just arrived?
Three more meals over there...
One of the girls in the soup
kitchen was undernourished.
Lord. Bless this food
we're about to receive.
Now the government is giving us
70 cents per child,
In the soup kitchen we can
only have ninety children.
Feeding a police dog costs
nine pesos a day.
We receive 170, 180
according to the lists.
BARBARITA TOD AY
Be eternal the laurels
that we obtained
Why Barbara?
Why?
And not my son,
I'm in a worse situation.
But, she's the chosen one.
How can you explain
she was chosen by Destiny?
Or hunger...
or chances?
In this school, this girl
has been assigned a priority.
And not any other child.
Barbarita's mum is the sister
of my sister in law.
- The Barbarita's family.
- This is Natalia's cousin.
She has malnutrition
as does Natalia,
How do you explain to those
that haven't received anything
that it wasn't personal, it was
not because of them or Barbara?
What I don't understand today
and I'm not talking enviously.
It was all of them,
they were all in the shit.
And all the things
went to one little girl.
I wouldn't profit from a
daughter to be able to eat.
The little girl kept repeating...
I thought it was terrible...
that the girl
was so well trained.
My dad has no work
and my mum gets no support,
we are a big family..."
She'd learned it by heart.
When you were doing the
paperwork in Buenos Aires,
she came with clothes,
hair and hygiene products...
and her mother sold them.
There's a lot of people here
that have kept quiet.
This could be called:
"The poor against the poor".
- How's it going?
- Fine, thank you.
Hi! What's up? Come in.
How are you sweetheart?
What I've noticed from some
of your neighbors...
is that they criticized you
for selling the clothes...
That's true! But I didn't sell them.
I swapped them for goods.
I want to be clear for all
the people who don't know.
Imagine, I have...
5 bottles of oil
but have no bread for the kids.
- Sure.
- How do you manage?
I go to the store and say,
Will you swap a bottle of oil
for a kilo of bread, "No!"
Well! So 2 bottles of oil
for a kilo of bread? "Yes!"
They negotiated with me,
I didn't negotiate with them.
Now, is it her fault or?
It's not her fault.
She's a kid.
This generated one thing,
"Barbarita, Barbarita...".
What's also true about
what happened to Barbarita,
is that many people sent
many things to everyone.
Yes! Yes! It's true.
It works.
All the media chaos and
the social chaos was good
to list all the undernourished.
There's 28,000 to 30,000
undernourished in the province.
And the population is?
400,000 under 14 years old.
When did it all begin,
as far as I know,
the undernourishment,
the people hungry,
began, more or less in
or around 1966
- During Onganía's...
- They closed the sugar mills.
People lost there jobs and
kids lost out on nutrition...
people used to work in the mills
from my dad, an accountant...
to the local people who
were manual laborers,
they would eat round a table
and had a good standard of life.
Is the increase in malnutrition
related to this? Yes!
Look what I have here!
This is a photo of Tucumán.
Or at least what it looked like
until the mid sixties...
Do you know what that is?
A plan of Alsogaray and Onganía
changed the economy of Tucumán.
As requested by the World Bank
who wanted to modernize it.
They felt the best thing to do
was to concentrate the industry...
into a few firms and get rid
of the smaller businesses...
that sustained the economy
in the province.
They did it. The cost of that
was to close 11 of 27 mills,
More than 200,000 people in
Tucumán lost their jobs.
Because of the sugar debate
and the concentrated market...
the lemon business appeared.
Today Tucumán is the 2nd
biggest producer of lemons.
19.4 % of the world's lemon
exports come from Tucumán.
The 1st producer is the USA
Why the lemon?
It's cheap to produce and
whole families work unofficially...
for a pay that
is $1 or $2 a day...
for the whole family.
When we speak of malnutrition
we don't mean one generation,
we mean the sons of those
already undernourished.
So why build a 5 star hotel
in the Third World?
Because it was near Venice,
as I always say.
He's a legendary Italian chef,
His name is Cipriani,
he invented the Rissotto Primavera.
The 3rd world is a
European invention,
it doesn't exist.
He's a European,
millionaire
who has partners in Angola...
for money laund... I mean,
to open a hotel in Uruguay.
The idea of the Public Debt has got
more to do with a financial concept...
than with something real.
Do you all know
what debt means?
Lets see! Someone tell me
what debt means.
- When you owe money.
- When you owe money,
only money?
Anything else?
The Ministry of Economy
explains the International debt.
Come on.
Think of a typical family,
for example.
When they don't have
enough money, they borrow.
When you run out of money,
do you borrow?
He earns $25,000 a month.
Money isn't everything.
Countries and people borrow
money from richer countries.
England's growth happened...
thanks to the large
Public Debt it had.
Yes! Also the U.S.A.
I think the Public Debt should be at
the service of other initiatives.
I think there must
be a Public Debt.
Numbers are incredible!
There's numbers for everything.
Look! It's the social debt.
To avoid poverty, Argentina
needs that blue bar.
16 billion were needed
last year...
For the people not to be
below the poverty line.
It's more or less
the interest of the debt.
The more I think about it
the more I can't understand.
What do you need to react?
Too much agony.
You and your coffee
Surely at night it'll
be champagne.
You have it
all and you want more,
nothing's left
for the rest.
You can be seen
suffering on T.V.
But if you see misery
you change the channel.
It's not true that
we either eat or we pay
I believe we must try
to pay and eat.
Honestly, I believe all
debts must be paid.
The debt must be paid...
in any possible way.
In this country there are jobs
but people don't want to work.
We're in Uruguay,
there's lots of Argentines
and lots of debt.
No, it can be paid,
we must make an effort.
BECAUSE SHE HAD NO FOOD SHE
FED HER CHILDREN WITH CATS.
This is from last year
in the "Gazette".
What she says isn't true:
She never ate cat.
She says it's true because
she had cat skins in the fridge.
It's a lie,
it's a lie!
Not even she believes that.
The neighbors laugh...
what else can they do.
Listen there's no need
to kill a cat and eat it.
I never saw her working...
things don't come for free.
Aug 6th,2002,
they saw this
in the Washington Post.
After the collapse of
the economy, poverty...
is taking dignity
as one of its victims.
35 lbs of rice, cereals,
nappies, carrots, potatoes...
this is what they sent.
People in the U.S. A,
who sent us...
all these things
Are complaining due...
to the paper work
and bureaucracy.
Lost papers...
The boat arrived on the 5th
and was held until the 24th
24th, October.
Are you blaming "Caritas"
for that?
No, I'm not blaming anyone,
I'm just saying,
that what you said about
the ship being held...
at Customs.
It's a lie to the people!
Because in the Customs
that I administrate,
we check, and
whatever arrived
from the USA was rubbish.
I'm not ashamed...
of my country but...
but in the US,
I was embarrassed to go...
into those people's homes.
Saying "I'm from the place
where you sent the food..."
Then came an odd media event.
The Customs Chief...
and a "Post"
journalist were shouting...
and I didn't know
who was right...
Until I met the people
that had sent the things.
I started to question myself,
Thinking back...
I asked myself...
Why do we blame others
and never ourselves.
They should worry about
malnutrition in the country,
not only in Tucumán,
your country has
a lot to do with it.
It's got nothing to do with us?
People would like to help,
are you saying they can't?
We accept the help!
Come on then!
Come on!
Without control?
There must be control!
Now we control!
Before they smuggled
weapons, drugs...
We control.
- This is Franco...
...s a baby.
And me?
What shocks me most
is the lack of men...
in the neighborhood.
The men must be sleeping,
and I don't want
to bad mouth them.
- What does your husband do?
- He's on Benefit.
And Friday, Saturday and Sunday
he has his music like the rest.
They get the benefit.
So now they're resting.
The parks here are full of men
and youngsters playing soccer.
My husband left me 3 years
ago with 8 children.
I had a two month old baby
when he left.
And I carry on.
My daughter is in 4th year.
- How do you manage with ten?
- How do I manage?
I go out and I beg.
Everyone asked!
"Is it true?"
They didn't believe it.
I say it's true...
and they never asked again.
They call me the "cat eater"
How is it possible in a country
full of food...
that children die
of malnutrition?
We're either mad or we just
cannot govern our Nation.
The responsibility...
belongs to those who have
the nerve to talk.
Every day at 5pm, they start
to distribute food.
Ask him if that matches
the American dream.
This is very odd. Were there
any poor people in Washington?
There were.
And this is even odder,
they were eating
in a soup kitchen.
The building you see behind
is the World Bank.
This is the toilet.
You dig a hole, lay the tiles
and put the toilet on top.
This is the toilet.
The toilet.
I don't have a toilet.
They said a thousand times
they'd build a sewage system.
You don't have sewers!
There are no sewers!
In 1992 there was a project,
to build a sewage pipe line...
at a cost of $26 million.
It would have been treated
in biological pools.
The Nation provided resources...
from organizations
to international finance.
That work was planned,
offered to society, tendered...
It received the resources.
They weren't used...
for its completion.
I think that
the Bank's worries...
are not only
that countries pay
but that it creates
an impact...
and benefits the people.
To fulfill
the credit's objective
You spoke
of the sewage works...
If I'm not wrong,
ten years ago there was
a project to build...
the biggest plant
in the city.
They didn't have the resources
to complete it.
They sent 10 million dollars.
They built the 1st section,
and then stopped.
Here we are at the bottom of
what should have been a pool.
The development loan
is actually a rescue loan.
Then they use the loan to patch
things up, not to build anything.
Ok, we shall have a crisis in
6 months, let's invent something.
We say we need 500 millions
to paint Avenida de Mayo green.
We never paint but with
that money we pay salaries.
You cannot pay salaries...
with money that's there
to buy books.
They got the loan
as a cover up
The bank has an evaluation
committee for all the projects...
that's independent from the bank
Every time they consider
a loan...
they study the risks extensively
I believe that
the Wolfenson era...
was spectacular
in the sense...
that it created a "renaissance"
in terms of combining...
knowledge, technology,
infrastructure,
human capital and a social role.
When we went to ask for
the resources to begin...
development we found out
that the resources
had been sent to Tucumán
The Nation couldn't send
the money twice...
Tucumán had already
received the resources,
the work was still incomplete.
Most of the loans had local
subsidies, were budgeted...
then added to external finances
If the local subsidies
are not there,
Argentina, like every country
pays commission on commitment
What's the commitment rate?
When a credit entity
lends to a country...
it deprives another country
of the use of that loan.
It's a commitment
that they assume.
They pay the interest
as if the loan was on course.
Actually the money's frozen...
If we borrow money
and don't spend it,
we still pay interests.
So we owe twice, we don't
have the money or the work.
That's the commitment rate.
The infant mortality figures
are getting higher...
More cases of malnutrition
with more debt,
So obviously we're not
doing things right.
There are two things.
One: Why are we in debt?
Our debt is for things
to go on as they are,
while someone gets richer.
Argentina has always
had a debt...
which it couldn't pay back!
This is a part of the history
of Argentina, always in crisis,
getting money to save itself.
I always say there are 3 things
that should be addressed:
Illegitimacy, insolvency,
and co-responsibility.
A new chapter in the Argentine
economic history begins.
We've turned the page of state
interference and oppression...
to give way to the freedom
of productive powers.
So the IMF,
the World Bank
and other international entities
found it a solution...
to assign that huge
amount of dollars...
to countries that
would absorb credit.
Argentina was among
those selected.
This means,
the international debt...
is created, in fact
not to solve its problems...
but to solve the problems
of the banking world.
The 80 % say: Who is he?
That is the question.
Yes! Who was Olmos?
Where did this "nonpartisan"
man, come from...
who denounced the debt?
Who was Olmos?
Well! His story
is important because...
it was the only case
that came to trial.
There's 3 causes.
Olmos I,
the debt during the Junta,
Olmos II, the debt under
democracy from '83-'92,
The Brady Plan & Megacanje.
The debt has no economical
foundation or any other.
The debt comes from
illicit acts...
Who knows where the funds went?
Olmos was persecuted,
had no job had no identity...
for more than 10 years.
Considered disappeared...
Were you asked at school
about your dad's job?
- What did you say?
- Journalist,
I didn't say
he was in prison.
May '57.
How old were you?
Five years old.
The landlord that sheltered dad
as a fugitive and my brothers.
When did he start worrying
about the debt?
At the beginning of the
military dictatorship.
Term of Martínez de Hoz
Right yes!
Frondizi talked to Martínez
de Hoz and he tells him,
his political Project was to
dismantle the Argentine Industry.
Frondizi says this
in a public act in '82
and Olmos reports
his speech...
and tells the judge: "this guy
conspired against Argentina".
That was Olmos's power,
he was a man who said "no".
That's all that was needed
a guy that said "no".
Who would take the report
to the judge and...
and would say no.
Hello.
I'd like to speak to
Martínez de Hoz, please.
- Who's calling?
- Jorge Lanata.
He's not here right now.
What time will he be in?
After 9 o'clock.
Please tell him
I'll call back.
- O.k.
Thank you, bye.
They take over
power and start...
the National
Reorganization Process.
He takes charge of the
presidency until the next day...
The debt is 160 billions.
It's about 180 billions.
180, 185 billion dollars
are owed.
Around 186 billion dollars.
The total debt is 179.702544
and continuously changes.
So it ticks like a taxi meter
every hour of our life, it runs
and Argentina has to pay
1.700.000 pesos in interests.
15.488.233.
What was the role
of the State in this?
- Was there any control?
- Well! Here's the problem.
They talk of the responsibility
of operative levels,
but I feel the role
of the controlling mechanisms
is essential here.
Sir, we received the $200m
loan from the World Bank...
who in the Ministry of Economy...
vouched for the capacity
of repayment?
The Nation's Gral Auditor is
the one who controls the debt.
Regarding the debt, you control
if some money came in,
how it was spent?
Well, we have two areas,
We generally audit...
the Finance and Accounting Dept.
We also watch over the
completion of the project...
and if objectives
have been reached.
We should be doing
a lot more.
There's a bureau in the
ministry that works on that.
Apart from the internal control
that the ministry has...
we also have a specific team
that depends on us,
and there's one in the ministry
for easy access to information.
- Can we see it?
- We could see it.
We wanted to go to the office
of the Ministry of Economy.
The control office for the debt
in the Ministry of Economy,
what happened was incredible.
Yes, Audit Bureau...
Audit Bureau.
First hurdle, the chofer...
Audit Bureau, please.
Can you hear me?
Where?
The President of the Audit Bureau
comes to see the Debt Dept.
He insists.
The president is coming.
Well! We're going in.
I told you: They control
the debt.
Interior, Lift, Day.
- Where are we going to?
- Which floor? - Tenth
- It's in the other building. - What?
Are you going to see the Auditor?
- The National Audit Bureau.
- The other building.
- 2nd floor.
- No! It's on the 10th fl oor,
we've people
at the Yrigoyen entrance.
The auditor isn't up there.
That's the Ministry of Economy.
The face of the auditor.
The Auditor's office
in the Ministry of Economy.
- Ah! Yes! Auditor no!
- Office yes!
- What floor is it then?
The tenth, but let me check
with these people. They've set up
a camp for a few years now
Corridors.
A corridor.
Another corridor.
And here we are.
Did I say they control
the debt.
You don't control how
the money is spent...
- You control whether it comes in.
- Yes.
- Basically.
Can you tell today,
how much the debt is?
Around 170 billion dollars.
On September 30th, 2003
it stood at 166 billion dollars,
plus arrears.
What year did this office
begin to control the debt?
'93, they created
the Audit Dept.
What happened before '92?
It was in a process of
recognition of the debt,
when the Brady bonds appeared,
The "Brady" bonds agreement
is a mix of a previous process.
They consolidated an amount,
they never finished checking.
That was before our time,
but yes... kind of...
So, no registries of the debt.
There's neither
hide nor hair of them!
At that time they didn't know
how much, to who, or why...
when it was due,
at what rate,
it was total ignorance.
- That's not a metaphor, is it?
- No, no, no.
Wasn't there
a note book saying...
Chase Manhattan Bank:
4 billions?
We had to ask to add
up to the amount.
- Ask who?
- The private sector,
to see what their
international debt was.
What's the Olmos II case?
When they implemented the Brady Plan,
he opened another case,
the idea was, something that's
illegitimate can't be legitimate.
The debt was administrated by
Price Waterhouse Consultants
and the agent was the Citibank.
The dealings of the debt was
based on the creditors data.
What the Citibank did was
ask all the banks world wide
if they had made loans
to Argentina
To back up what was said
before, we must point out...
that the government had to check
the registry of creditors...
to get information on the debt
including the Brady Plan...
that was then assigned
through a consulting company.
The process of getting
the resources via the debt...
was done without any
control or registry.
There were only statistics
registries, simple notes.
The Ministry received notification
of the expiry dates...
or the creditors' claims
to proceed with the payments.
What payments? Of the debt
they said we had,
Was it verified?
Let me understand!
If they said...
100 not 200,
was that the same?
No, that's why they did all
the work I'm telling you about.
Alejandro said that in a bank
in Arkansas, they said...
Argentina owes u$ s100 millions.
So come collect your pay.
That was declared here,
we did the registries...
of the debt asking the creditors
how much we owed them...
and after 18 years,
our justice is not very fast,
it came out that there's
a lot of documents where...
the judge agrees with Olmos.
They can't incriminate anyone
as so much time has gone by.
The documents would be worth...
something if the politicians
were bold,
honest, patriotic and if
the Nation was behind pushing.
Up to now that's not happening,
the documents are sitting on
the basement of Congress.
The basement of Congress.
The debt is being paid
unconstitutionally...
because Congress should pass
payment on the Nation's debt.
Our government opens the
door on Congress to see files...
of everything related
to Argentina's debt,
including this mandate.
You don't proclaim transparency,
you achieve it.
The books will be open for you.
This case nobody
wants to see...
has 28 parts, 6333 pages
with 477 irregularities,
5 judges neglected 477 crimes.
It's in the Central Bank.
Anzoátegui, Castillo,
Dibur, Wexler,
and Pati Ballesteros, judge,
he was the one...
who had the case
on his desk for 8 years.
38 times Congress refused
to address the issue of the debt.
38 times it refused to read it,
28 parts, 20 reports,
30 statements, 500 annexes,
30 accountants
5 judges and 477 crimes...
on the Argentine debt
which today is 178.795 millions.
- Hello.
- Is that Dr Martínez de Hoz?
- Yes.
- How are you?
- My name is Jorge Lanata.
Well, thank you.
I'm a journalist.
I know who you are.
I'd like to have a chat with
you for about half an hour.
Could it be possible?
Listen! If it's private I'd be
happy to but no interviews.
At the end of '91, I published
a book called "15 years on".
A chapter in the book
is about the debt.
Ok! Thank you!
Good bye.
No one of importance, Cavallo
or Martínez de Hoz talk in it.
We want to get a Stand By
Credit from the IMF,
We want important disbursements...
from the World Bank and
the Interamerican Bank
as those just mentioned are needed,
not to stop the Convertibility Plan
or to stabilize Argentina,
but it's needed so we
can start negotiating...
the arrangements
of the debt...
with the Commercial Banking
and...
if all's well, we start 1992,
with the debt as a memory
rather than a problem.
The debt that was built through
years of corruption...
is the money that was stolen.
Pay, we must,
but for years they've
killed us with the interests.
We can come to an agreement...
but you can't subject a people
already hungry and in poverty...
to pay a debt.
Our government was the one
that looked for the speculators.
After World War 2, the IMF,
gave Belgium one option:
That they paid only
what they could.
They lent as long as
the country's country's GDP...
didn't go below 10 % .
That was in '49,
it's different now,
now you have to pay.
Come in.
- How are you?
- Fine!
Welcome to our
humble little home.
Claudio Loser was...
the highest ranking
Argentine in the IMF,
He was director for
the Western Hemisphere,
the richest part of the world.
Sorry to interrupt you on Sunday.
That's alright!
It's not any Sunday.
It's our anniversary Sunday.
- Would you like some cake?
- Yes! Please.
This is cheese
and this is peach.
International organizations
pay well, no one starves.
The World Economic Forum
meets once a year in Davos.
To get to Davos, to the
World Economic Conference,
costs any businessman
u$ s 30,000.
Davos is also this:
Different credentials allow you
access to levels of power.
It's not easy to go through
these levels if you're press.
You have to go back.
Credentials for Davos,
for the kids in Tucumán.
Would they let them in?
She's Anne Krueger,
the Vice-president of the IMF.
Those four on the right
are the delegates of Argentina.
They've come to explain
that they cannot pay.
- Five?
- Five.
Your opinion
on Anne Krueger?
She is...
...let's say...
Get to work, do it!
She's very obstinate...
You can't change her mind.
Considering your economy
I can only lend you 10 cents.
The institution as it is,
is like a small market,
a small world where those inside
don't relate to the outside
It's a bureaucratic culture.
They're bureaucrats.
They have there own sports
clubs, gyms, restaurants,
they don't relate
to the rest of society.
If you play golf, it costs
about $200 to $250 a month.
There's a lot of criticism
in the U. S about the IMF,
and World Bank's social dealings
with the rest of the world.
Mummy's over there.
Hello! How are you?
What are you going to call it?
If it's a boy Rodrigo Nicolás,
if it's a girl Priscila Luciana.
We wanted it, we've been
together for a year.
If it's a girl, Priscila, right?
- Yes! Yes.
- And if it's a boy?
- Rodrigo Nicolás.
- How many kids have you got?
- Ten.
We're almost the forgotten ones,
must be because we're poor.
Where does Nancy live?
Hi Nancy! How are you?
How many people live here?
10 kids plus me and my husband.
- How many kids have you got?
- Seven.
- How many have you got?
- Eight.
I have eight kids.
All 12 sleep here?
In this room
and in the other one.
- Who are underweight?
- The little girl...
and the five year old boy are.
You tell Mary:
"I need tennis".
We won't buy them,
we'll get them, you go
to the soup kitchen.
We'll get them.
We'll bring them or Mary will...
There's no initiative,
there's no reason to have,
- these are people that have...
- Nothing.
No toilet, no table, no chair
What initiative can you have...
- There is nothing.
- The problem is,
they just wait for
the benefit and that's it,
They wait for the milk, they do
nothing to better themselves.
You stop them from living,
you stop them from loving.
They don't have a house, car,
shower, they have nothing.
They need sexual education.
They don't feel motherly love,
Maybe with the 1st or the 2nd,
after 5 or 6 it's not the same.
I think that more than love
they lack sexual education...
Sometimes they have many partners,
even from the same family.
That's horrifying
because it's not love.
I'd like to know what you
know about contraceptives.
Nothing at all?
Do you know that we women
can decide...
when we want to
get pregnant?
That's why we've contraceptives.
You've 2, how old are you?
19.
How old were you when you
had your 1st baby?
15.
- How old are you?
- 19.
- How old are you Maira?
- 16?
Is this your 1st baby?
- It's her 3rd baby.
- How old are you?
- 18.
So you had your 1st at 15?
- At 14.
- At 14!
She brings home
another brother.
They don't have partners,
they go back to the family home.
The most important thing is
that they want to get pregnant
as that changes their status.
A patient used to say:
"Dr., I can't go back home...
because my mum won't
feed another baby.
We must blame someone.
It's not the girl's fault that
she's pregnant.
It's the work of the government.
International credit institutions
share responsibility also.
They always blame someone else.
It's very clear that
they share responsibility.
Barbarita, Barbarita...
Teenage mothers.
There's lack of solidarity.
For me, it's the debt.
The IMF is the ultimate lender,
the loan shark that you go
to as a last alternative,
and if the loan shark charges
excessive interest...
and is brutal
the IMF instead,
charges you
with reforms,
with measures that
are meant to "tighten belts"
And normally this falls back
on the weakest in society.
They heard from the press
accusations about corruption,
that didn't stop the IMF
from lending money.
- Why?
- Corruption.
It's a problem...
An internal problem.
The economic policy is also
internal but they intrude.
This corresponds to the mandate.
The economic adjustments...
fall into the IMF's jurisdiction.
We'll try again.
Press.
We can go in.
There's only one door.
That's not the place either.
I don't know exactly.
Here they plan...
the agenda
for the year,
the politicians...
business people,
what happens
in here nobody knows.
We decided to visit
the Open Forum. Can we go in?
There's Stiglitz, one of the
most remorseful bankers.
I asked him: "Does the IMF
have any lessons to learn?"
I asked that
and the answer was
"We always have things to learn".
Like a soundbyte I could use
to analyze with other analysts.
What I do remember, is that
an official asked me...
who did I think I was asking
those questions to?
You're not a journalist.
We're inside the IMF.
Finally, after many phone
calls and mixed information.
They were afraid we would
bring Barbarita Flores.
We're without Barbarita.
There were 2 people coming
with us, now there's 3.
They don't want to answer
our questions or talk to us.
Until we speak with
the spokesman.
They won't go on camera.
No.
Because the camera shows them?
They don't want to be seen.
Well! Let's walk around.
- When are we meeting him, at 2?
- At 2.
The idea is: We go to Dawson.
Am I really trying to get an
interview with a bureaucrat?
What was the responsibility of
the IMF in the Argentina crisis?
How do you explain that a
country that owes 170 billions
is now worse off than before?
How much do you earn a month?
Ask him what would happen
if he couldn't pay his mortgage,
the bank repossessed his house,
his son had to change career,
and ended up working in
"Kentucky Fried Chicken"
and his wife had
to clean houses?
Ask him if he knows that the
image of the IMF is not good.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
We could say, the IMF's
no crook...
but by the way he acts
and the way
he relates with society,
it makes him look like
an accomplice.
The IMF is the agent for
other governments,
say the Italian government,
the Spanish government,
They want a good relationship
with Argentina.
So someone has to be
the bad boy.
The problem is not only the IMF,
it's the people behind it.
Desperate solitary nights...
In there, they take drugs...
Barbarita: For a time I've been
thinking how I can explain,
as I had promised,
what happened to you.
I can't remember it.
I never said anything
but I should have explained.
I can't stand it when...
I can't explain it
The easiest way is
to find the guilty...
I tried...
until I realized that real
life is not like silent films.
I wish it was as easy as it
is in the movies but it's not.
Here the heads of state aren't
the most important people.
The most important are
the businessmen from Europe.
You see more VIPs here
in 3 days than anywhere else!
Did you see that in this film,
they all have an excuse?
They all say they understand
that it's an atrocity.
You come from Argentina,
you know how things are there.
Do you think this is worth
anything to the poor?
On the contrary.
They'll get poorer.
No, no, they talk about how
to stop the explosion of poverty
as happened in Argentina
in December 2001.
I see people in the north
worried about what happens to us.
But I feel they don't
understand what happens to us.
They think they have the answer
to the problems of the south.
They don't realize that they
themselves are the problem!
They make the rich richer
and the poor poorer.
Meeting bureaucrats, men
in ties, italian managers,
professors, golfers,
top novelists,
Guys that say:
"We're looking for solutions".
Yes, it's a farce, nothing more.
This is the heart of Davos
and the meeting's in Davos.
It's like a big stage...
and this place, come on...
These are the important places
They're called "Bilateral Room",
bilateral meeting rooms.
In this horrible brown place
with no ventilation,
The president of the IMF can
meet the president of Nigeria,
Cisco System's CEO
can meet Windows'
Nestle's Manager for L. America
and a Brazilian minister.
There's 200 meetings a day
in the heart of Davos,
It's the big PR operation
of the world's richest men...
in one of the most expensive
places in Switzerland.
It seemed unbelievable, didn't it?
We had to pass all
the stages to get here.
This is Davos.
I asked myself a 1000 times
why we were making this film,
what we wanted to say in it.
I wondered, was worried about
what was happening to you.
And I remembered something
I always say...
A guy meets someone
and asks:
Are you desperate?
Yes! He says!
Are you sure you're desperate?
Yes, yes of course.
Can you sleep?
Yes.
Desperate people cannot sleep.
There was a worsening social
situation in Argentina...
that was parallel to
the increase of the debt.
The money borrowed wasn't
used as it had been promised.
And Argentina's responsible
for spending it incorrectly.
That's Argentina's responsibility.
What's the lenders' responsibility?
Did they lend it incorrectly?
One last thing.
We started this working on the
story of an undernourished girl.
There is a link between
that girl in Tucumán...
and the credit institutions.
One last question:
Do you have any
conscience problems?
Because of the policies
you carry out.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Sounds naive, but I look at you
and ask: How can the world sleep?
Three sad tigers...
Three sad "triggers"...
No... tigers.
...they swallow wheat...
...and they choke.
Let's try again.
3 sad tigers,
...eat wheat...
- Eat! No!
Come back in March.
Maybe we forget,
to be able to sleep...
but I wonder how long
we can keep forgetting.
I believe that the USA
has some responsibility.
The Clinton administration
at a certain time,
gave Argentina an incentive
to keep the Convertibility.
Brazil is the 4th biggest food
exporter in the world.
And they have hungry people.
Argentina is an agricultural
heaven, yet we have poverty.
Please don't tell me
that the problem of Argentina
or Brazil comes from the outside!
What's true is that the verdict
in Washington didn't help,
It didn't rid Argentina
and Mexico of malnutrition.
And 20 years have passed.
We must ask ourselves why...
We must look for alternatives.
But the existing link
is a lost illusion,
of opportunities, failures,
concoctions that didn't work.
If you asked me,
would I rather...
feed a child or pay the IMF,
I'd rather feed a child
but that doesn't mean...
I wouldn't prefer that the money
robbed by the politicians,
was returned in order
to pay the debt,
so Argentina wouldn't be
in so much debt.
I'd prefer that.
Is it the IMF's fault?
Yes! That's no news.
The World Bank also,
The North against the South...
but also the governor
of Tucumán
and president "Who knows".
And the minister of "Who".
The man your life depends on.
It's night now and Anne Krueger
will have her nightdress on...
and she sleeps so well.
The 2000 richest men in the
world are dreaming of big fish.
Cavallo sleeps in Harvard...
and Martínez de Hoz
in the Kavanagh building.
Nobody sleeps well in Tucumán,
and they are all gazing
at the ceiling...
for the desperate cannot sleep.
I'm going to sleep in a while...
even if I now think
I will never sleep again.
But in a while I will sleep.
Never had the world so much
wealth as in the 21st century
Never before had the north
accumulated so much wealth
yet half of the world's
population lives on less...
than $2 a day.
Hunger's a political problem.
But selfishness, the mother
of hunger is a human problem.
You know what? I don't know
if human problems have solutions.
A kid cries of hunger, then stop
everything, stop it now.
Stop! A kid's crying of hunger,
close the bank,
don't go to work.
Get off the buses,
stop everything now,
This camera, this computer.
There's a kid crying of hunger.
Why don't we do anything?
Perhaps as we're cruel,
God created forgetfulness, to forget.
The mirror that we built and
we're incapable of breaking.
It's complicated isn't it?
Barbarita, it's complicated.
Maybe with time we can
find a better answer.
I wanted to talk about you
but ended up talking about us.
I feel I want to ask you to
forgive me but I don't know why,
perhaps I should,
because I've only
just noticed you.
We know we are all
a bit afraid.
It's difficult to get up at times.
Everything hurts.
Yes! Very happy.
He doesn't care
how he'll earn more,
- Is he asking?
- Yes.
He thinks how he'll
enjoy himself.
Tell me, policeman or lawyer
A lawyer earns more.
He mustn't be materialistic
of course,
A good person isn't
materialistic, I believe.
It's true.
My name is Patricia,
I'm 12...
I want to be a vet.
My name's Cecilia,
I'm 11...
and I want to be a doctor.
I want to be a chofer
- Supermarket cashier.
- Policeman.
Car salesman.
- Lawyer.
When I grow up I'd like to be
a kindergarden teacher.
Sometimes you must kill
Sometimes you must forgive
Sometimes you forget...
and smile...
Like fear at night
Like fear in the morning.
And carry on
and carry on.
We know we are all
a bit afraid.
Ripeados por Tylerg
Visita www.clan-sudamerica.com.ar