THE NIGHT OF THE PENCILS
To Beba who encouraged me
THIS FILM IS BASED ON REAL
CHARACTERS AND EVENTS...
A FEWCHANGES HAVE BEEN
INTRODUCED WHICH DO NOTALTER...
THE SPIRIT OR THE AUTHENTICITY
OF THESE EVENTS.
LA PLATA, SEPTEMBER 1975
Stop it!
Let him speak!
- Chicken!
- Strike-breaker!
Quiet, "compañeros"!
No more delays!
C'mon! Quiet, please!
Silence!
"Compañero" Crivelli
still has the floor.
I believe in dialogue,
it's still open.
Fuck off, you asshole!
I insist! We should give
dialogue a chance.
And talk to who?
The Pope?
It's simply a question
of money!
Many of us can't
even buy books!
Finished, Crivelli?
"Compañera" Falcone has the floor.
Let's not be naive!
This dialogue is just another delay.
- Right, Claudia!
- That's right!
No more talking!
We, the high school delegates
of La Plata, are here...
to give in orto fight?
- The UES is taking over the meeting.
- What can we do?
Justwatch.
The student pass is at stake.
At Fine Arts, we believe
the main issue is...
if we demonstrate
tomorrow or not.
Not all of us at Fine Arts
think that!
Shut up, you nerd!
The question is, will there
be police repression?
Probably... and infiltrates, too.
In that case, we could ask
the guerrilla for protection.
- No way!
- Bullshit!
Order, order!
Not a bad idea!
- Right!
- Yes, that's right!
Silence!
Please, think before you speak.
"Compañeros", with
orwithout repression...
tomorrow we'll march
to the Ministry together...
to demand a student pass.
Silence, please!
Let's vote.
Those in favor of a demonstration,
raise your hand.
NATIONAL UNIVERSITY
HIGH SCHOOL
Unfurl the banner!
WE WANTTHE STUDENT PASS
SCHOOL OF FINE ARTS ALL OUT FOR THE PASS
Let's go!
Hand in hand,
with all our might.
TECHNICAL SCHOOLS PRESENT
For the pass we'll fight!
Hand in hand,
with all our might.
For the pass we'll fight!
It's time, time, time,
bus fares for a dime!
HIGH SCHOOL STUDENTS COUNCIL
Hand in hand,
with all our might.
For the pass we'll fight!
It's time, time, time,
bus fares for a dime!
- Good morning.
- Good morning, teacher.
Díaz, to the front of the class.
I demand respect.
Sit up straight.
Stop holding up the wall.
It's a run-down school.
The fucking wall might fall.
Out! I won't stand
for rudeness.
Sorry I said "fucking".
Out!
Stop wasting my time.
Stop it!
Enough!
Why don't you concentrate
on your studies...
instead of demonstrating?
Are you practicing
with a machine gun?
Some beating!
C'mon.
- After you, sir.
- Please, doctor.
After you, engineer.
Look... Claudia Falcone.
She's lost her head for you.
Claudia, give him a chance.
Tell her you love her.
Is she dating a Fine Arts student?
I know everything about Claudia,
but I'm no rat.
Oh, yeah?
Get off it.
We couldn't hand
in the petition...
butwe proved we aren'tweak.
My poor baby!
Stop it!
It hurts when I laugh.
Boy, did they get you!
Tell the others it was
worthwhile, anyhow.
We know the matter is being
carefully reviewed.
Sure, we'll have our pass.
Pablo, what are you doing here?
Nothing... justwalking.
And you?
- Me? School's finished.
- Sure.
- You're...
- What?
Got something to do?
- Nothing.
- Fine. Let's go.
Tucumán,
in the operational zone...
six non-identified guerrilla
were killed by the Army...
in two clashes.
La Plata, Government House.
Any news on the pass?
You must be patient.
There's a rumor.
Once again. It's being
carefully reviewed.
Mendoza...
Bullshit!
They're fobbing us off again.
- We'll have to wait.
- How long?
Afew days.
If there's no answer
we'll demonstrate again.
In politics,
one must be patient.
Sure, Dad.
Where did patience get you?
Leave her alone, Dad.
That I don't know...
but I do know one thing.
In politics, nothing is free.
Make sure you don't pay
a high price.
C'mon... stop arguing.
- Don't annoy your father.
- Ok, Mom.
La Plata...
A Law School professor...
has been reported missing...
while two of this students
were kidnapped yesterday.
- Perhaps your dad's right.
- How would you know?
- Let him speak.
- He's a traitor!
You were a Peronist,
weren't you?
Perón is dead.
And now it's
the Che Guevara Youth.
- Che is also dead.
- That's different. He...
Perón's dead,
but the people are his heir.
What people?
Isabelita Perón?
No. We, the youth.
Hi, Pablo.
Up so early?
- Is Horacio home?
- Sure, come on in.
Wake up, listen.
"To protect
the students' interests...
a cheaper bus fare
has been granted."
The pass!
- No!
- Yes!
Hand in hand,
with all our might,
we got the pass all right!
What about me?
- I won't be back for lunch.
- OK.
One less.
- Good morning.
- How are you?
Hello.
Pablito, I wasn't expecting you.
I finally came.
Thanks.
- Is your sister in?
- Out shopping.
Give her this, please.
You know him, don't you?
Che Guevara.
Never heard of him?
Remember to give her this.
CLOUDY
SUNNY
Underdevelopment
Comics presents:
"The failed revolution
of two Mulattos Mulé".
Today's episode:
"The right book to read".
Text and cartoons:
Claudia and Jorge Falcone.
As usual a parching sun
shone on Mulé Island.
Look!
Someone's shipwrecked!
What a clown!
Sorry, I want to meditate.
Sorry, sir?
The revolution
is like a bicycle,
if it stops, it falls down.
Sure?
Positive.
I've been to the Congress.
The coup's a fact.
Isabelita Perón will fall tonight.
What are we waiting for?
Yes. Social exploitation,
the will to change. It's a fact!
The Mulattos read the book.
I found a secondary contradiction.
While I burn,
you enjoy your hat.
Stop it,
you underdeveloped savages!
Never analize reality
like the ruling classes do.
Rebel against Western culture!
It's over!
Dad was right.
Each people has
the government it deserves.
MARCH 24, 1976
Communiqué Num. 1
of the Military Junta.
As of today...
the country is under
the operational control...
of the Military Junta.
A new era has begun.
An era with a very
clear objective...
National Reorganization.
And the schools,
which cannot be islands...
...will start their
own reorganization.
The high schools...
...will never again
become trade unions...
or political committees.
Schools will never
again encourage...
...the diffusion of atheistic,
antinational ideas.
I hope these words...
will serve as a calm,
but firm warning.
That is all for now.
Welcome to the new era...
of National Reorganization.
Wonderful, Corchito.
- Hi, Pablin.
- Hi.
A super hotdog from Panchito.
Very funny!
No, thanks.
Too dangerous.
You're kidding.
I'm an expert.
Who's the blonde with Horacio?
María Clara?
She's from Bahía Blanca.
She left cause things
were getting heavy.
Don't spread it.
Not bad, huh?
Yeah.
- I'm a lousy dancer.
- Me too.
No, you're good.
Don't believe him.
What's your perfume?
Jasmin.
- What's so funny?
- Mom uses it.
I stole it from mine.
- Tell me something.
- Yes.
Rememberthe meeting
about the pass?
Why did you mention
the guerrilla?
Just had to say something.
You wouldn't let
anyone else speak.
You wanted to be heroes.
That's silly.
But I did shock them.
Look... don't I resemble Evita?
Claudia, I like you a lot.
No, Pablo.
You're very nice, but no.
Stop the music!
- Let go, you beast!
- Keep still!
- The bastards...
- Calm down.
Darling...
Be sensible.
Things are getting difficult.
What am I supposed to do?
I've been Mayor here.
The military put me in prison.
I almost didn't make it.
I know what I'm talking about.
Stop sticking your head out.
You can't ask me that.
You've always said
one has to fight.
I'm not asking you to give up...
but don't be foolish.
What then?
Should I take up embroidery?
Don't rush things.
You've got time.
No, Dad.
I haven't.
You just said things
are difficult.
One has to take sides.
What if the police is inside?
C'mon, you dummy.
Let's go.
REINTEGRATE FIRED TEACHERS
GIVE US THE STUDENT PASS BACK
LIBERATION OR DEPENDENCY
DOWN WITH DICTATORSHIP
IN SCHOOLS
DOWN WITH THE COPS
The face of the witch!
Go ahead, laugh.
You'll get us all screwed.
Shut up, big mouth.
You know how many
teachers they fired?
Fifty eight.
Won't you have anything else?
No, thanks, Aunt... really.
They'll abolish the pass.
They can't. The whole town
will come down on them.
They want us to stick
our heads out.
We already have.
But now the kids are scared.
They don'twant to fight.
They will forthe pass.
It isn't easy.
We're being watched.
I was warned yesterday.
We're all for it, aren'twe?
Yes, slogan-painting
and leaflets.
Then we'll see.
Three students are missing.
The cops deny everything.
Let's meet tomorrow.
We'll see things more clearly.
Some mess!
Claudia...
You better leave your
house for a while.
Stay here with me.
It's safer.
Everybody knows
Aunt Rosa lived alone.
Now kids come and go
all the time.
Remember, María Clara
went underground.
We're not that stupid.
Maybe. But your
security is lousy.
Meet somewhere else.
A revolution takes more
than five minutes.
Bye, brother.
Claudia, you can't rush things.
See? You talk like Dad.
Stop it.
C'mon, Mom.
- What's come over you?
- Guess.
- How much?
- Got to buy things for school.
- Baby...
- Not again, Mom!
You know what's going on.
Be careful.
I am.
Well. Gotta go.
Claudia.
How's your aunt?
- Better than she'll admit.
- How's that?
Really. She likes
one of my friends.
Nonsense.
She tried to seduce Horacio.
It's a pity, though.
The difference in age...
his parents object.
If your poor aunt heard you.
- Bye.
- So soon?
They're waiting for me.
Take care.
We better stop meeting.
I think a cop followed me here.
They want to frighten us.
Can I stay here tonight?
I'm leaving.
Can I take it?
As soon as I finish it.
- Bye, Danny.
- Bye.
I'll see you out.
- Take care.
- Yes, Mom.
You look great today.
Afight to death.
A double lock...
Mercenary Joe
is about to surrender.
Stop it, you blockheads!
Joe's mother tries
to stop the fight!
It's obviously a trick!
Behave and I'll make pancakes.
Do you like Horacio?
Do you like Pablo?
You do like Horacio.
It's late, Claudio.
Go to sleep.
Yes, Mom.
Open up, open up!
Don't move!
What's going on?
Quiet or I'll bust you!
- What is it?
- Don't move!
Let go of me!
Pablito, Claudia's mother
is on the phone.
María Clara, Claudia
and Horacio...
And Daniel and Panchito.
And Claudio too.
What do you think?
Must have been the cops.
They want to frighten them
and then let them go.
I hope so.
C'mon, help me.
If the owner sees you, I'm fired.
Besides... where?
Hey, shorty!
- Get me some water.
- Yes, sir.
Careful, you idiot!
Sorry, I fell asleep.
Hurry up.
Go back to sleep.
- In this Che Guevara group...
- Che Guevara Youth, Dad.
What did you do, apart from
fighting for the pass?
Same as the kids they took away.
Paint walls, hand out leaflets,
work in the slums.
Okay.
If they come for you,
we can explain everything.
Will there be time?
You've got nothing to hide.
Go back home,
and tomorrow to school.
Please, not to school now.
All right. But return home.
You'll be better there
than anywhere else.
C'mon, baby. Keep still!
- Are you Pablo Diaz?
- Yes.
- Where are the guns?
- What guns?
- Don't play dumb.
- I don't know anything.
I swear I don't.
- I swear I don't.
- Talk, you asshole!
Talk, you mother fucker!
Take him away.
Sir, listen please...
It's a mistake.
Please, sir, please!
We'll question him
and send him back.
Please, let me go!
Please, sir, let me go!
Take it easy!
We're going to talk.
Walk!
Don't budge.
Don't touch the wall!
Can't you see?
She's just a high school kid.
Calm down, madam.
Perhaps herfriends
took her away.
Officer, all the neighbors saw it.
We're not idiots.
Be respectful...
and lower your voice.
Very well.
You know my father wrote this.
Dr. Delfor Méndez.
- You're his daughter?
- Yes, I am.
A great man.
Go to the Police Headquarters
and ask. Don't mention my name.
And go alone.
Thank you.
Jorge, calm down.
Don'twaste my time.
What's your group and rank?
What's all this?
What organization?
UES?
- "Montoneros"?
- No, sir.
Bring him.
What about your school?
What are you up to?
I'm in the students' council.
- What magazines do you read?
- I read nothing...
You don't know
what I'm talking about?
No, I swear.
What's Pablo Diaz up to?
I... nothing.
C'mon, don't act stupid.
You know...
He was the school delegate.
He fought for the pass.
That's all.
OK, you're off the hook.
But get this into your head.
You'll live, if I want you to.
Got it?
- Yes.
- Yes... sir.
Yes, sir.
I'm fed up with you two.
Diamanti, come here
with your things.
This'll be your seat.
You, Chirom, take his place.
C'mon gentlemen, move.
Pisani, come over here.
Sir, Pablo Diaz sits there.
Obey, young lady.
Move over, shitheads!
Out of the way, Jewish pig!
Where are you taking me?
- What's this?
- Shut up.
Whatwill you do to me?
You won't feel like
fucking around anymore.
Please... What is this?
Whatwill you do to me?
Why did you fuck things up?
Heard of the truth machine?
Well, now you will.
A lie detector will show
I'm not lying.
So you want the machine?
Fine.
If you want to talk,
open your hands.
Give us a name.
C'mon, open your hands.
Your superior.
Be smart.
The name and we'll stop.
Open your hands.
I have no superior.
Are you screwing with us, shithead?
I haven't got one.
I'm going to break you.
You won't feel like
fucking around anymore.
I can't, Jorge.
But you've known
Claudia for years.
Do you know how many lawyers
disappeared...
for invoking habeas corpus?
- Do you?
- No.
Twelve.
They know I've been in politics.
You'd have to get
another lawyer...
but for me.
I'm sorry.
Water...
Easy now.
Water, please.
Not after the electric prod.
I'm desperate.
If you drink you'll
burst like a toad.
What's your name?
Don't be afraid.
I'm Carozo Schunk.
Pablo Díaz.
I know you.
I saw you at the meeting.
I'm the one that mentioned
the money, remember?
Where are we?
In Campo de Arana.
Other students were here before.
The kids of the
night of the pencils.
What?
The soldiers call it like that.
The night they
grabbed the students.
Who? Claudia Falcone?
Horacio Ungaro?
Panchito Lopez Muntaner?
Yes. They took them away
before you arrived.
How were they?
They've been through hell.
My son, I'm a priest.
I've come for your confession.
I didn't do anything.
Confess your sins, my son.
Confess, there'll be
more executions.
I don't want to die, Father.
Resign yourself, my son.
The tree must be pruned
to give better fruits.
Please, Father...
I don't want to die.
Confess your sins.
Your life depends on God
and on your cooperation.
Who is your superior?
C'mon, up!
C'mon, c'mon, quickly!
God, no. God... Lord!
Why mention God, old fart?
We are god.
Filthy Jew!
I'll kill you myself.
To make soap!
Repeat: I'm a filthy Jew.
Say it or I'll bust you.
I'm a filthy Jew.
Don't cry, children.
You'll be better off
where you're going.
Get ready.
We pray to God, our Father,
for our brothers.
Aim!
Don't kill me!
So that you may comfort
them, Father...
and fortify them.
Long live Argentina!
- Mother!
- And the "Montoneros"!
Fire!
My sons, you've been spared
this time.
And you, subversive
motherfucker,
you won't feel like
yelling anymore.
How do you do, madam?
- Good morning.
- Allow me.
Take a seat.
So you're Dr. Méndez's daughter.
I was a cadetwhen I first read...
"ln sports, we were
always the winners...
to defend the Argentine flag."
The club's anthem.
Also written by your father.
A great man.
What can I do for you, madam?
I came to inquire about
Dr. Méndez's granddaughter.
Claudia Falcone, my daughter.
She was kidnapped ten days
ago, apparently by the police.
I only hope she's
in some police station.
Surely you know about it.
Who told you the police
kidnapped someone?
Tell me, who said that?
Different people.
Give me a list.
We'll investigate.
I don'twant to get them involved.
What? Someone slanders
our institution...
and you don't want me
to investigate.
Don't let Marxists
give you ideas.
I'm sure the subversives
kidnapped your daughter.
They disguise themselves
as policemen and soldiers...
so that people
may go around saying...
we don't respect human rights.
Captain, is my daughter alive?
C'mon, help me.
Another lamb for the collection?
But never a real guerrilla.
You only get the sissies.
Go get yourself fucked!
You motherfuckers
have a real good time.
Let's go.
Who are you? Tell me!
Don't be afraid.
Who are you?
Pablo Díaz.
Is it you, Pablo?
I'm Horacio.
Hey, Pablo is here!
Pablo!
Panchito?
Sure, you nerd...
It's me.
You're all here?
Yes. Hi, Pablo.
Claudio here.
- You're all here?
- Yes, María Clara.
I'm Daniel.
Is Claudia here?
Yes... I'm here.
Can you hear me?
Ladies, to the corridor.
You're through?
Yes. A list of missing people.
Under arrest.
No one's missing here.
My daughter isn't there.
We can't do anything.
You all say the same.
If you'd looked after
your daughter...
she'd be all right now.
I've always looked after her.
- Have you?
- As if one wasn'tArgentine.
You are, not your daughter.
Yes, Captain, she is.
- You asked about the Falcone girl?
- Yes.
- Claudia Falcone?
- Yes, my daughter.
She and my son
Horacio were friends,
they disappeared
the same night.
You're out of luck, Pablo.
You got the bad guards.
One almost strangled me.
He's a beast.
I bet the Mulattos Mule...
could free us.
Horacio.
Tell me how to do it.
Relax, there's plenty of time
in here.
Hey, Claudia...
the night you were grabbed?
I slept in Corchito's fridge.
The fridge?
Like Walt Disney in the freezer.
The torturers asked me
about him but I kept silent.
You held on.
I was so scared
I forgot his name.
The lucky asshole!
I was no hero.
My head wasn't straight.
Got it, Horacio.
Take one hand out.
Careful, don't untie it.
- Stop it!
- No way!
He's a swine.
Is anyone else here?
Two pregnant girls
and a guerrilla.
- "Montonero"?
- ERP. A leader.
Come on, baby.
Come on, you shithead.
- Dany, are you eating?
- Yes.
Double helping, baby.
You can't say I'm a swine.
"Our Father who art in Heaven...
hallowed be Thy name...
Thy kingdom come,
Thy word be done...
on Earth as it is in Heaven...
give us this day
our daily bread...
and forgive us our trespasses...
as we forgive those
who trespass against us.
2736, 2737, 2738...
2739, 2740.
2741, 2742,
2743, 2744...
Pablo.
Pablo, are you asleep?
No, good morning.
Good morning...
I haven't heard that in ages.
Don't come. They're nasty
and you can't stand it.
Women can get away
with a lot more.
Do it for me.
I suffer when they humiliate you.
But you can't go alone!
I'm not alone.
Ready.
- Claudia.
- C'mon, kid!
Hey, blockheads,
do some exercises.
You organize everything.
OK, let's stretch.
I'm too weak.
I'm for it.
Come on, Horacio.
I'll start.
One...
C'mon.
Two...
C'mon, Horacio.
Three.
Remember "Papillon."
He stuck a tube up his ass.
Five...
Six...
Eight...
Dany, c'mon...
Just a little.
Leave me alone!
I hate exercises.
Claudia, are you with us?
Hey, what's wrong?
Cheer up, they'll let us out.
They can't keep us here for good.
We'll get out, trust me.
Then I'll take you out to dinner.
I dream of a steak...
two eggs and lots
of French fries.
Or better, you invite me...
and you cook.
But only hamburgers.
That's fine.
Orwe'll look for a recipe.
An easy one.
A difficult one, I'll help you.
I'll be your assistant.
That'll be something.
Claudia, sing a song.
Sing with María Clara.
- You sing too.
- I can't sing.
If you sing, I'll cook.
OK.
Once I was beautiful...
C'mon, María Clara.
and truly free.
You too, Pablo.
I kept all my dreams
in a crystal castle.
That's dreadful!
Yes, it is.
They vanished
like soap bubbles.
I'll find you one morning
in my room...
and you'll make
the bed for two.
Clean his wound.
Then get back in your cell.
Do as Dr. Mengele says.
C'mon, be a man.
I can't use this, it's filthy.
Never mind, just do it.
How many shots?
Three.
How does it feel?
Why do you ask?
Osvaldo, will they let us go?
Sure, they didn't nail you...
on anything big.
- Then why bring us here?
- This is a depot.
They'll have to make a decision.
They'll release you,
you're no use to them.
And you?
What about me?
Will they release you?
I'm a hostage.
I may be useful to them.
Officially, I was killed
in a clash.
That's why I'm not blindfolded.
Don't worry!
Bye, Osvaldo.
Come here.
Remember: "The makers
of revolutions are the people,
not individuals."
I'll remember.
Claudia.
You're so thin.
I look horrible.
No, you look pretty.
Remember I said I liked you?
I like you even more.
Liar...
No, it's true.
- Thank you, Pablo.
- Why?
I thought... well...
if you want...
when we're out...
We'll never get out.
Yes, we will.
I'd like to go outwith you.
I have nothing to give.
Why? Don't say that!
- A guard.
- Be careful.
You guys stink!
You... out!
Silence!
You!
Dry up!
So you're a wise guy.
Trying to peep, huh?
We're no fools either.
What an idiot, Pablo!
I can't stand it anymore!
Remember there are pardons...
for Christmas, surely.
Leave me alone!
Don't touch me!
Let go of her!
Leave her alone!
Stop it, please!
Drop dead, you crazy bitch!
I want to die!
Stop, please...
Stop it, María Clara!
I want to die!
Please, stop it.
I want to die.
The Armed Forces know
nothing about your children.
Tell us the truth.
Madam, you don't know
what your son was up to.
Captain, they're just kids.
So what?
You don't know the UES,
the Che Guevara Youth,
the GESA.
They're the hotbeds
of subversion,
the guerrilla's logistic support.
I don't understand.
First you know nothing,
now they're subversive.
Don't misunderstand me.
Your daughter has probably
gone underground...
or abroad, it's quite common.
I know my daughter.
She'd get in touch with me.
I know her.
That'll be all.
Good day.
Ivana?
I prefer Patricia.
It's old fashioned.
So? It's cute.
It's horrible.
- Laura? - An old witch
I know is called Laura.
It'll be a boy.
It hurts.
Relax.
It'll soon be over.
When it's born,
they'll let you go.
Yes, they promised
they'd let me keep it.
At a farm.
It hurts!
Some midwife you have.
Not you, klutz!
It hurts!
It's the contractions.
- Do something!
- Do what?
It's coming! Help me!
- What do I do?
- Take it easy.
It hurts!
Help me, it's coming!
What do I do, Eugenia?
Easy. Count the contractions.
- What?
- Count them!
How?
Somebody call the guards!
Quickly! The guards!
Guards! Guards!
The baby's coming, guards!
Make the guards come!
The guards, please!
Relax, we're taking you.
Good luck, Moni!
The Archbishop cannot see you.
His secretary will.
Did you mention my name?
When my husband was Mayor...
the Archbishop asked
him some favors.
An Archbishop sees
so many people.
Well...
as it'll soon be Christmas
we thought the Church...
Tell me.
Your children were taken away
on September 16th?
Yes.
Accept it with
Christian resignation, ladies.
You'll never see them again.
What?
What's that?
I can't deceive you.
There must be a mistake.
There's no mistake.
Only God is infallible.
It can't be.
Aterrible injustice.
Accept the facts.
They won't be back.
For you.
Blockheads!
Think of yourfamilies.
It's Christmas Eve.
Claudia, will you pray with me?
- Will it help you?
- Yes.
All right.
Why pray?
If God existed,
he'd get us out.
He's too busy.
What?
Either that, or he's a fascist.
Don't say that.
Don't argue.
Let's sing something together.
Come on, Claudia.
If we all sing.
I'll sing if I know the lyrics.
Haven't you learned them yet?
Behind the walls
that were risen yesterday
I beg you to keep breathing
I lean on my back and
wait for your embrace
through the wall
of my days.
And scratch the stones,
scratch the stones...
scratch the stones
until you get to me.
Let's make a toast.
To our families...
and to freedom.
To us.
To us...
but free.
Here's to Mum...
to Dad...
and to Jorge.
He's in bad shape.
Don't open your eyes.
Let's see if you're a man.
Don't look.
Let's see.
C'mon... men don't cry.
Some photo we'll take.
- Shall I comb him?
- Don't be a fool.
Put that away!
Is he ready?
Don't open your eyes.
Look kid,
you're with the NEP now.
- What?
- Say "sir".
He's a Lieutenant Colonel.
You're going to live.
We'll take you away
but I'm warning you...
and I want it to be crystal clear.
You must forget everything.
Better still,
you were never here.
Understand?
The bastards!
Who do they think they are?
Remember, you're leaving tonight.
Horacio, what's the NEP?
- Why?
- What about the NEP, Pablo?
I'm with the NEP now.
Then you're legalized.
It's the National Executive Power.
Now you're legally arrested.
That's wonderful!
I told you, blockheads,
they'd let you out.
No, we'll be killed.
No, no!
Claudia, can you hear me?
Claudia!
Let's go.
Wait!
I have to see Claudia.
Please, before I leave.
OK, only a minute.
Or they'll kill me.
Look at me.
Remember me.
I never tortured you or anything.
It's my job.
I treated you like a human being.
Don't cry.
They'll let you out too.
You're leaving?
Listen...
you'll all get out.
No.
We're going to be killed.
Don't say that.
Go see my parents.
Tell them I'm fine.
Sure, I will.
What about us?
Will you be my girl
when you're out?
I was raped in Arana...
When they tortured me.
They raped me front...
and back.
I've nothing to give you.
Claudia...
Who will I talk to now?
You'll be out too.
We're already dead.
On New Year's Eve...
drink to us.
C'mon, Pablo.
Don't forget me... Pablo!
Goodbye, Pablo!
Bye.
Good luck, Pablo!
I'll be seeing you outside!
See me at the café!
Take care!
Pablo!
You'll all be free!
They'll let you go... they will!
ON DECEMBER 28, 1976, PABLO DIAZ
WAS PLACED IN CUSTODY
OF THE NATIONAL EXECUTIVE POWER...
ACCUSED OF HAVING BEEN CAUGHT THAT
VERY DAY DISTRIBUTING SUBVERSIVE LEAFLETS.
HE WAS IN PRISION FOR ALMOST FOUR YEARS
WTHOUT A TRIAL AND WAS SET FREE
ON NOVEMBER 19, 1980.
MARIA CLAUDIA FALCONE,
HORACIO UNGARO,
CLAUDIO DE ACHA,
PANCHITO LOPEZ MUNTANER,
DANIEL RACERO AND
MARÍA CLARA CIOCCHINI,
AS WELLAS 232 OTHER
ARGENTINE ADOLESCENTS...
ARE STILL MISSING.
THE STUDENT PASS
REMAINS IN FORCE IN LA PLATA.