LIKE A CRASHED PLANE
Yes, in the morning I guess...
but I'm not sure yet...
...yes...
...when it stops raining I guess...
I'll drop the bags
and go to the vet.
Yes, I paid everything.
Benito! Hello!
This is aunt Luchi.
Hello! Listen, is Ani there?
Yes, yes.
I'm bringing you a gift.
Listen, can you
wake your mom up?
Something I made
for you, with shells.
No, sea shells.
I collected them.
These shells have little holes,
then you tie them to a twig...
...painted them
with granny's help.
Ana, hello, how are you?
Yes, fine, everything's fine.
Listen, sorry
my calling at this hour...
I'll be quick because
this will cut off any moment.
The plane was late. I don't think
I'll get there tomorrow...
...in time to open the shop.
Can you go?
- No, not now, I'm waiting...
- Great, great.
- No, I already paid for it.
- No, no, because...
- Oh! Wait... have you a coin?
- What?
It's going to cut off...
- Yeah...
- Wait
Ana?
No, it cut off...
doesn't matter, thanks.
- Bye.
- Get out, Santi.
- I thought you'd died, dude.
- I arrived yesterday, really late.
- This one's really good!
Yeah, so is this one.
Yes, it's the son.
Let's go for a walk?
Okay, let's go.
- So what d'you do in the end?
- Shall we play best of three?
Let's.
- Goal, dude.
- No way, pinwheel.
No? Hell of a goal!
Will you tell me what you
fixed up yesterday?
- We're going to a rock concert.
- What are you going to see?
I don't know.
I'm not going... no way!
Didn't you say you liked her?
I lied, she's stupid.
- Aren't you going
to let her know? - No.
You, what,
any chicks in Valdivia?
- I met one...
- So tell me about her.
- What do you want to know?
- What she's like.
What's her name,
where she lives, what she does...
- She's pretty, she's cute.
- What else?
That, that's the fun.
Come on! The ball!
What's her name?
- I don't know, come on! The ball!
- Wait... where does she live?
I don't know.
But you must have her phone,
you're going to see her again.
- No, no, I haven't got it.
- But... you must be kidding...
- Well, that's how I do things.
- You do things like an asshole.
Hey look, it's a goal.
Serves you right... asshole.
Here, feed it
and put it in a cage.
What's it called?
Arturo.
Hi, Arturo!
Yes, I hope so, okay...
Hello, yes, how are you.
I spoke to you the other day?
Ah! The guy
I spoke to isn't there?
Because he knows everything,
I already explained...
...yes...
Yes... about a house in Valdivia,
I don't want the gas cut off.
No...
...no, the thing is that
the holders can't sign.
The other guy said he'd
fix things for me.
Yes, I know... but now
I'm in charge, I could sign it...
No...
...no, it's impossible.
Yes...
No, all I can do is fax you
the holder's death certificate.
I can send it to the subsidiary,
or to Valdivia, or...
...I can give it to you personally
but I sign.
Yes, I know
my father was the holder.
No, no,
my mother can't either.
Nico,
can you bring Arturo?
Here, Nico, go get some change
and give her the rabbit.
Hi, Arturo!
I came to fetch you.
"Hey, that's great.
I was already thinking...
...you would leave me here."
Where are you going
to get change?
Because I live near from here
and I'm in a hurry.
If you're going that side we can
go together and then I go on.
What?
I said if you're going that side,
we can go together...
Yes, yes, okay.
When is the treatment over?
Monday is the last shot.
Next Monday?
Yes.
What's wrong with it?
It's a breathing problem.
He needs some nebulizations.
Look, there is a kiosk over there.
"Oh, Luchi,
I missed you so much!"
He didn't have any...
Since when have you had him?
My sister gave it to me
a year ago.
His name used to be Jorgelín.
Do you remember when
you were called Jorgelín?
"Ah, yes! What an ugly name.
Arturo is much nicer!"
I once had a dog.
Yes, his name was Coco.
His name was always Coco.
He was run over by a train.
"Look, Luchi, there is
a flower shop over there."
- D'you want me to go?
- Well, no... I'll go if you want.
No, no, it's okay.
You hold Arturo.
"When are you coming back,
Luchi?" Be right back.
Thanks.
Here.
Ah... it was 20.
Well, I'll go my way...
- Okay, bye.
- Bye.
- Bye, Arturo.
- "Bye, sir!"
Not sir, Nico.
"Bye, Nico.
Say hello to the rabbits."
- Bye.
These?
They're good!
Say, what'll I do?
I don't know, do something
so she'll have to come back...
...just seeing her for a moment on
Monday at the vet isn't enough.
What d'you think?
Once you give the rabbit
the last shot, that's that?
Yes...
...unless it gets sick again.
So, poison the rabbit.
- Do I look good in these?
- Seriously, Santi, come on.
I don't know, do something so
she comes back.
That's all I can say.
You guys, you going to
buy something or not?
He wants to get a teddy bear
for his girlfriend.
This.
D'you want, would you
like something to drink?
No, thanks.
- The treatment is over, isn't it?
- Yes, I hope so. Besides...
...it doesn't Arturo any good
to be out all the time.
All the same, you don't
live far from here I think.
No, about three blocks from
where we went for change.
Will this take long?
No, I don't think so.
It must be over by now.
- Why, you have to work today?
- No, I'm not working today.
- You have to go to college?
- No, but I've a lot to study.
- There it's over.
- How is he?
- A bit low.
- He's very weak, Arturo.
"Yes, I feel very dizzy,
let's go home, please!"
- How much is it?
- Forty five.
Here, Nico, you take the money,
give her those...
...antibiotics over there,
behind the cash register.
Okay, now just keep an eye
on him, see how he gets along.
He might be a little low the first
few days, it's normal.
But don't worry,
he'll get over it.
Well, I'm leaving,
I have a lot of work to do.
Thank you, bye.
Take this, it's all inside.
I put a bunny inside, for Arturo.
"Ah! That's nice, thank you!"
- Bye.
- Bye. Bye, Arturo.
"Bye".
- You think I mustn't call her?
- How are you going to call her!
If you call somebody to
give them back the money...
...is either because you like her
or you're dumb. Let her call you.
- What if she doesn't call?
- It's fifty bucks. She'll call.
Here, have some.
- What is it?
- Peanuts.
- You didn't pay for it!
- Then don't eat!
You're an asshole.
You call me an asshole but
you stole from the girl you like.
- I'm going to give her the money.
- Yeah, that's how I started.
We've been here
for more than two hours.
- Why don't we go to my place?
- I'll stay a little longer.
Doing what?
Nothing, dude.
After that, you going home?
No, Enrique is staying with
my mother. I'll stay here.
- Come on, let's go to my place.
- I don't want to go to your place.
- Did you fix your bedroom wall?
- Not yet.
But you can sleep on a mattress
in the living room floor.
I won't sleep well that way.
Do as you please.
Come over later if you want to.
- Okay.
- Bye.
Don't go stealing things
on the way.
Bye, man!
Hello!
Ah! Hello.
You're still there!
Let me see, hold on.
The gas bill?
It was paid on March 14 of 2002.
It's all right.
What time you coming back?
Yes, well, yes, I'll stay.
No problem.
Hey, you forgot to buy
the ventilator that broke.
Okay.
Bye.
Did you know that Fran hangs
with my father's friends...
...to play squash and have dinner?
How come?
Where does he know them from?
Julio, the one he plays with,
he met him in Valdivia...
...and the rest he knows
them from the club.
We used to spend
summer holidays together.
Sounds hilarious.
He used to go every weekend.
I don't know... it seems...
it's odd.
- Are you jealous?
- No.
What's that you're taking?
Don't know,
stole them from mom.
- Want some?
- No.
Hello.
Forty-eight pesos.
Have you got your ID?
I think I forgot it.
Why don't you
have another look?
No, I haven't got it.
You know me.
I always come here.
It's a gift for him,
it's his birthday.
You're Enrique?
Yeah.
What's my name?
Enrique.
See?
- Happy birthday.
- Thank you.
- Happy birthday, pal!
- Get out, you moron!
Bye, thanks.
- Hi, there.
- How are you.
Take this.
- What is it?
- Chocolate, for you.
Thank you.
What, are they imported?
Yes,
it was well worth the effort.
Shut up!
What, are you funny now?
- What's wrong with him?
- He's sleepy.
- Your mom? How is she?
- Same as always.
- Is she home already?
- Yes, Enrique's looking after her.
Don't you want
anything to drink?
No, he doesn't want anything.
Did you call the plumber?
No, I didn't have time.
I was all day after the gas thing.
Yes, I know, but my bedroom
wall is dripping all over.
Well, I can't be
in charge of everything!
But you do take care of things in
Valdivia. My bedroom wall...
...waters for two weeks and you
didn't even pick up the phone.
The house needs
to be taken care of.
We never go there,
why don't we just rent it?
This isn't the right time
to talk about this, see?
I've got to go to work,
my ears hurt.
Go see the doctor
if your ears hurt.
Drop it! You're going to set
the whole house on fire!
Nico, this isn't the right time
to talk about this, see?
Fuck you, asshole!
Veterinary.
Oh, yes.
How are you?
No, frankly I have no idea.
I'll take a look and if I find
anything I call you, okay?
Okay.
No, please.
Bye, see you.
- What's up? You finished?
- Yes.
Who was that?
The rabbit girl.
Remember? Says we made a
mistake with the change.
Why do you care
who's calling now?
No, it's just
that I think I charged her.
So?
I don't remember
what I did with the money.
Well,
be more careful next time.
Hey, we could cash up,
couldn't we?
Maybe I made a mistake.
Bad show, she's a client.
What's wrong with you, Nico?
I just think we should check.
It'll only take two minutes.
If you're busy, I can do it.
You're a jerk.
Okay do it.
You do it.
Yes, leave it up to me.
- Hello?
- Hello.
It's from the veterinary,
I've come to bring some money.
Nico?
Yes.
This is Luchi.
Come on in.
- Hi.
Take this.
Again, I apologize.
No, it's okay, thanks.
- Arturo?
- Better.
Even so, yesterday
he was behaving strangely.
He seemed kind of down,
didn't want to eat.
D'you want me to take
a look at him, since I'm here?
- Yeah, come on in.
- OK.
I'll bring him over.
"Hello, Nico, hey
how are you doing?"
Hi, Arturo.
Now let's take a look at you.
Were you studying?
Yes, I have an exam tomorrow.
Are you studying
Natural Science?
No, Gardening.
- Where does one study that?
- At the Botanical Gardens.
The Botanical Gardens...
"So, tell me doctor,
what's wrong with me?"
Nothing, Arturo.
Only the antibiotic.
There's nothing wrong with him.
You were just pretending
to be sick.
"No, Luchi, I swear to you,
I fell really bad."
Is that Valdivia?
- Yes.
- Ah, my father was born there.
- Really?
- Yes, we have a house.
I go there very often.
Well, to Santiago and Valdivia.
My grandmother lives in Valdivia.
Ah! Yes, it's nice,
it's very nice.
Yes.
Done?
Yes, all done.
I leave you to your studies.
I won't bother you any longer.
OK.
Any problem,
just call the vet.
- Bye.
- Good luck tomorrow.
- Thank you.
"So long, Nico,
so long, good luck."
- Bye now.
- Bye.
- Yes, what can I do for you?
- We want this.
The duplicate,
do you have it?
You have the card?
- What card?
- The medical scheme card.
I always come here.
I can't give you the drugs
if you haven't got the card.
They've never
asked me for no card.
Without the card
I can't give you the drugs.
My mother's sick.
She must have her medicines!
I can't give you these medicines
without the card.
We'll bring it to you later.
- When you bring me the card...
- No, my mother needs them now.
I already told you, without the
card, I can't give you the drugs.
I know him. And I also know his
mother, they always come here.
Well you attend them, then.
- Thank you.
- It's okay.
I'll bring them to you.
He's a son of a bitch!
Well, so I'll go
fetch you at your house.
Let's.
Could we go to dinner?
Yes, all together...
I guess so... yes, in any case
we have the court until two.
We could...
...let's...
...okay... Julio, be seeing you,
my regards to Lucía.
Fine,
bye, bye.
- Hi there.
- Hello, how are you?
I'm fine, and you?
Very well.
- How's the veterinary?
- What?
- The veterinary...
- Oh! Fine, fine...
...just fine... how's Arturo?
- All right, better.
- What?
- I said he's all right, better.
You can sit here if you like.
I'm expecting a friend...
...of mine who's
just taken her exam.
- You also had an exam,
didn't you? - Yes.
- So, how did you get on?
- Very well, I got a 9.50.
It was quite difficult, but I've
only two more subjects to finish.
- That's wonderful!
- Thank you.
I was killing time
to see some friends...
...of mine who are
rehearsing near here.
- Have they got a band?
- Yes, they're playing tomorrow.
My Small Death?
That's what they call themselves.
But they play really well.
- What is it, some kind of party?
- Yes, in a house.
First they play and then
there's a party.
It's outdoors, in the garden.
D'you feel like coming?
Oh! I don't know...
- It's quite near here.
- Ah! It's three blocks from here.
- I'd have to ask my friends.
- They can go too if they like.
Could be. In any case,
I still don't know.
- No, keep it, it has the address.
- Thank you. It's nice.
Could be good.
You can go and celebrate
you both passed your exams.
Yah, yah...
it could be... that's good.
That's my friend coming,
she's coming with the other girls.
I won't bother you anymore,
Tell them that if they
want to go there's no problem.
- Bye.
Bye.
Yes, I wanted to know the cost
of rents...
...for the summer season.
And also per month.
And also per
month out of season?
Nico, next Sunday after squash
we're getting together...
...with Julio and the rest to eat.
A barbecue, want to come?
No, it's okay.
Well, as you wish.
I spoke to some
real state agents in Valdivia.
To find out
about prices for rent.
What?
Here it is, these are the costs
per month and for the season...
...plus their commission.
What did you go down there,
Nico? Did I ask you to go?
It suits us,
it's another income.
It's not enough
with the veterinary only.
I'm working on that!
How do you know it isn't enough?
It's obvious.
No, it's not. Renting Valdivia is
a mess. We're out of season.
Then, let's sell the house. What
do you want that house for?
I don't want to hear
another word.
When is the plumber coming?
- Don't know, I left a message.
- That's bullshit, you didn't call.
- You can think what you please.
- Yes, I do think what I please.
Until I see that wall fixed
I don't believe a word you say.
What happened to our hands...
...that can no longer
hold flowers?
When the wind drowns our song...
When an abyss
dwells in my heart...
I will remember
the springtime...
...of our love
The springtime of our love
Who?
Who will I wait for...
...now that the years...
...cast a mist over my eyes?
And where does my voice...
...go now that the dead
no longer wait for my words?
I don't want to stay here.
I will not stay here
Benito, does he go to pre-school?
No, he just began kindergarten.
- He already has three girlfriends.
- Three girlfriends.
But one of them
he hasn't told yet.
- Is he your only nephew?
- Yes.
Ana owns the greenhouse,
or does it belong to your parents?
My parents helped her from
Santiago, but it belongs to her.
Come to the greenhouse
one of these days if you want.
You're not there Tuesdays
and Thursdays, right?
Every day, except
Tuesdays and Thursdays.
- Okay, then I'll drop by.
- Yah.
- Do you have this one?
- I thought of going next week.
Why wait so long, dude?
She invited you, go today.
- No, she's not there today.
- Okay, then go tomorrow.
D'you think so?
I don't know, that's what I think.
You decide what you want to do.
Yes, I know.
Why don't you ask if they
have "Grace" by Jeff Buckley.
- Haven't you got it?
- I lost it.
- Why don't you ask?
- Because I'm shy, man.
Come on, dude.
One question...
"Grace" by Jeff Buckley?
Let me have a look.
Nico...
Come on, man!
Come on!
You're an asshole!
Wait a minute,
what's wrong with you?
What's wrong with you?
We went to a record store and
bought some CDs, what's wrong?
Don't play the fool, Santi!
Here, take these...
...I chose them for you.
- Great present, thanks!
Stop it dude,
they scratch easily...
- You can change them if you want.
- Stop it.
- Did you ask for the receipt?
- I'm serious, Santi, cut it out!
What are you being
serious about?
- About what you're doing.
- What am I doing?
- You're being an absolute jerk.
- I'm a jerk, why does it bug you?
- Yes, it does bother me.
- Then don't let it bother you.
It's my business,
it's my problem if I'm a jerk...
Look...
It's not your problem only.
They're perfect for outdoors.
Yes... but what about now,
with the cold?
No... I think... these resist both
the cold and the summer heat...
...except this one is more
likely to grow in winter.
This is it.
- Here?
- Yes.
How much sugar?
Two.
There's also a wood,
I like going there, but it's far.
- Next time, then.
- Okay.
What's that?
It's Benito,
my nephew's birthday...
...in a few days and I promised
to entertain his birthday party...
...in the kindergarten.
- That's great!
You can come if you like.
- Really?
- Yes.
- You can invite Santi, so you
won't get bored. - I don't know.
Yes, come on, tell him
that way I can get to meet him.
I'll see, thank you.
- Want some?
- Okay.
Hi, children!
I see many children here today!
I'm looking
for my friend Gandolfo.
Have you seen him around?
Did he go that way?
Or that way?
- That way!
Thank you children.
I'll go that way, then...
Looks surprised...
It can make many
different gestures...
...it can even show anger.
Let's see, can I try?
There...
Let's see...
When you don't know
how to do it...
...the head goes that way
upwards...
...you have to hold it downwards.
Did you put your hand in there?
Like this?
Or do I have to squeeze less?
And you can comb it...
These are easy,
they have only one stick.
"Hello, hello..."
His name is Gandolfo.
- Gandolfo.
And does your sister
live near here?
More or less. She often
asks me to go fetch Benito.
And how long is it since you
went to live with your brother?
No, I didn't go to live with him.
My parents died over a year ago...
...they were flying this plane of
theirs and they had an accident.
Since that happened
I've been living with him...
- I'm sorry, I had no idea.
- No, it's okay.
Feed him a little more, see.
Do you know who sent it?
What are you doing?
Wait.
Hey, in the end
what's going on with the girl?
I don't know,
what do you think?
That she's into you,
you need to do something.
- Yes, I have to do something.
- That's obvious.
- There's nobody here.
- There's one on duty not so far.
But I'm not buying anything,
there's usually no one this time.
- The pharmacist comes out.
- So what for?
- I'm robbing the drugstore.
- Come on, there's one over there.
I don't want another one,
I want to rob this one.
Did you have a good time?
Yes, the kids
enjoyed themselves.
Did your friend
have a good time?
Yes, I think he liked it.
He seems a nice person,
I liked him.
Although some of his jokes,
I just couldn't understand.
- Lately, he's being quite a jerk.
- I liked him anyway.
He played with Benito
all afternoon.
He was so happy
with that gift you gave him.
I brought this.
- Didn't have time to wrap it up.
- What is it? Is it for Benito?
Yes, well no, actually,
it's for you.
It's a puppet,
to keep yours company.
- You don't like it?
- Yes, of course, I love it.
- Where did you buy it?
- I searched for it.
Looked for it in several places
and finally found it.
I bought mine during summer,
at a fair...
...from a big, bald-headed
gentleman.
Yes, an old man with glasses.
He also had the pink fish...
...same as the one you have.
Thank you, it's really great.
Nico, I wanted to tell you I'm off
to Switzerland for two years...
- What?
- Yes, I'm going to study Botany.
There's a very good
school over there.
I... I had no idea.
I didn't tell you because it was
confirmed only two days ago.
I won a scholarship.
I'm so happy. They chose me
among 200 other people.
- Isn't it wonderful?
- Yes, wonderful. Congratulations.
Anyway, we'll keep in touch.
- When are you leaving?
- In 20 days time.
But I'm going to be very busy,
I have to prepare everything...
...and besides I have to take
the remaining exams.
But I suppose we can still see
each other before you go.
Yes, I guess, I'll manage
to find some time off.
Thank you, Nico,
I really liked it.
She's scared, if not, then why
didn't she tell you sooner?
- It was only confirmed.
- Bullshit.
She was playing fool, until
she began to feel something...
...for you and she got scared.
I don't think so, I don't think
she has feelings for me.
My idea is she just wanted to
keep her distance and that's all.
You have to do something
about it, forget about the trip.
If she wanted to keep a distance,
she should have done so before.
- Hi.
- How are you.
Hello
This one is for the barred door,
and this one for the glass one.
Tomorrow at one-fifteen.
The drugs are those beside the
counter, they're in a green box.
Don't take too long, the old man
is out 10 minutes and comes back.
You asshole, Santi!
What's the matter? He's the one
who's gonna help you?
- Yes.
- You sure?
Yes, he's my best friend,
he's going to help me.
Well, let's continue.
If a customer shows up,
don't let them in...
...tell them the owner's gone
and is coming back later...
...don't open the door
for anyone, got it?
Yeah.
Nicolás, all these bills arrived,
you didn't pay anything.
- No, I forgot.
- But, idiot, the money was here.
Yes, but I forgot, so what?!
- You didn't even take the money.
- You forget to get my room fixed.
Can't I forget too?
- What's wrong with you, man?
- Nothing. I just forgot to pay.
Now they're going to cut off
everything, what do we do?
I've already told you what we
can do with that house.
- Don't bust my balls with that.
- You never listen to me.
I'm in charge of
that house and this one.
You're in charge of nothing.
You waste all your time
with that Valdivia shit...
...or with those old creeps, what
the fuck are you in charge of?
Since when it's your business
what I do now?!
I see whomever I please.
I don't meddle in your things!
I don't mess around with Santi!
You're an asshole!
You left the gas on!
- The wind must have blown it off.
- You can't forget the gas on!
It's because I started reading
all that shit you didn't pay.
You never accept anything.
You don't listen.
- Cut out the insults, you prick.
- Fuck off. Do what you want!
You fuck off, asshole!
- Nico...
- What are you doing here, moron?
- I'm okay, and you?
- What d'you want?
- I need a favor.
- No fucking way.
5.000 pesos are missing at my
place and my mom is blaming me.
Did you see the guy at the
pharmacist's? He buys drugs.
- Did you steal the money or not?
- Yes, I stole it, yeah.
- You're a real asshole.
- Yeah, I know...
- Do you?
- Yes, I'm not dumb, I know.
- I have to replace the money.
- Fuck you.
You're at the counter, just in
case, nothing's gonna happen.
- We're in and out. Five minutes.
- Get out.
I'm asking you a favor, what
the fuck's the matter with you?
D'you think I like it? I'm asking
you a favor and you play dumb.
You are a prick...
you're a chicken.
- No, it's not that.
- You're a fucking chicken!
- Don't you realize?!
- I'm going to steal it anyway.
- Why don't you...
- I can't talk to my mother.
I'm going on with this.
And if it gets screwed up,
I don't mind, d'you understand?
If you want to help, call me,
otherwise, go to hell.
Hi.
Hello, Nico!
- Everything okay?
- Just fine, and you?
Is your answering machine
working? I've been calling you...
Ah, yes... I know...
but I had a lot of work to do.
- Can I help you?
- No, no, it's okay.
- You're about finished, right?
- No, I'm staying one hour longer.
- Shall we go for a drink?
- I can't, I must study.
- Aren't the exams next week?
- But I already started reading.
What about later,
in the evening?
I'd love to, but I'm having dinner
with my sister and Benito.
- Are you okay?
- Yes, why?
It's nothing...
When can we meet?
I'll see, maybe one of these days
I find the time, I don't know...
- Luchi... can you come, please?
- I'll just finish this.
Well... bye.
I'll call you, okay?
Hello, Lucía?
How are you, it's Francisco.
Is Julio around?
Ah, you don't know if he
was coming to the Club.
Ah, yes?
I didn't know...
To eat, where?
They were all going?
No, no... how strange...
Yes, I was home until now, but,
he didn't leave a message either.
Don't worry,
I'll speak to him later.
Okay, thank you.
- Hurry up, Santi, how long?
- Coming... hold on a minute.
- Hurry up.
- Yes, I can't find then
It doesn't matter, let's go.
- Here they are.
- Are they those?
Yes, yes,
we're leaving now.
- What do I do?
- Attend them, send them away.
- No, you go.
- They've already seen you, go.
- What do I tell them?
- Anything, just send them away.
Hello, I need either
espasmosedan or espasmoactril.
Quickly, please,
he's not feeling well.
Wait here,
just a second.
- Espasmosedan?
- Don't know what that is.
- Espasmoactril or something?
- Don't know. Give them anything.
- No, I think he's with fever.
- Come on, man, give him this.
- Look, this is all I have.
- It's different.
- This is for the fever, kid.
- He doesn't have just a fever!
I've got a temperature,
dizziness, sharp pains...
You didn't go to a hospital?
I called a friend, he told me
to just give him these...
- I also have palpitations.
- Okay, take it easy, Dad.
They told me I could find
these drugs in any drugstore.
- Did you take a good look, kid?
- It's just that I'm new here.
- Isn't there a book to look it up?
- A drug handbook.
Isn't there someone
who can attend us properly?
The chemist will come back
in half an hour.
We can't wait half an hour...
He's not feeling well and...
...he must have the drugs now.
- Maybe he'll come sooner.
How sooner?
I don't know, maybe he'll
come sooner, don't know yet.
- Can you wait for half an hour?
- Yes, yes, I can stand it...
Let's go home
and we come back later.
- Are you sure?
- Yes, I'm sure.
- No, we'll go to the E.R. Ward.
- No, dear, it's not necessary.
I don't care what you think,
just look at you.
I'm sorry.
- No, kid, forget about it.
- Come on.
Okay, we're leaving.
Nothing happened, man,
it's over that's that...
...bad luck, that's all.
I'm talking to you.
- Well?
- Hello.
Everything cool?
- The keys are in there.
- Any problems?
None, I got up early,
that's all.
- What's this?
- Aropax, what you asked me for...
The anti-depressant.
But I told you to get the 30 ones.
- What? - What does it say here?
- It's all I could find.
- Where did you get this from?
- The middle shelf.
I told you beside the counter.
- You didn't say that!
- I did.
- These are no good to me!
- Give me less money.
You're telling me how much
I have to give you?
Give me half the money,
I already pulled the job.
You did it wrong,
I explained it to you very well.
What else did you need
a bloody map, imbecile?
Shove them up your ass,
these are no good to me, punk!
Come here!
Dammit, fucking dammit!
- Hi, there!
- Hello! How are you!
- Still playing?
- Yeah.
I need a leash
for my girlfriend's dog.
- How is it? Big, small...
- Medium.
You have these leather ones...
...these are a bit longer...
- Hey, you didn't go on Saturday...
- Where to?
- It was Julio's birthday.
- Really?
Your father told me nothing.
I was there for a short time
because I had to play.
- And who were there?
- All the guys from the club.
- And was it fun?
- It was a bore...
They spent the whole time
organizing their holidays.
- You going to Valdivia on summer?
- No, I don't think so.
I'm going with my
girlfriend to the countryside.
- Okay.
- How much is it?
Nothing...
just leave me five pesos.
- Okay, fine.
- Thanks.
- Tell your old man to call me.
- I will.
- Bye.
- Bye and good luck.
A teaspoonful in a pot
more or less like this one...
...and then water it regularly.
- You didn't call me.
Hello!
I've almost finished.
- I left you three messages.
- Nico, wait a minute, please.
Couldn't you just call?
I'd better come
some other time.
Yah... I'm sorry.
Nico, Can't you see
I'm with customers?
I just want to talk to you and
you're not capable of calling.
I said I'd phone if I could.
If I didn't is because I was busy.
Just pick up the phone,
it's five minutes.
- I didn't have five minutes.
- Don't lie to me.
You know I'm working a lot
and I've got the exams.
- Cut the bullshit.
- It's not bullshit, Nico.
I only have ten days left,
that's all. I'm off on a trip.
What is going on, Luchi?
About what?
With me...
...what's going on with me?
I'm traveling.
You know the way I feel,
don't you?
I think we'd better not see
each other for a few days.
I'll call you.
I think this one's empty.
Are you okay?
Yes, why?
Don't know, you seem
rather strange these days.
Strange about what?
No, nothing's wrong with me.
Nico, wouldn't you like
to take some days off?
What?
It's just that there are things to
pay in Valdivia and I thought...
- Still insisting on that, Fran?
- No, no... to rent it...
I can't do anything
about it from here...
And I thought maybe
the trip would do you good.
You can ask Santi, if you like.
- I'll give you money for it all.
- You want to rent it?
Yes, maybe for a couple
of months in the year...
...and then we see.
But everything
has to be paid for now.
Is something wrong?
No, nothing's wrong.
While you're away,
I can call the plumber.
- Would you like that?
- Okay, let me talk to Santi.
Ask him and let me know.
Otherwise. I'll go, no problem.
Yes.
Let me know when
you're through with that...
...so we can get
something to eat.
Okay.
I'm going to buy smokes.
There's a bigger kiosk
next block.
- I need batteries.
- I want to smoke now.
Come on man, are you looking
at those fucking little fish?
Do you want something
to eat now?
Drink?
No.
- C'mon, Santi, it's over now.
- It's not fucking over, man.
I can't sell those drugs. I won't
be able to replace the money.
- Cool it, man.
- I do what I damn well please.
You have no idea what's
going to happen at home now.
Do you have the money? No.
Then keep your nose out of this.
Go to hell!
- What d'you say?
- I said go to hell!
You know you're
my best friend, don't you?
I'm sorry I got you
into this mess...
...and also for that thing
about the fish.
Look at all the fish you like,
that little fish was cool.
It was wooden, wasn't it?
It was cool.
And... isn't it possible that
he went back to your house?
No, I went there before coming,
and everything was the same.
Besides, he didn't have a key.
And... had he ever been
to Niebla or Valdivia?
No.
And... didn't he say if
he wanted to go somewhere?
No, he said nothing.
What was the last thing
you two spoke about?
Nothing...
nothing important.
This is what you'll have to do.
You go home, wait overnight...
...and if by tomorrow he hasn't
shown up, call your brother...
...because we need a responsible
adult to begin the search.
Okay.
Nothing remained, see?
Last time you could
still see the ailerons...
...the engine,
which was over there...
...and the propeller.
Grass didn't grow there before,
it was all burnt, remember?
Nico!
Come on, we're home.
You'll sleep better in bed!
- Everything okay?
- Yes.
- D'you want to dine out?
- No.
- Come on, let's go.
- No, I'm not hungry.
Nico...
I've been thinking, we're
selling the house in Valdivia.
- Really?
- Yes.
What about
the summer holidays?
Julio and the others?
Don't know... it's been ten days
since I last heard of them.
That's great. We don't have
to go there again, do we?
Whatever you like.
I must go over there
to sign and all that.
But only when a potential buyer
appears, not just yet.
Okay.
There are several
messages for you.
I just spoke to Santi's mother...
she said that she an Enrique...
...will cope with everything
from now on.
Hi, Nico,
this is your cousin Martín...
...I wanted to ask you a favor...
Hello! Nico, this is Luchi.
I just wanted to tell you my trip
was put forward, and...
...well, I wanted to see you...
well, call me...
...kiss...
- Hello! Is Luchi here?
- Was there nobody in front?
- No, is Luchi here?
- I don't know any Luchi.
Luchi, she works here, she's from
Chile, she's the owner's sister.
- Could be Luciana.
- Yes, could be, is she here?
- No, she no longer works here.
- How come she doesn't?
- No, she went off on a trip.
- Has she already left?
Was leaving one of these days.
I think she was leaving today.
- Today, at what time?
- I really don't know.
Okay...
Make me feel...
...that things
do have a meaning...
...that everything is not lost...
...that there's still tomorrow.
That I no longer need...
...these pills...
...to light me up...
...to shine
And I'll never think
of dying again
of dying again...
If you are with me...
...I want to be alive
Believe me...
...I've been through hell...
...and the taste of the gun
in my mouth...
...is no longer a game
In fact, my past...
...is a whole mess
If you want to change it...
...I won't refuse.
And I'll never think
of dying again
of dying again...
If you are with me...
...I want to be alive
Subs by Knaya