BORN AND BRED
Daddy.
Daddy, wake up!
Come on, Daddy!
What are you doing here?
What time is it?
You shouldn't be
in Mummy's and Daddy's bed.
It's nine! We overslept!
Come on!
We're going to be late, come on.
Jose, ask Anita
to dress you for school.
Anita, will you dress me?
Excuse me.
- Didn't you hear the alarm clock?
- No.
No?
Me neither.
No, I don't like it.
Dad, come here! Dad!
Are you having yogurt or juice?
Yogurt.
I said I don't like it...
I don't want to!
Jose! You can't throw
your socks like that!
Stop winding Anita up.
Good morning, Sir.
Everything is ready.
Hurry up or we'll be late.
I'm coming!
Anita, have you seen my blue sandals?
Yes, they are in the laundry.
- Where?
- In the laundry, Madam.
Thanks.
What a morning, sweetie!
Good morning, Anita.
Good morning, Madam.
Jose won't come back for lunch.
My mother will pick her up.
Just leave some dinner ready.
- Thanks a lot.
- Your mother called last night.
And?
She wants to talk to you.
- Call her.
- Later.
Anita, have you got Jose's
things? It's late.
Yes, Madam. I'm just sorting them.
Are you ready, sweetheart?
She hasn't finished.
Okay, have a little more.
She'll eat at school.
The coffee!
- We're ready, Madam!
- Great.
Hurry, sweetie, you're late.
You'll eat at the nursery.
Bye!
See you later.
Take this. Bye!
Bye!
Their agent will contact you directly.
Everything fits
into one container:
Lamps, furniture, sofas,
tables, everything.
When will they confirm
its arrival in Milan?
Just a second, can you hold?
You forgot to send me the samples.
I forgot. I've just finished.
But at least let me tell you
how it went!
I found another one.
Hi. It's really nice!
It's a good one.
Look, what do you think?
I'd try more saturated colors.
I was looking at the
upholstery samples...
for the hotel lounge...
Here, I think white would work best.
Looks good.
Yes. There's
another option though.
That's really nice.
Isn't it too much work?
Not at all. We have two months.
But we are talking about 30-35 rooms.
But 20 are identical.
There are only 10 exclusive ones.
It will be fine!
Look, here are some bed options.
- Aren't they nice?
- Yes.
And your lamps will go nicely.
Milli, you just
blew smoke in my face!
Come on! What's wrong with you?
- When will you stop smoking?
- I need time.
- Don't press so hard.
- Jose, it's bedtime!
Coming, mom!
Come on, sweetie.
Pess gently
or the paper will tear.
Coming, Mummy!
Come on, Jose.
Come on, sweetie.
Coming!
That's pretty!
- Yes!
- You worked hard!
I drew the house and he coloured it.
It's very good!
Kiss Daddy goodnight.
- Can I do a bit more?
- No, no, it's very late.
Let her, she's not finished yet.
That's it.
What a pretty blue!
- A kiss for Dad.
- Now the green one!
No, that's enough.
You have school tomorrow.
A kiss for Daddy.
Let's go.
What are you two whispering about?
Tidy the things.
- Let's go brush your teeth.
- Jose!
Off to sleep!
I don't want to go to sleep...
I love you.
I love you too.
Are you going to leave me?
You're such a bore!
You're always fighting me.
- No, I'm not.
- Yes, you like the fight.
- No.
- Yes, you do!
- Yes, yes, yes.
No, there's nothing wrong.
We're just tired...
that's all.
Everything's fine.
What if we go away
for a few days...
But, where to?
To Victoria's country house.
When?
Tomorrow... perhaps.
- Tomorrow?
- Tomorrow.
Not tomorrow. It's a working day.
Come on!
Let's take a few days off.
- I won't fall! I won't fall!
- Jose, you're going to fall, stop.
That's enough, you're going
to fall, stop it.
I won't fall! I won't fall!
Jose, what did Mummy say?
I want to go now.
We're going soon...
but first finish your cereal.
I have finished.
No cheating,
there's still a lot left.
Are you happy to miss school?
Yes.
Let's go then.
Go fetch your things, we're off.
Darling, I left the ice box for you.
OK.
Are you taking your toys?
Yes.
Jose, look what
you are leaving behind!
Thanks Anita. I'll miss you.
Anita, if necessary,
you can call me.
Very well, Madam, I'll see you.
Hello!
Hello, my darling! How are you?
Hello, mom.
Hello, Milli. How are you, my dear?
You okay?
- How's everything, Santi?
- Hello, Victoria.
Thank you.
Look what I have for you...
as promised.
Let's see if you like it, sweetie.
Thank you.
This is Pedro's salary from
last month.
Ah, great.
And this is for the bathroom work.
Fine.
And of course, the keys
which you're familiar with, so...
That's great.
You can wear it in the evening.
It gets chilly in the country.
When will you stay over
with Grannie? When?
Next week...
when we get back.
After the trip, right?
Good. I'll be waiting
for you. Come back soon.
- Here, dear.
- Mummy, I want to stop.
Come on, not now, Jose,
don't start. It's a long trip.
Here, Santi.
Thanks.
Mummy, can you tell me a story?
OK, a story...
Once upon a time, there was a bear
who liked honey so much.
One day, whilst walking in the forest
he met a little boy...
And the little boy said...
You! Come on!
"Hello, Mr Bear."
Come on, give it a bit more sentiment!
"Good day, Mr Bear!"
And the bear said:
"What are you doing in my forest?"
"I'm eating your honey."
"How can you eat my honey?"
"I want you to leave my forest!"
Lie down, sweetie. Go on!
Lie down properly.
Go on!
- Go on.
- Mummy...
What is it, baby?
- I want to be at the front.
- Go on, sit back.
- I want to sleep at the front with you!
- No, we'll be there soon.
- Please, mom!
- You can't ride at the front.
- Sit back.
- No. - Lie back, Jose.
Come on, Jose, sit back.
- Daddy, you tell her!
- No, no...
Don't insist, sweetie, you can't.
Jose, you can't.
Children must ride at the back.
Lie down properly.
- I want to be at the front.
- Lie back!
- You're making us a cross!
- Please, mummy!
Jose, lie back!
I want to be at the front.
Jose, stop it!
Josefina, sit back please!
- Let me be at the front!
- Sit back!
- Josefina, stay still, please.
- Stop it!
I said sit back!
- Stop yelling at her!
- What?
- Sit back and shut up!
- I hate you!
Stop it!
Watch out!
Slow down!
Milli!
Jose!
Good day.
OK... what's up? Some furs!
How much?
I've been paying 20
but make it 18 each.
- Take it or leave it.
- 20 and we have a deal.
- No. I said 18.
- Let it go, Robert.
OK...
18. How much for the hare?
And what about the hare?
15 pesos.
No. For the hare, I'll give you 10, no
more. And just to give you the business.
That's my price.
Can't pay more.
Go on, Robert.
I won't sell them now.
I'll have to store them...
for at least a year.
- Fair enough.
- Help yourselves to some food?
Thanks.
Come on, Cachilo, let's go.
Bye, Santiaguito. Bye, Robert.
Bye!
You dropped some cards.
- Can I take them?
- Yes.
Isn't Betty here today?
She took the little one
to the clinic. He's not well.
Ready, boys?
What for?
To go to Riojano's bar!
There's nothing to do over there.
Why are they asking us to go anyway?
Rosales wants us there anyhow...
even to stand around.
Even if no planes come in...
just for the sake of it.
One more glass, please, Riojano!
Right away.
How was the hunting?
OK. But he's paying less
and less for the skins.
Riojano is turning foxy.
He used to pay OK.
Not anymore.
And this one?
Is he learning?
Sort of.
Good day.
- Hi, Betty.
- Hi.
Hi, Johny, how's my top boy?
I'll show you a great hunting spot.
He'll have a good chance to practice.
There's plenty of beautiful foxes!
- What's that?
- My new cell phone.
- Well, a new cell phone!
- Hello, hello.
You've got to fix that van.
- Hello?
- Hello, Victoria?
No, Victoria is not here.
Can I take a message?
Can you put Jose on?
Sir, with Jose I cannot...
Pardon?
- Come on, Santiago!
- Who's calling?
Don't leave it all to me!
Watch your heads, please.
Follow the path, please.
Good morning, Sir. Follow the path.
Taking the bus, Sir?
Then, stay on the path, Sir.
This way, please.
Thank you.
Hello.
Your name, Sir?
Your name?
35 kilos to Calafate.
- You need to handle things
more carefully. - Good, Sir.
Careful, that's very fragile.
OK, Rosales.
Another 25 kilos to Calafate.
Was it that bad? Your work.
No. Sort of.
Or, did you leave a woman behind, ah?
No.
OK, Riojano.
- Hi, Betty.
- Hi. How are you?
- How are things?
- Fine... and you?
- Can I have some ice?
- Just a minute.
Listen...
We should fix a date.
Stop the chatting.
There's work to do.
Go, you're my man Robert!
There Jonny, great!
Thanks, mate.
It's all a fix. Favouritism.
Let's go, Dad.
See you later.
Bye.
- Sorry, boys.
- Hurry up!
Pass me my jacket, will you?
- Good evening.
- Bye, Cacique.
It's real punishment.
Melchora's been in agony
for two years now.
It's killing him.
No, it's his wife who's dying.
Stop! Stop! Stop!
What's wrong?
What is it, Santiago?
What did you see?
Get out of the way!
What did you see, Santiago?
What's wrong, asshole?
Nothing.
It was nothing.
You're such a dickhead!
Good morning. TWR Foxtrot Alfa 510,
from Comodoro to Rio Turbio.
It's a Papa Alfa 28.
Flying VFR 075.
Request runaway conditions.
Over.
Good morning, Foxtrot Alfa 510!
Weather conditions here...
are below the minimum.
You'll have to decide...
whether to cancel the flight.
Over.
Will you pour me some tea?
Yes.
This flight is turning around.
The weather's too rough.
Awful weather.
How many passengers are downstairs?
- Five.
Can I have your attention, please?
Please, Sir, wake up.
Wake up, please, Sir.
Sir? I'm afraid the
flight's been cancelled.
Not again! Goddam it!
I'm sorry you waited in vain.
- My family's waiting!
- I gotta get to work, boss.
- What am I supposed to do now?
- I've just been informed myself.
We inform all passengers
travelling on flight 097...
to El Calafete and Santa Cruz,
that due to...
critical runway conditions,
the flight has been cancelled.
We apologise for any inconvenience.
Thank you.
Stop the car!
Look over there!
- Let's take it!
- Sure!
The poor thing is lost.
Give me a hand, Santiago.
- Poor thing.
- Have you got it?
Robert, make some room on the truck.
Up! That's it.
A professional job.
- What a stink.
- The poor animal is frightened.
Ride on my brave cowboys!
This is some lamb!
We'll have to roast it
at the weekend, right?
Otherwise Rosales and the others...
will want to crash the party.
Parasites!
I guess so.
Hello!
Hello. Yeah...
What's wrong?
Wait! Just a second!
Are you crazy?
Don't fuck with me.
I've got nothing to do with this!
Hello there, Muddy!
Morning, Robert.
Morning, Cacique.
Come on Cacique, we're hungry.
Hi, Santi.
Shit, we've hit a tendon!
A bit more wood
and we're ready to go.
How's your wife, Cacique?
I don't know. It's getting worse.
Can't last much longer!
It's been 3 years now.
A terrible illness.
And she suffers terribly.
She's in God's hands.
They're hungry.
They've not eaten
properly for a week.
Robert, your cell phone!
I'm not answering.
Why not?
It's my ex-girlfriend.
She says she's 3 months pregnant.
Pregnant?
When did you last see her?
Three and a half months, roughly...
You're going to be a daddy.
Well done, Robert!
We'll see.
What do you mean, we'll see?
I'm too young,
it's too much responsibility, Cacique.
You're 30.
I'm 29.
A baby is always a blessing.
"They bring their bread with them."
That's nonsense, Cacique.
Switch it off, if you won't answer.
Don't piss me off, Santiago.
Easy there, Robert.
Stop it, boys!
Santiago!
Calm down, both of you.
Stop fighting.
Pass me the wine!
Thanks, Robert.
What're you doing, Santiago?
You're disgusting!
Use the fucking bucket!
And take it out!
Hello?
Hello.
- Is that you, Santiago?
- Victoria, put me on to Jose.
Santiago, tell me where you are.
Are you alright?
Put me on to Jose, please.
But you can't talk to Jose.
Don't hang up,
tell me where you are!
Put Jose on please!
She can't talk to you.
Please, don't hang up!
Look at me, Santiago.
I'm not fit to be a father.
You don't know the mother.
What if a girl called you,
before you came down here...
and said she's pregnant
and you're gonna be a daddy?
I don't know.
You couldn't have taken this job,
for instance.
Even with the hardship pay,
the extra pay...
you can't bring up a kid here.
What's he going to do?
Work at Riojano's bar?
Or at the airport?
Become a policeman...
or a miner and join these zombies?
Shut the window, Santiago!
Throw me one.
I don't know
Fuck off, Romina! Bye!
I don't care!
I can't talk now. Bye.
Oh, piss off!
Hello.
Hello, Milli?
10 kilos, Sir.
Very good.
- This way.
- Three.
The plane leaves in 2 hours.
- Hello, Sir.
- How many passengers today?
There are three later.
- The plane arrives in 2 hours.
- Yes, Boss!
Line up the signals.
There's a strong wind.
Once they've finished...
move the tractor to the runway.
Yes, Sir.
We inform all passengers
that the flight...
arriving from Gallegos
to Rio Turbio was cancelled.
Your attention, please,
all passengers.
The flight was cancelled.
For information
check with the office.
I want my money back.
Did you give someone
my cell phone number?
Pardon?
You did, you gave someone my number.
No.
Someone keeps ringing you.
Impossible.
A middle aged lady.
I don't know.
Don't play smart with me, Santiago.
This way, Boss.
Thank you, Ortega.
Come on, boys.
Here, with the boss.
Afternoon.
Good afternoon.
Runway maintenance
has been very poor.
We do our best.
It's not our job.
But, I gave you an order.
We've tried, Mr Rosales.
We try really hard...
with what little we have.
We need more equipment.
We tried to repair the runway, Sir.
Watch your attitude, Cacique.
All flights will have to be cancelled.
- We get the day off?
- No. You'll do your regular work.
We'll be out of a job, soon.
That's right.
They don't need 5 guys...
to attend one plane a month.
- I'm off, boys.
- OK.
- Bye, see you tomorrow.
- See you.
On top of things,
this scum Rosales...
he wants us to fix the runway.
What the hell!
It's not our job.
What will you do without a job?
I don't know. Go somewhere else.
I don't know.
Santiago, I'm still
getting calls for you.
Must be a wrong number.
What wrong number?
They must've called 10 times.
They don't
get it wrong 10 times.
They want the blonde guy.
They're looking for you.
I've no idea who it is.
Who did you fuck with?
At least tell me what to say.
That I'm not here.
Go get it.
We need a fox.
Hell, there's nothing over there!
It's chilly, huh?
It might even snow.
So, Cacique, what's the plan?
Don't worry.
The skins are good quality.
Riojano will try to fuck us over!
Leave him to me.
I'll deal with him.
18... take it or leave it.
Five skins, five times two
equals ten...
Settled: 100 pesos.
It's the last time.
Will you give us some wine?
Take a seat and relax.
Relax.
A little wine for my friends!
- Excuse me.
- You look happy!
Polenta and sauce.
- What's up, Johnny?
- Nice polenta.
Thanks.
- Hi there, Betty.
- Hi.
- How are you?
- Fine. You?
Can you give me some ice?
Coming.
Always the same story.
He's pulling our leg.
Hello.
Don't you want your dummy?
Santiago! Come here!
Santi!
Santiago!
Don't!
Get your hand out of there!
Yes, that's it.
Come on!
Come on, I said!
Stop it!
Don't! Stop! Stop!
You fucking whore!
What's your problem?
Relax...
What's wrong with you?
Let me go!
- Let me go!
- What's wrong with him?
Get out, get out of here!
Faggot!
What's with you?
Tonight I'll go
my breathing slow
far away, to listen
with my eyes closed, to your song
And at dawn
your wise call will reach me
Together like yesterday
will embrace those who are gone
Robert...
Betty...
Can I come in?
You always have to begin again
Always have to keep going on
I need to be with you
before I die
I travel through dreams
to find you again, my love
in this life or another
My heart is yours, and my soul
My soul
Come on over, Rober!
You idiot!
I made some toast.
How are you feeling?
Why?
I don't know.
I'm better.
The Meteorological Service
has issued...
a weather warning for the region
advising the use...
of chains when travelling by road.
On the other hand...
My ex-girlfriend called.
And?
She wants the kid.
And you?
Well... if she wants it...
let her have it.
OK.
See what the storm did to the gate?
They'll make us fix it.
But... if this keeps up,
that will be it.
Because of the weather?
Right.
We can go hunting with Cacique.
Slow down!
Can't you see it's too muddy?
You can't see anything!
Go easy there!
Stop! Stop, you idiot!
Stop!
You want to drive?
I don't drive, you fucking asshole!
Come on!
Come here you pansy!
Stop that! Are you crazy?
Stop that!
- Hello!
- Try here.
It's Robert.
Hello.
Hello!
We're stuck with the truck.
See if it works.
You answer it!
What!
You deal with it.
It's the old lady calling you!
- You answer it!
- I'm not answering.
I can't keep telling her
you're not here. Come on!
You're going to have
to answer someday.
OK. I'm sorry.
I don't want your excuses.
Your shit...
is contaminating my life.
I'll fix it.
You said the same thing last week.
I need time.
Playing tricks, Cacique?
- Bring a towel, Johny.
- I'm coming.
Hello, you've reached
Victoria's house...
please leave a message. Thanks.
Listen!
I was waiting for you.
What's up?
You owe me money.
It's been over a month now.
But... why so much?
It's for one month
and your stuff with Betty...
OK, but Betty was
with Robert, not me.
That's your problem and Robert's.
Don't worry.
I'll sort it out with him.
- Take it.
- Don't worry.
Can you sort this out?
Give me another bottle, Riojano.
We're celebrating a special occasion.
I'll make an exception.
Listen, everyone. Tonight,
let's drink to our friend...
Robert, who is going to be a father.
Let's do it!
Cheers!
Betty is going to be a Mummy!
No. She's got nothing to do with this.
Sit down and be quiet.
And you, don't worry.
What's happening?
It's not Betty.
Let's try!
Robert has a girl back home...
and he just told me
he's going to be a father.
Congratulations, Robert!
Let's drink till dawn.
I'm going to celebrate...
with my friends, Cacique and Santiago.
We're going to party all night
in Rio Turbio.
Raise your glasses once more!
Good health to everyone!
Cheers!
Good evening.
- Let's go, Daddy.
- A toast.
I'm coming, dear.
Mummy needs you.
Tell mother I'm coming!
Come on, then!
Damn it!
Are you deaf?
Tell her I'm coming!
Easy...
Go on!
Start up! Damn it!
- Come on, boys!
- There it goes! There it goes!
Turn it on, go Robert!
Hurry up, faster!
Push hard.
Go on!
Push hard, you bastards!
What's with this truck!
We'll arrive at noon...
and the girls...
will be already asleep. Then,
we'll go to have sex between us!
- Coming!
- Hurry up!
It's almost dawn!
Father, don't go. Mother is sick.
I have to work with the boys.
- Don't, Dad!
- Look after her!
- Please stay home, Dad.
Dad!
I wanna girl!
Take it easy
or they'll arrest us.
Hello, girls!
- Not here, Cacique. Come on!
- This is a book shop.
Where the hell are these girls?
Calm down!
- Where the hell are they?
- Three blocks from here.
We've walked all morning
and still not there!
Piss off, Cacique.
You should have a good 'stag party'.
- We're almost there.
- I pay. I'll pay!
Bye. Good luck!
Bye, sweetie!
Come on Robert, I'm freezing!
- Well, tough.
- It's cold.
Come, take me home.
Bye, boys!
Let's go, Cacique!
The heat is unbearable.
When things get mixed up...
and roses bloom, midst the nettle...
you no longer know what you know.
Cheers!
It's my party. You must try
some of my stuff. Cacique?
Whatever you say,
but leave me to my coca.
Come on!
One shot.
These, my coca leaves, so green
and lush with hope and life...
Santiaguito!
I'm sorry that Santiago will be
left behind, alone like a dog.
Alone like a dog!
Robert, dear, you're gonna be a daddy!
A good old macho!
Here!
- Cheers!
Cheers!
And you? Stuffing it in, eh!
You too Cacique, go on!
Cheers!
I'm not Mapuche.
Who named you Cacique?
A Gringo son of a bitch.
Many years ago, I first
came here for 6 months but...
I'm still here.
My kids were born here.
Then, they grew up here.
What about your kid?
Don't know.
I won't bring him up here.
God took her with Him
so she would no longer suffer.
She was so good!
Melchora, take me with you!
I'll miss you, Mum.
Please don't leave me.
I'll miss you so much!
We are here to say farewell
to our good friend...
who gave so much to our community.
May the Lord bless her...
forever and ever. Amen.
Goodbye, Melchora.
God bless you.
You were so good to us.
May God keep you at his side.
Get off!
Go, leave me alone!
That's right.
Lock it.
Up here.
On the shoulder.
Fire.
Open.
Take out.
Close.
What's wrong?
Close it.
Lock it.
On the shoulder.
Fire.
Fire anywhere.
Try again.
Listen carefully.
You have to look from this point.
- What's wrong?
- Nothing.
- Are you OK?
- Yes.
- Standing steady?
Put it down.
Santiago, put it down!
Who's there?
- No one. Put it down.
- Get off!
- Put the gun down, you moron!
- Stop it! Put it down.
- Get off, Robert!
Put it down, Santiago. Please.
Stop, Santiago!
There's no one there!
There's no one, stop!
Santiago!
Stop!
Who's there?
Don't be a dickhead, put it down!
I'm burning!
I won't chase after you, Santiago!
You'll hurt yourself!
Santiago!
What's wrong?
Cover up. You'll freeze.
I miss Milli and Jose.
Go find them.
- Calm down.
- Go find them.
Sit up cover up.
Let go!
Stop!
Relax, Santiago, please.
Calm down, Santiago.
Come on, you'll freeze to death.
Please, go get them.
Easy, relax, tell me...
Come here, sit up straight.
Please, Santiago, tell me.
Look at me.
Go on.
Come on, tell me what's wrong.
I killed them.
Who did you kill?
My family.
I killed my family.
- What family?
- My family. I crashed the car.
I killed them.
But... you don't drive, Santiago.
And you have no family.
I was in hospital a long time,
many months.
Jose and Milli were my family.
I kept asking about them...
but no one would give
me a straight answer.
So, I realized what had happened.
What could I do? Wait there and
get the answer I already knew?
So, I pulled off
the I.V.'s and left.
You have to help me.
You call home.
I'll talk to Rosales tomorrow.
It will all work out.
Talk to Buenos Aires
and it will all work out.
Hello.
- Hello.
- Victoria, please.
Santiago?
- Is that you?
- Milli?
Tell me where you are.
Don't hang up.
Victoria? Who is this?
Milli?
Are you dumb?
Santiago, listen.
Please calm down.
We need to talk.
Please, Santi, we have to talk...
Where are you?
I'll come and get you, please.
I can't take this anymore.
Where are you?
Talk to me, say something!
Hurry up. The plane's coming in.
Right.
Just one minute, everyone.
We're saying farewell to a
fellow worker.
A civilian who's leaving for
better pastures. Let's make a toast.
I'm giving you the go ahead.
Go ahead.
Cheers!
Safe journey.
Good luck!
The best of luck.
Cheers, Cacique.
Hand me Santiago's present, please.
A souvenir...
- to remember us by.
- Thanks.
A little local handicraft for you.
Thank you.
Let's hope he remembers us.
It's beautiful.
Well, then, off to work.
Plane's coming in.
Come on, let's go.
TWR, do you read me?
Over.
I request runway
conditions for landing.
All clear for landing.
No animals on the runway.
All ready.
Your stuff.
Good luck, Santiago.
Thanks, Cacique.
Take care.
Thanks for everything.
We'll miss you.
Call us some time.
Bye.
Robert...
- Bye, my friend. Take care.
- OK.
What about you?
I don't know.
She'll come here with the kid...
and we'll take off.
OK.
This way, please.
Head towards the plane.
Safe flight.
Thanks.
Don't forget to call.
Bye, my friend.
Bye.
- Ring me on the cell phone.
- Sure.
Shall we go for a walk?
I've quit smoking.