swimming alone
Wake up, Martín.
It's getting late.
Do you want a lift?
No... classes start later.
The Geography teacher isn't coming.
And I'm supposed to pick Guille up.
Aren't you eating?
No. I'm not hungry.
You must eat,
you are still growing.
Is there any raspberry jam?
No. Peach and
plum jam, as usual.
I wanted raspberry jam today.
Do you need a hand?
What does "osmosis" mean?
Osmosis... the whole line.
"The osmosis".
Your collar, Martín,
or they won't let you in.
- Hi.
This is a message for
Martín Canepa's parents.
Please contact the
school principal ASAP.
Hi. This is a message for
Martín from Diego Lindl
I used to be Pablo's room-mate.
Could you call me back?
My number is 4774-7649. Bye.
Hi.
How are you doing, Fede?
It's 5:25.
I know, I'm late.
My Mom hid my bass.
She wouldn't give it back till
I passed my English exam.
How did you find it?
I waited till she was gone.
She put it behind
the washing-machine.
It was soaked in foam.
I'll kill myself,
if that's what you want,
but then don't miss me
the way I miss you.
if that's what you want
but then don't cry for me
as I cry for you.
Things are not the
way we wanted them to be.
Excuse me. Do you know
where 2500 Arenales St. is?
Could you break this bill,
I need change.
No. Arenales St.?
Yes. It's 4 blocks away: French,
Juncal, Berutti and Arenales.
Thanks.
Hi.
- Anything else?
- No.
All right. Thanks.
- Could you give me some change
for the payphone? - Sure.
Thanks. Bye.
I expected you earlier.
I was listening to
the rehearse tape.
- What time are you meeting Eugenia?
- 12:30.
OK.
Fede's always late to rehearsals.
There's always something, right?.
- Is it late?
- Twenty past twelve.
Do you remember Diego, Pablo's
room-mate for almost a year?
- Yes, a friend of him. - I don't
know if they were friends...
- He left a message today.
- So?
I don't know. It could
be something important?
Did he leave his phone number?
- Yes. Probably
- Are you coming to the party?
Could it be about Pablo?
Hey! Do you want
to come to the party?
No, I don't feel like going.
I have to go.
- Which way are you going?
- Arenales and Laprida St.
2500 Arenales St.
I'm going the other way.
Bye.
- Hi.
Have you seen a white T-Shirt...
- Go to the laundromat.
- ... with a singer's picture on it?
- No. Oh, look at this!
- Can't Julieta go?
- She went to a birthday party.
- Does it have to be today?
Yes. Hurry up or they'll close.
You might find your T-shirt.
Is it the one round the corner?
No. On French St.,
four blocks from here.
Why didn't you use
the usual laundry?
Because there's a raffle
for a washing machine.
But we've already got one.
But this one is high tech.
- It's six blocks from here.
- Please.
- I bought you raspberry jam.
- Thanks.
- Hi.
I'm here to pick up some laundry.
- Have you got the receipt?
- Yes.
- How is it going with the drums?
- What?
Your mum told me her son wants
to be a drummer. Is that you?
Yes, that's me.
And a daughter who wanted
to be an English teacher.
Yes, my sister.
And another one.
Give my regards to your Mom
and tell her next week...
we're moving twenty yards
across the avenue.
Two blocks further away.
That's it. It's $5.
Bye.
Wait! Don't forget your coupon
for the washing-machine raffle.
And a candy.
If you raffle a washing-machine,
the winner won't be coming back.
This is a laundromat,
we couldn't raffle a TV set.
- Bye.
Can you drive me to Juan's
tomorrow to pick up a drum?
- At what time?
- About noon.
No, I can't. I've got to pick
Julieta up at Agustina's.
She's sleeping over.
It's close by.
You can walk, then. Last time you
messed up my car upholstery.
Don't do that! Use your plate.
There's fish on my plate and I don't
want to mix it with the salad.
Then get up, and
get a clean plate.
Don't smash anything.
The T-shirt wasn't in the bag.
The old one you use
for gym classes?
I've done some spring cleaning
and threw all the old stuff.
No, it was Pablo's.
A Morrisey T-Shirt.
The morley polo-neck
you got for Epiphany.
- It was for Christmas.
- Epiphany.
It's a T-shirt, not a polo-neck,
and I mean Morrisey, a singer.
- The one with a drawing?
- With a black and white picture.
It must be among
the ones I threw away.
Why do you want that T-Shirt now?
Did you call?
He was out. I left a
message for him to call me.
Leave the keys for your brother
with the superintendent.
I had a fight a row with him.
I went to pay the monthly expenses
and woke him up from his nap.
I don't want to go out late.
Perhaps Diego goes to sleep early.
If you want me to go with you,
we must wait for Mauro.
Otherwise, go alone,
or we go tomorrow.
I don't want to go late.
Diego may go out or go to be.
There was a message from school
about our absence today.
What did your parents say?
They were out, and I erased
the message just like you did.
Fede phoned me today.
He asked me to put
Monday's rehearsal off.
It's the second time this month
he's put a rehearsal off.
I saw him yesterday.
He gave me my skateboard back
the wheels are shot.
I have to sell it.
I've never seen Fede
on a skateboard.
He skated across his
grandma's yard but...
she wouldn't let him skate
because he ruined her flowerbeds.
- Call to see if your brother's
back. - I've just phoned.
It's... getting late.
- You have a dog?
- No.
A cat?
No.
- You must have a pet.
- No. I don't.
Do you want to come in?
No, thanks. There's nobody in.
- So what do you do?
- Nothing. We just talk.
Everyone in their pajamas?
Everyone but Agustina.
She wore a nightgown.
- And that's amusing?
- Sort of.
No! This is not a toy.
This is for playing tennis.
- Give me your bag.
- I'll carry it with me.
Let's get going.
Are you on your way to school?
Yes. But I'm going with Guille.
- Alright. Bye.
- Bye.
Sit down, everybody.
We'll start the class.
Arcuri.
Here.
Bavio.
Speak up, next time.
Cánepa
Is Cánepa absent again?
He's ill. He's got the flu.
He sprained his ankle last week.
No, that was me.
Are you getting better?
No, but I don't want
to miss any more lessons.
Cánepa's a red-haired boy
who wears glasses?
No. The red-haired boy is Santín
and the one with glasses...
the Chinese guy, Chen-Tung.
Oh, yes. Chen-Tung.
Yes, Cánepa.
Tell him about
Thursday's test. OK?
Casenave.
Here.
Hi. This is another message
for Martín. It's Diego, again.
I'd like you to come Thursday 6pm
to pick up some of Pablo's stuff
My phone is out of order.
My address is 2139 Olleros St
4th floor, apartment B. Bye.
Fede is in his English class.
Says he'll pay next time.
I've already booked it
for next Wednesday.
- Do you know if Fede's free?
- I don't know.
- Shall we go?
- Which way are you going?
The other way. We'll pick up
her little brother from school.
Bye.
Hi.
- Hi, Diego. It's me, Martín.
- Come in.
- The door is locked.
- I'll be right down.
I'm leaving next week and I didn't
know what to do with that stuff.
Like I was saying, I painted
all this myself.
What stuff are we talking about?
Just stuff belonging to Pablo.
The walls were light blue, right?
Yes.
Did they look OK?
Yes, I liked it better.
No, light-blue draws
all the light in.
There's the window.
Yeah, but the sun rises from
there and sets here.
It never shines here.
Then light green, as arranged.
Light-blue for the bedroom.
The bedroom's white.
The bedroom window's on that side;
Plenty of light.
You can use any color you like.
White looked great.
Can we see it?
Yes.
This is the box. Take it.
I should give it to Pablo, I guess.
I don't know. I can't find him.
Do you know where he is?
Sort of...
This huge!
The previous tenant used
to keep a bicycle in there.
We could put a lot
of shelves in here.
This is full of holes.
Pablo had pinned up
drawings and photos.
He ruined the wall.
It needs new plaster.
I'll see what I can do
to give this to him.
Hang on, we'll all leave together.
Do you like white?
Yes.
I think solid light blue
would look nice.
I'll wait in the living-room.
- Are we going to take a break?
- Hold on.
You should've studied early
in the morning, like I did.
I set the alarm-clock at six
but I overslept...
and dreamt I got up and studied.
- Ask me what the capital city is.
- Hang on.
Ask me about population.
Ask anything...
- Cut it out...
- Shoot.
What are you doing, asshole?
It's the only one I've got.
I can lend you another map.
And I'll help you with the test,
but let's go down for a snack
the brake will be over.
Ask me a couple of questions.
Please.
Then we can go.
What's wrong?
What is it?
I got Austria mixed
up with Australia.
What are those maps of yours of?
Austria, everything's Austria.
A fjord?
No, it's not a fjord, Bavio.
And what's this?
- It must be a fjord.
- Not, it's not.
Bavio, this will earn you
a three... rather a two
Yahut... step forward.
Get that shirt tidy.
And point at the different
Australian regions.
Excuse me. Can I take Cánepa
and Lucena out for a while?
Bring all your stuff.
Thanks. Sorry.
Delicious! What flavor is it?
It's new. Raspberry-flavored.
Eugenia's got to stay in studying
tonight, shall we do something?
Alright, let us.
At least we weren't tested.
I played tennis with Ricardo
yesterday and at one point...
he lent me his racket.
A graphite racket.
Very ligth.
You know my backhand is weak.
With this racket I got all
the balls in. Amazing.
I have an inter-club tournament
next week. I'd like you to come.
- We can have lunch together after.
- Ok.
How are you doing?
Fine.
What about school?
School?
Hi. What is it?
Look in my desk's third drawer,
it should be there.
How's school coming along?
School as usual.
Try to avoid sitting for
any March exams...
so we can all go on
vacations together.
I must sit in March for
last year's pending exams.
Don't add on any new ones.
Does it have a red cover?
That's it.
I'll be there in an
hour and a half.
It was Agustín, Ricardo's son.
He started working with us two weeks ago.
He's a great guy, your age.
He's saving money to jump off
bridges. He likes extreme sports.
He wants to buy a bungee cord.
He'll study to be a gym teacher.
He's a great guy.
Have you made up your mind
about your studies next year?
No, I don't know.
I've still got half a year left.
You'd better start
thinking about it.
- There you go.
- Thank you.
No. I don't know. Isn't he
in touch with your parents?
Mum and dad don't talk with him.
Since he left two years ago, they
probably talked four times.
He did the same to me.
After being together two years,
one day he took off...
and he never called me again.
Why are you looking him for?
I don't know.
I'm sorry, I can't help you.
The last thing I knew
about your brother...
is that he was working for an
aquarium in Mar del Plata.
- In Mar del Plata?
- A friend of mine ran into him.
Is he still there
or has he come back?
I don't know.
It was an aquarium in Camet.
I don't know where Camet is.
Close to the airport,
by the city entrance.
- Is it important?
- Yes.
No. In fact, it isn't.
- If I hear anything else,
I'll let you know. - OK.
- I'd better be going.
- I'll stay.
- OK. Bye.
- Bye.
It's been a year since
I last walked past here.
Do you remember when your Dad
used to drive us every morning?
And on Tuesday my Mum would
bring me to my swimming lessons.
And she'd chat with my Mom in the
bar there until we'd go out.
This is where I
learned how to swim.
This is a big pool.
It used to be. The other day I
walked by, and felt like going in.
They were all strangers.
Remember where the pool was?
The kindergarten is there now.
What happened with the
kindergarten classrooms?
- They have computers now.
- Computers?
Did you tell your
dad about school?
- No, not yet. What about you?
- Me neither.
They were coming in
as I was going out.
I'll kill myself,
if that's what you want,
but then don't miss me
the way I miss you.
If that's what you want
but then don't cry for me
as I cry for you.
Things are not the
way we wanted them to be.
Have you got 20 cents?
Yes.
I had plenty of change last
night, but now... I ran out.
Can you take the #67 bus?
Yes, but with the #113
I walk two blocks less.
- Don't you feel like walking?
- No. I'm tired.
Do you want to stay at my place?
I haven't said anything
and my folks are sleeping.
It's OK. Never mind.
Here comes your bus.
Bye.
Hi.
Hi. Don't make any noise,
Mom and Dad are sleeping.
Are you leaving?
In a while. Is it cold?
Yeah.
Have you just bought croissants?
Yeah. Martín and I
were kicked out of school.
- Want some?
- No.
- When are you telling them?
- When I see them.
Hi. It was at the door.
Leave it on the table
for your Dad to read.
You should have told us
you were coming this late.
Yeah, I know, but there
were no phones where I was.
There's no hot water.
The water was emptied
for cleaning.
You should have told me.
Suarez put up a notice in the
elevator. Thought you'd read it.
I don't go around reading notices.
And now what?
Wash your hair in
the laundry-room.
Have you seen the sports section?
No. Martín brought the paper.
He's just gone to bed.
Is anything wrong with him?
I don't know. Didn't he tell you
anything when you two had lunch?
No, we just talked.
- Excuse me, got a light?
- I don't smoke.
- What time is it?
- I don't wear a watch.
Are you Martín Cánepa?
Remember me? Tomás Forte.
Elementary school mate.
How are you?
I didn't recognize you.
You look different.
I lost like twenty pounds.
I cut my hair. It used to be brown.
You look just the same.
Yeah. Didn't you use
to live near Crámer Ave.?
I still do. I came to visit a
friend but he seems to be out.
- Here?
- Yes.
Anyway, I can visit my brother.
He's rehearsing near here.
Weren't your brother and
my brother in the same class?
Maybe.
We used to walk back from
school together, remember?
Do you know if he stills sees him?
No idea. Why?
No, it's nothing.
Come with me, and we'll ask him.
Ok.
- Let's wait another five minutes.
- OK.
After school I hardly
ever saw Pablo again.
Once on a bus,
but we hardly spoke.
Where did he go?
We were not close friends. He was
always on his own or with Lucas.
- How much did you spend?
- Lucas Tamborino?
Is it tomorrow noon or evening?
Have you got Lucas's phone number?
No. He moved to Mar del Plata
before finishing school.
Call me later, around 11 pm.
I know who's got it.
- Can't you call now? - No,
my friend works till 10.
You never answered.
Noon or evening?
Tomorrow noon.
OK. See you tomorrow.
- Let me out.
- What?
Let me out!
- Want some potato chips?
- Alright.
What an asshole!
He forgot his backpack.
Let's see what he has in here.
- What is it?
- A tuner.
For a guitar?
Bass, Guitar, whatever.
You connect it and play a note,
then it shows if it's tuned.
In the middle, it's tuned.
An "A".
With the instrument you go... LA.
Well, that wasn't it,
but if you sing a La...
No, that was wrong.
You try.
There, there it was in the middle.
It's more like...
No. It's like...
Almost there.
Too high.
- Tomorrow's my birthday.
- You mean, Friday?
No, today.
- Happy birthday.
- Thanks.
Do you still see
anyone from school?
- Guille.
- Guille?
Guillermo Lucena.
Remember him?
Oh, yes. The crazy skater?
- Does he still skate?
- Yes.
And you? Do you still
go to the same school?
No. I was expelled as a sophomore.
I was the best student,
but I was expelled.
Do you see anyone?
Nicolás Araujo.
Does he still live near here?
No. He moved near
the Botanical Gardens.
This band... They're playing
on Saturday. We could go.
Yeah, sure.
They play near my house.
If it gets too late, you
can sleep over in my house.
Yes, we'll see.
- We forgot to call my brother.
- Is it too late?
I don't know.
I'll call him tomorrow.
- Do you want to stay
here tonight? - OK.
I'll phone home
to let them know.
Sure. Take a look.
The phone is somewhere around.
When did you get up?
A while ago. I was woken
by the workers next door.
I didn't hear them.
You should have woken me up.
I did try, but you
were fast asleep
Yeah, I slept like a baby.
- The milk's there.
- Thanks.
We could go out or something.
It's my birthday, I'll do something
with my folks. We go out for lunch.
I can't make it to that
concert on Saturday.
I'm traveling with my folks.
Going on a trip?
My Mom won it at the laundromat.
We're going to Europe for a month.
They raffle washing-machines
at the laundromat near home.
Washing-machines?
- That's ridiculous.
- Why? I think is OK.
Yeah, it's a laundromat.
Exactly, a washing-machine.
Have some.
Yes, I'll call your brother.
The phone is somewhere.
This one has an
anticipatory subject.
That's when the subject
is there and it isn't.
Alright. Go ahead.
Anticipatory subject.
Now it's your turn.
I swear...
that what Martin tells me
I won't tell anyone...
particularly Mom or Dad...
lest I be ran down by a ship.
You have to do like this...
Promised.
You'll catch a cold.
I won't be swimming in the sea.
I must go.
Tomorrow Paula
will show me a hole.
What hole?
A hole in the fence
to skip gym class.
- Tomorrow after school?
- Yeah.
Then I won't see you.
Do you want me to bring
you something?
No.
Do you want me to give Pablo
any message from you?
Would you review these sentences?
- Aren't you late?
- Yes, I'm leaving.
Tomorrow's Fede's birthday.
I was invited to spend the weekend
at his house in the country...
Guille is also coming.
- Isn't Fede's birthday in August?
- No, it's tomorrow.
I'm staying at Guille's tonight.
Fede's parents are picking
us up on Saturday morning.
Phone me from Fede's.
There's no phone in the country-
house. I'll see what I can do.
Anyway, write down Guille
and Fede's phone numbers.
Take some clothes to change.
I'll pack a bag after school.
I won't be here
when you come back.
I'll phone from
Guille's tonight.
- Bye
Do you think it'll be
cold in Mar del Plata?
I don't know.
I guess I should
take a sweatshirt.
- When are you coming back?
- Sunday evening.
Remember the letter from school
will be arriving on Monday.
Yes, I know. I want to be there
to do some explaining.
We should continue rehearsing
whithout Fede.
Until He learns English.
Sure.
His mother hid his bass again.
He's been looking
for it for over a week.
Or shall I take a sweater?
Or a jacket...
Yes... may I speak to Lucas?
Martín Cánepa speaking.
He'll be back late?
Please tell him I'll
call him back tomorrow?
Thanks, bye.
Hi.
I'm Luciana, Lucas's sister.
He is not in.
When can I find him?
I'm meeting him for lunch later.
Shall I give him a message?
No, thanks.
I have to go to the aquarium
near the airport.
What bus takes me there?
Many buses stop right there.
You can take the 131.
That's the one I'm taking.
- Bye.
Do you like fish?
Yes, I like colored fish.
But I'm not going to the aquarium
to buy fish, I'm looking for someone
for other reason.
Want some candy?
- What flavor are you looking for?
- Raspberry.
Take it, there's only one left.
- No, it's alright.
- Please.
Thanks.
We are having lunch with
Lucas near the aquarium.
I'll give you the address
so you can talk to him.
Alright.
- Are you going there now?
- We're meeting later.
I am going to the beach.
- Do you like fish?
- Yes.
You can come with me to the aquarium
and then we could meet your brother.
Alright.
He went to Montevideo
15 days ago looking for work.
- He almost didn't tell me.
- What do you mean?
- He called me the day before.
- So he did tell you.
Yes.
Did he say where he would stay?
In a hotel across
the bus station.
What was Pablo doing here?
I don't know.
Nothing, I think.
We didn't see each
other much lately.
You've got sand in your hair.
I spent the night at the beach.
They put the two orders together.
It doesn't matter.
Hi, can I help you?
I want to go to Montevideo.
There's a bus leaving tomorrow.
Yes, 5 pm. Two?
- What?
- Two tickets?
No, jut one, please.
I'm afraid it'll be
a stand-by ticket.
Tomorrow's bus is fully booked.
To Montevideo?
There's a whole school
volleyball team travelling.
They're playing a
Brazilian team tonight...
and if they win, the final
match is in Montevideo.
My nephew Felipe is playing.
Give me your name and phone number
If they don't travel,
I'll book you a seat.
Martín Cánepa.
4-9-1-0-9-2-8.
It's mine. Is it OK?
Call me tomorrow morning, then.
OK, thanks. Bye.
When we came in winter,
my Mom would get mad...
because I wanted to swim,
and I'd get a cold.
I like swimming at night,
When the water is warm.
But it's cold at night.
No, the water takes longer to
change temperature than the air.
At day, even when it's warm,
the water's cold 'cause the moon
cooled it the night before.
At night, the water's warm because
it was warmed by the sun.
I didn't know that.
I'd like to live by the sea.
It bores you in the end.
By year end, I want to go
to live to Buenos Aires.
You'll be going in summer when
everybody there comes over here.
Are you going on holidays?
I don't think so.
- It's getting cloudy.
- Yeah, and I only brought this.
Take this.
Thanks.
When I was a kid, I believed here
could also predict the weather.
Because you have the sea-lions
that change colors.
I could nevertell
if that was true.
Neither could I.
My Mom once bought one,
but the heating is always on
and it turned purple.
To avoid that I taped
mine outside the window.
But someone stole it.
Are you still cold?
No, but it's too large for me.
It was too large for Pablo as well.
It must be a large sweatshirt.
Do you know who won
the volleyball match?
No.
Yes, I saw people celebrating
the victory in the streets.
What was their team?
I don't know.
Did they speak Spanish
or Portuguese?
English.
They were singing "We are
the champions", Queen.
That bed's got a metal bar.
Pablo was always
complaining about it.
He slept there for
the first three months.
I remember once you stayed
with us, I was about six...
and you and Pablo woke me up
to tell me there was an
alien in the living-room.
Really?
I couldn't go back to sleep.
Do you know if
it's cold in Montevideo?
I don't know. I can lend
you a sweater, if you want.
Alright. I'll let you
know if I need one.
- Hi.
I couldn't sleep.
Must be the bed.
Yeah, I slept better on the beach.
- What are you studying?
- Geographic features.
Will you give me some juice?
There's a glass for you there.
Ah... ok.
I'm sorry.
- It's a...
- What were you saying?
- And you?
It's a pity we ran out of juice.
What were you saying?
The same thing.
The sun will rise soon.
Can we get the paper here?
I don't know. Why don't you ask?
They only have
the Economy section.
There is Lucas.
He always gets up early.
There's only one shot left,
take any picture you like.
Is Massera still on business?
Yes, but there are
very few branches left.
My Mom took a picture of me
outside one of the branches...
hugging a huge ice-cream cone.
Massera's caramel flavor
had real caramel in it.
And they'd give you a
free chocolate coating.
Have you noticed there are
three taps in baths...
cold, hot and the
one in the middle?
When I was a child, my brother told
me the middle tap was for chocolate.
Did you believe him
for a long time?
No... I can't remember.
But now I prefer taking
baths to showers.
Near my home in the capital city
there's also an Arenales St.
Really?
The laundromat would move
three blocks that way...
and my home would be
three blocks that way.
- Shall we go that way?
- Yes. Let us.
- Did you call?
- Yes.
I'm not going to Montevideo.
- Did they win?
- No, they lost.
First time in over a year.
Why aren't you going then?
Are you leaving now?
There's a train
leaving in 2 hours.
I think I'll have a swim.
Here's my phone number.
I think I have a cold,
I shouldn't have got into the sea.
What are you going to do now?
I may go to Sacoa.
Sacoa used to be only
in Mar del Plata.
It was in a basement.
You'd go downstairs and everything
was lights and sounds.
I used to play Bubble Bobble.
- So did I. With my brother.
- Me too.
I didn't like to play alone.
How did the Bubble
Bobble theme go?
I can't remember
Wait a second...
Do you love your brother?
He's my brother.
Do I look like him?
He's your brother.
Martín... come here.
Can you plug in the
Christmas tree?
It's lovely.
Do you like it?
One line won't turn on.
Where are you spending Christmas?
- I don't know. What about you?
- At my cousin's.
Have you thought of a new school?
There is a new school near home.
We can go tomorrow
to check it out.
Tomorrow is Christmas day.
I've got a bass-player's
phone number, we should phone him.
Sure.
Let's get together
after Christmas...
and we could rehearse then.
I have to take this to my mom.
- Merry Christmas!
What is this I'm feeling?
It's me, somebody inside of me
Is asking me
not to be still while I grow up
Who am I? I'm finding out
It's me, somebody inside of me
I'm telling myself
I can have time on my side
This time I want
to go farther than ever
Ripeados por Tylerg
Visita www.clan-sudamerica.com.ar