What would happen if you knew
that you were never going to die?
That there's no way to stop
existing?
What would happen if
you knew that?
So real such as touching
or seeing...
What would happen if you knew
that this doesn't end up here?
That we come back many times...
And we forgot every
time we come back...
This time I remember
everything from the beginning...
But it seems that nobody
listens to me...
This was the day that
my family helped me...
The great path is not so difficult
For those that don't have any preferences.
When both love and hate are absent.
Everything becomes
clear and illuminated
However if you make the
slightest distinction,
the sky and the earth will
become distant forever.
If you want to see the truth, don't hold
any opinions in favor or against.
The struggle between what
you like and dislike,
It's a mind's sickness.
The struggle between what you
like and dislike,
It's a mind's sickness.
It's a society's sickness.
It's my disease and yours too.
Hello
Who are you with?
I've just got out from
the shower... I'm coming
- Are you pulling my legs?
- No.
Come on... Come on... COME ON!
Mom. She always in trouble
she never tells me about them.
As if I didn't know what was happening.
I know she can't pay the bills,
that's why I never ask her
for anything.
I don't want to be
another problem for her.
I don't know what to do
so that she doesn't worry.
That's why... keep on moving...
if you're already in heaven...
I love her anyway... she is my mom.
My princess, you go to work every day...
Just one day without working...
You've worked yesterday already
I have to go.
Stay here with El Mono.
Come on! They're gonna kill me...
kill me... they're they're gonna kill me
Who's gonna kill you, you're so
heavy metal. Come here!
Ow! I'm leaving.
No. No. Come here!
Where are you going?
Come here, stay here with little Mono.
It's my sister, you idiot.
So, are you staying here with
me, or you are not darling?
Dogo! Dogo!
How's it going?
When are you going
to give me the money?
- I still don't know.
- Are you going to give me the money back?
I don't know... it's not
up to me Laura
You can't just say "I don't know"...
I need an answer... your mom has called me.
My mom? Don't you
get how this works?
What do you want, a guarantee
signed by a public notary?
No... I'm just asking you.
Are we really friends?
Yeah... so what?
So, you gotta know something,
some kind of intuition of what's going on...
it's the only thing that I'm asking you...
just tell me more or less what's going on...
What's going on?! Laura,
the world is a mess,
or at least it seems that, but the cosmic
order has everything under control.
You're such an idiot.
Am I?
What's wrong with you?
Do you like see me suffering?
Am I making you suffer?
You suffer all by yourself!
You're not telling me anything...
I'm involved in this mess and you...
you turn all into a mystery.
Ok, I've heard you Laura, call
me tomorrow to see if I've got news...
Close to my house lives a girl
that sucks your dick for 5 bucks.
I've known her since she was a kid,
that's why she doesn't charge me if
I wanna touch her tits.
She lives two houses from my
dealer so when I go to buy pot I meet her.
She says to me... "Boy".
What are you listening to Camilo?
Good morning... Shall I
turn this a bit down?
Yes... please!
Ahh... this turned bad...
What do you drink, Cami? Milk?
- Yes
- There's none left...
Well...
It's got hop.
Is this the guy of the glycerin soaps?
- So... How are you doing at school?
- Fine
- Fine?
- Yeah
Are you gonna give me a kiss?
My aunt Ama lives in her own world...
she doesn't
think God lives in ours...
because it's unsafe... uncertain.
But there's something about her
I like,
beside she's always cleaning...
her smell.
- Ok Auntie, I have to go to school
- Go, go. Don't be late.
Your overall is a disaster...
- Which way did she come from?
- No... I didn't see her when she arrived
What's going on?
Everyday you ask
the same thing...
Which way did your daughter come from?!
I don't know anything about your daughter...
Juli, give me another double
coffee with three croissants...
- Dogo
- What's up Mono?
Everything's good man?
A bit weird, isn't it?
Where did you sleep man?
At the Jack Sparrow Hotel. Where
am I going to sleep asshole? At home!
At your house?
Yeah. Don't you smoke a morning joint?
Change your face...
Who is it?
Who's following you? What's up man?
You prick.
Ama... what are you doing?
You didn't have to do that.
Just helping you a little bit...
I saw Camilito.
Did he go to school?
Yes
Don't you work today?
They're on vacation.
Don't say... so nice... travelling abroad.
And you... you're not
going to the store today?
Are you ok Lau?
What's wrong?
I can't do it, I can't, I can't afford
I can't afford anything,
the telephone,
my mobile phone, not even
Camilo's books. I owe two months rent...
they're going to cut off the water...
the water! How is it possible
that they cut off the water?!
Doesn't it come from the
river, the sea, the rain
...and I have to pay 200
pesos per month?!
And, they never came to install
the water meter!
I don't have the time to go there
and ask for it.
The credit I asked to paint
the house
I couldn't pay it back in time and now the
expenses, the taxes, the interest
from I don't know what...
they're going to take it out of my salary...
what do I do?
Have you got any money to lend me?
Have you got any
money to lend me?
Can you see?
I don't forget
I owe you already from the
three previous times I've asked you.
And, if you lend me some
now, you won't see the money again.
It's the way it is. Who's gonna
lend me money? No one.
What do I do?
- Work
- I work 10 hours a day!
- 1,500 pesos per month... it's not enough.
- I make 1,400
You live in the countryside.
You don't pay rent,
you don't have a child!
This is the city.
The suburbs are not the same
as the countryside...
...and Dogo, doesn't he help you?
- Yeah, he made me ask your Mom again
- And?
I gave it to your brother to do
some business... which are going to fail.
Laura, don't say that, he
never fails on these things.
- You better pray.
- Laura, everything's going to be fine.
- Well, I have to go to work.
- Yes.
Look, the guy with long hair left this
plant for you... poor thing, it's so dry...
so I put it into water to see if it revives.
- Can I read you something darling?
- Yes, my love.
The great path is not difficult
for those who don't have preferences...
When both love and hate are absent,
everything becomes clear and illuminated...
However, if you make the slightest
distinction, the sky and the earth will
become distant forever.
If you want to see the truth,
never have opinions in
favor or against. The struggle...
between what one likes and what one
doesn't like is the sickness of the mind
Don't take too long to wake up
The scorpion will sting, will sting
Its poison doesn't know how
to wait, like the sun and the moon,
the wind, the pen, the earth, the skin.
We have designed a
game so we kill each other.
A kind of fight for power
yourself to squeeze yourself into being.
It's important that you're
ok in order to see clearly...
Who loves you, who will kill you.
It's important that you're
ok in order to see clearly...
Who loves you, who will kill you.
...with an endless variety
of shadows and tones...
My Grandma is really crazy. She had kids
all over the place. My Aunts and my Dad...
...can you dial Lucia for me?
... have different fathers.
- Hello.
- Hi Damian?
- Her new boyfriend helps her a lot...
- How are you? This is Billy speaking...
- Yeah I know.
- Is Lucia there?
...and, he's a millionaire...
I was specting to talk with her.
- You want to talk to her?
- No... she does
Oh... Lu... you've got a phone call.
Mom
- How are you, my darling?
- Hi Mom
- Your brother?
- Umm, I haven't seen him.
Can you tell him I'm looking
for him? That he should call me.
Yes
- Good... Love you
- Love you too mom
- Bye sweetie.
- Kisses
Hi, I'm Homer. You have
a text message. Wanna beer?
...Camilo put it on.
- Homer
If you're not going to kiss the earth
It'll do the same when you fall on your face
I grew up with Mommy saying
"I warned you, don't touch that", but...
Without the power to stop it, the internal
power is your temple and the patience and
the spirits will protect you
The wasps' nest has moved,
I'm the salamander elf,
mounted in the whirlpools.
Oh, God gave me the word and for
this he came.
Mission completed.
I told him and I'm telling...
...him, flowing.
I found the way to go in life.
When somebody asks you,
with great sincerity; Where can I find God?
Don't try to evade the question.
Tell them that God is inside them.
And if they ask you... Where inside me?
Well... you must search inside...
forth from But where should we search?
In your heart. Yes, of course.
But in which part of my heart?
Do you want a vision of God?
A clear signal from the Creator?
Abandon your wishes... Shake them away.
Look at yourselves into the mirror...
For this we've got our mind,
a spirit with will power,
The worst enemy in this race
of finding God Is desire.
Be free, Be divine.
Althought sometimes it's difficult.
- Let's go and look for him man
- Where?
- Don't know... what do I know... to a park
- I can't believe he did this to me
- What? This guy makes deals with cops.
- A lot of drugs. It was bound to happen...
- What? Is this your first time?
- For what?
That they got you so easily,
that they fucked with you like this.
Welcome to the club!
- Where did you sleep Mono?
- When you get your proud touched,
you start bothering me and your sister...
No... where did you sleep? Nothing else...
just answer me where did you sleep.
Where I always sleep.
Dogo... don't be afraid...
I'm trembling too.
Let's go... let's do it.
How Christ loves us, no one...
He guides us like stars.
He's my body.
The bread of our love.
Nourish us... I will nourish your love.
He is my blood, come
and drink, because I am life,
I am love, your eternal love, take us Lord.
How Christ loves us, no one ever knew
how to love. He guides us like stars...
He's...
Ama... Ama...
what are you doing?
Hello? Hi Dad... yeah...
I couldn't find the phone... yeah... yeah.
Martin get out. Martin please
get out of the bathroom.
Luci, stop messing around and
come out... Camilo just got here... Come on.
Luci... my beautiful Aunt Luci...
she's the only one that looks
at me straight in the eyes and
talks to me as if I were her equal.
You little twerp... Do you
know how much I love you?
She's like a mom, I know she loves
me like my mom and dad do.
I know but it's better because
she's not my mom... and I have fun.
Yeah, she's a little bit weak,
but we are all a bit lost...
- And your mom?
- I don't know.
And what about grandpa?
No hug for him?
Grandpa isn't really my grandpa...
but Luci loves me so much that he thinks
I'm his grandson, neither my dad or my
mom are his kids, but no one argues,
he's really convinced... so,
he's my grandpa.
He takes care of Luci so
much that he doesn't let her breathe.
- Would you like a banana milk shake?
- Yeah!
What?
Did you talk to me?
I have to go downtown to pay
some bills from your father...
I mean, because of the dinner tonight.
I'm also going downtown...
Oh... Ok. And Belen?
I'll pick her up. If you want I can
drive you home after that... around 7 or 8.
No, that's ok... Thanks.
It's strange you didn't go away...
You love travelling.
Yeah, but not with my parents.
Can you bring me some wine?
- Wine? At midday?
- Ama, please, can you relax...
Sorry... I'll bring you
some in a sec
I'm not going to be able
to give it back to you.
It doesn't matter. Take it.
Living like this sucks
- t's weird...
- I can't get out of it.
What if you leave... I don't know...
Go to another town, another place?
I can't. First I have to solve
the problem with the bank...
How are you doing?
In love... Behind a glass.
It makes me think of
something else... I think
But every time it comes
back even stronger, doesn't it?
- What?
- The reality that you believe in
- From where?
- For me it comes back like ethereally.
- What?!
- I don't know if it really matters...
What doesn't matter, that I don't
understand anything you're saying
...or whatever it is that
you're talking about?
It doesn't matter.
And I'll tell you more...
Cañas is gonna be Boca's coach...
look who's coming.
- Look at those characters!
- They're here!
What's up man!
Dear Monito... How are you big man?
Always insisting with the guitar.
Yeah, of course! I support you.
Dogo, brother, Everything cool?
Check that you've got a bill to pay...
- Julio!
- How's that going?
- Yeah... wait a sec...
- Yeah, ok.
- How's everything going Cami?
- Yeah, everything's fine
Should I go on with the
music or go on with the...?
Keep on going with music.
Oh man what a morning. What's up?
Ok. Look.
120 pesos plus...
no, no, ok... but you know that this guy
cancelled the old bill he had
Ok, it's ok that he pays
the old bill he owed
but he also has to pay the new one...
it's 500 bucks!
Yeah fine, but you tell things as
if they were easy to say at night.
No, I'm not telling you that the night is
easy, I'm just asking you to charge people!
It's nice that you make
friends, but charge them!
Look at the cash register
It's empty man. Nothing but papers.
You don't have any
money left to pay?
I don't have nothing. I'm broken.
Ok, I'll charge him, I'll charge him but
let's see how we solve the problem now
Come on, just do it, put your face and,
charge them it's over! It's enough...
it seems easy to talk in the morning
about what happened yesterday night.
Ok, I'll come tonight... done.
You will see that this
chat we're having...
Is this guy coming tonight?
He's coming but he said that this
week he'll pay 50% of what he owes
Yeah.
- Isn't it dangerous?
- Well... it depends.
- On what?
- On the point of view, Laura... for you it
could be horrible, but for me,
I couldn't give a shit...
Anyway, it's not a matter
of life or death, is it?
- Family!
- You were just missing this guy...
...to complicate things right now.
- I feel like home here.
That's what you feel like.
What, I can't even speak?
You don't know that the first
thing you have to do to be here
- Yeah, I was gonna do it!
- Give it to me man.
- Everything in its time.
- Give it to me.
- This is how you're gonna be buddy.
- Now we can chat.
Mono, we're gonna be clear... I don't
want to have any problems because of you...
And I don't want you to put my daughter
at any risk. Do what you know doing,
- This comes out naturally?!
- Stop with your bullshit.
It comes out naturally?
- Yeah, music comes naturally out of me.
- Fine, then break up with your girlfriend.
- What could be so horrible to me?
- That he doesn't show up...
- Is that possible?
- I don't know.
You set up the deal, you are
responsible for it... get angry... move...
Push them into the rhythm...
I'm going crazy. I need an answer!
You don't seem to get
how serious this is for me!
It seems to me that you don't
understand anything about anything Laura.
What is it that I don't understand?
You come, you want to do some
business with someone...
...you don't even know,
you want to take it all,
fast and on top of that
you want me to worry
about my mom finding this out?
You're Heidi! Do you listen to yourself?
Do you listen to what you're saying? Are you
even aware of who we're dealing with?
Do you think I'm Ricky >?
That we are dancing at the cumbia disco?
Push them into the rhythm?!
Serious?! Do you know what's serious?
Do you understand
that we are slaves of a sinister power?
That they're capable of destroying their
own Twin Towers and kill their own people?
In order to invent an enemy!
They have all the scientists in the world
putting chips and shit in mobile phones
but they still don't know how are
they gonna save us from this
ecological social disaster...
that is serious Laura! That's serious!
The USA is a bluff Laura it's a lie.
They're gonna fall in any moment.
Everything is gonna fall down at any time.
- Can I play a song for her?
- We don't have to deal with this guy.
Can't I sing her one song? I wrote it
for her. One little song... then I'll leave.
I'm with you...
- Go go go...
- Yeah!
- I'm leaving... I'd prefer to
resolve this little issue.
And the gods will dance at our side
And we'll erase the past,
and heaven will run side by side.
Like a dance, for two people in love.
And fly and enjoy and feel.
And abandon the laws of fear,
painting you with the color
of the sunrise... eternal flower
What does that have to do with it?
How can you ask me this? All the governments
know the exact moment...
that any person on earth will go to have
a shit, Laura. They have total impunity,
they can change anything with the press...
so, it just gets worst,
out of control...
Can you see the huge paradox?!
I don't know what a paradox is.
A paradox Laura is controllable
and uncontrollable at the same time.
And the gods will dance at our side,
and we'll erase the past,
and the heaven will run side by side.
Like a dance, for two people in love.
Poison get out of me, cause it burns
Poison get out of me, you're burning me.
A paradox is controllable
and uncontrollable at the same time.
...they control everything,
but they can't control anything.
You know why? Because man
Man never learned how to control himself,
he never learned how to
observe, never learned how to love...
All this technological strength, all this
high level science is right here... ok?
...the atomic power that illuminates
the world is an atomic bomb Laura,
it's a double-bladed sword,
Do you understand? Has...
...this power has to be supported
by a spiritual power.
But right now, humanity is like this...
There is no spirituality Laura.
The world is on the verge of
self-destruction at any moment...
Right side of the body, left side of
the brain... left side of the body,
right side of the brain...
now what? They've mixed up
chemistry with computers.
Do you know what does that mean?
It's lethal and wonderful
at the same time.
...and it's normal that with
all these problems I have,
I don't give a shit about my
mom's 10 grands, Laura
Have you forgotten that I
have Mono's sound system?
What does Mono have to do with it?
What does he have to do with us Laura?
If your friend doesn't
show up today...
I'll sell all the equipment...
and you can go
to hell with the whole group of
assholes you are surround with.
Why do you insult Laura?
I knew you were gonna
come out with this...
don't fuck with me Laura!
Put that away, put that away.
Get me out of this mess.
What did you think? That I was going to give
you all that money without being covered?!
Poison, get out of me, cause it burns
Mono is like a bee. He looks
evil... but he makes honey...
he's got something special, magical...
he's like Maradona with a guitar.
He should be playing the guitar
in a stadium, but he doesn't want to.
He prefers to play for my
aunt... I would do the same.
One thousand nights I was
crying, dancing to your shadow.
Wait Laura, don't you realize that
what you're saying is irrational?
What does Mono have
to do with our business?
Laura, do you know what would
happen to him if he can't play,
if he doesn't make music?
And do you what can happen to me?! I'll
sell everything today! I need the money now!
Calm down! Calm down!
So, I'll have to kill you if these
guys don't show. I'll have to kill you then?
You couldn't kill a fly... behind
those tattoos and your mean face...,
you're just a little shit that
doesn't asume his life... Let's see,
how are you gonna kill me?
With Zen poems?
With that gun you've never
used in your life?
With quantum physics?
I can't tolerate you anymore!
Laura can you calm down!
If that money doesn't appear today,
I'm selling...
...everything...
who do you think you are?
Laura!
That's it, Monito, you're done.
We heard enough enough
Ok... he turned into a pumpkin.
Dogo! I'm done.
Let's go.
Camilo! Camilo!
Dad... That's the way he is.
I love him so so much...
he says he's a Samurai... that's why he
never takes his gun out... it's strange,
a Samurai here in the neirborhood...
he says that it's a sword.
If he takes it out it's to kill or die...
I know that's how it is...
he's not uncertain...
he brought me up...
what I want more than anything in life,
is that he never takes his sword out...
What's the matter? Is it Mom?
She is getting worse...
...you know that her dad...
her dad died because...
...he couldn't find his ID...
do you understand?
- No
- He couldn't find his ID
...and he died from a heart attack... do you
get it? They're all crazy in her family.
- Is there any problem?
- No
Karma, isn't it?
Did you do my...
what is it called?
- Huh?
- What was it called the...
- Astrology chat.
- Did you do mine?
No, tomorrow morning I'll
bring it for you for sure.
It shows the future
and everything right?
I'm totally into it? Personality, the sun,
the moon... Can you explain it to me?
- Yeah, we sit down together
and I explain it to you.
- 50 pesos
- We take it off your bill.
Man... you have to be strong, strong.
You don't get poisoned with the things
...that happen around. Are you listening?
You must fly high man.
You don't care about me or your mother.
Are you listening to me?
If we live or we die, it doesn't
matter... you must fly high, high...
so that stones can't reach you... if I shoot
you, it shouldn't reach you... can you hear?
I'm just like him...
Are you Istening to me?
My word is worth it...
Give me your word
That's why it's so hard to give it to him.
Camilo, do I have your word?
But he's my dad, I want him to be happy.
You have breakfast, milkshakes...
we take off the astrology chart.
- Perfect. Awesome... thanks.
- When can you pay me back?
If I'm still alive, or if I'm not
in a mental institute,
next week I promise I'll
pay you back.
Camilo let's go!
Cami. That Homer
ring tone is great.
Let's go. Thank you.
Martin please... Martin! You know that
your father doesn't want you to... Martin!
Ama, do me a favor, why don't you
call him and tell him that
I'm taking his car... then, right after
don't forget to tell him about the Jacuzzi,
...he'll love that... come on!
- Fine!
- Oh yeah?
It doesn't matter, I'm going to call him.
Are you going to call him? Ok but...
tell him everything, I'll wait for you here.
No Martin! No Martin! Martin please no!
- Ama just get in please.
- No Martin, this is bad, really bad.
- Ama
- This is a bad omen Martin.
- A bad omen?
- No, no, you don't have any idea Martin...
- What?
- Please... this is bad, this is really bad.
- I see death. I see death everywhere.
- Where?
- I see death.
This is all bad... everything's
really bad... no Martin please no!
Come on Ama.
No this is bad. I see death. I see it
everywhere. Martin... no, Martin... no!
- What are you doing? Ama!
- This is bad, this is really bad,
- Ama!
- No! No! This is bad! No! No!
- What are you doing?
- This is bad! This is really bad!
- Stop! Stop! Stop!
- No! No!
- Stop! Stop!
- No! This is bad! This is really bad!
- Stop!
- This is really bad!
- Wait, stop!
- This is bad!
Ama!!! Look at me! Look at me!
It's over, it's over, it's over...
it's over.
Ama! Let's get up,
let's get up... come here come here.
What happened? Are you ok?
Your sweater
Let's go...
Dogo... Dogo... Kill him!
Dogo kill him. Kill him!
Come on Camilo!
Kill him! Kill him!
Come on Camilo! Shoot the ball...
Kill him!
Kill him Dogo!
- Come on Dogo, it's over, it's done.
- Dogo!
Come on! Come on Camilo!
Kill him! Kill him!
GOAL!!!!
It's an energy normalizer.
If energy circulates really fast,
...it'll contain it, if the energy doesn't
circulate it will bring it to circulate.
- So, it stabilizes energy then?
- Exactly... yes yes yes yes
- OK. Thank you very much miss.
- The place where you put it is the key.
- Do you understand?
- Thanks.
- You're going to love it!
- Thank you.
- Laura Lavot?
- No.
Of course... she comes in the morning.
- Oh ok ok.
- Why?
Look, it's actually not good news...
the bank garnished her wages...
...can I leave the document with you?
- Sure...
- Your ID?
- Oh, I didn't bring it.
- Ok, no problem. Just tell me your name.
Laura... yeah, we have the
same name... she's Lavot, I'm Fidalgo
Laura Fidalgo... like the one on TV...
the dancer... the dancer Laura Fidalgo?
- Ok. What's your ID number.
- Yeah it's 22984515
- Good. Can you sign here for me please?
- Ok
Yeah there. Done. Great.
This is for you.
So, tell her to communicate
with the court ASAP.
- Yes yes yes yes I'll tell her.
- Thank you very much.
Bye.
Stop it Luci!
You're gonna damage yourself...
Your dad's coming!
Stop idiot... you're going
to burn your brain... stop
- What's happening?
- The truth is I don't know what's going on.
Martin? Ama... I'm here at the church.
What should I do, wait for you here?
When you're here you'll
call me? Ok. I'm going inside.
I have to turn on the sprinklers
Ok. I'm going inside. Hurry up.
Lucia! Lucia! Lucia God damn it.
Did I take care of you badly?
Did I raise you badly?
What did I do to you?
Ok. OK. I'm hanging up
cause I'm inside... bye bye.
How can you reject my love?
Now that I go to your temple
and ask you forgiveness.
How can you reject my love?
Lu! Lu! Stop stop stop stop stop!
What are you doing?
Stop stop stop a sec damn it stop!
Now that I go to your temple
and I sing for you gospel, gospel, gospel.
Luli, Luli I know what you do
when you lock yourself in the toilet...
come here, let me talk to you.
You're going too far.
No! Stop! You're going to hurt yourself
damn it! Stop! I know what you do.
You're going to far,
to a place of no return...
How can you reject my love? Now that
I go to church and I ask your forgiveness.
Your brother fills your head
against me...
you have to talk to me,
my little girl... Lu... Lu... Lu!
How can you reject my love?
Do you know why your brother
fills your head against me?
Answer me daughter.
Answer me damn it!
Hymns
Your brother wants to fuck you!
No. You didn't do it, did you?
Tell me you didn't. Luci no,
my baby Luci no!
Noooo no no my little girl no,
look what you did to yourself...
Luci what did I do wrong?
What did I do wrong, please,
what did I do?
I love you Dad.
I love you too.
Give it to me Dad... fuck me
and let's have kids...
it doesn't matter... nothing
matters to me... fuck me.
What?! What are you doing?!
No no no no no no no no no no.
Get out of here! Get out of here!
Go away! Go away!
You son of a bitch!
Get out of here!
Go! Go! Go! Go away!
Go away!
Martin? What? I didn't hear you.
Where? The street? Let's see... wait...
Luci? Luci? I'll call you right back.
Luci! Luci what happened?
What did you do?
Ama... don't... I don't know
if I have AIDs...
Luci! Luci what happened
to you?
Who did this to you?
Him? What happened?
No, I dropped an acid and I
wanted to touch the ground...
but... how can they put grass into a cage?
How can they put a square in a cage?
What are you doing here Ama?
I was in the church.
Let's take her Mono?
Ama!
Ah Martin.
And that spaceship?
It's my sister, she collided
against the railings.
Wow, so what?
Are we going to the hospital?
No, to the bar.
Ok, we'll see you there.
Ow!
Sorry!
Ow! You idiot!
Was it a UFO?
Very good!
No, no isn't there any water?
I'm thirsty.
No. They don't sell it here.
But I saw some
At mass don't they drink wine?
Yeah, but that's something else...
it's a sip.
You can drink it in sips! Cheers!
In sips
Besides, didn't Jesus get
drunk all the time?
Come fish, come bread, come
wine... it was like that, wasn't it?
The truth is I love this place...
whose is it? Your sister's?
It's her father's.
Oh I see, and your brother?
No... no he didn't come.
He's not the one who plays the guitar?
No, no, he didn't come he didn't come.
Well, cheers.
In sips.
Sips.
The pasta...
Yes, pasta!
Great.
She's the one from the railing.
Ah, you don't say.
Hey baby.
Would you like some cheese?
Yes please... a little more.
Ok.
That's enough, thank you.
Got a light?
Thanks
Pretty nice isn't it?
Thanks man.
Your other sister's pretty too...
nice... nice family.
You're saying that we're
gonna lose respect?
If you respect yourself... I don't
know where you left the great macho...
the dog... that... wild animal?
What happened...?
Dogo is because of a soccer
team, it has nothing to do with dogs.
Hey Santa Claus!
What's up man. Take this,
they almost sold it for scrap metal.
You have no idea how much I
needed this today.
This guy is phenomenal
and his brother is a fag.
You don't think I'm capable of killing?
Today you couldn't.
When you were little you liked
bowtie pasta,
and you asked for bowties
bowties bowties, I remember.
Yes, but I knew about
the point of pasta after.
When? If you never cooked.
How much does it worth getting
dirty in a bottomless Karma man?
10 grand? 10 grand to kill someone?
It's the money for your girl,
it's your mom's... it's your kid's...
your honor... the whole neighborhood
is talking shit about you.
Let them come get to me man.
Why did you forgive him man?
Cause I have a spiritual practice.
Because the Great Path is not
difficult for those
that don't have preferences...
understand?
No.
You know, you're never
gonna understand.
No.
It's something you'll never get.
You know what, I don't wanna
understand anything of yours. Little dog.
We're not more than one more.
Under this sun, above this earth.
About to burst!
About to burst...
Mmmmm... it smells good...
homemade food... hands of mom,
of grandma, of my Aunt Ama, maybe
a dad too, not my dad, but... smells good.
Camilo! Have you seen
your birth certificate?
No.
We're going on a trip. Here, this is
your bag, pack your clothes.
No, you can't travel like that.
Go take a shower, now!
What?! Wait, come here
come here.
Why are you looking at me like that?
How?
What did you do?
Nothing.
What did you do? What do you think,
that I don't realize?
Come here you little shit!
You think I don't realize?
That you've hidden
your birth certificate?
You hide it from me? You shit.
My love, forgive me, forgive me...
Get out man.
What's it with you man?
- Get out Mono!
- What's up?
Stop
You stay calm... stay here...
what the fuck is up man?
Go away Mono.
- What you're going to hit me?
- Let me talk to my sister.
What you're going to hit me?
Are you gonna hit your sister?
You can't take care of your
fuckin family man...
Get out of here man!
- ¡¡Get out!!
- Me? Hit me! Fuckin asshole!!
Get the fuck out of here now!
Now!! Get the fuck out of here.
Fuck you! Mother fucker!!
I don't want you to live like
this any more Luci!!!
I don't want you to
live like this anymore!!!
Idiot... wake up!!!
Wake up!! Damn it!!
I love him! What should I do?
Listen to me, listen to me...
What?
Listen... go away, together... tomorrow,
you guys get away from here.
But where?
Far... I want you to leave
this place now, Luci.
What about you?
I'd die without Camilo.
Me too, I'll die without Camilo.
You're going to die anyway!
Luci... go... just go Luci, please.
Leave this place... please!
Promise me.
Did you talk with Mono?
Mono doesn't matter, he'll do it.
Give me your word Luci.
Yes.
It's not that I don't want to,
it's what I want to do most!
That's the problem... I'm not
PHD in administration...
I can't. I just can't do it.
Strong... strong... high...
high but really high!
Where stones can't reach me,
if they shoot me, they won't reach me...
I gave him my word.
The bills of this building for example...
what's this that I have to pay for
a lawsuit that happened with
the last administration?
When I didn't even live in the
building. What about gas?!
Why do I have to pay for gas?
I don't get it. Anyway, gas is ok.
The birth certificate? The number
they gave Camilo when he was born.
It's his number... why do
I have to pay for it?
Another!! Another one!!
Another! Yes! Yes! There's
She's OK.
Yes, yes! Very good Luci!
Ok, this song is dedicated to
my friend Dogo, my spiritual brother.
He should have been born in China or
Tibet, but he was born in Buenos Aires.
But above all, he's a great friend, a
great person... after Luci.
For any president in particular,
but for all the government in general,
the thought of the people is like a river,
when the water stagnates,
the Dengue fever grows.
Dengue, Dengue!!
He is like Dengue fever. He's our president.
He's Dengue fever he's our president.
He is like Dengue fever, he's our president.
And he says "blah" and he says "blah" and
he says "blah blah blah, blahbity blahbity
blah blah blah blahbity blahbity blah".
It lives in the stagnant water of a town.
He lives in the stagnant water of town.
He lives off your hunger, lives off
your blood, he is like Dengue fever.
your blood, he is the Dengue fever.
He is the Dengue fever,
he's our president.
He is like Dengue fever,
He is the Dengue fever,
he's our president
And he says "blah" and he says
"blah blah blah blahbity blahbity...
<<... blah blah blah blahbity
blahbity blah".
Yeah... it was bound to happen.
What are you doing here? Go away.
Bye, take care.
Bye Luci.
Good luck good luck good luck!
I love you.
Take care of yourself.
Here you have the check for table
8 and the table outside.
And I have the money from Danny's
birthday party,
you just have to give me
10 pesos for my trip.
Ok.
Can I use the phone?
For what?
To talk to Camilo.
This phone isn't for fooling around.
But he's asking me to go to his house.
So go... or his father should go,
why is he calling you?
Martin what are you doing?
Are you crazy? Crazy, get off!
How many secrets do we
have? What's one more?
Secrets?
Yeah, secrets, one more, one less...
Martin get off.
What do you mean get off?
You have a girlfriend...
Ahh yeah.
Do you like me?
I'm crazy about you Ama,
I always have been, really.
It's in your contract that you
have to attend to me isn't it?
No!
Why no? Yes, yes yes!
No no get off... Martin get off.
- Why get off?
- Get off.
I'm dying to do this.
Get off... let me go... no.
Ama Ama come here.
Let me go, No no no!
Ama Ama! Come here!
Get off.
Why?
Why do you do that shit?
Hey! It's food for the monster.
What monster?
The monster that we have
inside... Watch... eat monster eat!
It makes you live in a total illusion man.
And you? How's it
going at your house?
With the condensed
milk and diet cookies?
What's up? You're a really
special guy, are you?
No.
You're a little suspicious too.
Look, a cricket... very good luck!
We're gonna have good luck today!
You believe in that?
Yeah, I believe in that, sure.
- In the cricket here? In this moment?
- Yeah.
- Well, should we go?
- Let's go.
- Auntie!
- Cami? What happened?
Mom...
What are you doing here?
Get out of here.
You want to take my son away?
Do you think I don't realize?
He talks about you all the
time. Get out of here.
Get out! Get out! Get out!
Call grandma.
What did we do Martin?
We made love.
Martin we did something
that's not right.
No, it was fine.
What did we do?
That's 39 years working
for your father... 39 years of
service... do you understand
what that is?
On his couch, where he
watches TV! I can't believe this!
I can't believe this!
No, but don't think of it
like that, it's useless.
I betrayed your girlfriend,
I betrayed your family,
I betrayed everyone,
everyone I betrayed.
- Nobody is going to find out.
- Martin, I changed your diapers!
It's sacrilegious... We're working
for the fallen...
I knew it
Fallen from what Ama?
I knew it! I knew it! I felt it
when I was in the Jacuzzi.
I felt it, I felt it. What did I do?
But, it takes away your energy,
creative energy, divine energy,
you're a musician man, a poet!
Why do you have to bust
my balls so much?!
For Luci... I'm going to miss her,
I'm gonna miss her so much man.
I don't know for how long I'm
not going to see her...
For her you have preferences huh?
Am I your blood brother or what?
Yeah, so?
So, do you trust me or not?
More than anyone in the world.
That's what I wanted to hear brother!
Let's go.
Let's go in, let's go!
Auntie...
...it's grandma.
- Hi mom.
Get off.
- Nothing happened.
- Get off.
Get off Martin, get off, get off!
Everything is ok, nothing happened.
Get off, don't touch me.
Fine but nothing happened here, relax,
everything is ok, there's no problem for me.
Do you know what it means
to me to loose my virginity?
What do you mean with virginity?
Hello. Satan has arrived.
Wait wait wait stop
Give me the money... give me
the money! Let's go!
Where's your daddy's money man?
You be quite... you understand
me... shut up.
I don't know. I don't have
money here! I don't know.
Stop it! Stop it!
You shut up! I'm gonna look.
Get it out of this guy
where the money is.
There's no money here
man, there's no money.
Where is it?
You stay calm.
Take this take this.
I don't have money man.
Where is it?
Stop it!
Take it man, take my watch.
I'm going to fuck you up.
What watch man? What watch?
Where? What are you thinking?
Stop. There's no money here.
You wanna remember
me for the rest of your life?
I don't want your wallet.
Where is your father's safe?
- Get off.
- You shut up.
Enough!
- Stop! No!
- Stop! Stop, stop.
You stay calm or I'll
fuck you up, ok?
We can go to the ATM man.
Come on... I'm really crazy man!
Let's go, cause I love this!
Give me the money, come on!
Stop man, stop! Stop, really!
Stop for a second.
You wanna raise my baby man?
Come on bitch!
Stop please!
Come on! Give me the money man,
don't be stupid... look look how I fuck her.
No don't do that, you
don't have to do that.
Come on! Come on!
Go and look around. Look!
Enough stop stop!
Shut up! Shut up!
Without any today when
finally I find the silence...
Stop you don't have to
do this man, please!
You want to see blood?!
I'm going to tattoo her ass.
Ah Ama! You cut me girl!
It's like being a distant star.
So much light without a
destiny, navigating in lonelyness.
Blood! Blood!
Stop man stop!
Blood! Blood! I like blood! Come here!
Stop!
Yeah, come on! You like it. Yeah!
Stop man, stop man!
This is your fault man!
This is for the money! Now take it!
Stop, stop, stop man stop!
Come and go...
What would happen if you knew
that you were never going to die?
That there's no way to stop existing?
Why there are childs born in a golden
chair and others born on a wheelchair?
Can the sea be unfair?
Is there anything before?
This was the day that my
family helped me...
They helped me to decide
that this is my last time...
Everything's going to be
all right... Stay calm, Camilo.
I'll be right back to get you.
No!! Dogo no!
He didn't do anything to me...
It was his blood!! His blood!
Mono, mono, mono
- ¡Ama!
- No.
No! It's useless. It's useless.
People reincarnate in groups.
I'll find you. I have a son!
Billy is strange. He's
different and kind...
He helped my Grandma...
...and now he's going to help us...
Go... Go with your grandma.
Camilo!
You're so young,
I know lots of things
happened to you...
But I swear, that it's
possible to be happy...
They couldn't return.
Maybe now my mom and my
dad can forget about themselves...
And get born again in a luckier body...
What gives life to the sea and the sky?
To come and go feels just like the sea...
It's open to everybody...
And always, just thinking about this,
makes me happy...
Although here, they choose to
see it in a different way...
Move! If you're already in heaven...
If you want to be like that,
no one can stop you.
That's why, move. If you're
already in heaven.
Move... If you're already in heaven.
Ripeados por
Tylerg - Escuadrón Tigre
Visita www.clan-sudamerica.net
Cine de Latinoamérica y España