I've said for years that
our special equipment is obsolete.
And now, computer analysis reveals
a new approach: Miniaturization.
For instance, radioactive lint.
When placed in
an opponent's pockets...
...the personnel and location fix
seems obvious.
What we want
is a location fix on 007.
Number 10 is making ugly noises
about Operation Bedlam.
Miss Moneypenny, did you check
with Communications?
Replies to our Cairo, Amsterdam
and Madrid inquiries: All negative.
The PM wants to be informed
personally when we find 007.
Good morning. My name's Bond.
James Bond. Miss?
Don't move, Mr. Bond.
Now get up!
Put your hands behind your head.
Move!
Get in.
Lie down.
This never happened
to the other fellow.
- Baggage, sir?
- In the boot.
- Take care of those clubs.
- Right, sir.
- Commander Bond. How are you?
- Good to see you, Manuel.
Everything seems up to
the Palacio's usual standards.
Yes, it's a good season.
That red car,
does it belong to a lady?
Yes. Contessa Teresa di Vincenzo.
Our best.
Fortunately, we have had
a cancellation.
Allow me.
This will do.
This will do me nicely.
I'm sure we can look after
your special needs.
I'm sure you can. Thank you.
Thank you.
Twenty thousand francs.
Too rich for my blood.
Madame?
I don't have the money.
I regret too, but I don't have
any money.
The dame can't pay up.
Forgive me.
My mind was elsewhere.
Madame has forgotten we agreed
to be partners this evening.
Please continue.
That's lucky, being bailed out
like that at the last minute.
Waiter.
- Dom Perignon, '57.
- Yes, sir.
Why do you persist
in rescuing me, Mr. Bond?
It's becoming a habit,
Contessa Teresa.
Teresa was a saint.
I'm known as Tracy.
Tracy, next time play it safe
and stand on five.
People who want to stay alive
play it safe.
Please stay alive,
at least for tonight.
Come later.
I hope it'll be worth it, partner.
Send it to suite 423
with caviar for two.
Tracy?
Gatecrasher.
I'll leave you to tidy up.
Royal beluga,
north of the Caspian.
- You're full of surprises, contessa.
- So are you, Mr. Bond.
Do you always have a gun
for a rendezvous?
Occasionally. I seem
to be accident-prone.
I'll take that, if you don't mind.
You're very confident.
Suppose I kill you for a thrill?
I can think of something
more sociable to do.
Stop playing games.
Who was that man in your room?
- You're hurting me.
- I thought that was the idea tonight.
Now, who was he?
I don't know
what you're talking about.
I can be a lot more persuasive.
I'm sure you can.
Whatever else I may be,
I'm not a liar.
Get dressed.
You're the most extraordinary girl.
I'm not interested in
your opinion of me, Mr. Bond.
- I'm here for a business transaction.
- Really?
Isn't Le Bleu a bit heady for that?
You know your perfumes.
What else do you know?
A little about women.
Think about me...
...as a woman you've just bought.
Who needs to buy?
Look, you don't owe me a thing.
I think you're in trouble.
Would you like to talk about it?
No, Mr. Bond.
The only thing you need know
about me is that I pay my debts.
Twenty thousand francs
is a lot of money.
- Good morning, Commander Bond.
- Good morning. Cafe complet for two.
- Yes, sir.
- Connect me with suite 423, please.
The Contessa di Vincenzo
has left the hotel, sir.
- Checked out?
- A few minutes ago.
Thank you.
Paid in full, as well.
- Mr. Bond?
- Yes.
- You've lost something.
- Really?
We'll give it to you outside.
Why not? Perhaps we can make up
a foursome.
You've thought of everything.
What a lovely surprise,
our meeting again so soon.
Where's the party this time?
- You have an appointment.
- Business or pleasure?
Mystery tour, eh?
I think we'd enjoy it
more without that.
Do not kill me, Mr. Bond.
At least not until we've had a drink.
Then if you wish, I'll give
you another chance.
I'm Draco, of Draco Construction.
- But today is the 13th, commander.
- I'm superstitious.
- A martini for our guest.
- A pleasure.
Shaken, not stirred.
- Of course.
- Campari for me.
My apologies for the way you were
brought here today. Please sit down.
I was not sure you would
accept a formal invitation.
There's always something formal
about the point of a pistol.
Thank you, cheri.
Olympe, we will finish
our struggle later.
As you wish.
And she also plays
a very good game of chess.
Cheers.
You usually drink Corsican brandy.
What else do you know about me?
Marc Ange Draco:
Head of the Union Corse.
A big crime syndicate in Europe.
- The biggest.
- Not quite.
An organization known as SPECTRE
operates worldwide.
But your legitimate business fronts
are more extensive.
Construction, electrical supplies...
...numerous agricultural holdings.
Your dossier on me...
...is not entirely complete.
I am also Teresa's father.
- Tracy.
- Yes, Tracy.
Tracy. My only child.
Her mother was an English girl.
A romantic who had come to Corsica
to look for bandits.
Rather like those women who ventured
into the desert looking for sheiks.
She found me in the mountains...
...hiding from the police
at the time.
I came to love this girl.
We married. The result: Teresa.
Twelve years later, my wife died.
I sent Teresa to Switzerland...
- No, thanks, I prefer my own.
...to finish her education.
Unfortunately, I didn't give her
a proper home.
She was without supervision.
So she joined a fast
international set.
One scandal after another.
When I disapproved,
cut off her allowance...
...she committed some greater folly...
...to spite me.
And yet, behind her bravado...
...something was eating away
at her soul.
This can happen
to men and women.
They burn the heart out of themselves
by living too greedily...
...and suddenly...
...all is finished.
- Why tell me this?
She married...
...an Italian count
who killed himself...
...in a Maserati with one
of his mistresses.
I gave her too much,
and it brought her nothing.
Now, why I tell you all this.
I've been informed of everything
you've done for my daughter.
- Everything?
- Don't worry. Don't worry about that.
What you did,
the way you behaved...
...might be the beginning
of some kind of therapy.
She needs help.
Your help.
I find her fascinating, but she needs
a psychiatrist, not me.
What she needs is a man
to dominate her...
...to make love to her enough
to make her love him.
A man like you.
You overestimate me, Draco.
She's very attractive,
but what you ask is not for me.
Listen to me.
On the day you marry her...
...I'll give you a personal dowry
of one million pounds...
...in gold.
That's quite an inducement.
But I don't need a million pounds.
And I have a taste for freedom.
Please, just see her some more.
Who knows what will come of it?
I'm sorry, Draco,
but in my profession, I can't...
- What?
- You have connections not open to me.
Where is Ernst Stavro Blofeld?
Blofeld?
Some of my men defected to him.
I don't know where he is.
- Can you find out?
- Lf I could...
...I wouldn't tell
Her Majesty's Secret Service...
...but I might tell
my future son-in-law.
Go on.
Next week is my birthday.
For that, Teresa always comes
back to me.
You understand?
- Let's say I'll sleep on the idea.
- You do that.
James, where have you been?
- Much too far from you, darling.
- Same old James.
Only more so.
Heartless brute, letting me pine away
without even a postcard.
Pine no more.
Cocktails at my place,
8-ish, just the two of us.
Oh, I'd adore that...
...if only I could trust myself.
Same old Moneypenny:
Britain's last line of defense.
You'd better go in.
He's running a very tight ship today.
I'm relieving you
from Operation Bedlam, 007.
But, sir, Blofeld's
something of a must with me.
You've had two years
to run him down.
You've lost confidence in me?
I'm well aware of your talents, 007...
...but license to kill is useless
unless one has a target.
I'll find you a more suitable
assignment. That's all.
- Sir...
- That's all.
That was a quick conference.
How do you expect a girl to keep
herself alluring...?
Take a memo, please.
- Ready, James.
- Sir, I have the honor to request...
...you will accept my resignation,
effective forthwith.
- Resignation from what?
- Her Majesty's Secret Service.
And kindly present it
to that monument in there.
Sorry, ma'am.
007...
James Bond here.
He wants you, James.
Request granted.
Not even with regret.
What did you expect,
a knighthood?
Why don't you read it?
"Two weeks leave."
You didn't really want
to resign, did you?
Moneypenny, what would I do
without you?
My problem is that you
never do anything with me.
It's a date. The moment I get back.
- Where are you off to?
- Just someplace to laze about.
Beachcombing.
What would I do without you,
Miss Moneypenny? Thank you.
Bonjour, Miguel.
- Teresa, hello.
- Good morning.
- It's so nice that we see you.
- How are you?
- Yes, very well.
- There's Tracy.
Where is she? Ah, there she is!
- Teresa!
- Happy birthday, Papa.
You make it so by being here.
You look marvelous.
There's someone
I want you to meet. Come.
- Olympe, how are you?
- It's good to have you back.
- You look wonderful.
- Thanks.
Mr. Bond, may I introduce
my daughter, Teresa?
- Contessa.
- Mr. Bond and I have already met.
Each time is a renewed pleasure.
Madame always makes one feel
so welcome.
She likes you. I can see it.
You must give me the name
of your oculist.
Olympe, I didn't know
Mr. Bond knew Papa.
There is much about Mr. Bond
one does not know.
It would be interesting to attend
night school, perhaps.
Papa is up to something.
I'm sure of it.
Your father loves you
very much, Tracy.
Whatever he may arrange,
I know it's for your happiness.
What has Papa arranged?
- Ah, Mr. Bond!
- Thank you.
- Many happy returns.
The best years are still to come,
let's hope.
Allow me.
What are you doing here?
Yes, wasn't it kind of your father
to invite me?
We're discussing a business deal.
Really?
No woman would waste this excellent
champagne discussing business.
Unless she happened to be part
of the arrangement.
What did you say?
Don't blame Olympe.
I'm not your daughter for nothing.
I detect a certain
family resemblance.
I suggest you revise the terms
of your contract, Mr. Bond.
- Your liability is too expensive.
- There you're mistaken.
- Papa.
- Yes?
- Mr. Bond wants some information.
- What are you talking about?
You taught me that a good host
supplies his guests' needs.
And without obligation.
- And then?
- "Obligation" is not the right word.
Tell him, Papa.
Tell him what he wants to know.
- Now!
- Please, Teresa.
There's only a possibility.
Nothing definite.
Tell him, Papa,
or you'll never see me again.
All right.
There may be a connection
between that man Blofeld...
...and a lawyer with offices
in Bern, Switzerland.
- Named Gumbold.
- Gumbold.
- Bern, Switzerland.
- Yes, Gumbold.
So...
- Mr. Bond need have no interest in me.
- Another mistake.
She always was a headstrong child.
I'm sorry...
Where has he gone?
Tracy!
Tracy.
I was always taught that mistakes
should be remedied.
Especially between friends.
Or lovers.
I'll catch up with you later.
- The story of our life, James?
- Just keep my martini cool.
I will be back in an hour.
Such things should be left
to a girl's father, who knows best.
But what could be better
than being in love?
Mr. Bond is in love with you?
That may come too...
...someday.
Life's too short for "someday,"
Teresa.
Tomorrow I will speak to him alone,
man-to-man.
- No, Papa. No talk.
- Why not?
Whatever happens,
there'll be no regrets.
Please.
- Good afternoon.
- Good afternoon. Is the admiral in?
Excuse me, sir.
Commander Bond to see you.
Show him in.
- Aye, aye, sir. If you please.
- Thank you.
Unusually small for
a Nymphalis polychloros.
I wasn't aware that your expertise
included lepidoptery.
- Why are you here? You're on leave.
- Genealogy.
Fascinating subject.
Found a letter from Gebruder
Gumbold, solicitors in Switzerland...
...to a certain
Count Balthazar de Bleuchamp.
- De Bleuchamp?
- French form of Blofeld.
You've been relieved from
Operation Bedlam, remember?
I assumed you'd reassign me, sir.
This is a Photostat copy
of a letter...
... addressed to College of Arms
in London...
... with a request to establish
de Bleuchamp's claim to the title.
Sir Hilary Bray, the sable
basilisk of the college...
... has replied to Gumbold,
suggesting they meet in person.
I've taken the liberty of working
with the college on this...
... using an examination
of my own family as cover.
I've also been studying
the technical side of heraldry.
- Sir Hilary Bray. Commander Bond.
- Ah, yes, sir.
If he consents to a meeting, I could
act as a college representative.
Come.
- Good afternoon.
Look at this. Let me take your coat.
Arms of Sir Thomas Bond,
Baronet of Peckham, died 1734.
Argent on a chevron sable.
Three bezants.
Good motto, eh?
"The World is Not Enough."
- Phidian's doing a splendid job.
- Thank you, sir.
We've traced your line
to a Sir Otho le Bon...
...who held the manor of
Wickhamsbreux by a knight's fee...
...from the Earl of Thanet, 1387.
We're in luck.
Gumbold's telephoned from Bern...
...to say that his client will see me.
- You mean me.
- Yes, you.
But, Commander Bond...
...I'm only able to countenance
this deception...
...on your assurance this matter
is of national importance.
I haven't exaggerated.
We appreciate your help.
All right. During the deception period,
I've arranged to go to Brittany.
I want to do some brass rubbings.
Where do I go for this meeting?
They want a description of myself.
- Tactfully adjusted to favor me.
- Yes.
They will send the time and place
where I am to be...
...collected, as they put it.
It's not our sort of thing,
but under the circumstances...
- Sounds like they're suspicious.
- No, not suspicious.
Just discreet.
There was no objection
to my fee of 1000 guineas.
- Could their claim be genuine?
- It's hard to say at this point.
We never like to speak until
we're absolutely certain...
...that there's no error
on our side...
...or forgery on theirs.
I hope I meet your high standards.
One helpful physical point might be...
...that the real de Bleuchamps
are without earlobes.
It's not the sort of thing
that we rely on, but it could help.
- No earlobes.
- You might invite him to Augsburg.
They've been there for generations.
Yes, I'd like to get him away
from Switzerland.
- Sir Hilary Bray, baronet?
- The same, dear lady.
I am Fraulein Irma Bunt,
personal secretary to the count.
- Have you had a good journey?
- No, quite intolerable.
I'm not a good traveler.
I'm sorry. Grunther will take
your luggage.
- No, I can manage.
- I take it.
- You know Switzerland, Sir Hilary?
- I'm afraid not, Fraulein?
- Bunt.
Interesting name for a genealogist.
- Are you from a naval family?
- Naval?
It's a nautical term, meaning
the baggy or swollen parts of a sail.
- Nothing personal, of course.
- Interesting.
- You speak German?
- I'm afraid not.
- French?
- A little. Where are we off to?
You will not be disappointed.
Please?
Like the bugs in a rug, yes?
- You are comfortable?
- Yes, indeed, fraulein.
- Your kindness is quite overwhelming.
- Good.
So we are halfway.
Now we will have a little flight.
I've never been in one of these.
You must your pipe knock off.
"Knock out," you mean.
I hope.
Mind your head, Sir Hilary.
Please fasten your safety belt.
Now, up into the Alps.
That is avalanche damage.
You enjoy the skiing
or the bobsled perhaps?
I'm not a sporting man, fraulein.
Even when I'm at my best.
Do you feel the airsickness?
Up to there is for the public,
and from here upwards it is private.
No one may come through without
permission from the count.
There is the Bleuchamp Institute
for Allergy Research.
- What kind of allergies?
- All of them.
Like the hay fever, or the sickness
caused by the oysters...
...or inability to eat meat.
The count is a great specialist
in this field.
I'll be glad to get my feet
on the ground.
Not ground. Ice.
I should warn you,
guns make me very nervous.
They are to keep the spies
from the chemical companies.
Many times already they have tried
to steal our discoveries.
We live in a world
of avarice and deceit.
- Here at least is no avarice.
- Really?
The Bleuchamp Institute
is not for profit, Sir Hilary.
The count does his work
for the sake of mankind.
I'm very happy to hear it.
He wants to leave his mark
on the entire world.
- Characteristic ambition.
- Characteristic?
Of a true humanitarian.
Formerly it was a sports club,
open to the public.
Now it belongs to the count,
who has given it to scientific research.
Joseph, Sir Hilary Bray will take
number four.
I'll show you there after Grunther
takes you for medical examination.
- I'm quite all right now.
- You are our honored guest.
Thank you.
After your experience
in the helicopter...
...we must make sure
you are well again.
Grunther, take Sir Hilary
to Dr. Von Sant.
Yes?
Give him the usual comforts.
You have 10 minutes...
...and then take them to number four.
If you wish anything for your comfort,
you must ring this...
...and the attendant will come.
Very considerate. Thank you.
You must also ring for him to open
the door when you wish to leave.
- Complicated arrangement.
- To stop patients leaving their rooms...
...when they should be resting.
The count believes very strongly
in undisturbed rest.
Prudent fellow. When can I see him?
We have much to discuss.
He will send for you
when he's ready.
Meanwhile, I'd like you to join me
in the Alpine room before dinner.
- Alpine room?
- Yes. Grunther will come for you.
- Shall we say 7:00?
- Thank you.
Fraulein Bunt will receive you.
Sir Hilary, please,
come to meet our patients.
- This is Sir Hilary Bray, baronet.
- How do you do?
He's a famous genealogist.
You will have a drink, yes?
- Please, come and sit down.
- How do you do?
Thank you.
- What is a baronet?
- An inferior sort of baron.
- Oh, how disappointing.
- Well...
Oh, I don't mean you're inferior.
I mean the title is.
What's a gyn... genealogist?
What is that?
An old people's doctor.
So he's here to cure Fraulein Bunt?
Be careful. She's got ears
like an elephant.
- What will you drink, sir?
- Malt whiskey and branch water.
I'm sorry I was so rude
about what a baronet is.
You gave a very accurate
description.
- Sir.
- Thank you.
It's a treat, having
a man here for once.
You mean there aren't any others?
Only the staff, and you can't
really count them.
Don't discuss the affairs
of the clinic.
Yes, but what is a genealogist?
Will nobody tell me?
- I would be pleased to tell you.
- Well?
Genealogy is all about ancestors
and families.
It could easily be that any one of you
here is related to a royal house...
...if only we could go back
far enough to find out.
Now, if you will tell me your names...
We do not use surnames here.
It is a rule of the clinic.
I'm so sorry. I didn't know that.
Come, it's time for dinner.
Our schedule is rather strict.
So is our diet.
Please, if you will sit
there between Helen and Ruby.
I've never had much to do
with young ladies.
I have ordered you
a steak Piz Gloria.
- I hope you enjoy it.
- Thank you. I'm sure I will.
- Are you here for Christmas?
- Well, I might be if...
- We can have a party before we go!
- That's not quite in my line.
Delicious! I used to hate chicken.
It used to make me break out all over.
You'd be surprised where.
Potatoes did it to me.
Now I adore them.
No medical histories, please.
Girls, I'm sure Sir Hilary would like
to tell us about the College of Arms.
Go on, Sir Hilary.
Please tell us.
- Lf you'd really enjoy that.
- Please. Yes!
- We promise to listen.
- Would you?
Come on, tell us all about it.
The Heralds' College,
or College of Arms...
...consists of 13 members
of the royal household...
...appointed by the sovereign
to superintend...
...armourial, genealogical,
ceremonial and other matters.
The 13 members are divided
into three categories...
...kings, heralds and pursuivants.
Their titles and offices
are of great antiquity.
Well, the first Clarenceux
King of Arms...
...was created in 1334...
...and the first
Somerset Herald in 1448.
Now, when we authorize
a coat of arms...
...it can include all sorts
of funny things...
...crescent moons, portcullises...
...beasts couchant and rampant,
bars, bezants...
Please, what is "bezant"?
Gold balls.
I brought a book on the subject
with a picture of my coat of arms.
Which includes four of them...
...if you'd care to see them.
I'd love to. I'm in room...
No, no. He will give the book to me.
I will pass it to everyone in turn.
- It is fairer like that.
- Of course. If you think so, fraulein.
Is anything the matter, Sir Hilary?
Just a slight stiffness coming on
in the shoulder.
Due to the altitude, no doubt.
The count will see you.
Grunther will take you.
Thank you.
Please excuse me, ladies.
May all your allergies
be swiftly cured.
- What a nice man.
- Sweet!
I know what he's allergic to.
Bezants...
Antisepsis.
Please wait here.
- Good evening, Sir Hilary.
- Good evening.
Balthazar, Count de Bleuchamp.
If you'll forgive me, that's what
I'm here to find out.
To confirm. There can be
no doubt of the truth.
- Please, sit down.
- Lf there were no doubt...
...I'm sure I would not
have been sent.
Well, since you are here, I'll make
everything very plain to you.
To begin with, I was born
without earlobes...
...a well-known congenital distinction
of Bleuchamp ancestry...
...like the Hapsburg lip
or the hawk nose of the Medicis.
Granted, but the fact that
you're a de Bleuchamp...
...doesn't make you
the reigning count.
I feel it in my blood
and in my bones.
I'm afraid the college
will require more concrete proofs.
And it shall have them.
I have assembled all
the relevant documents...
...title deeds, certificates
of birth and death.
I'll send them to your room
for authentication.
You've only to ask Fraulein Bunt
for anything you require.
- Are you comfortable here?
- Yes, but puzzled by your clinic.
The methods of the great pioneers
often puzzle conventional minds.
I've devised a cure for allergies...
...which depends on
holding an unusual...
...and delicate
psychological balance.
So I must impose rather special
conditions on my patients.
And your laboratories?
The cure is not entirely
psychological, Sir Hilary.
There are special vaccines
to be prepared.
Vaccines which must be modified
to suit each individual case.
So I'm a very busy man...
...and I cannot spare you
as much time as I might wish.
To be confirmed
as Count de Bleuchamp...
...you must give me
some of your time.
I need details of your living
relatives, parents and grandparents.
- The documents you will see...
- Can answer questions, but not all.
Oh, one more thing.
It would help if you could
accompany me to visit Augsburg.
- Augsburg?
- The de Bleuchamps' ancestral home.
There are tombs in the cathedral...
...and important records
in the city archives.
You there to assist
with your personal knowledge...
That may not be convenient
for some time...
...but my title shall be recognized.
You may proceed
with your preliminary research.
I'll be happy to start immediately.
Thank you, Herr Grunther.
Sir Hilary!
I brought you the book.
- The illustrated book?
- No, don't turn it on.
- I want to see the pictures.
- You're a picture yourself...
...and twice as lovely
in the firelight.
You are funny,
pretending not to like girls.
Well, I don't usually.
But you're not usual.
That lipstick was an inspiration.
So are you.
Oh, Sir Hilary.
Call me "Hilly."
Hilly.
What's your name?
Ruby Bartlett, from Lancashire.
- Morecambe Bay, actually.
- How did you get here?
Do we have to talk about that now?
It's true!
How did you get here?
I had this awful allergy
about chickens.
My family has a chicken farm...
...and whenever I had to work on it
I nearly died.
A specialist said
there was a Swiss clinic...
...where they cured you, free,
because they're doing research.
Go on.
No, about the clinic, I mean.
Well, the specialist had me meet
Fraulein Bunt in London...
...and she said I had
a very interesting case.
How right she was.
Oh, Hilly!
Oh, bother!
No, Hilly.
It's part of the cure.
Cassette number seven.
Number eight.
Do you remember when you
first came here...
... how you hated chickens?
How you were sick
when you even saw one?
But all that is over now...
... for I have shown you
how foolish it was...
... and your cure is nearly done.
I have taught you
to love chickens...
... to love their flesh,
their voice.
Yes, your cure is nearly done.
And soon you will go home...
... to look after the chickens
that you love so much.
You do love me just a little,
don't you, Hilly?
- Learn one more thing before you go.
- Ruby.
I must teach you
how to give them special care.
I will tell you what to do.
- Ruby, wake up.
- I will tell you when.
I will tell you how.
And after you've done
what I teach you...
... you will forget it forever.
Forever.
Hilly, you old devil.
- It is me, yes?
- Quite undeniably, yes.
How did you get out?
With a fingernail file.
It's so easy.
I wouldn't know.
- I come to see the book, the pictures?
- Jolly good idea.
Now, where did I put it?
I had it a few moments ago.
- Perhaps if we turn on the light?
- No.
You're a picture yourself.
And twice as lovely
in the firelight.
- But, Sir Hilary...
- Hilly.
But I think you do not
like girls, Hilly.
Usually, I don't,
but you're not usual.
Coming here was an inspiration...
...and so are you.
You'll need to be.
- What you say?
- A miracle, our meeting like this.
I don't even know your name.
I tell you all about myself later.
In the morning.
Hey.
What about a lift to the top?
It is not permitted.
All is private.
But surely there's a restaurant,
a club up there.
I've seen them advertised.
- It's all closed now.
- Since when?
- I've seen them advertised.
- You are mistaken.
For many weeks,
they are finished.
But I'd still like to get to the top.
From here up, it's forbidden!
Private! Closed!
All right.
It's my turn now.
- Sir Hilary!
- Good morning.
Good morning.
Your stiffness of last night...
...it is all gone?
- For the time being.
- Then come and do curling with us.
- Won't that be frightfully energetic?
- No.
- We'll show you.
- Perhaps you'd teach me.
- Have a go.
- We expect great things of you.
We're leaving very soon.
I must see you.
Eight o'clock tonight.
And the man was alone?
- Good morning, ladies.
- Good morning!
Good morning, Sir Hilary.
How's your research?
Riveting,
and very promising too.
I've never heard anything
so ridiculous in all my life!
Since when is climbing
a criminal offence?
Excuse me.
Piz Gloria, sir, is private property.
The whole bloody Alp?
Ridiculous!
There are many signs, and my servant
warned you down at the station.
Your throw, I think it is.
I had my throw.
Made a mess of it, I'm afraid.
That didn't count.
You can throw again.
- Yes, go on.
- Very civil of you, fraulein.
- Doesn't entitle these goons to
shoot at me. Who the hell are you?
I am the director of this institute.
You'll be sent back down and
will refrain from troubling us again!
What about my belongings?
- They will be sent later.
- But they're mine!
We have certain rules
which must be observed.
- The authorities will hear about it!
- Good day.
Director... Or count,
as I think I can now safely say...
I thought I'd take the afternoon off,
so if you send the car down...
But you've already had
the morning off.
Must have a bit of fresh air.
Those ancestors are hard work.
And the College of Arms
is being very well paid.
- Lf you put it like that...
- I do put it like that.
I'll show you what I've done,
then we'll plan the trip to Augsburg...
...and finish it.
- Over Christmas?
The archives will be closed,
will they not?
Come, girls,
it's time for our massage.
Girls, that is enough curling
for today.
- I must see you tonight.
- Nine o'clock?
Ten? Well, back to work.
You've no idea how it's piling up.
Ruby! It's me, Hilly.
Hilly's so sad that Ruby's leaving.
Has that old cow told you...?
Fancy meeting you here, fraulein!
Merry Christmas, 007.
I'm Sir Hilary Bray.
No, no, Mr. Bond.
Respectable baronets
from the College of Heralds...
...do not seduce
female patients in clinics.
On the other hand, they do get
their professional details right.
The Bleuchamp tombs are not in
the Augsburg Cathedral, as you said...
...but in the Saint Anna Kirche.
Sir Hilary Bray would've known.
A small slip.
Takes more than a few props
to turn 007 into a herald.
It'll take more than cutting off your
earlobes to turn you into a count.
I may yet surprise you, but I'm afraid
you have no surprises left for me.
I know all about your mission,
Mr. Bond.
Your colleague...
Such a keen climber,
such a brilliant conversationalist...
...before he left us.
- Of course he reported where I am.
- I doubt that.
In any case, no one's going
to come to your rescue.
In a few hours, the United Nations
will receive my yuletide greetings:
The information that I now possess
the scientific means to control...
...or to destroy the economy
of the whole world.
People will have more important
things to think about than you.
If they believe your threat.
They will. In any case,
I have prepared a demonstration.
Remember that
disagreeable outbreak...
...of foot-and-mouth disease
in England last summer?
Well, I shall instruct them,
in very convincing terms...
...exactly how I arranged that.
And my capacity has improved since.
Allergy vaccines?
Bacteria. Bacteriological warfare.
With a difference.
Our great breakthrough
since last summer...
...has been the confection
of a certain...
...Virus Omega.
- Infertility.
Total infertility
in plants and animals.
Not just disease in a few herds,
Mr. Bond...
...or the loss of a single crop...
...but the destruction
of a whole strain, forever...
...throughout an entire continent.
If my demands are not met...
...I shall proceed with
the systematic extinction...
...of whole species of cereals
and livestock all over the world.
Including, I suppose,
the human race?
I don't think, do you, Mr. Bond...
...the UN will let it come to that.
Not after their scientists
analyze a small sample...
...of Virus Omega they have received.
Epidemics of sterility.
Nothing is born.
No seed even begins to sprout.
- They'll find an antidote.
- Of course!
If I give them enough time.
They'll have time.
Once they're warned, you'll have
a problem dispensing it.
That problem has already
been solved.
I have been training
my own special "Angels of Death."
Those girls.
Those girls,
and many others like them.
But exactly how?
That will remain my secret.
How many hundred millions do you
want for your services this time?
This time? This time,
the price is of another kind.
You'll be amused
when you know what.
In the meanwhile,
I will keep you here as my guest.
You'll be very useful in helping
to convince the authorities...
...that I mean what I say...
...and I'll do what I claim.
Come. Let me show you
to your new quarters.
You're likely to be with us
for some time, Mr. Bond.
So first...
...a little therapy to soothe
your restless nature.
Poor fellow. He was restless too.
You perverse British,
how you love your exercise.
Every year, dozens of amateur
climbers end in the same predicament.
A kind of waxworks show
for morbid tourists.
Dear, dear me.
Now, now. Now, Mr. Bond, you
must learn to be absolutely calm...
...before we can accept you
back into polite society.
Presents!
Going-away presents...
...from the count himself,
in appreciation.
- I want to open mine now.
- No.
It is more fun to open them
all together, yes?
Please sit down.
We will wait for the others.
Look, look, look!
Eggnog on Christmas Eve.
Just like home!
It is a treat
for the going-away party.
- Your very good health, my dears.
- Cheers! Cheers!
It has been so nice to cure you.
It has something special in it
for the Holy Night celebration.
And now you're going on a journey.
A journey home.
But first you must rest for a while.
Rest. Rest.
Rest...
I will tell you when,
and I will tell you how...
... but it must be our secret.
Yours and mine. Our secret.
And after you've done
what I teach you...
... you will forget it forever.
Forever. Forever.
And now you may
open your eyes again.
Each of you has been given
a present...
... such a prettily wrapped present.
Now is the time to open them.
Open them.
You see, they're beautiful...
... and you're longing to know
what's inside.
You may use anything
but the atomizer...
... which you must never touch,
never...
... until I tell you how and where
to use it.
Open the compact.
Adjust the bottom control.
Every night at exactly 12:00,
you must be alone...
... so you can switch on
that receiver...
... and listen for my voice.
I'll tell you what to do,
I will tell you when...
... and I will tell you how.
After you've heard what I say...
... push the mirror back
to conceal the receiver again.
Push it back now
and close the case.
Now rest again. Rest.
Rest.
In a few minutes, you will wake up.
You will not remember
what I just told you...
... until you return home.
- What a lovely present.
- I don't feel too good.
Please, girls, we are in a hurry.
Merry Christmas.
Maybe you should've
been gift-wrapped.
Flare.
- He's making for the village.
- Head him off at the precipice.
Idiot!
Goodbye, girls. Merry Christmas.
And a happy New Year.
Goodbye!
Bye!
Come on.
James.
Darling, what is it?
- There's people after me.
- Can I help?
- Have you got a car?
- Outside.
Let's get out of here.
Stay close to me.
Not far now.
Near-side door.
- Maybe he didn't see me.
- I wouldn't go "Banco!" on that.
Giving up bad habits?
- Where are we heading?
- Nearest post office to contact London.
I know, Feldkirch.
Why are they looking for you?
I suspect they're trying to kill me.
Drive on!
No sign of them yet.
Or of someone saying thank you.
Thank you, Tracy. You've got
sharp eyes and beautiful...
Earlobes. What were you doing
so near Piz Gloria?
Now I have a new interest in life.
Winter sports? Very wholesome.
Just one winter sportsman,
and Papa told me where to find him.
Just keep my mind on your driving.
Good. There it is, James. Hurry.
James!
Shoot at them!
Good girl.
That crowd might discourage them.
Looks like we've hit the rush hour.
We must stop them!
How do we get out?
Knock him out of the way!
I hope my big end
will stand up to this.
James! How do we get out?
Keep straight!
- We can get out there.
- Lf you say so.
We didn't even stop for the prize.
I told you that crowd
would discourage them.
That's all we need right now.
Pull in there.
Keep moving. I'll open the doors.
Sorry about the accommodations,
contessa.
We should have rung ahead
and booked.
If only I'd got through to London.
- At least you'll get another chance.
- But when?
Let's get some rest.
We'll push on as soon as we can.
At least it's dry.
What really went on
up there, James?
Her Majesty's Secret Service
is still my job.
But there isn't anything you can do
about it at the moment, is there?
No.
Then why are you thinking
about it now?
I'm not.
I'm thinking about us.
Tracy, an agent shouldn't be
concerned with anything but himself.
I understand. We'll just
have to go on the way we are.
No.
I'll have to find
something else to do.
Are you sure, James?
I love you.
I know I'll never find
another girl like you.
Will you marry me?
Do you mean it?
I mean it.
Mr. And Mrs. James Bond.
Of Acacia Avenue, Tunbridge Wells.
How about Belgrave Square?
Or the Via Veneto, Rome.
Paris, convenient for Le Touquet.
Monaco, handy for the Rainiers.
I wonder how much they're asking
for this place.
The proper time for this
is our wedding night.
And that's my New Year's resolution.
- Whatever you say, darling.
- And that is yours.
Good night, Tracy.
Good night, James.
It's not New Year yet.
- James!
- Keep going!
- Simple!
- Good girl.
He had lots of guts.
You three keep going.
Let's head for the trees!
- James!
- Keep going!
Tracy, cling onto me!
A grave deep enough, I think,
to prevent even 007 from walking.
Get the girl.
United Nations, sir. Red scrambler.
M here.
Yes, we're standing by
as instructed.
I understand.
Thank you, sir.
No decision
has been announced yet.
Of course, it's a total news blackout.
But my informant was very plain.
- How plain, sir?
- They're going to buy Blofeld off.
Sit down.
- And the price?
- Amnesty.
A full pardon for all past crimes.
Official recognition of his title...
...when he retires into private life
as Count de Bleuchamp.
He seems to set great store by that.
A very curious thing, snobbery.
- When will they conclude the deal?
- Blofeld wants to know...
...the council's decision not later
than midnight the day after tomorrow.
That gives us time
to get to Piz Gloria first. In force.
No, 007. My instructions are clear.
Destroy the institute and destroy
Blofeld and his virus with it.
It's been rejected as too risky.
Those girls...
God knows how many,
let alone where.
If we destroy the center of
communication controlling the girls...
...they can do nothing.
I have my orders, you have yours.
Forget it.
The girl who helped me escape,
we just leave her?
This department is not concerned
with your personal problems.
This department owes her a debt.
She saved my life.
Operation Bedlam is dead.
- Do you understand?
- Yes, sir.
I understand.
Your call to Marc Draco,
head of Draco Construction.
- Hello, Draco?
- Yes, who is it?
- James Bond.
- Thank God, James.
I'd like to interest you
in a demolition deal...
...that requires aerial activity
to install equipment.
Are you sure we're going to find
Teresa when we get up there?
I'm pretty certain. If not, there's
a good reason for going anyway.
So you've explained.
Quite a crusade.
It is a time for celebration.
Perhaps, if they agree.
They can do nothing else
and you know it, and they know it.
I shall be able to offer you anything
your heart could wish for.
Paid for with how many lives?
Oh, come now, Tracy,
don't be so proud.
Your own father's profession
is not entirely within the law.
His brotherhood also have exotic
ways to keep it a closed shop.
Basle approach calling
unidentified aircraft.
You're flying
in controlled airspace.
We have no flight plan filed on you.
I think some people don't know
we're crusaders.
Now, if you're very, very nice
to me...
...I could make you my countess.
But I'm already a countess.
Whereas if you displease me, I can
promise you a very different estate.
- Excuse me, sir.
- Yes?
There is something on the radio
you should hear.
- Excuse me.
- This is Zurich information...
... calling unidentified aircraft.
Over.
This is Zurich information
calling unidentified aircraft.
- Well?
- That helicopter is one of three.
- None have answered air control.
- And?
There are suspect aircraft
in the vicinity.
- pilot's name and destination.
Over.
Zurich, this is Foxtrot, Gulf, Sierra,
leading Red Cross helicopter flight...
... carrying Red Cross medical
supplies to Italy.
What's the trouble? Over.
We have no record
of your flight plan.
Over.
I repeat, we have no record of your
flight plan or registration. Over.
Then your registrations
must be out-of-date. Over.
Foxtrot, Gulf, Sierra,
this is Zurich information.
You must land at Zurich and report.
I say again,
land at Zurich and report.
- Over.
- Do you wish to commit murder?
I told you, this is a mercy flight...
... carrying blood plasma
and emergency equipment...
... for the victims of the Italian
flood disaster...
... at Rovigo.
I repeat:
Mercy flight. You understand me?
- Gulf, Sierra?
- Yes?
Zurich. Very well,
you may proceed. Out.
You see? It is nothing.
Seems to have settled it.
In case one or both of us
is delayed on the way home...
...it's better to have
a rendezvous for later.
Before we start getting sentimental,
I think we're being followed.
I've been thinking
about your proposition.
Please, tell me more.
This is military air control.
There is no record of your mission.
Alter course to Zurich and land.
Fighters have been dispatched
to intercept you. Over.
I suggest you check your records
again, carefully. Over.
I repeat, return to Zurich
and land. Over.
Check with Geneva. Check
with the Red Cross in Geneva.
Meanwhile, call off your air force.
- It is making my passengers sick.
- Foxtrot, Gulf, Sierra...
- ... you are carrying passengers?
- Of course I am.
Distinguished representatives
of the world press.
They've had enough
of your nonsense. So have I.
Over and out.
There's a lot more to tell,
but there will be plenty of time later.
Take me to the Alpine room.
Are you unhappy here?
I want to see the dawn.
So poetic a pleasure.
What were all the world's charms
to mighty Paris...
...when he found that first dawn
in the arms of his Helen?
When do you expect the signal
accepting your terms?
Any time before midnight tonight.
"Thy dawn, O master of the world,
thy dawn.
For thee, the sunlight
creeps across the lawn.
For thee, the ships are drawn
down to the waves.
For thee, the markets throng
with myriad slaves.
For thee, the hammer
on the anvil rings.
For thee...
...the poet of beguilement sings."
- Helicopters! An attack!
- Get all positions covered!
Look to the girl!
- Tracy! Darling!
- Thank God, Teresa!
James, wait!
Guns make me nervous!
You've done your share.
Get her to safety.
Come on! Let's go!
And you!
Get the circuit set up now!
Let's go!
- All points covered?
- Yes, sir.
All set to blow?
The fuse is set for exactly
five minutes and 10 seconds.
The place will be sealed forever.
Will that give the Englishman
time to get out?
He knows the schedule.
- Where are you going?
- Where's James?
- He'll join us soon.
- But we can't leave him!
- He doesn't need help!
- I won't go without him!
You'll have to!
Spare the rod and spoil the child!
Five, four, three...
...two, one. Now!
He's branched off.
Never mind that.
Go and get the brandy, huh?
Five-star Hennessy, of course.
Your Royal Highnesses...
...my lords, ladies and gentlemen...
...the toast is,
the bride and bridegroom:
Mr. And Mrs. James Bond.
- Good luck, Teresa.
- Thank you.
Anyway, it's a pleasure...
...to meet the man who cost me
three of my best operatives.
Yes, November '64, the bullion job.
You even got away with quite
a chunk of the haul. Tell me...
Congratulations, 007.
I must confess that I've sometimes
thought you a little...
- Irresponsible?
- That's exactly the word. Thank you.
- This time, my boy, I can't complain.
- Nor can I.
- Teresa?
- Yes, Papa?
Look, James, I know that we haven't
always exactly seen...
Anyway, don't forget, if there's
anything you ever need...
Thank you. This time I've got the
gadgets, and I know how to use them.
Remember, obey your husband
in all things.
- You promise me?
- But of course I will.
As I always obeyed you.
Of course. Well, James,
I wish you luck.
For the first and last time.
Remember?
An old proverb: "Her price is far above
rubies, or even your million pounds."
Just because you are Mrs. Bond...
...don't forget my birthday.
- Have I ever?
Both of you, maybe all of you.
Come on, James.
Very happy. Be happy, my darling.
Come on.
On your way.
- Goodbye!
- Drive carefully!
Miss Moneypenny,
what would you do without me?
I always cry at weddings.
007 never had any respect
for government property.
You know, I haven't given you
a wedding present yet.
I had an idea about that.
Three girls, three boys.
- Pleased?
- Not bad for a start.
But, darling, now we have
all the time in the world.
Say it with flowers!
He's got a point. We do look like
an ad for a flower shop.
That reminds me, I didn't even
send you flowers.
Anyway, you have given me
a wedding present.
The best I could have: A future.
Mrs. Bond, shut...
...up. And don't eat it all at once.
- He loves me...
- Instinctively.
- Infuriatingly.
- Intensely.
In...
- In...
- In?
Indubitably.
First a boy, and then a girl.
It's Blofeld!
It's Blofeld.
It's all right.
It's quite all right, really.
She's having a rest.
We'll be going on soon.
There's no hurry, you see.
We have all the time in the world.