You came here to kill me.
This is precinct 80: Niedermann
should be considered extremely dangerous.
Approach with extreme caution.
81-20, please acknowledge.
Over.
81-20, can you hear me?
Eight - one - two - zero. Can you hear me?
Over.
Her name is Lisbeth Salander.
She's 27 years old.
In this edition of Millennium we reveal...
...how Swedish government officials
conspired against her...
...to cover for a pathological killer.
Alexander Zalachenko, a dissident GRU agent
from the Soviet Union,
is responsible for a series of serious crimes in Sweden.
These include arms dealing, human and trafficking and Assault.
Alexander Zalachenko is Lisbeth Salander's father.
This edition of Millennium
is dedicated to clearing her name.
Hi,
Can you open your eyes?
I'm Anders Jonasson.
I'm the doctor in charge of your case.
You are at the Sahlgrenska
hospital in Göteborg.
Can you count to ten?
One, two, three...
That's great.
My report is about 40 to 50 pages,
and I will include copies of documents
from Björck's original investigation...
...to back up and validate the claims.
What photography do we have?
- Not much.
We could include pictures of Gunnar Bjorck,
Teleborian and Zalachenko.
And some of St. Stephen's Hospital.
- Oh, and Lisbeth.
That sounds like a good 75 pages.
- Could well be more - it will make good reading.
Can we unearth any more names?
- No, let's focus on those we have for now.
and hope that more will come up
by the time we publish.
It'll only be a matter of time,
and then...
Let's get to work.
Latest news:
police mobilise additional forces following
the brutal murders near Gosseberga this morning.
A massive search is underway for the suspect,
whom police have identified...
...as Ronald Niedermann,
a 35 year old German national.
According to police sources,
he is armed and extremely dangerous.
I'm here to see Fredrik Clinton.
- May I say who is calling?
I'm Evert Gullberg,
an old colleague of his.
Dad's sleeping at the moment,
but do please come in.
Zalachenko will always act in his own best
interests, no matter what the consequences.
My reputation is at stake.
We can't risk him talking.
He must be silenced at any price.
Agreed, as ever.
But look at the state I'm in.
Fredrik, we need you.
One final time.
I really can't help you.
I'm in hospital every other day...
...for five hours of haemodialysis.
I haven't got much time left.
They can't find me a kidney donor.
This is it, my friend.
Thank you, dear.
- They're freshly baked.
I didn't realize you had a daughter.
No...
We know little of each other's
personal lives...
Despite having worked together...
...oh, over 35 years.
What about Lisbeth Salander?
Her prosecution has already begun.
What do we do with her?
Hi Lisbeth.
How's it going?
Remember me?
I'm Anders Jonasson.
I can understand if you're still tired...
...You took a shot to the head.
We sucessfully removed the bullet,
as far as we can tell,
no vital regions were damaged.
You also had gunshot wounds in
your right shoulder and left hip,
but those will heal nicely.
Is there any brain damage?
Brain injuries are complex and
sometimes difficult to anticipate. Don't worry.
The police want to interview you.
But I refused
due to your condition
They'll be back, but for now
I won't let them near you.
Is Zalachenko alive?
He's been patched up and is stable.
But he is rather badly messed up.
Fuck.
I was wondering when you'd show up.
We've been discussing how to help you,
but we need to hear your version in order
to come up with an effective strategy.
Any thoughts on what form that should take?
Between us, we'll come up with something.
But it's going to be difficult
to avoid a prison sentence entirely.
Gee, you reckon?
We'll help you with a lawyer
and anything else you need.
But you have to cooperate
and we must have guarantees.
Niedermann...
Niedermann's the scapegoat.
He's the one who shot Lisbeth.
There are serious allegations against you
which will be difficult to make go away
That's your problem...
...entirely your problem.
Either find a solution...
...or I'll contact the press.
I have names, dates, events...
everything.
I can take you all down.
I'm a survivor -
you should know that by now.
Zalachenko, you don't understand...
- No! you, don't understand!
This conversation is over.
Just one more thing.
Lisbeth...
What about her?
- She has to be taken care of, understood?
Good. Good...
Hi. Sorry I'm late.
My sister's arrived.
Let's talk later.
Is no one in?
- No.
...but Micke, she tried
to hack her father to death with an axe.
That's attempted murder.
Or self-defence.
But hasn't she been arrested for attempting
to murder Zalachenko?
So she needs a criminal lawyer.
You know women's rights.
Lisbeth and her mother were subjected
to physical and psychological abuse...
...By both Zalachenko and the authorities.
It started long before Gosseberga.
This document proves it.
They're records of the investigation, compiled
by Gunnar Björck of the Security Services.
They prove that an innocent twelve-year old girl
was to comitted to St. Stephen's...
...purely to silence her.
Is it confidential?
Say you got it from a journalist
who refuses to reveal his sources.
You're really prepared to stick your neck out
for Lisbeth Salander, aren't you?
Yeah.
SJ's X2000 No. 429 from Stockholm
has just arrived at platform 6.
I don't need a lawyer.
You're accused of attempting
to murder your father.
Micke thinks that they'll try to commit you
to a psychiatric hospital again...
...so you will need a lawyer.
but you're free to choose someone else....
...unless you prefer the court to
appoint a public defender.
Would you like me to leave?
It's entirely up to you.
Do you have a cigarette?
Do you have any nicotine patches?
- Yes, just one moment please.
I got this copy off Micke.
You're familiar with the contents, aren't you?
We'll need to spend
much time together,
and I need you to be completely
honest with me.
Micke has explained most of it,
but there are some areas which he wants you...
...to decide how much you wish to disclose.
I assume you understand what he means...
Something to do with computers
and a DVD recording.
After all we've done for you
through the years...
...and now you're threatening us.
You're treading dangerously.
I'm a survivor.
I'll do whatever it takes.
You haven't the slightest shred
of loyalty, honour...
and have absolutely no morals...
I'm here to forward a message.
You're on your own this time.
Full stop.
I have no choice - understand?
There's always a choice.
Idiots.
Idiots!
I'll take you down if it's the last thing I do
- That's your choice!
Lie still. Please!
I'll go and see what's happening.
Out! Now!
He's got a gun!
What's going on?
Hurry!
Hang on, I'm coming.
Hold me tight.
Hold on.
Hold on tight!
He tugged at the door, but couldn't
open it. It was so unreal.
An old man with a gun.
I heard him shoot himself.
Are you sure he was after Lisbeth?
Absolutely, it was awful!
I've never been so scared.
Shall I come down?
- No.
It won't be necessary. I'll stay with
my friend Vera Åkerlund in Kålltorp.
Press conference - police headquarters - 3pm.
- I have to go.
Take care.
- Sure.
We'll talk later.
- Ok. Bye.
How come there wasn't better
police protection?
Absolutely incredible.
Here of all places
To carry a weapon into a hospital ward
and shoot patient - unbelievable!
Heavens! Fredrik?
What on earth happened?
Come in, come in.
We're trying to get further
details right now.
What time did it happen?
Find out.
What the hell?
Any idea what happened?
- Zalachenko's been shot.
By all accounts Evert Gullberg shot him.
It's chaotic down there.
Nothing's been confirmed as yet.
Then I'll confirm it.
Evert did shoot him.
Exactly as planned.
Should I organise coffee or something?
- No, not now.
What the hell are you talking about?
What plans?
Gullberg had liver cancer.
He only had a few months left to live.
He chose to help us one last time.
He died with honour.
Did you know he'd kill Zalachenko?
- Of course.
His job was to silence Zalachenko...
...and Salander, as planned.
Are you as fucking deranged as Gullberg?
Watch your tongue, Hallberg.
It was the right decision.
We did what was necessary.
- Necessary? Decision?
Neither you nor Gullberg had any mandate to
make any kind of decision at all, damn it!
In any event, we can never be
connected to either Zalachenko's death
...or Evert Gullberg's.
It's our job to make decisions...
...that no one else dares to.
Least of all politicians.
It comes with the territory.
One more thing...
I'm returning to active service.
I'll take charge of operations...
...until this crisis is over.
The man who pulled the
trigger and later took his own life...
...has been identified as a
78-year-old pensioner.
He used to work as an accountant
and tax lawyer.
What was his name?
- We're not at liberty to diclose that at this time.
Is there any connection with
Lisbeth Salander?
We have firmly ruled out any possible
connection with Lisbeth Salander.
It was the act of a lone assailant
who has acted...
...out his own paranoid
imagination.
He has sent confused messages,
to the media and politicians...
...containing death threats towards
Alexander Zalachenko.
Security Services have analyzed them, and
believe him to have been mentally unstable.
That's all so far from
the police press conference.
We return to the incident at
Sahlgrenska hospital in Göteborg.
No!
Feeding time?
- Yeah. Salisbury steak today.
Go on in.
- Thanks.
Lisbeth?
Need any help?
- No thanks.
Bon apetit!
I have a suggestion.
I'm not going home.
I've booked a room here.
Why don't you stay overnight?
I'm completely exhausted. I slept badly
with all that editorial shit.
We'll just sleep then.
This is the fourth time that car
has been parked in the same spot.
Are you sure?
- Yes.
How do suggest we get out of this?
- We couldn't have forseen everything.
Hospital security has been tightened.
- Thanks a fucking lot for that!
How the hell are we going to
avoid a trial now?
I don't think that's possible.
Only a psychiatric evaluation
and having her comitted will silence her.
She has to pay for the
attempt on Zalachenko's life...
...and be committed to psychiatric care.
How about here at St. Stephen's?
- Yes.
For her own sake.
Who's the prosecutor?
Ekström.
Not a star, but ambitious.
We can handle him.
And the copies of Björck's
investigation? - We destroy them.
Now there's something you might
be able to handle, hmm?
You worry too much.
What about that blond thug
who worked for Zalachenko?
Whatever happened to him?
- Ronald Niedermann...
He's on the run.
It's only a matter of time...
He's Lisbeth Salander's half-brother.
Zalachenko once had an affair
with a woman in Hamburg.
It's like a bloody Greek tragedy!
Zalachenko tries to kill his daughter
with the help of her brother.
Then she rises from the dead...
...to bury an axe in dad's head...
-heh...
...You could look at it that way.
I'll be in touch.
See you later, Vera. Bye.
Hey!
Give me my bag!
What the fuck!
Someone on a scooter snatched my bag.
What? And you?
Are you okay?
I'm fine, but Björck's files
were in the bag.
Don't worry.
I'll get another copy to you.
Annika, I'll call you back.
Milton Security, Armanskij.
This is Mikael Blomkvist.
I need your help.
What is the problem?
- Someone broke into my house.
We can help you with that.
Can I call you back from my office?
Of course, call me on my mobile.
- Ok, bye.
The indictment against Lisbeth Salander
is simple.
Even with Zalachenko dead.
But if the truth about Zalachenko comes out,
the trial will get very complicated.
It is about human lives, about our
relationship with a foreign power...
...and the secret contacts of
the Security Service.
Yes, I've read the report as
background material.
For the prosecution of Lisbeth Salander,
the report has little relevance...
...and the Director of Public Prosecutions
has confiscated it.
However, some bits are useful.
Especially where Lisbeth Salander tried
to kill her father in the past.
I'll see if you can have access
to that part.
Yes, that might help.
Then I'll make sure you get it.
Who d'you work for?
My orders come from the very top.
That means that you can't discuss
this with anyone but me.
I'll be especially discreet.
Anders Jonasson?
- Yes.
My name is Peter Teleborian.
I am a physician at St. Stephen's
psychiatric clinic in Uppsala.
I need to talk to you.
It's about one of your patients,
Lisbeth Salander.
Uh huh...
- Well... shall we.
I have been dealing with her
since she was twelve years old...
...and I am very familiar
with her clinical profile.
Which is?
- Lisbeth is extremely disturbed.
She is highly delusional
with paranoid schizophrenic tendencies.
And as with all sociopaths
she exhibts a total lack of empathy.
In a nutshell.
I have found her to be quiet and withdrawn,
but not a paranoid sociopath.
She's extremely manipulative,
it's all part of her symptoms.
She manifests what she
believes you want to see.
As you can imagine, I'm greatly
concerned about her mental health.
Yes, I understand.
I have to see her to assess
her fitness for the trial.
I can't help you with that.
I'm responsible for Lisbeth.
She's not strong enough to
meet with anyone other than her lawyer.
The prosecutor has given me
specific instructions to asses her.
I'd hoped to avoid getting formal with
a colleague, but you leave me no choice.
As a fellow doctor you should know that
it's my diagnosis that counts...
...regardless of the prosecutor's wishes.
So, you'll have to be patient
and wait until I change my diagnosis.
Well...
I had hoped for a some
professional courtesy.
Can we rule out the government
knowing anything about it?
They must have known a Russian spy
had defected to Sweden.
We had a conservative government in '76
when Zalachenko defected.
30 years, and nothing has leaked out.
It couldn't be kept secret, if many
politicians were aware of it.
A lot of them have would have written memoirs by now.
The same's true of the Security Services.
It would have leaked out sooner or later.
There must be a small secret group
acting independantly.
One with substantial resources and influence.
If there were no leaks about the group in
30 years, where do we start digging?
Our best bet is Evert Gullberg.
There's a good chance of getting somewhere
By digging into his background.
However, it mustn't take too long
or Millennium will be in trouble.
The magazine release has to
coincide with the trial.
Take a look at this, please.
How am I doing?
- You're steadily improving.
I'll make sure you get help
to get started with physiotherapy.
I don't need any help.
- You do - and don't scratch the scab.
What's more, you need to eat better.
Have you tried the food recently?
The food?
- Get me a pizza or something.
I doubt the budget covers pizza.
A certain Dr. Peter Teleborian wanted to see you.
He said that you'd had contact in the past.
Anyway, he had to leave disappointed.
Good...
It seems this is for you.
Hello. We were at the hospital the same
night Lisbeth Salander was brought in.
Yes, I do remember.
- I want to talk to you about something.
I can't disclose any information
about Lisbeth Salander.
No, I have information about Lisbeth
for you. Important information.
A conspiracy like that... sorry,
but it sounds extremely unlikely.
I can understand your scepticism,
but I assure you - it's all true.
Everything has been documented
and I'm publishing the full story.
I'm preparing the defence for Lisbeth's trial.
That's why I'm here.
I'll only ask you one thing.
- What's that?
Lisbeth has secrets.
Personal ones. She may need them
for her defence.
To gain access to evidence she'll need this.
The prosecutor has imposed restrictions.
- That's why I'm asking you.
Hi, how are you doing?
- Fine.
May I examine you a little?
- Sure.
Let's take a look...
Do you feel any pain?
- No.
Any headaches?
- mild ones.
They are gradually improving.
- That's good.
The Stockholm police called again.
Hans Faste was his name. He said he was
in charge of the investigation.
He wanted to come here to interrogate you.
Can you bend your head backwards slightly?
Not too far. I'm a little annoyed
that they're so persistent.
I can't keep refusing on grounds of your
medical condition for much longer.
You're improving rapidly.
Do you understand?
I told him that you needed a couple of
more weeks of rehabilitation.
After that you'll be transferred to
prison in Stockholm.
I've seen the tattoo on your back.
It's rather large.
Why d'you get it done?
- Why d'you ask?
Pure curiosity.
- For personal reasons I don't want to share.
Okay. Sorry.
It must have hurt and taken alot of time.
Yeah, both.
Excuse me.
Hi Lisbeth. You can recount
your version of events with this.
Your memoirs.
Annika doesn't know that you have your PDA now,
and it's better to keep it that way.
Should I give her the DVD?
We also need to know more about Teleborian.
I'm staying in your apartment.
Mine's under observation and possibly bugged.
Murder suspect Lisbeth Salander will be
transferred from Sahlgrenska in Göteborg...
...to Kronoberg prison in Stockholm
as soon as her condition permits.
According to a police spokesman.
The trial is scheduled for the beginning
of November this year.
Plague, are you there?
It's okay to give the DVD to Annika.
But I'll write about the rape myself.
I've contacted Plague about Teleborian.
He'll contact you if he finds anything.
I have links to the government.
Guess who visited the Prime Minister at the
Cabinet Office on October 5, 1976?
No guesses? Evert Gullberg and a person named
Hans von Rottinger.
They were there three weeks after
Zalachenko defected.
How did you find that out?
- I checked the visitor's book.
There was only one visit, on October 5, 1976.
Well done, Christer.
however, we still need to prove that they were
there to provide information about Zalachenko.
Did you find any notes?
- No, just names and dates.
Where do we go from here?
- We'll check the Secretaries of State.
Two people who worked there
might know something.
- Do we have any names?
One's dead and the other's
a retired ambassador.
His name is Bengt Janeryd
and he lives outside Grisslehamn.
We should have a chat with him.
- Good. I'll take care of that.
I know the case better than you do,
so I am more of a threat to him.
I said...
- Yes, I heard what you said...
Address?
Okay.
And you...
...well done!
You're aware that Gullberg
has shot Zalachenko, aren't you?
Did you read it in the newspapers?
- Yes.
Why didn't you call the police?
- I thought I'd wait for them to call.
That sounds likely.
- I didn't know anything about his daughter.
What she went through was terrible.
However, the Prime Minister wasn't aware of it.
Neither was I.
You need to convince me and
the Millennium readers about that.
I forbid you to publish my name in
connection with this.
I didn't have anything to do with it.
What I've read here is new to me.
You've only read only some of the material
we're publishing. There's a lot more.
Everything can be proved.
I won't hang you out to dry, but you
are liable, and you have a responsibility.
So tell me now and I'll keep
your name out of it.
That's blackmail.
- Call it what you will.
If you talk, I promise you
not to publish your name.
Did the prime minister have contact with
Evert Gullberg and Hans von Rottinger?
Did you also contact them?
- Yes.
There was one other, named Clinton,
like the American president.
Clinton?
- Yes.
How often did you meet?
A dozen times during my time as
a Secretary of State.
I didn't know anything.
Only that Zalachenko collaborated...
...and that the information he gave
was invaluable.
Who took over the contact then?
I don't know.
You didn't hand over to anyone?
- No.
And you didn't write any report?
No, everything was top secret, naturally.
I didn't even take notes during meetings.
So, no subsequent governments
had any idea...
...that there was a Soviet defector
in Sweden?
It might sound incredible,
but that's the way it was.
What's up?
- We've got a problem.
I've checked Teleborian's hard disk
and e-mails but haven't found anything.
Nothing?
- Nothing about you or the trial.
The only thing of interest
is two short e-mails...
...sent by Jonas through Hotmail.
"PSU 1 ready next week".
It's dated September 20, this year.
The second's equally brief:
"PSU 2 ready tomorrow".
PSU? Psychiatric opinion?
Yes, could be.
No files?
- No.
He didn't send anything
from his PC at work.
He's probably got laptop
with mobile broadband.
It might be difficult to access.
- But not impossible?
Given sufficient time, anything's is possible.
I'll keep an eye on his mailbox.
- Do it. But don't call me again.
Send me Text or E-mail.
- Okay, bye.
Damn it!
Hello, Mikael Blomkvist. I'm Monica Figuerola,
Constitutional Protection Department.
Yes?
- I'd like to invite you for a chat.
It's an informal invitation.
There's nothing to worry about.
Can I get my mail first?
- Of course.
And a pair of clean underpants?
- Absolutely.
Torsten Edklinth,
Constitutional Protection Department.
Blomkvist.
- Please, take a seat.
You probably know why we
want to speak to you.
So let's get straight to the point.
We have information that there's
a secret group, a conspiracy...
...in an exceptionally sensitive
area of state administration.
My meeting with the Prime Minister yesterday
evening has intigated a full blown investigation.
Meaning...?
A complete investigation.
The report will go straight to the
General Prosecutor, who'll decide
whether to prosecute.
But we need some time to identify
those involved.
I understand.
Where do I come in?
We need to know when you're planning to publish.
If happens before the investigation is complete,
it could jeopardize the whole operation.
When do you think I can publish?
We have no way of knowing that yet.
It's entirely up to you, but I'm
asking for your cooperation.
I have this to say...
The state, the government, the Secret Service:
they all piss me off...
...as well as all the other fucking assholes
who locked up a twelve-year-old girl...
...in a mental hospital, for absolutely no reason,
and declare her mentally incompetent.
I'm also very upset about
what happened to Lisbeth Salander.
and those responsible will be punished.
But until then, we have to identify
all involved.
That's exactly what I want as well.
But I also want Lisbeth Salander
acquitted and declared competent.
Neither we nor the goverment can get
involved, I'm sure you understand.
As long as I get full access
to the results of your investigation...
...you can tell me what to publish and when.
Information for information.
That can easily be arranged.
It's up to us who we recruit
for the investigation.
We can recruit Mikael Blomkvist
as an external consultant.
Evert Gullberg.
Do you have any other names?
Hans von Rottinger, Frederick Clinton.
One is dead, the other has retired.
Both were active in the group during the
'70 and '80s. - Group?
Can we give it a working title?
Maybe we should call it "The Section".
The Section? Ok.
How did you find out about them?
I have a reliable source.
Should we make that the working title?
- Absolutely, I'll take care of it.
I was strapped onto the bed.
Peter Teleborian stood next to the bed.
He smelled of aftershave.
I hated his smell.
I heard his breathing change
and saw his mouth move.
But I couldn't make out what he was saying.
I hated his mouth.
That was the night of my thirteenth Birthday.
Niedermann is your brother.
Come on Buster, search!
Yes, search.
- 80-1651, come in.
Come in, 1651.
We've searched the lower floor.
It's clear.
Someone broke into the house
next door, but the police is there.
Do you need anything to help you sleep?
Lisbeth tried on several occasions
to inform social services...
...about Zalachenko's abuse
of her mother...
...but nobody took the ten year old
girl's accusations seriously.
Finally, Lisbeth was driven to killing
her father in order to save her mother...
...by throwing a milk carton
full of petrol into his face...
...followed by a lit match.
Only then did society react.
But not by punishing
Alexander Zalachenko.
Instead, Lisbeth was punished.
At twelve, she was committed to St Stephen's,
a psychiatric hospital in Uppsala.
On her release, she was declared legally
incompetent and placed under trusteeship.
It's me.
-Why are you calling?
Teleborian is meeting with Jonas
at four in the shopping centre.
What time is it now?
- Nearly half past three.
Fuck!
Hi. I'm here to take some blood.
- I just need to go to the toilet.
Yes, Christer.
- I'm on the staircase.
Yes, I see you now.
I'm just below you.
Teleborian's in the centre of the hall.
Christer, you go. I'll stay here.
Ok.
You should see him soon.
Black jacket.
I see him. He just standing waiting.
Keep an eye on him, but don't get too close.
- No, I'm just watching him.
Someone's coming. It must be Jonas.
Grey jacket, middle-aged.
I don't recognize him.
Now they're leaving. Shall I...?
- Yes, follow them!
They've exited onto Vasagatan.
- Keep following them.
Mikael here. Teleborian's meeting
someone who works for the Section.
Ok, where?
- Vasagatan. Are you coming?
Ok. Yes, I'm on my way.
Hi.
- Hello.
They're in there.
Micke.
- They're leaving now.
Follow Teleborian.
We'll follow the other one.
Monica here.
I need information about a car.
Guess who went in there four hours ago.
- Who?
Fredrik Clinton.
Teleborian's statement?
- It's a draft.
It needs editing,
but it looks good.
Did Teleborian go from a meeting with
Jonas Sandberg of the Section...
...to a meeting at the police station?
With whom?
- We'll find out.
Jonas Sandberg joined the security department
in 1998. For counter-espionage.
In 2001 he was transferred
to a secret location abroad.
He's supposedly working at the embassy in
Madrid, but they've never heard of him.
These are the Section's properties.
A block of apartments, six floors,
23 flats.
I've checked all tenants
but nothing unusual came out.
In addition there is the penthouse.
11 rooms and a kitchen.
A company called Bellona owns it.
The owners live abroad.
Can we get a camera up there?
- Do we have the authority for that?
I'll get the authority,
if you can manage a pot of tea.
Never mind, I'll have one at home.
Hello.
- Hi.
Am I interrupting you?
- Yes.
I'll be back.
- I've nearly finished it.
I just wanted to warn you
that the police is coming tomorrow.
Ok.
I could delay it a couple of days, but...
...my colleagues would be suspicious.
- So leave it.
You sure?
- Yes.
You don't seem particularly worried.
- No.
I have a present for you.
What for?
You've been one of my most entertaining
patients in a long time.
In case you get bored in jail...
The latest on DNA research.
Your mobile phone...
- It's in the chocolate box.
Teleborian has written an expert opinion.
He'll conclude that you need
closed psychiatric care.
The prosecutor requested it.
So, we'll have to hire an independant
one who will come with his own opinion.
Lisbeth, it's for your own good.
I won't talk to a shrink.
I've already told you.
I hope they'll fit.
You're the only one who'll lose out.
Lisbeth...
Make way please.
- Miss Salander?
How are you feeling, Miss Salander?
- Lisbeth...
Do you have any comments?
Today murder suspect Lisbeth Salander
was transferred under police escort...
...from Sahlgrenska in Göteborg
to Kronoberg prison in Stockholm.
According to prosecutor Richard Ekström
the trial...
...has been scheduled for November 6.
Lisbeth Salander has been accused...
...of the alledged attempted murder of
her father, Alexander Zalachenko...
...who was later brutally murdered
at Sahlgrenska Hospital.
There will be increased security
surrounding the trial...
...after threats were made during
the course of police investigation.
Sonny? When the hell did you get out?
- This morning.
Magge too?
- No, he'll have to stay a little longer.
Good to see you again.
The police conducted a raid
the day you were arrested.
They found nothing. Later on that blond
bastard passed by and needed a hideout...
...you know: yours and Magge's buddy.
He's not my buddy, damn it!
He's wanted throughout Sweden.
So that's why he needed a hideout.
I sent him to Viktor's place.
Fuck...
Sonny!
What the hell...
Jenny... Jenny!
Jenny!
Jenny? It's me, Sonny.
Who was it?
Nied...
Niedermann.
Viktor, Viktor...
Niedermann...
He'll fucking die for this.
He will fucking die for this!
Lisbeth Salander's Autobiography...
Can any of this be proved?
- Impossible. They have no proof.
Blomkvist is no fool.
Nor is Erika Berger.
We have to try harder
to contain them.
Press the green button.
We don't have much time.
Let's pump up the pressure.
Who's turn is it today?
- It's Malin's, isn't it?
Hi. How's it going?
You want sushi?
- No sushi. No fish. Chicken teriyaki for me.
Are you having lunch, Micke?
- No, I don't have time.
Ok. Erika, eight pieces?
"You slept with the lights on last night.
Are you afraid of the dark, Erica?
And were late for work today.
I'm watching. Wonder what I want?"
Can I replace my battery with yours?
Mine's flat.
Micke... have a look.
It's anonymous. I think it's from
the same sender as the last.
Have you had many?
- I got one last week.
Why didn't you say anything?
- I didn't take it seriously.
Let's keep it to ourselves for now.
We'll talk about it later today.
May I take it then?
- Take it.
Would you like to have eight pieces?
- I'm not so hungry today.
I'll skip a meal.
You're due at the hearing.
So, we finally meet.
Ekström, prosecutor.
Let's view this initial meeting as more
of a conversation than interrogation.
A way to bring some order
to this complicated story.
I assume you don't have
anything against that?
The charges against you are serious.
However, as a prosecutor I have to
consider all mitigating circumstances.
It's important that you are aware of that,
for your own sake.
It's a simple question.
Answer yes or no.
When you went to Gosseberga
to meet your dad...
...did you already have plans
to kill him?
I will ask counsel once again
to convince Miss Salander to respond.
And I repeat that it's up my client to
decide whether she wishes to answer.
I must ask counsel to have a serious
talk with Miss Salander.
For her own sake.
Well...
I was surprised how small and delicate
she is, like a little girl.
The trial begins on the 13th.
The magazine has to be ready then.
We go to press the week before.
How can we manage that?
- We'll all have to help.
You and Malin write about Teleborian's
background and a bit about St.Stephen's.
Approximately 30 pages. Is that ok?
Yes, that's fine.
- Good.
Well...
And there's another thing.
I've received two anonymous e-mails...
...during the course of the past
week, of which you need to be aware.
Threats?
Shit!
What fucking idiot could do that?
Have you informed the police?
- I don't want to involve the police.
But they're threatening Erika.
We are taking it seriously. But I
don't want police here at the office.
So, you'll just forget about it?
- No. That's not what I said.
I'll sort it out myself.
- How?
The police wont't help.
They don't give a shit!
Please, stop it! God!
I haven't had any more, and no harm's
been done. Let's just forget it, Ok?
Next item.
- 30 pages.
How's Lisbeth Salander?
- She's ok, under the circumstances.
Any comment about the allegations?
- No comment.
You're defending her. Surely you
must have something to say.
Hi sweethearts. You're in here?
Sorry I'm late.
I'm glad you've already eaten.
I'm sure you'll find this interesting.
It's Lisbeth's autobiography.
What? When did she write it?
That not important.
Bjurman?
Lisbeth's guardian?
What's this?
- It's a movie.
You need to see it for yourself.
Lisbeth has authorised its use
in the trial, should it come in handy.
Want some?
Is Lisbeth Salander ok now?
- Yes, well enough to be interviewed.
Physically she's fine.
- Meaning not mentally?
Lisbeth Salander's medical history
indicates several years' treatment
in a mental hospital
Is Lisbeth Salander still mentally ill?
I'm not a psychiatrist, but...
...I have requested a psychiatric
evaluation to determine that.
Who'll be conducting that?
- Dr. Peter Teleborian.
He's chief psychiatrist
at St. Stephen's hospital.
Peter Teleborian...what a surprise.
Christer?
Is it from the same sender?
- Yes.
"It's getting worse now. For all of you".
Is it about all of us?
Has Micke tried to trace the sender?
- He called somebody.
That didn't help much.
We've got to report it.
We can't just wait for something to happen.
- I want to speak with Mikael first.
I'll call him right now.
- No. I'm in charge of publishing.
And what's more, I'm the one who received the
e-mails. I will not go behind Mikael's back.
We have to stick together and be united.
Particularly now.
I'll call him.
Mikael Blomkvist. I can't answer right
now, but please leave a message.
Micke, where the hell are you?
I've received another e-mail.
It's not just about me, any more.
And I feel extremely uncomfortable.
Call me.
Hi Lisbeth.
I want you to know how sorry I am
that you got dragged into this.
I'll try to help you in any way I can.
I hope that we can cooperate, you and I.
I feel we got very close, you and I....
...in those days.
You were a stubborn,..
...obstinate
twelve-year-old girl.
You bit my finger once...
...Remember?
You wouldn't understand that physical
contact was crucial to the treatment...
...that it promoted closeness and trust.
Particularly with children.
You do realize that I'm the one person...
...who can help you?
Don't you?
Hi. Are you still here?
- I tried your mobile several times.
I switched it off because I was writing.
Same sender.
Christer was determined to call the
police today. But I stalled him.
We need to sort this out immediately.
We're running a magazine.
And we're responsible for our staff.
It isn't just about us anymore.
I've contacted one of Lisbeth's
hacker friends, Plague.
Are you saying we don't need to report it?
If anyone can find the sender,
it's him, but it'll take time.
BUT... it's faster than the police.
Are we talking days or weeks?
To be honest, I've no idea.
Let's assume that Millennium has
something to publish...
...what could it possibly be?
Worst-case scenario is they have
a copy of Björck's investigation.
But they still might be unaware
of our involvement.
However, Blomqvist is very credible,
And so is the magazine.
Perhaps we could discredit them?
...All I know is...
...we have to put an end to this,
once and for all.
She called at quarter past three
this morning.
She'd locked herself in an upstairs room.
We got there in 20 minutes.
- Did you find any traces?
The police took care of that.
And we've installed alarms since then.
Erika told me about the e-mails.
They're probably connected with
what happened last night.
I've got a contact trying to trace them,
And I don't want the police involved.
You should. You and Erika are both
the subject of physical threats.
Me?
- Yes, you as well.
The silent alarm was tripped
in your apartment last night.
It took us 17 minutes to get there,
and when we searched the apartment...
...we found 180 grams of cocaine
hidden in one of your speakers...
...as well as 120,000kr cash in your wardrobe.
What the fuck?!
- They're trying to frame you,
As they can't discredit the magazine.
Is it still there?
- Only the money.
We got rid of the coke.
I've got to call Erika.
- I think she's asleep.
Erika.
- Hi, it's me.
I heard what happened. I'm sorry!
I want to see you. Can I come over?
- No, not here.
Let's talk later.
I have to see you right now.
- I need to grab a few hours' sleep.
How about at three o'clock then?
At Samir's Gryta?
Will you come?
- Three's good.
Great. Bye.
- Bye.
I'll print those three pages.
Have you heard from Erika?
I did talk to her. She wasn't feeling
well last night. Catching up on sleep
How is she now?
- Better. Bloody hell, I have to go.
Has she had any more e-mails?
We've really done a great job
with this edition, all of us.
Fancy a beer later?
- Can't, I've got meeting at Samir.
We're not sure how many of these...
...have connections with the Section.
There may be more than we're aware of.
The key players will all be arrested
in a coordinated operation.
You'll have more details later.
It's ten to three. We'll take a break
and reconvene in an hour.
Anything new today?
- Clinton's undergoing dialysis.
The others were coming and going.
Jonas Sandberg is probably the only one
who's been active.
He met with two individuals at a
pizzeria in Bredäng at 10:30.
Any idea whom?
- I didn't recognise them.
They looked East European.
- That'll be the Nikolich brothers.
Tomi and Miro Nikolich. Originally from Serbia,
but they've been living in Huddinge.
Very unpleasant characters.
Snipers during the Civil War.
Miro's wanted for assault, but since
they live in Serbia most of the time...
Mikael...
Hi, Samir.
Sorry I'm late.
How are you?
- How do you think?
Why didn't you call last night?
- What could you have done?
I called Milton Security
because I needed help.
We have to back down, Micke.
Samir's Gryta on Söder.
Patch me through immediately, please.
I've called the office and put
everything on hold.
- Everything on hold?
We have to put Malin and
Christer's safety first.
Have you called the printers?
- I don't want the responsibility.
It's too dangerous.
- Damn it...
Micke, there's a call for you.
- No, not now.
They say it's urgent.
Mind out!
Get down!
They're shooting!
- Take a shortcut, here!.
What the hell!
Get down!
Police! Police!
Show me your hands!
Now!
Police! Show me your hands!
How are you?
Are you ok?
Here, wipe yourself off.
- How are you?
Get Blomkvist and Berger
out as fast as possible.
Go through the kitchen!
The two police officers were
dining at the restaurant...
...and recognized the brothers,
one of whom is wanted for assault.
Shots were fired as they tried to
apprehend them, but no one was injured.
The brothers are now under arrest
for attempted murder.
Damn it!
Goddamit!
I spoke to Christer and Malin.
They can't stay at the office now.
- No...
We could have been killed today.
Both of us.
No job's worth dying for.
No.
We don't know if they just wanted
to kill you, Mikael, or Erika as well.
But the plan was that the police
would find the drugs and money...
...and connect it to a
Yugoslavian drugs deal.
What about the others and the office?
- We're closing it for a couple of days.
We're also postponing publication
of the magazine.
I'll organise personal protection
for you and Erika.
No, I don't want anyone following me.
Let's find out what's going on.
- Have you had any contact with her?
What's going to happen?
I will insist on psychiatric
care for Lisbeth Salander...
...as well as a long prison sentence.
Shouldn't it be the other way round?
Normally, but in this case...
...the psychiatric report is
so conclusive...
...that there is no choice.
Thank you very much.
Lisbeth Salander's trial begins
here in Stockholm's District Court...
...at 1 p.m., in about an hour's time.
It is expected to last three days, and has
drawn a large crowd, as you can see.
During the preliminary investigation
both police and prosecutor...
...have been talking to the media, while
defence has consistently refused to comment...
My God. Is it time already?
I didn't even sleep an hour last night.
- It'll all be fine.
Of course...!
It'll go very well.
Sure!
- Thanks. See you later. Bye.
Move back, please. A bit more...
Unfortunately...
...Lisbeth Salander didn't utter
a single word during all seven hearings.
But, that doesn't detract
from any of the charges.
Thank you.
The floor is now open for the defence.
The defence deny all charges.
I will demonstrate not only that all
the prosecution's allegations are unsound...
...but that my client has been
subjected to serious human rights violations.
I will demand that she be
declared innocent...
...that her guardianship be terminated
and that she be released immediately.
Thank you.
Does the prosecutor have anything to add?
For several reasons I propose that this trial
will be conducted behind closed doors.
The case is about the mental condition and
the welfare of a vulnerable person...
...and about material that is
classified as confidential...
...and in some areas may
affect national security.
We'll talk tonight.
That looks good.
Firstly I would like to clarify...
...why you went to Gosseberga...
...to try and kill your father,
Alexander Zalachenko.
Are we to take your silence,
as a refusal to answer questions?
I'm happy to answer.
Then perhaps you could answer that question.
I didn't hear any question.
I asked if you went to Gosseberga
with the intention to kill your father.
No, you said you wanted to
try to clarify...
...why I went to Gosseberga
to try to kill my father.
That was merely a general statement
in which you pre-supposed my answer.
Answer the question.
- No.
"No" what?
- That's the answer to the question.
Did you strike your father's head
with an axe?
Yes.
I put it to you that he was seriously
injured and that this was attempted murder.
What is your response to that?
You made two statements. To which one
would you like me to respond?
That striking your fathers head with
an axe was attempted murder.
It wasn't attempted murder.
It was self-defence.
Thank you.
Let me know if you need anything.
Can you get me some cigarettes?
- Forget it.
Thank you.
Hello.
- Hi.
How does it feel to be under guard?
- Not too bad.
As long as they stay outside.
Erika...
I couldn't do it.
You are an egotist.
And an idiot.
I'm staying home this week.
And next.
I want to be sure that I made
the right decision.
Well...
Is it about us or Millennium?
About both...
...I think.
You'll hear from me.
Take care of yourself.
Damn it.
Salander, it's time.
Lisbeth Salander's so-called
autobiography...
...lacks any credibility.
There are a number of allegations
against various people...
...each more absurd than the previous.
It's all symptomatic...
of the paranoid schizophrenia
Lisbeth Salander suffers from.
Can you give an example?
The most obvious is the depiction of rape...
...of which - she alleges -...
...her guardian, advocate Bjurman,
would be guilty of.
The entire story, with such vivid detail...
...is a classic example of
the grotesque fantasies...
...which children tend to exhibit.
But Lisbeth Salander is no longer a child,
she is a mature adult.
It still remains to be determined...
...the exact mental level she operating
under is now.
In principle however, you are right.
I understand.
In 1993 Lisbeth Salander was involuntarily
admitted to St. Stephen's hospital.
During the years she was a patient there,
you were responsible for her.
Is that correct?
- Yes.
For how many days was she lying restrained?
In other words: clamped to the bed.
I don't remember exactly.
But not very many.
Approximately how many?
Possibly... thirty times. But I don't
understand the relevance of this question.
Lisbeth Salander claims it was 381 days.
That is pure fantasy.
It doesn't make any sense.
So tell me, was she not restrained
to the bed for over a year...
...of the two years she was a patient?
- Of course not.
The defence has repeatedly tried
to obtain Lisbeth Salander's file...
...covering the years of incarceration
at St. Stephen's without any success.
Can you please explain the reason?
- Because it's highly confidential.
As is quite normal in these cases.
As a lawyer should be well aware of that.
I have here a copy of Lisbeth Salander's
file, covering the years:
1993 and 1994.
It's clearly stated here that Lisbeth
Salander was physically restrained to
her bed for a full 381 days.
Ms. Giannini, I fail to see the
relevance of that to this trial?
I want to prove that Peter Teleborian is
not being truthful in this matter.
Ms. Giannini, records from
1993 and 1994 can't be used today...
...to cast doubt on Peter Teleborian's credibility.
I understand.
I feel like an idiot.
When the prosecutor submits Teleborian's
new report, it will all have been for nothing.
She'll wind up in the mental hospital again
and there's not a damned thing I can do about it.
"Welcome to your private young girls"
Who the fuck...?
Plague.
What's this?
Peter Teleborian's private PC.
A USB copy
Oh, I'm sorry. Do come in.
What's on it?
Everything you need.
Plus real nasty shit.
Annika, I have everything you'll need
right here. Contact with the Section...
...Several different version of the
psychiatric report, with falsified dates...
...e-mail correspondence, everything.
Ah, there you are. Excellent.
Here.
- I'll never have time to read all of this.
Read it over lunch.
The dates are all important.
Good, great!
See you later. Bye.
You ended up at St. Stephen's...
...after dousing your father with petrol
and igniting it.
Yes.
- Why would you do that?
Because he had abused my mother
for several years.
On June 12 1993, he assaulted her
so brutally she became handicapped.
She suffered permanent brain damage.
- Did you tell anyone?
Yes, the police officer
who interrogated me...
...Social Services, a number of
doctors, a priest and that pig there.
When I arrved at St. Stephen's,
I tried to explain what had happened.
But he claimed that it was all a
Fantasy. As punishment I was tied to the bed.
That's utter nonsense.
Another example that your client
...lacks the capacity to distinguish
between fantasy and reality.
You're lying, you fucking bastard!
- Lisbeth Salander, I won't tolerate
that language in my court.
I would like to move on now
to the sexual abuse...
...that my client was subjected to
at the hands of advocate Nils Bjurman.
That has no relevance to this case.
Those allegations are absurd and
totally unsubstanciated!
It is an example of the violation of
human rights which Lisbeth has endured.
...With the exception of Frederick Clinton:
who might be on dialysis...
...in which case, he'll be at
Karolinska Hospital.
Everyone here will receive all
necessary information.
I repeat.
Group 1: Bublanski.
Group 2: Svensson.
Group 3: Modig.
Group 4: Figuerola.
Group 5: Holmberg.
In case of questions or problems
contact your chief of division.
Good luck.
You expect us to believe that Nils Bjurman
raped you? - Yes.
When did that allegedly take place?
- Not "allegedly"...
It was on Tuesday, February 18, 2008...
...and Friday, March 7 of the same year.
It is clearly stated in my biography.
Did you report the rape to the police?
- No.
Why not?
- The police have never listened to me.
Did you seek medical help for your injuries?
No.
Did you talk to anyone about it?
- No.
The late Nils Bjurman has never
been convicted for any crime.
He has never been reported to the police
nor was he the subject of any investigation.
On the other hand, I remind you
that Lisbeth Salander...
...has been diagnosed as paranoid
schizophrenic.
She has spent several years in a
psychiatric clinic for children...
...and has been under guardianship
since her eighteenth birthday.
However regrettable that may be,
there was, of course good reason.
Lisbeth Salander has her
very own confused world-view...
...which is demontrated very clearly
from her "autobiography".
Nowhere else has her lack of touch with
reality been demonstrated so clearly.
Because of this...
...we have serious doubts about the
credibility of anything she says or writes.
Has the prosecutor finished?
- Yes.
Then the defence may present their evidence.
- Thank you.
Peter Teleborian claims that
Lisbeth Salander is lying...
about the allegations that she was
sexually abused by Bjurman.
The prosecutor is of the same mind.
I will now prove to the court
that Lisbeth is telling the truth.
When was this recording made?
On March 7, 2008.
I used a hidden camera.
If you are sweet...
If you...
...I will also be sweet.
Are you sweet?
Are you sweet? Are you sweet?
It's too late now.
Stop the film!
That's enough!
Why did you film it?
- Nils Bjurman had raped me before.
He forced me to have oral sex.
He demanded more if I wanted my money.
It was the only way for me to obtain
evidence against him.
The only way to make him stop.
We'll take a recess. A one hour recess.
Sorry I'm late.
- It's ok. Thanks.
Is the defence submitting new evidence?
No, the court already has copies of these,
but with minor but crucial differences.
I will come to that later.
In that case, the defence has the floor.
- Thank you.
Well...
It can no longer be denied that
Lisbeth was the victim...
...of serious sexual abuse by her guardian,
advocate Nils Bjurman.
A person she thought that she could trust.
As I have said, it illustrates the
type of assaults against Lisbeth.
Assaults both judicial and psychological
in nature.
The person most responsible
for this, is Dr. Peter Teleborian.
In 1993 he wrote a psychiatric report...
...together with Gunnar Björck...
...- who was a member of an illegal group within
the Security Service -...
...in order to silence a dangerous witness...
...and that's why Lisbeth Salander was
commited to a closed psychiatric clinic.
Is there no end to these ridiculous allegations...
Excuse me, but I have the floor for now.
This happened after Lisbeth had poured petrol
on her father...
...Alexander Zalachenko, in a
desperate attempt to save her mother.
But those who protected Zalachenko...
...covered it up and marked the
investigations as classified.
And with the collusion of Peter Teleborian...
...they imprisoned Lisbeth at St. Stephen's
Hospital in Uppsala.
That's a ridiculous accusation!
I have tried to help Lisbeth
Salander in every way. She attempted...
Yesterday Peter Teleborian presented
his latest psychiatric report.
Once again, he recommends..
...compulsory detention and imprisonment
of Lisbeth Salander.
But just as in 1993 this has
been falsified.
That is completely...
I must ask you to allow counsel
to finish speaking, thank you!
Thank you.
His report is based on the "observation"
of my client.
That must have happened after she was
transferred to Kronoberg prison...
...on October 6, and completed on November 5.
Is that correct, Dr Teleborian?
I would like to call two witnesses.
No!
Police! Drop your weapon!
So... do you recognise this document?
Yes.
It is the psychiatric report on
Lisbeth Salander by Peter Teleborian.
There are three versions.
The first dated September 20,
the second October 1...
...and this one is the third,
dated October 6.
You gave me the documents.
And I have noticed that the first
report dated October 1...
...is identical to the report which
Peter Teleborian submitted yesterday.
Dated November 5.
Very odd, to put it mildly.
The only possble conclusion is that
Peter Teleborian wrote the reports...
...before he met Lisbeth Salander.
For this reason alone it lacks all credibility.
Superintendent Edklinth, it is true...
...that you received these reports
about Salander from Mikael Blomkvist?
Yes.
What are your overall conclusions?
- They have been falsified.
They were written long before...
...Peter Teleborian had the opportunity
to meet Lisbeth Salander in prison.
Moreover, they were completed with the
collaboration of a certain Jonas Sandberg.
That's a lie.
Is it a lie?
- No, not at all.
The documents are dated
and there is e-mail correspondence...
...between Peter Teleborian and
Jonas Sandberg that prove it.
He is part of a clandestine group
within the Security Service...
...who have protected Alexander Zalachenko
since the late 70's.
The group was responsible for the decision...
...to lock up Lisbeth Salander at
St. Stephen's hospital in 1993.
Jonas Sandberg is one of a dozen people...
...who were arrested today by order
of the General Prosecutor.
Sandberg is suspected of involvement in
the murder of Gunnar Björck...
...and probably of one other murder.
We have evidence and several witnesses.
Would Peter Teleborian like to
comment?
There are two policemen waiting outside
the courtroom.
They want to take Peter Teleborian
away for interrogation.
What for?
It is in connection with child
pornography offences...
Specifically, for possession of 8,000
pornographic images and movies...
...found on his laptop.
We are seizing this as evidence.
Please come with us.
You may sit down.
The court has not been able to assess
all the information yet...
...but can find no reason to keep
Lisbeth Salander in custody.
Therefore, you are free to go while
awaiting the verdict.
Are you sure that you don't want to
come Millennium with me?
You can drop me here on Folkungagatan.
You know that you owe all of this
to Micke, don't you?
Yes. But...
Yes.
How can I get hold of you.
- You can reach me by e-mail.
Ok.
See you.
How did it go?
- Justice prevailed.
So now you party?
- Now we party.
What will you do now?
- It's starting!
...suspected of murder, among other things.
The organization, which co-ordinated its
activities from this apartment in Stockholm...
...was responsible for serious human
rights offence against Lisbeth Salander.
But, this story beins in the 1960's.
When the Section was created to
watch over the nation's interests.
Officially they never existed, and
secretly operated from this apartment.
Evidence suggests that even the head of the
National Police was not aware of the group.
In the mid-70's the Section recruited
a top Soviet spy...
Lisbeth has been released
pending the verdict.
So, she'll either be acquitted or
receive a suspended sentence.
Here you are!
- What's this, "Estate inventory"?
It's Zalachenko's Estate.
I don't want anything from that pig.
No, but you're legally emancipated now.
So, I need your signature to prove
that you received it.
Bonds with a value of 300,000...
...plus property in Gosseberga
valued at 1,5 million.
I don't want to have anything
to do with any of it.
Then there's this...
An abandoned brickyard somewhere
outside Norrtälje.
The plot alone has been valued
at 150,000.
Ok.
Sell all that shit and give
the money to charity.
I think you should read it.
I can always sell it for you later.
Micke says hello.
Pizza Bussola? Here you are!
- Thank you. Bye.
What is this shit?
You deserve to die, you fucking freak.
Telephone directory service.
- Yes, hello.
I'm looking for the number of a
motorcycle club in Svavelsjö.
Who's that? - Are you interested in
the whereabouts of Ronald Niedermann?
OK, I'm listening.
Emergency services.
Police killer Ronald Niedermann is
at Skederyd's brickyard in Norrtälje.
There's a motorcycle gang is on their way
to kill him. They're heavily armed.
Am I disturbing you?
I was having a bath.
- Oh, I see...
Have you seen the news?
- No.
Ronald Niedermann is dead. A gang
from Svavelsjö has killed him.
Then the police came and arrested
the whole lot.
Thanks for everything.
Don't mention it.
Thank yourself.
See you again.
See you.
- Definitely.
Subtitles by [ch4cal]