NARRATOR: 1879...
The Civil War is over...
and the resulting
economic explosion...
spurs the great migration west.
Farmers, ranchers,
prospectors...
killers, and thieves
seek their fortunes.
Cattle drovers turn
cow towns into armed camps...
with murder rates
higher than those...
of modern-day New York
or Los Angeles.
Out of this chaos...
comes legendary lawman
Wyatt Earp...
retiring his badge and gun...
to start a peaceful life
with his family.
Earp's friend
John "Doc"Holliday...
a Southern gentleman
turned gunman and gambler...
also travels west...
hoping the dry climate
will relieve his tuberculosis.
Silver is discovered
in Arizona.
Tombstone becomes
queen of the boom towns...
where the latest
Paris fashions are sold...
from the backs of wagons.
Attracted to
this atmosphere of greed...
over one hundred
exiled Texas outlaws...
band together to form
the ruthless gang...
recognized by
the red sashes they wear.
They emerge
as the earliest example...
of organized crime in America.
They call themselves,
"The Cowboys."
[Man singing in Spanish]
[Singing continues]
[Crowd chattering in Spanish]
[Chattering stops]
[Laughs]
CURLY BILL:
Y'all killed two cowboys.
[People yelling]
[Cries]
[Yells in Spanish]
[Chuckling]
[Gunshot]
MAN: Looks like we win.
CURLY BILL:
Mexican police, huh?
[Laughs]
Tell him to get on his knees.
[Speaking Spanish]
[Man speaking Spanish]
He will not kneel, patron.
He is very proud.
Hey, somebody get
this spic on his knees.
[Bride screams]
MAN: Good shot, Billy.
[Laughs]
Gracias.
Unh! Aah!
They call me
Curly Bill Brocious.
I'm what you might call
a founder of the feast.
CURLY BILL:
So next time we come...
you better step aside.
I ain't kidding, neither.
[Man speaking Spanish]
Patron, he say...
uh, someone will come
to revenge for him.
Something like a sick horse
who comes to sit with him.
He talk crazy.
[Speaking Spanish]
That's not what he said,
you ignorant wretch.
Your Spanish is worse
than your English.
GROOM: You go to hell!
You first.
Unh! Ohh!
[Bride sobbing]
- No! No!
- What do you got there?
BRIDE: Help me!
[Man laughs]
[Bride screaming]
[Gunshot]
Have a seat, boys.
MAN: It all looks good.
MAN: I guess they knew
we were coming.
[Gunshot]
[Man speaking Spanish]
[Laughs]
[All laugh]
Hey, Johnny.
What did that Mexican mean...
a sick horse
was gonna get us, huh?
He was quoting the Bible...
Revelations.
"Behold, the pale horse...
"the man who sat on him
was Death...
"and Hell followed with him."
[Whistle blowing]
[Bell ringing]
MAN: Come on,
you old Southern mule, you!
[Man strikes horse,
horse neighs]
MAN: [Whistles] Move!
[Horse neighs]
[Man strikes horse]
MAN: Come on!
Action! You move!
[Man strikes horse]
Come on!
Come on, horse! Come on!
[Neighs]
Hurts, don't it?
Now let go of that stud...
and go on about your business.
Mr. Earp.
My name's Dake...
Crawley Dake...
U.S. Marshal
for this territory.
EARP: Forget it.
I'm retired.
Excuse me?
I said forget it.
I don't want the job,
and that's final.
I don't think
you understand.
No, you don't understand,
Marshal.
I did my duty...
and now I'd like to get on
with my life.
I'm going to Tombstone.
Oh, I see.
And strike it rich?
- Here you go.
- That's fine.
DAKE: I'll tell you
one thing, though...
never saw a rich man...
who didn't wind up
with a guilty conscience.
I already got
a guilty conscience.
Might as well
have the money, too.
Good day, now.
VIRGIL: That's him, all right.
Boy, I'd know
that sour face anywhere.
Ah ha ha ha ha!
Virgil, Morgan. My God.
[Laughs]
Hey, boy.
How are you, Morgan?
MORGAN: So, how do we look?
WYATT: Great. Both of you.
VIRGIL:
Wyatt, you remember Allie.
- Good God, well, he better.
- Allie, girl.
- And Louisa.
- Wyatt.
You're so lovely, darlin'.
I'm just at your feet.
I guess it's only right.
Ma always said
Morgan's the prettiest.
Yeah, but she doted
on the frowner.
That's right.
[Laughs]
- Wyatt.
- Mattie, they're already here.
Folks, this is Celia Ann,
but you can call her Mattie.
Pleased to meet you, Mattie.
It's nice to meet you.
Well, Wyatt,
I couldn't find...
a single store that
had laudanum anywhere.
WYATT: I've sure been
dreaming about this...
God, since forever.
Wait. Look here.
I want to...
Huh?
- Hey, Wyatt...
- Don't talk. Just...
Yeah.
Thank you for this, Wyatt.
It's all your doing.
We're going to make
our fortune, boys.
Well, come on.
Gracious,
we could be sisters.
Mighty fine.
I wonder where he found her.
Same place we found ours,
probably.
[Morgan laughs]
Mattie, honey...
did you say
you need some laudanum?
Yes, I did.
I have some right here.
Oh, you're a lifesaver.
Just be careful, now.
It's full of hop.
Oh, don't worry.
I just get headaches sometimes.
Virg, see anything of Doc
while you were in Preston?
He had us drink
when we left... him and Kate.
I miss Doc.
I miss that old Reb.
I don't.
He makes me laugh.
Yeah!
[Ball falls into slot
on roulette wheel]
ED: That's $500, Holliday.
Are you in or out?
[Coughs]
Five hundred.
Must be a peach of a hand.
Oh, thank you, darlin'.
Kate...
you're not wearing a bustle.
How lewd.
Come on, Holliday,
you in or out, god damn it?
Why, Ed Bailey,
you look like...
you're just about
ready to burst.
ED: Come on.
Come on. Show.
[Coughs] Well...
I suppose I'm deranged...
but I guess
I'll just have to call.
Cover your ears, darlin'.
[Coughs]
Isn't that a daisy?
Why, you son of a bitch, you.
Hey, Bailey,
just settle down.
Shut up.
ED: Take your money
and get out...
because I'm tired
of listening to your mouth.
Why, Ed Bailey...
are we cross?
Them guns don't scare me,
because without them guns...
you ain't nothing
but a skinny lunger.
DOC: Ed,
what an ugly thing to say.
I abhor ugliness.
Does this mean
we're not friends anymore?
You know, Ed...
if I thought
you weren't my friend...
I just don't think
I could bear it.
[Cocks gun]
[Click click]
There.
Now we can be friends again.
Uhh!
Touch that gun,
I'll burn you down.
ED: Aah! Aah!
[Horse neighs]
I calculate
that's the end of this town.
KATE: I had a boy at the hotel
pack us up.
The horse is outside.
So that's why
you're not wearing a bustle.
[Laughs]
My sweet soft Hungarian devil.
Well...
Good evening, then.
Let's not bother
about the luggage.
[Horse neighs]
[Laughing and chattering]
MAN: Hyah! Come on!
WYATT: Say, Morg,
pretty big, isn't it?
Oh, brother, you can smell
the silver in this town.
[Jingling]
Easy.
Look at these girls
over here.
VIRGIL: Whoa, girl.
Hot damn, this burg's jumpin'.
Here we go, ladies.
[Chattering]
Sheriff.
MAN: All right.
They'll take care of it.
BEHAN: Newcomers, eh?
Name's John Behan...
Cochise County sheriff.
Just hit town, did you?
Just this minute.
I'm Wyatt Earp,
and these are my brothers...
Wyatt Earp? Dodge City.
WYATT:
Gave all that up, Sheriff.
Going into business.
I don't even
carry a gun anymore.
Going into business, huh?
Well, then,
I'm the man to see.
Besides sheriff,
I'm also tax collector...
captain of the fire brigade...
and chairman of the non-partisan
Anti-Chinese League.
- Ma'am.
- How do you do?
Yeah, a man of many parts.
Say, you folks
got a place to stay yet?
Nope. Like I said,
we just got here.
Well, I also sit
on the town lot commission.
Really?
As a matter of fact...
we got three lovely cottages
coming up for rent.
I'll throw in a good cleanin'
no charge.
Believe me, Mr. Earp...
you won't find a better deal
within town limits.
I don't know.
Sounds pretty good.
Well, I'll have my man
show them to you.
Thank you.
MORGAN: Hey, Wyatt!
Get on over here.
I want you to meet Fred White.
He's the town marshal.
My pleasure.
A lot of law
around here.
I already met
the county sheriff.
Who, Behan?
He ain't no law.
The only real law
around here is the cowboys.
VIRGIL: Cowboys?
I had a run-in with
a couple of them up in Prescott.
Nobody does nothing
without them.
I mean, they're it.
There's three of them
right over there.
WHITE:
You can always spot a cowboy.
They always wear
those red sashes.
Fact is, the cowboys
are good for business.
WYATT:
How about all these saloons?
That's a real motherlode
here in Tombstone...
all up and down
Allen Street here.
24 hours a day, you got
liquor, hostesses, gambling...
making money hand over fist...
all except the Oriental.
That's a regular slaughterhouse.
Even the high rollers
won't go near it.
That's too bad, too.
It's a nice place.
WHITE: Hell of a waste.
VIRGIL: Wyatt?
- There he goes.
- Yeah.
[Spits]
Old Wyatt.
[Laughs]
[Spits]
[Piano music playing]
TYLER:
The money is on the board.
Five dollars
on that six of spades...
like that.
I'm not gonna tell you again.
Get that cigar out of my face.
Howdy, stranger.
What can I get you?
I wouldn't mind
one of those cigars.
TYLER: I wish y'all would stop
yakking and play cards.
Thank you.
It's kind of nice in here.
You run it?
Milt Joyce... owner, operator.
Wyatt Earp.
MILT: Yeah, sure.
TYLER: I said lay off
the queen, you jackass.
I swear I'm going
to slap somebody now.
WYATT: Excuse me
for asking, Milt, but...
kind of dead in here,
isn't it?
TYLER: You don't listen
too good, do you?
You see that bur
at the faro table?
TYLER: You back that queen
again, you son of a bitch...
I'll blow you right up
that wildcat's ass.
Do you hear me, huh?
He comes barging
in here one day...
slapping all the customers,
waving his gun around.
He chased out
all the high-class play.
The only trade
that comes in here now...
is just the bummers
and the drovers...
just the dregs.
Why don't you
get rid of him...
and get yourself
a straight dealer?
Sure, stranger.
That's easy for you to say.
TYLER: Shit.
God damn it, Junior,
how many times I tell you...
to keep that damn cigar
out of my face?
Huh?
Christ Almighty.
It's like I'm sitting here...
playing cards
with my brother's kids...
you nerve-wracking
sons of bitches.
Is something on your mind?
Just wanted to let you know
you're sitting in my chair.
[Laughs]
Is that a fact?
Yeah, it's a fact.
Well, for a man
that don't go heeled...
you run your mouth
kind of reckless, don't you?
No need to go heeled
to get the bulge...
on a devil like you.
Is that a fact?
WYATT: Mmm...
that's a fact.
Well, I'm real scared.
You're damn right you're scared.
I can see that in your eyes.
- All right...
- Go ahead.
Go ahead, skin it.
Skin that smoke wagon
and see what happens.
Listen, mister,
I'm getting awful tired of...
I'm getting tired of your gas.
Now jerk that pistol
and go to work.
Uhh.
I said throw down, boy.
Aah!
You going to do something...
or just stand there
and bleed?
No?
I didn't think so.
Here, Milt... keepsake.
Hang it over the bar.
All right, youngster,
out you go.
Don't come back...
ever!
Well, what do you say, Milt?
25% of the house take
sound about right?
[Man whistles]
Hyah!
[Cows mooing]
Well...
we're off and running.
I just acquired us
a quarter interest...
in the game at the Oriental.
- Acquired?
- So to speak.
Now all we got to do...
is keep our eyes
on that brass ring, fellas.
MORGAN:
You're the one, Wyatt.
DOC: Why, Johnny Tyler.
The madcap.
Doc?
Where you going
with that shotgun?
I didn't know
you was back in town.
WYATT: Well, well.
How the hell are you?
Wyatt, I am rolling.
Morgan.
Doc.
Virgil.
Hello, Doc.
TYLER: Wyatt Earp?
We're going into business
for ourselves, Doc.
Wyatt just got us a faro game.
Oh. Since when
is faro a business?
Don't you always say
that gambling's an honest trade?
No, I said
poker's an honest trade.
Only suckers buck the tide...
because the odds
are all on the house.
WYATT: Depends on
how you look at it.
It's not like anybody's
putting a gun to their head.
DOC: That's what
I love about Wyatt.
He can talk himself
into anything.
[All laugh]
DOC: Oh.
Johnny, I apologize.
I forgot you were there.
You may go now.
Just leave that shotgun.
Leave it.
TYLER: Thank you.
Sheriff Behan.
Gentlemen.
Sheriff...
have you met Doc Holliday?
Piss on you, Wyatt.
Mr. Holliday.
Forgive me
if I don't shake hands.
So, how's our
little town suit you?
WYATT:
Fine, but, I was thinking...
what this town could
really use is a racetrack.
BEHAN: Really?
That's not a bad idea.
It would send a signal
we're growing up.
DOC: Way ahead of yourselves,
aren't you, boys?
This is just
another mining camp.
BEHAN: Have you seen
how everyone dresses?
Awful tony for a mining camp.
No, sir, the die is cast.
We are growing.
Be as big as San Francisco
in a few years...
and just as sophisticated.
[Gunshot]
[Men yelling]
You son of a bitch!
MAN: Easy, Jess.
This is a private affair.
Don't raise that arm.
I'll kill you,
you cheatin' son...
Very cosmopolitan.
WYATT: I know him.
That's Creek Johnson.
Wyatt? Doc?
Jack.
What do you say, old friend?
What the hell was that
all about, Creek?
They crawfished a bet
and called me a liar.
Sheriff, may I present
a pair of fellow sophisticates?
"Turkey Creek"Jack Johnson...
and
"Texas"Jack Vermillion.
Watch your ear, Creek.
Afraid I'll have
to have those guns.
It was a fair fight.
We was legal.
I'm sorry, boys.
I got to take you
before Judge Spicer.
Hand them over.
Law and order every time...
that's us.
MAN: Hyah!
Whoa.
JOSEPHINE:
I'm frightfully thirsty.
VIRGIL: What the hell
kind of town is this?
Nice scenery.
Well...
an enchanted moment.
MAN: There you are.
JOSEPHINE:
Interesting little scene.
I wonder who that
tall drink of water is.
FABIAN: My dear,
you have set your gaze...
upon the quintessential
frontier type.
Note the lean silhouette.
Eyes closed by the sun...
they're sharp as a hawk.
He's got the look
of both predator...
and prey.
I want one.
- Happy hunting.
- Hmm.
MAN: Get a move on!
Hyah! Hyah!
[Orchestra tuning]
[Crowd chattering and laughing]
Let go!
Whoo!
Ow!
Hey, sister boy,
give me some!
Gimme, gimme, gimme!
Let him alone, Barnes!
Hey, sit with me.
[Orchestra playing]
This is so much fun.
We haven't been
to a show since years.
I hope they're good.
Wyatt?
Oh, sorry.
DOC: Darling,
you know the Earps.
Kate, how you been?
DOC: Mattie. Ravishing.
Doc.
WHITE: Wyatt...
I'd like you to meet
Mayor Clum and his wife.
Mr. Earp, your reputation
precedes you.
I was wondering if you...
Not a prayer.
Nice meeting you.
[Timpani drumroll]
MAN: There you go, boys.
[Orchestra playing]
Professor Gilman?
Hell, I seen him in Bisby.
He catches stuff.
MAN: Hey, Professor,
catch this.
[Audience cheers]
GILMAN:
They're shooting at us!
They're actually
shooting at us!
MAN: Whoo!
FABIAN: I guess we don't have
to wait for our notices.
CURLY BILL:
Prettiest man I ever saw.
[Laughs]
AUDIENCE: Whoo!
FABIAN:
Ladies and gentlemen...
St. Crispin's Day speech
from "Henry V."
FABIAN: To set the scene...
- Goddamn, Barnes.
- I shot the damn ear off.
If we are marked to die...
we are now to do
our country loss...
but if to live...
the fewer men,
the greater share of honor.
BARNES: He's got some nerve.
I'll say that.
What do you think there,
Billy Nilly?
I think he's wonderful.
[Laughter]
FABIAN: This day shall
gentle his condition.
Gentlemen in England
now a-bed...
shall think themselves
accursed...
they were not here...
[Man spits]
And hold their manhoods
cheap...
whilst any speaks
who fought with us...
upon Saint Crispin's Day.
That's great!
Yeah!
Heh heh!
[Taps cane]
MAN: Play it again!
[Violin music playing]
[Orchestra playing]
CURLY BILL:
Now, what in the hell is this?
MAN: Well, that's Faust.
He's going to make a deal
with the devil.
Is your soul for sale, dear?
Know what I'd do?
I'd take the deal
and then crawfish...
and drill that old devil
in the ass.
[Laughter]
How about you, Juanito?
What would you do?
Well, I already did it.
Heh heh.
[Applause]
Very instructive.
DOC: Mmm.
But who was the devil?
[Orchestra playing]
[Applause]
I'll be damned.
You may indeed,
if you get lucky.
MORGAN: Would you look
at all those stars?
I mean, you look up,
and you think...
God made all of that...
but still remembered to make
a little speck like me.
Kind of flattering,
really.
Wyatt, do you believe in God?
No, come on, really.
Do you?
WYATT: Yeah, maybe.
Hell, I don't know.
MORGAN: What do you think
happens when you die?
Something. Nothing.
Hell, I don't know.
MORGAN:
Well, I read this book...
a book on spiritualism.
VIRGIL: Oh, God.
Here he goes again.
MORGAN: Said that a lot
of people, when they die...
they see this light...
like in a tunnel.
WYATT: Yeah?
MORGAN: They say it's the light
leading you to Heaven.
WYATT: Really?
What about Hell?
They got a sign there or what?
MORGAN: Wyatt, god damn it.
I'm serious.
WYATT: Hey, Morg.
Coming to the Oriental, Virg?
- Well...
- Not tonight.
Tonight, me and my old man
are going to have some fun.
Get moving, old man.
Her maiden name was Sullivan.
[Laughs]
I think you better
go with him, honey.
I got to go to work.
Please stay with me.
Honey, I got to get to work.
All right.
Well, now, wait a minute.
I guess I don't have
to go right now.
L... I could stay a while.
No, no.
I don't want to keep you.
No, really.
I can stay a while.
Is that the bottle
Lou gave you?
Yes, it is.
Maybe you should see a doctor.
[Laughs]
Wyatt, it's just headaches.
I know what I'm doing.
No, I don't need
to see a doctor.
- All right, honey.
- Just go.
Everything's fine, Wyatt.
Work well.
All right, good night.
You look beautiful tonight.
[Laughs] Thank you.
MORGAN: Good night, Mattie.
Good night, Morgan.
Come on.
[Coyote howls]
[Piano playing
"De Camptown Races"]
MAN: Seven.
Seven stinkin' spades.
Let's do it.
- I'm your man.
- You win again.
Well played, sir.
You are on fire.
I told you
I was burnin' up tonight.
I'll take the red seven...
and I got some deeds here.
I'll take seven stinkin' dimes.
Awful lot of money.
Can't stand the heat, pal,
get out of the kitchen.
WYATT: You're the doctor.
Sad news, friend. You lose.
WYATT: So, now we're
in the mining business.
You're the one, Wyatt.
We're turning into
regular tycoons.
Think I'll call this one
the Mattie Blaylock.
Mattie will get
a kick out of that.
- That's her maiden name.
- And what a maiden.
Pure as the driven snow,
I'm sure.
Hey, Doc, come on, now.
It's just his style, Morg.
It doesn't mean anything.
Tell me something, my friend.
I'm curious.
Do you actually consider
yourself a married man...
forsaking all others?
Yeah, pretty much.
I was no angel when we met.
Neither was she.
People can change, Doc.
Sooner or later,
you got to grow up.
I see.
Ahem.
And what would you do...
if she walked in here?
She?
Yeah. You know damn well
who I mean.
That dusky-hued Lady Satan,
that's who.
- I'd probably ignore her.
- Ignore her?
I'd ignore her.
People can change, Doc.
I'll remember you said that.
What?
[Applause]
MAN: Brava! Brava!
Brava! Brava!
Ma'am. Miss Marcus.
Aw, hell.
[Piano music playing]
MAN: Bravo! Bravo!
[Crowd whistles and cheers]
Miss Marcus...
allow me the pleasure
of a drink.
- Thank you, sir.
- Milt, champagne.
WYATT: Satisfied?
I stand corrected, Wyatt.
You're an oak.
Thanks, Kate.
[Applause]
MAN: Bravo!
Bravo.
MAN: Good show, pard.
Good show.
Mr. Fabian, would you
come sit at my table?
MAN: Mr. Earp,
would you mind...
signing an autograph
for me, sir?
My wife's not going
to believe this.
Wyatt Earp, huh?
Heard of you.
Listen now,
Mr. Kansas law dog.
IKE:
Law don't go around here.
Savvy?
I'm retired.
CURLY BILL: Good.
[Laughs]
That's real good.
IKE: Yeah.
Yeah, that's
real good, law dog...
because law just
don't go around here.
WYATT:
I heard you the first time.
Winner to the king... $500.
[Laughs]
Shut up, lke. Ha.
You must be Doc Holliday.
[Coughs]
That's the rumor.
Are you retired, too?
Not me. I'm in my prime.
Yeah, you look it.
Ah, you must be Ringo.
Look, darlin'.
Johnny Ringo...
the deadliest pistolier
there is...
since Wild Bill, they say.
DOC: What do you say, darlin'?
Should I hate him?
You don't even know him.
DOC: No. That's true, but...
I don't know, there's just
something about him...
something around the eyes.
[Takes deep breath]
I don't know.
Reminds me of... me.
No. I'm sure of it.
I hate him.
WYATT: He's drunk.
In vino veritas.
Age quod agis.
DOC: Credat judaeus
apella, non ego.
Luventus stultorum
magister.
In pace requiescat.
WHITE: Come on, boys.
We don't want
any trouble in here...
not in any language.
DOC: That's Latin, darlin'.
Evidently, Mr. Ringo
is an educated man.
Now I really hate him.
CURLY BILL: Watch it, Johnny.
I hear he's real fast.
[Laughter]
MAN: Whoo!
[Crowd cheering and whistling]
Ha.
[Man laughs]
[Curly Bill blows, laughs]
[Crowd cheering and whistling]
[Laughs]
[Cheering stops]
[Crowd laughing]
MAN: You said it.
[Applause]
Bravo! Ha ha!
[Laughter]
[Curly Bill laughing]
[Light applause]
Drinks are on me.
[Crowd cheers,
piano music playing]
WHITE: Getting kind of
spooky around here.
MORGAN: Curly Bill, huh?
Who was that other idiot?
[Laughs] lke Clanton.
WYATT: Table's open.
The man dealing faro...
who is he?
That's Wyatt Earp.
Made a name for himself
as a peace officer in Kansas.
Hmm. Peace officer.
Very impressive.
BEHAN:
And I believe he's married.
[Both laugh]
More champagne.
Ah.
Now, hell.
- Hello.
WYATT:
We've never actually met.
- My name's...
- Wyatt Earp. I know.
- I'm...
- Josephine Marcus.
Everybody knows.
[Laughs]
I was beginning to think
we'd never meet.
This is fortuitous.
That means lucky.
Yeah, I know what it means.
[Neighs]
- Easy, now.
- What is it?
That mare is in season.
[Laughs]
Yes, she's starting.
How do they know?
They know. It's the scent.
Ah.
I guess we better split them up.
It's been real...
JOSEPHINE:
I have a better idea.
Let's run it out of them.
Yeah, I'm an oak, all right.
WYATT: Whoa.
Well... end of the road.
Maybe for you. Yaah!
Hyah!
JOSEPHINE:
Ahh. That was lovely.
WYATT: Lovely? You could've
been killed or busted up.
Fun, though, wasn't it?
You'd die for fun?
Wouldn't you?
[Laughs] Oh.
Oh, he's laughing.
I didn't think you ever laughed.
Yeah, I laugh sometimes.
Yes, but how often?
Are you happy?
Am I happy?
Well, I don't know.
As happy as the next man,
I guess.
I don't laugh all day long
like an idiot...
if that's what you mean.
Touchy about it, aren't you?
No, I'm not touchy.
I just...
It's a silly question,
is all.
Am I happy?
Are you happy?
Oh, I'm always happy...
unless I'm bored.
That blond woman...
is that your wife?
What about her?
Nothing.
What do you want out of life?
[Laughs]
How do you get these questions?
- Just answer.
- Well, I don't know.
Make some money,
maybe have some children.
It doesn't suit you.
Well, how would you know?
It just doesn't, that's all.
I ought to know my own mind...
and what suits me
is a family and kids.
Suits me right down
to the ground.
In fact,
that's my idea of Heaven.
All right,
what's your idea of Heaven?
Room service.
[Laughs]
Oh, he's laughing again.
That's what I want.
I want to move and go places...
and never look back...
just have fun forever.
That's my idea of Heaven.
I need someone
to share it with, though.
You mean Behan?
Well, then...
why are you with him?
Because he's handsome...
and he's charming, and...
he's all right... for now.
Oh, I know.
Don't say it. I'm rotten.
I tried to be good.
It's just so boring.
The way you talk...
Never heard a woman
talk like that?
Never.
I don't have time to be proper.
I want to live.
I'm a woman. I like men.
If that means
I'm not ladylike...
then I guess
I'm just not a lady.
At least I'm honest.
You're different.
There's no arguing that.
But you're a lady, all right.
I'll take my oath on it.
[Man whistles]
MAN: Get!
[Hums]
[Door opens]
Oh.
WYATT:
Is that the opium Lou gave you?
It's a new bottle, isn't it?
You better go easy
on that stuff.
Wyatt, leave me alone.
And where have you been?
Just out. Riding.
How are you feeling, Mattie?
[Laughs]
L... I don't know.
Uh, I'm all right.
I'm fine. [Laughs]
- You sure?
- Sure... I'm sure.
Well...
I was thinking today.
We've already made
a pile of money in this place.
What if we pulled up stakes
and just moved on?
Then we could stay
on the move...
just keep going.
See the world.
Live on room service
the rest of our lives.
How'd that be?
[Laughs]
On room service?
Wyatt, what are you
talking about?
[Laughs]
Nothing. I just...
just thinking out loud,
you know?
Nothing.
Forget about it.
[People laughing
and chattering]
[Classical piano music playing]
MAN: Ha ha! What's she doing
with that lunger?
Ha ha!
Hey.
Is that "Old Dog Tray"?
That sounds like
"Old Dog Tray" to me.
DOC: Pardon?
You know, Stephen Foster...
"Oh! Susanna"...
"De Camptown Races."
Stephen stinkin' Foster.
Oh, yes. Well...
this happens to be
a nocturne.
A which?
You know...
Frederic fucking Chopin.
[Kate laughs]
Mmm.
Oh, yea.
Boy, I feel great.
I feel...
just capital.
[Laughs]
Unh!
Aah!
[Laughs]
WOMAN: Aah!
Aah!
[Laughs]
[Gunshots continue]
Do you see what's going on
in the street?
Somebody's
got to do something.
CLUM: Well, I believe
you're the sheriff.
No, no, no.
This is not county business.
This is a town matter.
Marshal?
CURLY BILL: Yaah!
[Laughs]
[Gunshot]
What don't you just
leave it alone?
No. I, uh...
I got to do something.
[Curly Bill howls]
CURLY BILL: Waah!
Here's your down card.
CURLY BILL: Ow-ooh!
[Howls]
Unh!
Argh!
[Gunshots]
Curly Bill!
Come on, now.
Why, howdy, Fred.
[Laughs]
WHITE:
Hand those over, Curly.
Hand them over.
Why, sure, Dad.
[Laughs]
I'm only funnin'.
Here you go.
Uhh!
Uhh.
Fred?
Come on, now, Fred.
MAN: He got old Fred White.
MAN:
He shot the marshal!
WYATT: Better get him
off the street.
MAN: Fred White's dead!
They killed him!
WYATT:
All right, back off.
- Get a rope.
- String him up!
Nobody's hanging anybody.
MAN: He just killed a man.
He'll stand trial for it.
Now get back. Move!
Turn him loose.
MAN: He said
to turn loose of him.
WYATT: Well, I'm not...
so go home.
I swear to God, law dog...
if you don't step aside,
we'll tear you apart.
WYATT: All right.
You die first, get it?
Your friends
might get me in a rush...
but not before I make
your head into a canoe.
You understand me?
He's bluffing.
Let's rush him.
No. He ain't bluffing.
You're not as stupid
as you look, lke.
Now tell them to get back.
IKE: Go on, now. Get back.
Go on! Billy!
He'll kill me.
And you, music lover...
you're next.
[Laughs]
The drunk piano player.
BILLY: You're so drunk
you can't hit nothing.
In fact...
you're probably seeing double.
I have two guns...
one for each of you.
All right, break it up now!
[People chattering]
Go home now.
MAN: Come on.
MAN: All right, come on.
I'll see you soon.
BILLY: We'll meet again.
Well...
as you can see...
never a dull moment.
[Curly Bill laughs]
WYATT: So it takes
Judge Spicer...
three weeks to get back
to town...
and he says,
"Well, did you actually see it?"
I said, "No,
by the time I got there...
"Marshal White
had already been shot."
Then Spicer leans forward,
and he says...
"Well, can't have a murder
without a witness."
- What?
- Case dismissed.
Can you beat it?
After all that?
Heh. Hell, who cares.
None of my business anyway.
Ready to go, Milt?
MORGAN:
God, I love this game.
You know, boys,
when we're finally set...
we gotta each have
a billiard room in our houses.
Been thinking.
Maybe we ought to open up
a place of our own.
You know?
There's the real money.
Build it up.
Milk it, sell it off
for a bundle...
and breeze out of this burg
with more money than Croesus...
and ready to live like kings.
What do you think, Virg?
Virg?
Why don't you and me
take a walk around town...
see if we can't spot us
a couple of nice lots.
It's workin' out
just like you said, Wyatt.
Goddamn, boys,
we're lootin' this burg...
six ways from Sunday.
Pretty fun, too, isn't it?
Kinda, actually.
I gotta admit.
Excuse me, Wyatt,
do you have a moment?
Please,
will you just hear me out?
MORGAN: Hold on, Mayor.
He already told you no.
WYATT: You tell him, Morg.
What about you?
You were a lawman.
I'm busy.
We're all busy.
Sorry, Mayor, but you're
barkin' up the wrong tree.
You men are making
a lot of money in this town.
That's good.
Good for you.
In the meantime...
a lot of decent people
are suffering.
But please,
don't let me take up...
any more of
your precious time.
Rack 'em.
[Pool cues clatter]
I tell ya, I'm sufferin'...
from a hangover.
[Billiard balls colliding]
[People chattering]
[Gunfire]
[Man yells]
[Woman screams]
[Gunfire]
[Horse neighs]
[Gunshot]
[Yelling and arguing]
[Hammer banging]
[Yelling continues]
MAN: Come on,
you can't do this!
Hold on a minute!
Wait a minute!
Calm down and listen to me.
Nobody's saying
you can't own a gun.
Nobody's even saying
you can't carry a gun.
All we're saying is
you can't carry a gun in town.
[Crowd yells and argues]
VIRGIL:
That's not so bad, is it?
MAN: Yeah!
SECOND MAN:
Cowboys are rustling our herds!
Listen, Mayor, I have
to talk to you about this.
No, we don't have to talk.
You can read, can't you?
It's a town matter, not county.
WYATT:
What the hell are you doing?
I told you
we weren't gettin' involved.
You got us involved
when you brought us here.
You hold on a minute, Virg!
Hold on, nothing.
I walk around this town...
and look these people
in the eye...
it's just like someone's
slapping me in the face.
These people are afraid
to walk down the street...
and I'm trying
to make money off them...
like some goddamned vulture.
If we're gonna have
a future in this town...
it's gotta have
some law and order.
Please, Virg,
don't do this to me.
It's got nothing
to do with you, Wyatt!
Nothing to do with me?
I'm your brother,
for Christ's sake!
God, I don't believe this!
Talk to him, will ya,
or hit him.
Ah, God, don't tell me.
Like you said, Wyatt,
we're brothers.
Gotta back your brother's play.
Just did like
I figured you would.
All right, now,
you listen to me.
Both of you.
For the first time
in our lives...
we've got a chance
to stop wandering...
and finally be a family.
Now this is trouble
we don't need.
You saw what happened
to Fred White.
We know what we're doing, Wyatt.
Fine. Say you're right.
Say you don't get
yourself killed.
There's something else.
All those years
I worked those cow towns...
I was only ever mixed up
in one shooting.
Just one.
But a man lost his life,
and I took it.
You don't know how
that feels, Morgan.
Believe me, boy,
you don't ever want to know.
Not ever.
Didn't even make a dent,
did I?
[Gun belt jingles]
All right.
You're both making
a big mistake.
[Door closes]
[Singing] The sunshine
That brightened
the pathway awhile
Come and sit by my side
If you love me
Do not hasten
to bid me adieu
But remember
the Red River Valley
And the girl
who has loved you so true
What do you think
of the singer?
Won't you think
of the valley...
Nice voice.
Wyatt.
Doc won't quit.
He's been at it
for 36 hours straight.
Clanton and the McLaury brothers
came in an hour ago.
I tried to get him
to go to bed...
but he won't let go.
I know.
And nobody can make him.
[Coughs]
Wyatt, just in time.
Pull up a chair.
Doc.
Been hittin' it awful hard,
haven't you?
[Slurring] Nonsense.
I've not yet begun
to defile myself.
I was wonderin' if maybe
you wouldn't want to go...
I will not be pawed at,
thank you very much.
That's right.
Doc can go on day and night
and then some.
[Spits]
That's my loving man.
Have another one,
my loving man.
I'm in.
Hey. Loving man.
You've been called.
Oops.
What is that, now?
That 12 hands in a row,
Holliday?
Son of a bitch,
nobody's that lucky.
[Money rustles]
Why, lke, whatever do you mean?
Take it easy, boys.
Maybe poker's
just not your game, lke.
I know.
Let's have a spelling contest.
How 'bout if I just wring
your scrawny neck?
- Uh-uh-uh.
- Enough, lke.
Are you takin' his part?
Huh?
I'm the one got cheated!
You goddamn pimps!
You're all in it together.
Nobody's in anything, lke.
You're drunk.
Go on home and sleep it off.
Get your goddamn hands off me!
Don't you ever put
your hands on me, see?
Don't you ever try
to manhandle a cowboy...
'cause we'll cut
your goddamn pimp's heart out.
You understand me, you pimp?
Don't you threaten me,
you little son of a bitch.
WYATT:
All right, all right.
Come on, easy, Virg. Easy.
You just go on home
and forget about it, lke.
I ain't gonna forget nothin'.
DOC: Well,
that certainly was a bust.
Come, darlin'.
Let's seek
our entertainment elsewhere.
WYATT: Forget it, Virg.
Go on, get some fresh air.
[Doc coughing]
[Coughing]
What's wrong, Doc?
Nothin'. Not a thing.
I'm right as the mail.
WYATT: Doc? Doc!
All right, get him up.
Let's get him to the hotel.
What's wrong with him?
MILT: Lunger.
Well, I hope you die.
Gimme my guns.
My rifle.
Goddamn bastards.
Think they can cheat me.
Nobody cheated you, lke.
Just go home.
Don't take no mouth
from no bartenders, neither.
There, you see?
Give somebody
a rap on the beard...
get some respect around here.
You tell the Earps...
I see 'em on the street,
and Doc Holliday...
I'm gonna send them
to Hell on a shutter.
You tell 'em that... Unh!
Pick these guns up.
Come on.
[Crickets chirping]
[Horse whinnies]
[Sighs]
[Glass rattles]
All right, Mattie.
What about this?
I need it.
At least you admit it.
Admit what?
Admit what, Wyatt?
I'm an opium fiend?
No, no,
I just said I needed it.
I need something
to keep me warm at night...
All right. I know...
You know nothing.
[Ragged breathing]
I see you smile
sometimes, Wyatt.
I even see you laugh,
but there's no light...
in your smile for me, Wyatt,
and I get so cold.
[Sobbing]
Oh... no...
What's between you
and that woman?
All right.
Mattie... Mattie...
- No! No!
- I promise you, l...
- No!
- I can make this right.
- I swear I can.
Will you go to her...
and tell her,
right in front of me...
right out loud
so I can hear you...
tell her she's nothing?
Tell her she's nobody,
she's just dirt!
Will you do that?
[Sobbing]
[Ragged breathing]
Now just... leave me alone.
[Sobbing]
[Keys jangle]
Come on, lke.
Come on!
Lke, can you walk?
- Give lke back his guns.
- Not till he sobers up.
Wearin' that badge
don't make you right.
Who the hell you think you are?
Watch where you walk,
you stupid bastard.
Easy, kid. I'm sorry.
I ain't easy
and I ain't your kid.
You take sorry
and shove it up your ass.
I'll fight you right now.
God damn it.
You're gonna bleed.
You got a fight comin'.
Comin' today.
Bastards. It's comin'!
Your condition's quite advanced.
I'd say you lost 60% of
your lung tissue, maybe more.
What's the verdict?
Two years, two days,
hard to say...
if you stop now.
Your smokin', your drinkin'...
your gamblin', your nightlife.
You need complete rest.
What I mean is,
you must attempt...
to deny your, uh,
marital impulse.
DOC: Get out of my sight.
How are you feeling, Doc?
Mm, better.
That's good.
I knew it wasn't nothing.
We must talk, darlin'.
It appears, uh,
we must redefine...
the nature of our association.
I'm a good woman to you, Doc.
Don't I always take care of you?
Nobody cares for you like me.
I'm a good woman.
Yes, it's true...
you are a good woman.
[Sighs] Then again...
you may be the Antichrist.
MORGAN: God damn.
There's six of 'em.
Man, this is
like a bad dream.
Just stay calm, use your head.
It'll be all right.
Just the same, though...
guess maybe you better
swear me in.
[Footsteps]
Those cowboys been telling
everybody in town...
they're gonna clean you out.
They're back there
in that lot...
behind the O.K. Corral.
Thank you, Mayor.
MORGAN: What are you doin'
out of bed, Doc?
DOC:
What the hell's going on?
Had five people
come up to my room...
tellin' me the Clantons
and McLaurys...
are gunnin' for us.
MORGAN:
We goin' down there or not?
What are we gonna do?
WYATT:
Wait'll the liquor wears off.
Soon as they start
gettin' headaches...
they'll lose interest.
Lose interest, hell!
They're threatenin' our lives.
You'll never make that stick.
They're carryin' guns, Wyatt.
For Christ's sake, Virg,
that's a misdemeanor.
You go down there
and arrest 'em...
something goes wrong,
maybe this time...
somebody really
gets his head broke.
You'll have cowboys
comin' around...
Iookin' for trouble
from here to Christmas.
You wanna risk all that
over a misdemeanor?
You're damn right
I'll risk it.
They're breakin' the law.
It's not your problem, Doc.
You don't have
to mix up in this.
That is a hell of a thing
for you to say to me.
All right, Virg.
Your call.
Give Doc the shotgun.
He'll be less apt
to get nervy...
if he's on the street howitzer.
BOY: Bang, bang, bang!
MORGAN: Go on, get home!
Goddamn kid.
[Whistling]
How the hell did we
get ourselves into this?
You don't have to worry
about a thing.
I just went over there
and disarmed 'em.
VIRGIL: You did?
Come on, let's go arrest 'em.
BEHAN: Gentlemen,
I won't allow any trouble.
We're here to disarm you.
Throw up your hands.
VIRGIL: Hold!
That's not what I want.
Oh, my God.
Billy! Billy!
[Whinnies]
IKE: Stop! Don't!
Don't! Don't shoot!
I got no gun! Please!
Don't shoot me!
I got no gun!
This fight's commenced.
Get to fightin' or get away!
Uhh!
Shut the door!
Aah!
Gimme your gun!
- All right!
- Damn it!
Billy!
Watch behind us!
[Cocks gun]
[Click]
I got you now,
you son of a bitch.
You're a daisy if you do.
Uhh!
WYATT: Morgan, hold quiet now.
[Talking indistinctly]
WYATT: Easy. I got you.
All right.
BEHAN: All right!
All of you are under arrest.
I don't think I'll let you
arrest us today, Behan.
Virg!
Virgil!
I guess we did our good deed
for today, Mayor.
MORGAN: You were right.
It's nothin' like I thought.
- I almost wish...
- I know, Morg.
I know. Me, too.
[Bell ringing]
[Horse galloping]
MAN: Get out of the way!
Yee-haw!
Gettin' warmer.
Guess spring's coming.
MORGAN: Hello, Billy.
It's "Deputy,"
and I don't want to talk to you.
Those men you killed
were my friends.
I'm just a nothin',
but if I wasn't...
I'd fight you right now.
All they ever did
was laugh at him.
[Clank]
Sister boy
should've stuck around.
What do you want, Ringo?
I want your blood...
I want your souls...
and I want 'em both right now.
I don't want
any more trouble...
Well, you got trouble!
And it starts with you.
Not gonna fight you, Ringo.
There's no money in it.
Sober up. Come on, boys.
RINGO: Wretched slugs.
Don't you have the guts
to play for blood?
DOC: I'm your huckleberry.
That's just my game.
All right, lunger.
You go to hell.
I'll put you out of your misery.
Say when.
Johnny, don't!
MAN: Whoa, whoa, whoa!
RINGO: Get off!
- Easy!
- Get off!
Don't mind him.
He just drunk, that's all.
Ha ha ha ha.
MAN: Cool down, Johnny.
No!
I want them spittin' blood!
Easy, son, easy.
Now ain't the time!
Slow down, Ringo.
I tell you, even I'm worried
what's gonna happen...
once Ringo runs this outfit.
God have mercy!
DOC: Gentlemen.
- Barber...
- Yes, sir?
Proceed, sir.
[Thunder]
Listen to me.
I need to speak with you.
Not now. I'm busy.
I see what's going on
between you and Wyatt.
I'm not a fool.
Listen to me.
Lots of so-called
hard cases and tough nuts...
come and go
around this town...
but none of them has a clue
about the real play.
None of them.
Now after tonight,
there'll be...
one man in charge
of Tombstone.
You'll be happy to know him.
Bet on it.
[Thunder]
Be one of those nights.
It's gettin' late, boys.
I'm gonna go to bed.
Night, Virg.
Good night, boys.
Bundle up, Virg.
Gettin' cold out there.
Yep.
[Thunder]
[Horse whinnies]
Tower of Babel, Death...
and the Devil. Oh, dear.
Allie, I wish you'd learn
to play a real card game.
[Thunder]
- More tea, Mattie?
- No, no.
- Are you all right, Mattie?
- Yes.
- You expecting someone?
- Only Virg.
[Knocking]
Uhh.
JOSEPHINE: Please.
I know it's awful
to come here, but listen.
I think something's
going to happen tonight.
It's Virg.
No! Get down!
[Woman screams]
[Thunder]
[Whining]
That thunder's
sure getting close.
[Door opens]
[Door closes]
Virgil.
What'd you forget?
VIRGIL: Wyatt...
[Dog barking]
[Thunder]
DOCTOR: Will you hurry
with that water, please?
Come on, Lou.
VIRGIL: Uhh!
MORGAN: Wyatt. Wyatt!
They hit Clum's house, too.
Shot up his wife!
Whoever heard of that?
They're bugs, Wyatt.
All that smart talk
about live and let live.
There ain't no live
and let live with bugs.
You listen to me now.
We gotta get out of here.
Get out of here?
Listen to yourself, Wyatt.
Lie down and crawl,
or you might get hurt?
What kind of talk is that?
Do you see
what's happening here?
What do you mean?
What are you saying?
[Grunts]
ALLIE: No. Please, no.
DOCTOR:
I'm afraid your husband...
is going to lose
the use of his arm.
Oh, God, no.
Uhh...
Don't worry, Allie girl.
I still got one good arm
to hold you with.
MORGAN: Goddamn.
Goddamn son of a bitch!
Morgan, wait a minute!
Virg...
ALLIE:
You had to be so damn smart.
I'm sorry, Allie.
I told you, Virg.
Not now, Wyatt.
All right,
what do you want me to do?
Just leave me alone,
for God's sake.
Virg...
He doesn't want
to talk now, Wyatt!
[Virgil groans]
[Thunder]
I heard about your women.
That was wrong.
I'm here to let you know
that it wasn't me.
I had no part of it.
No?
Brothers to the bone,
right, McMasters?
No. Not anymore.
Not after this night.
He's right, Wyatt.
You want us for anything,
we're with you.
Come on.
[Thunder]
[Gunshot]
Uhh! Uhh!
Uhh!
[Barking]
DOCTOR: Hold him.
[Louisa screaming]
No, get her out
of here! Jesus!
Somebody shut that dog up!
MORGAN: Uhh!
Aah!
I said hold him,
god damn it!
Somebody get that goddamn dog
out of here!
DOCTOR:
The bullet's too deep.
I can't get it out.
[Panting]
DOCTOR: The way
it's lodged in the back...
I'm sorry.
WYATT: Easy, Morg.
Is that better?
[Gasping] Yeah.
You were right, Wyatt.
They got me good.
Don't let 'em get you, brother.
You're the one.
WYATT: Easy, Morg.
[Lnhales]
Don't worry about that now.
Remember what I said...
about seein' a light
when you're dyin'?
WYATT: Yeah.
Yeah.
It ain't true.
I can't see a damn thing.
WYATT: Morg?
Morg?
[Sobbing]
LOUISA: No!
[Louisa screaming]
LOUISA:
I love you! Oh, God!
Why?
Why him?
[Sobbing]
No! Get away from me!
Wyatt!
Can't you see?
Get away from me!
[Crying]
[Thunder]
Morgan!
"Weave a circle
'round him thrice..."
"Close your eyes
with holy dread..."
"For he on honey-dew
hath fed..."
"And drunk the milk...
"of paradise."
[Thunder]
[Sighs]
[Flies buzzing]
[Buzzing stops]
[Buzzing]
[Woman crying]
And so she walked out
of our lives forever.
[Snaps reins]
Get up.
I want you to know it's over.
Well...
Bye.
RINGO: You smell that, Bill?
Smells like someone died.
[Spits]
Jesus, Johnny.
There, get!
[Chuckling] Adios.
Ike.
Take Stillwell and finish it.
[Dog barking]
KATE: It's Wyatt, isn't it?
It's always Wyatt.
Why? Why is he so much?
Kate, try to understand.
The man's given up everything
to do what he must.
Now, if I call myself
his friend, then...
Oh, never mind.
[Coughing]
I don't understand.
I'm your woman.
You get killed...
where's it leave me?
Without a meal ticket,
I suppose.
You bastard.
I'm leavin' now, darlin'.
You bastard, Doc!
Have you no kind word
to say to me...
before I ride away?
[Sighs]
[Coughs] I calculate not.
Doc!
[Lndistinct conversation]
MAN: Now, you take care
of yourself, Martin.
That's Virgil with the women.
He's mine.
CONDUCTOR: All aboard!
Hey, Mattie.
Where's Wyatt?
WYATT:
Right behind you, Stillwell.
All right, Clanton.
You called down the thunder.
Well, now you got it.
You see that?
It says
"United States Marshal."
Wyatt, please don't kill me.
Please. Please!
Take a good look at him, lke...
'cause that's how
you're gonna end up.
The cowboys are finished.
Do you understand me?
I see a red sash,
I kill the man wearin' it.
So run, you cur.
Run!
Tell all the other curs
the law's comin'!
You tell 'em I'm comin'...
and Hell's comin' with me,
you hear?
Hell's comin' with me!
[Horse whinnies]
Nobody move.
DOC: Nonsense.
By all means, move.
Uhh!
[Gunshot]
Get down!
CURLY BILL: Ha ha ha ha!
Hey, Wyatt!
How the hell are you?
Ha ha ha ha!
RINGO: Ha ha ha ha!
Oh!
RINGO: Whoo! Whoo!
Got some boys
over there behind you.
Got you in
a little crossfire.
How do you like that?
Ha ha ha ha!
Come on!
Think of something fast!
Wyatt.
[Coughs] Hey, Wyatt.
No.
SHERMAN: Wyatt!
MAN: Wyatt,
what are you doin'?
Look at that.
Yeah.
Come on and get some, boy.
[Gunshots]
No! Let me!
[Click] God!
WYATT: No.
Son of a bitch.
No!
Aah! Aah!
BARNES: Jesus Christ!
Aah!
No.
No!
Did you ever see
anything like that before?
Hell, I ain't never heard
of anything like that.
Nothin'.
Where is he?
Down by the creek,
walkin' on water.
Let's hope he's got
another miracle up his sleeve.
If I know Ringo,
he's headed straight for us.
If they were my brothers,
I'd want revenge, too.
No, make no mistake...
it's not revenge he's after.
It's a reckoning.
[Coughing]
Doc, you ought to be in bed.
What the hell are you
doing this for, anyway?
Wyatt Earp is my friend.
Hell, I got lots of friends.
I don't.
DRIVER: Ho! Ho!
My God.
Are you all right?
What do you care?
It's your friends that did it.
IKE: Must've been
Claiborne and Fuller.
They left here last night.
Oh, no.
JOSEPHINE:
They tried to take my watch.
He cursed them for cowards
and they shot him.
I don't understand any of this.
I just know it's ugly.
You're all ugly,
and he was beautiful.
JOSEPHINE: He tried
to bring something fine...
into your ugly world,
and you shot him for it.
Not that you care.
Billy.
Where are you going?
BILLY: I'm not going with you.
Billy!
Billy, get back here!
I'm sorry, sir,
but we got to have some law.
- Billy!
- Yah!
RINGO:
Let him go. Who cares?
Go on!
Get the hell out of here!
The party's over, boys.
Let's go!
Hold.
[Click]
Ringo and Behan are out front.
There's about 30 of 'em.
They're all wearin' badges.
[Coughs]
Christ.
[Doc coughing]
Well, we gotta find
a place to hole up.
WYATT: Doc.
Grab him!
I got it.
WYATT:
Is this Henry Hooker's ranch?
MAN: That's right.
And I'm Hooker.
WYATT: We got a sick man.
Our horses are done in.
Put him up at my place.
As long as it's just tonight.
We're in debt to you.
[Coughing and shivering]
HOOKER: I know you boys
have gotta keep moving...
but he looks pretty bad to me.
[Distantly]
MAN: Ho!
I, uh...
They got held up...
and their boss actor
got killed.
They came here
to water the horses...
then they'll push on.
I'm sorry about your friend.
And I'm sorry that l...
I forgave you
the moment you said it.
You did?
Well... thank you.
DRIVER: All set.
I have to go.
Wait.
DRIVER: Huh!
[Whip cracks]
Get up! [Whistles]
Yah! Come on!
Yah!
Well, look who's back.
The prodigal returns.
Hello, Sherm.
You wanted to talk?
Yeah. Kind of.
Wanted to see if
you'd join back up with us.
That's what
you got me up here for?
You're a cowboy,
not a dog catcher.
Come back.
No hard feelin's.
Isn't there anything
I can say...
to make you
change your mind?
You're gonna stick
with your new friends.
Least they don't
go around scarin' women.
You're the boss.
Hey.
Sherm.
Just one thing.
[Cocks gun]
How you gonna get back to 'em?
What the hell is that?
They got McMasters!
[Coughing] Jeez!
Ringo wanted
to make sure...
he got your attention,
Marshal!
He wants a straight-up fight,
just you and him.
Settle this thing
once and for all.
Oak grove at the mouth
of Silver Springs canyon...
seven o'clock!
You tell him I'll be there!
Are you crazy?
I'll be there!
It's not finished.
[Thunder]
[Hoofbeats]
After I'm done
with Wyatt Earp...
take your cowboys
and finish off...
Creek Johnson and Texas Jack.
[Thunder]
You burn 'em, lke.
Burn 'em all.
Hell, Johnny...
he ain't even gonna show.
Hee-aw!
He'll show.
WYATT:
I spent my whole life...
not knowin' what
I wanted out of life.
Just chasin' my tail.
Now, for the first time...
I know exactly
what I want... and who.
And that's
the damnable misery of it.
What makes a man like Ringo?
What makes him
do the things he does?
A man like Ringo
got a great empty hole...
right through
the middle of him.
He can never kill enough
or steal enough...
or inflict enough pain
to ever fill it.
What does he need?
Revenge.
For what?
Bein' born.
It all happened so fast
with Curly Bill...
I didn't really have time
to think about it...
but I've had plenty of time
to think about this.
I can't beat him, can I?
No.
DOC: Wait. [Coughs]
I'm going with you.
[Coughing]
Oh, God. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, Wyatt.
It's all right, Doc.
What's it like
to wear one of those?
Don't worry.
If they want him...
they gotta come over us first.
[Coughs]
He's waitin' for you
by the big oak.
Quarter mile up that trail.
They're not giving you
any safe conduct.
Shootin' starts,
you better kick east...
to the New Mexico line.
I ain't got the words.
I know.
Me neither.
Well!
I didn't think
you had it in you.
I'm your huckleberry.
Why, Johnny Ringo.
You look like somebody
just walked over your grave.
Fight's not with you, Holliday.
I'll beg to differ, sir.
We started a game
we never got to finish.
Play for blood, remember?
I was just foolin' about.
I wasn't.
And this time...
it's legal.
All right, lunger.
Let's do it.
Say when.
Come on.
Come on!
Oh, Johnny. Come on!
Uhh...
You're no daisy.
You're no daisy at all.
Poor soul.
You were just too high-strung.
[Running footsteps]
I'm afraid the strain...
was more than he could bear.
Oh, I wasn't quite as sick
as I made out.
Good God.
My hypocrisy goes only so far.
All right. Let's finish it.
Indeed, sir.
The last charge of Wyatt Earp
and his immortals.
Get on! Yah! Go on!
Go! Yah!
[Praying in Latin]
In nomine Patris...
et Filii
et Spiritus Sancti.
Amen.
[Weakly] Hello, Wyatt.
Father Feeney
and I were just...
investigating the mysteries
of the Church of Rome.
DOC: It appears...
my hypocrisy knows no bounds.
WYATT:
You're no hypocrite, Doc.
You just like to sound like one.
I brought you something.
Well, let's see.
Where are we today?
I'm $17 down to you.
Two bits a hand, stud.
You keep coming back here.
I told you not to,
and I meant it.
You're the only person...
I can afford
to lose to anymore.
[Dealing cards]
How we feelin' today, Doc?
I'm dying. How are you?
WYATT:
Pretty much the same.
So now we can add self-pity
to your list of frailties.
All right, Doc. All right.
How many cards you want?
I don't want to play anymore.
[Holliday breathes weakly]
How many?
Damn you.
You're the most fallible...
stubborn, self-deluded,
bullheaded man...
I've ever known
in my entire life.
I call.
You win.
Yet with all...
you're the only human being
in my entire life...
who ever gave me hope.
I was... in love once.
[Breathing laboredly]
With my first cousin.
She was... 15.
We were both so...
That's good, Doc.
That's good.
What happened?
She joined a convent
over the affair.
[Swallows]
She was all I ever wanted.
[Weakly]
What... what did you want?
Just to live a normal life.
There's no normal life, Wyatt.
There's just life.
You get on with it.
Don't know how.
Sure you do.
Say good-bye to me.
Go grab that spirited actress...
and make her your own.
Take that beauty and run.
Don't look back.
Live every second.
Live right up to the hilt.
Live, Wyatt.
Live for me.
Wyatt, if you
were ever my friend...
if you ever had even
the slightest feeling for me...
leave now.
Leave now.
Please.
Thanks for always
being there, Doc.
I'll be damned.
[Gasps]
This is funny.
[Bells ringing]
WOMAN: I never thought
I'd see Gilbert and Sullivan...
performed
right here in Denver.
MAN: Oh, yeah?
Good night, Josie.
Good night.
Good show.
[Men talking indistinctly]
You ever see the sun
come up over the Rockies?
It hits all of a sudden...
and below
there's California.
And you swear
you're looking at Heaven.
I have nothing left.
Nothing to give you.
I have no pride...
no dignity.
No money.
I don't even know how
I'll make a living, but...
I promise I'll love you
the rest of your life.
Don't worry, Wyatt.
My family's rich.
[Laughing]
[Sighs]
What should we do first?
What you wanted to do
the first night we met.
Remember?
Uh-uh.
May I have this dance?
Ah, ha ha.
Yes.
WYATT: And then,
we'll have room service!
NARRATOR:
The power of the Cowboy gang...
was broken forever.
Ike Clanton was shot
and killed two years later...
during an attempted robbery.
Mattie died
of a drug overdose...
shortly after
she left Tombstone.
Virgil and Allie Earp
moved to California...
where Virgil, despite
the use of only one arm...
became a town sheriff.
Wyatt and Josephine
embarked...
on a series of adventures.
Up or down, thin or flush...
in 47 years they never
left each other's side.
Wyatt Earp died
in Los Angeles in 1929.
Among the pallbearers
at his funeral...
were early
Western movie stars...
William S. Hart and Tom Mix.
Tom Mix wept.