This UNRWA notice says:
"They have stopped distribution
from Tuesday the 8th".
A week ago,
and until an unknown date.
There will only be
when the supplies are available.
You see how long now?
Since a week, and
until an unknown date.
This is due to the siege.
You have to wear this
to be visible.
OK, I'll give it to him.
Don앖 give it to him.
It is clear that he is a civilian,
but you...
Do you want to go?
For sure.
Look around,
look what's happened to this area.
So this place was all planted
with olives and palm trees?
It was all trees.
Now they have completely erased it.
Do you remember the Nakba?
Are you a local or a refugee, sir?
I am a refugee.
Where from?
>From Salama.
Where is Salama?
In Jaffa.
It was a long time ago,
my father was still alive.
In which year were you expelled, sir?
In 1948?
Yes, in 1948.
This is my place.
I have two sons.
Both of them working.
What do they do?
They farm parsley and spinach.
It's like if I give you
this piece of land to work on...
But on other peoples property,
not our property.
Are your sons married?
Yes.
May Allah protect them for you.
Thank you.
Where is your wife?
My wife is at home.
What is wrong with her?
This year she broke her hip.
Only Allah knows,
we will go there
and meet her later.
The army hit the houses
and last year they
also hit my sons house
with a shell.
They asked the baby
to cover his ears
and they made a big hole,
even bigger than this tent.
Really, they asked the baby
to cover his ears?
His mother told me that.
He dug this hole to hide in
when there's any shooting.
I go down there,
but it doesn't protect me...
The bullets whistle over my head...
If there's any shooting
he goes and climbs in there to hide,
in this hole in the ground.
My wife is over there.
How are you doing?
How is your health?
Oh, how are you cute little girl?
How are you?
I am fine.
The Israeli army
is shelling with F16's.
Maybe they have hit the tunnels.
We are living a very hard life.
We just want the
world to do something fair.
This is the situation in Gaza Strip.
Can you hear that?
It's the same every day.
Maybe this is an invasion
of the whole of the Gaza Strip.
We are normal people.
What do you think about it?
You can film it with your camera.
Can you hear it?
The surveillance plane
will see us and fire at us.
The situation is critical.
I am sure this is an invasion
of the whole of Gaza.
This is a small
example of our daily life
We have no idea of what is going on.
I think this is a complete invasion
of the whole Gaza Strip.
Go! Go!
Get him out of here!
Come on! Come this way!
It's near here! I'ts near here!
Film it, film it!
It's here!
We are in the buffer zone,
near the border.
The Israeli army began bombing.
The children are
now in terror and fear.
We live in the buffer zone
and here the
situation is very difficult.
The war has been resurrected,
and the situation is critical.
There is no food or drink,
no flour or even
milk for the children.
They are terrified,
what can we say more than this?
Planes have hit many positions.
What can we say?
Here are the carpets from the mosque,
let압 try to find Abu Jamal.
Have you found him?
No, he hasn't appeared.
Here are the carpets,
let압 try to find him.
Be careful,
don앖 come near this part.
Please, get out from there.
Don't go under the building.
Please, one or two
people should be there,
not all of you.
Quickly, quickly!
Only one or two.
Abu Jamal!
His cellphone is ringing!
Listen, listen!
His phone is here.
The sound is here, here!
Listen, listen, please!
Don앖 speak, listen!
There are gas bottles over there.
Brothers,
please, don't make me
have to give an order
and get all of you out!
May Allah burn
Israel and all the Jews
in the fire of hell!
Do you see the blood of the martyrs?
Do you see our blood?
How many casualties?
At least ten.
All around!
Everywhere!
May Allah curse the Jews
and those who
established their state.
Britain and America,
and the Arab world
that is just watching.
They should be hit with an old shoe
like Bush was in Iraq.
They deserve it, the Jews, the dogs!
Move!  Get out of here!
There are planes in the air!
Tell him to be ready and
focus the camera on the gate.
Be ready to be at the
gate when they come in.
Bring the stretchers!
Run, run! For the sake of Allah!
May Allah bring you another daughter!
It's God's will,
she will be in heaven.
God is our only
saviour and protector.
You can film more.
He's just a child.
He is only eleven years old.
What is his name? Saeid?
No, no, Ismael.
Ismael Hamdan.
You can film more here.
You can come.
There is nothing more we can do.
She's dead.
Bring me the nasal tube.
Insert the nasal tube
and clean her nose
Is there any pulse?
May Allah surround
her soul with mercy.
Bring me the tape to write her name.
That's all. It's over.
Cover her.
These two girls were just
to take the rubbish
out from their house
and the plane bombed,
them and their brother
The sticky tape.
What is her name?
Something Hamdan.
The other one is
Haya and this is Lama.
A pen? A pen?
Here.
Lama what?
Lama Talal Hamdan.
A pepper?  I'm doing a interview!
You cannot have white beans
without green chilli peppers.
This one's dirty, pass me another one.
Thanks.
I like peppers a lot.
Don't get pepper in your eyes...
The pepper,
don't get it in your eyes.
OK, thanks.
There is a ten metre
deep hole from an F-16.
We cannot take patients,
they're bombing all over,
we can't,
we cannot even reach the injured.
The Jews can't defeat the resistance,
so they take revenge on the civilians.
In Jabalia they are
attacking heavily, very heavily.
What we know for sure is that
they are attacking with tanks.
They are attacking simultaneously
from the sea, with
helicopters, with F-16's.
And the confirmed news is
that they are also using tanks.
It's like lighting it all up
so they can see everything.
What are you saying?
That it's for lighting up?
Don앖 talk nonsense!
A light comes down
slowly on a parachute.
and it burns.
It is something that burns.
Sorry, let's continue.
In December no food entered. Full stop.
What is the meaning of giving bread
to those who've just been
freshly baked in a cemetery
question mark.
the urgency lies in
stopping the bombs,
even before replacing supplies
full stop.
Dead bodies can't eat...
comma,
they just fertilize the land
that here in Gaza,
has never been so fertile,
full stop.
Children's corpses...
...in the morgue of the hospital
should feed the
feelings of guiltiness...
...of those who could
do something, comma,
but they are on holiday in Hawaii,
having fun with friends, full stop.
The image of a smiling Obama
playing golf,
has been broadcast
on all the Arab satellite channels
comma,
but don't worry,
nobody here believed
that a president압 skin colour...
...would radically change
US foreign policy,
full stop.
Yesterday, Israel
opened the Eretz crossing
to evacuate all
foreign nationals from Gaza,
comma,
We,
internationals of the ISM,
comma,
are the only ones remaining,
full stop.
My back is killing me...
Isn't there a proper pan?
Is this a pan for boiling?
This is for coffee.
When it is crowded here
we have to use it to make coffee.
Resistance,
resistance...
How many spoons will you add?
Listen, this needs at
least 10 more spoonfuls.
I will put three.
Three?  What's wrong with you?
In the small pan,
we do it with three spoons.
Add another two, add much more.
OK, I put four and a half.
Come on, put more,
I don앖 want weak coffee.
The smell is great.
They are shelling randomly.
It sounds like
it's getting really close.
We are evaluating the situation.
Do you think that they can see us?
They are shelling homes in
the west of Ezbet Abd Rabbo.
If you want to come,
come, but be careful.
Take a good look
when you reach Jabalia.
It is OK, come.
I wish you luck.
Can you hear?
It is all around us.
May Allah end it well.
We can't go out.
They are bombing out there.
I don't even have an
ambulance here right now.
If we had one we would escape.
We don't have ambulances,
the centre is surrounded.
The bombs are falling all around.
OK, I will see. My regards, bye.
Vik is not here.
I think he left with
one of the ambulances.
Did you forget anything?
Cellphones or anything?
Should we bring all the equipment?
Did you check the power switches?
The phone that I gave you?
Yes, it's here.
The whole area,
Abu Rame's house is on fire,
the whole area, listen to me...
OK, we will see,
May Allah end it well.
The situation is all ablaze.
They hit four of our
ambulances with F-16's.
When the resistance shoots a bullet
they answer with one million missiles.
A three year old boy
was killed in the last attack.
>From the Al Kourd family.
There are no injuries,
only martyrs in Al Attatra
but they won't allow
us to reach that far.
We went three times with coordination,
and they shot at us.
The first time with a tank
the second time with an F-16,
then again with a tank
so we could not bring them out.
I will be at home in half an hour
if it is Allah's will.
It's not known if
there are more martyrs.
Maximum one hour and I will be home.
Do you want me to
bring something home?
I am trying to call him
but he is not answering.
I am calling the hospital,
but no one is answering.
The communications have been cut.
Please,
don't film this!
Guys, there are surveillance planes!
Hi? Listen!
A bomb has just fallen
on the Al Awda hospital.
There was a Jeep and they bombed it.
A bomb came down
in the courtyard of the hospital.
Around ten metres
away from where we are,
there are injuries.
No, no, I'm OK.
Fuck! Sorry, sorry, bye.
The guys are over there.
Stand up, Jamal.
Shrapnel has hit his face,
let압 take him to this corner.
Stay where you are!
Where are you going?
Move them like that,
move them over to there,
there may be flying shrapnel hitting.
Hi? Who am I talking to, please?
Listen to me: two bombs
have just hit the hospital.
I have it live on film
now they are
getting rid of the oxygen
because it could explode.
They're directly attacking a hospital,
do you understand? I've recorded it,
some of the paramedics are injured.
No, but shit!
I don't know what to say,
but please report this, please.
Hospital Al Awda, a-l-a-w-d-a!
In Jabalia refugee camp.
Two missiles have just come down
in the courtyard of the hospital.
Abu Jahy, get out of
the square! Get over here!
They have launched two rockets there.
In Al Awda?
Did they hit Al Awda?
Yes, the Palestinian authority Jeep.
But it's a hospital!
Fuck them!
They have no honour.
Two rockets. three injured.
Hi Youssef, where are you?
I am at the hospital.
These cellphones...
Who do they belong to?
Yes, we are at the hospital
We can앖 get in or out
and we are waiting
for them to hit again.
They meant to target the hospital.
But they hit the Jeep.
They can justify it by
saying it was a military vehicle.
They can strike if a rocket
was launched from here.
But they can't strike
without justification.
What is that building close to here?
It is the medicine warehouse.
Maybe somebody will go
there to get the medicine?
If someone does he'll
be walking to his death.
Will you keep on going?
Yes, but every time.
I go out I lose two kilos.
I know I will be killed.
I swear to God, I swear to God...
What can we do?
Nothing.
I think it's what, one
hundred and fifty metres from here?
Less.
So what did your wife say?
She said: "I know you'll get killed".
Last night we were
talking about Arafa,
who was killed yesterday.
She knows I am going to be killed.
She says she is
prepared for my death.
And my kids, I only see
them for 5 or 10 minutes,
and the hour I went home
yesterday they were sleeping.
I couldn't see if they need anything.
They have no food or gas,
the water will run out soon.
They only have Allah.
They've already got used
to the idea of my death,
even my children.
When I go home,
they refuse to leave me.
They tell me: "don't go out daddy",
as all children do.
They understand the situation.
The children talk
about my friend who died,
they say: "Poor man".
And I explain to them
that all of us will die.
The problem is that no one cares.
The Jews think
that extensive shelling
and attacking us like this
will bring the people down.
On the contrary,
it only encourages people.
We would say:
"I am dead anyway, why die in vane"?
"I will launch a rocket
blow myself up against them
instead of dying in my home".
It is better to die fighting them.
So people are getting more mobilised.
Sir, why are you
recording us on tape?
Why are you filming, sir?
We need two more ambulances.
I will get two more.
Who belongs to the third crew?
Who is there with you?
Where is he?
He's sleeping, write down his name.
Do you remember your
vehicle's plate number?
Write it: Fayez al Ajramy.
And the medic, Mohammad Salah.
Do you have their ID numbers?
I'll give you the
number of their ambulance.
6-6915-90
Do you want a fourth
crew or is that enough?
A fourth crew.
Naim, you will drive.
Naim Rajab Khalil.
Where are we going while
all this shooting is going on?
Do you want to go, Youssef?
Youssef Abd El Hameid.
The boss, he's the boss!
Give me the number of the ambulance.
3-99...31.
Bye, goodbye.
Go in peace.
Naim, let압 go!  Naim!
Stay behind each other!
Abed, you have my phone number, bye!
Forgive us!
Tell Al Ajrami to turn his siren on!
There is a martyr
near the traffic lights!
Where can the ambulances get to?
He's there, lying on the ground!
We want to rescue the
corpse but they shoot at us!
So we cannot reach it.
We managed to drag
the body to the roundabout.
He's dead.
We dragged him and they shot at us.
There, there, they're over there!
Go back both of you, get back!
They will shoot at us! Get back!
Go and get yourselves killed!
Don앖 leave the vehicle! Stay inside!
Keep your camera inside!
Bastards!
It is only a bullet. Only a bullet.
I have a bullet in my leg.
Do you want to lay on the stretcher?
Relax, relax.
I'm fine Youseff, I'm fine.
It's nothing.
Don't worry man, it's OK.
We were carrying the body.
When they opened fire on us.
So we left the body
behind with the stretcher.
Is your other leg OK?
Yes, it's OK.
Call Dr. Bashar and
tell him it's a minor injury.
Go to Al Awda Hospital.
Is your head OK?
Yes.
Don't worry Abu Ali, it's OK.
Dear Abu Ali!
Hi, how are you?
What happened?
It's OK, thanks to God.
We went to rescue a martyr
near Zimmo, and they shot at us.
Were you outside the vehicle?
Yes, with my colleague.
Where is the sniper?
Take care.
He's over there in one of the houses.
They opened fire on us
and last night
they completely destroyed us.
Where do you live exactly?
Behind the mosque,
they destroyed the house,
so now we are leaving,
we are evacuating to a UN school.
There is nothing left,
we can't even find a sack of flour
or anything.
Were you here yesterday
when they shelled with phosphorus?
Yes, with phosphorus.
There is a house there
which we can't reach
because of the snipers.
We cannot take you there.
There are unexploded
shells inside the houses.
Can you describe
to me the phosphorus?
This thing burns the clothes
of every human being.
When you try to get rid of it,
you can't.
If you breathe it, you will faint.
So, how can you get rid of it?
No, you can't get it off you,
you have to put
sand over your clothes.
and we don't even have
water in our houses...
I am leaving, peace be upon you.
How many people are leaving?
Our whole neighbourhood is leaving!
How far did the army reach?
Netzarim and around.
There are only 300
metres between us and them.
Are there snipers?
It's all tanks and snipers.
Special forces and planes,
even the mosque was hit.
Everyday it is like this.
We take our children out
when they say there
is a truce for eating.
We are staying at
other family's houses,
we don't know what to do.
Allah is our only saviour.
When we find a car, we'll leave.
In the house we are staying
there are 50 people
and it's 100 square metres or less.
We can't sleep
because of the
bombing and the planes
they fall on top of us.
Our houses are full of holes.
Do you see the mosque?
Our houses are like that.
Madam, I don't know what to say.
Only Allah can protect us.
He's the only one taking care of us.
At any moment we could be killed.
We are waiting to die.
When we walk, eat or drink,
we are waiting for death.
We don't want
anything else from this life.
Only to die and rest in peace.
Could you speak one at the time?
So this is this phosphorus thing?
Yes, Yes.
When you move it,
it sets on fire again.
It'll ignite if we move it?
Get back to make
space for the cameraman!
See the writing, see the writing.
This is illegal according to
international regulations.
Phosphorous, can you see?
Don't touch it with your hands,
it will burn you.
Where did this hit?
Here, in this house.
These are burnt parts from the house.
Could you please put it
in the back of the car?
Can you see the
ceiling of the house?
So this is the
missile that hit the roof.
How many days has it been like this?
Three days now.
Pour some water, please.
Pour a little bit more water.
You see, do it again.
Thank you so much
may Allah reward you.
Pardon me, but there's
no gas to make you any food.
Thank you very much, really.
We haven't had water
for almost 14 days now.
Wash your hands two or three times.
These are very toxic materials.
Slaughterhouse, an Israeli butchery.
How much blood does Israel need
to stop this?
You are good at
nothing but making tapes.
Act for us!
Are you escaping
from the occupying forces?
The occupation has destroyed us!
We are escaping from our houses.
They destroy us with shells, missiles
and planes, they are killing us.
Have mercy on us, you foreigners!
Have you had to leave your homes?
We already left.
We have taken refuge in a school.
We are going back home
to take a shower and
to change our clothes.
Can we follow you?
Of course.
Were there any injured?
Here a boy was killed.
His name was Adam Maamoun Al Kourd.
How old was he?
He was three years old.
This was my brother's house,
two floors with four flats.
And this one is my house.
These are some of the
remains from the other house.
Welcome.
Are there any old people at the
school who lived the first Nakba?
Yes, many.
What do they think about being forced
to evacuate for the second time?
Does it bring back memories?
Yes, for sure.
At the school we speak about it.
They used to tell us about it
and now we are living it.
But this Nakba is much
harder than the first one.
In the first Nakba they were
not destroying the people this way.
Now shells are
falling on people's heads.
May Allah provide you with patience.
I don't really know
what more I can say.
May Allah give you health
to see her grow to become a bride.
Sir, I understand, listen to me.
She understands me too.
They are doing their best,
telling the world what is going on...
That people were sheltering...
Allah is the greatest.
He who thanks Allah will be rewarded.
Oh Allah, loosen your power
and strength on the Jews.
Amen.
Please Allah,
kill them all...
And don't leave any of them alive.
Amen.
Oh Allah, with your great power.
Allah!
We are asking you with
your infinite power, dear Allah.
Allah!
Please dear Allah,
take revenge
for our martyrs blood.
Allah!
Please Allah, get rid of the Jews.
Bring them down.
They are not as powerful as you.
Please Allah, make the earth shake
and destroy the
pillars of their civilization.
Please Allah,
cast fear and
terror into their hearts.
Oh Allah, disperse them
so they become lost once again.
Oh Allah, show us a sign.
Oh Allah, surprise them
in a way they don't expect.
Oh Allah, cast fear and
terror into their hearts.
Oh Allah.
Bring the flags, not the poles.
No stay here.
The snipers are operating in a square,
one where they can see clearly.
No, don앖 film me.
Go, straight on.
Is that a tank in that hole over there?
Are we going to stop to film a tank?
Are you crazy?
Turn off near that street,
the Islamic University is there.
Keep going and don't stop at all.
We don't want to see
if there's a tank or not.
The tank will
directly target us and kill us.
They don't wait.
Keep going straight on, go, go!
Can you see that bulldozer there?
The one from the UN.
The wood is going to burn!
The warehouse is full!
Is there anyone inside?
We don't know...
They started to shoot
from planes and from the sea.
These are phosphorous bombs.
This is the warehouse.
Spare parts and medicine.
What is burning here is
all our medicine and flour.
This is a huge mistake!
An horrific mistake!
This is a crime!
Is that flour over there?
Yes, flour, medicine...
Everything!
Not only flour. Also blankets!
This is the aid we received
from the international community.
Everything we had.
It's gone, it's finished.
This is the central warehouse which
distributes to the whole Gaza Strip.
>From Beit Hanoun to Rafah!
This is the centre!
How many people
does this warehouse feed?
A million!
The whole population!
What about you?
Are you filming me? Why?