My name's André...
André Moussah.
I'm 28, single and an American citizen.
Paris is a spectacular city,
but I'm too busy to make the most of it.
I also do business in Argentina, Chile,
a little in China...
Not much in the U.S., in fact,
but I love to chill in my apartment
overlooking Central Park.
Back to Paris.
I've made a lot of friends here.
I expected the French to be more hostile
about Iraq and all that,
but not at all.
Maybe it's down to me
being such a cute, fun-loving kind of guy,
who's pretty hot in bed.
So, yeah, I'm doing good.
I can honestly say, without bragging,
I'm a good guy.
That's about all I can tell you about me,
my ambitions and dreams...
Because I lie to myself
and the whole world, all day long!
You piece of Yankee shit!
You think we'd buy that crap?
I'm not American.
I won my green card in the lottery.
I'm from Morocco originally.
I don't like Arabs either!
Stop hitting me!
You got it wrong, I can explain.
10 seconds.
If not, I'd have paid it back ages ago.
You haven't got a cash card?
If I did, I'd be at the bank. There. Now.
Shut it!
Keep it shut.
When you open it, you piss me off more.
You don't get it.
Not even "okay." You shut it 100%.
You understand 100%?
Not a single word. Breathe, that's all.
That's good.
Must be hard for a Yank
to keep his trap shut!
Always preaching!
Not a word. Quiet!
Listen carefully to what I have to say.
You remember Mr. Mamoud?
You owe him money.
€40,000!
Not your stinking dollars, euros.
You pay up tonight
or I come looking for you,
and break your fingers.
If that doesn't work, your arms.
Then your legs...
Then your head...
I know that song, I...
You have till tonight.
That's till midnight. Then, it's tomorrow
and tomorrow, you're dead!
See you later.
Race you to the car!
Two things were suddenly crystal clear.
I really had to change my life.
And I definitely hated Paris!
Monsieur Frank.
Please!
I don't get you, André.
I treat you good, I introduce you to people,
I lend you money,
and what do I get in return?
- I can explain...
- Nothing. Not even a call.
And now you drag me up here?
Do I look like a tourist?
No, you're not a tourist.
Let me explain.
I'm listening.
If he'd pull me up, it'd be easier to talk.
I can hear you fine from here.
Spit it out.
I lost everything, passport, credit cards...
- I went to Amex and...
- Drop him!
Please, don't drop me!
Please, Monsieur Frank!
There's more?
Tonight! I'll pay tonight!
On my mother's life!
I don't know her!
On anybody else's life then!
How? You're in over your head!
I don't know...
I can't think straight like this.
My men are everywhere.
I know.
Don't try running.
That'd be a terrible idea.
You have until midnight.
Thank you, Monsieur Frank.
Boy, am I glad to see you!
Do you have some I.D., sir?
It's cool, I'm American.
You cancel your credit cards?
All of them.
I can't get any cash.
It's a hassle.
Paris is expensive.
Tell me about it!
A new Amex card takes 24 hours, no?
Sure, with proof of identity.
- I can't prove my identity.
- A vicious circle.
And it's Saturday.
All my friends are away for the weekend.
Baldwin Street... Is that Manhattan?
No, Brooklyn. Number 720. Fifth floor.
- Phone number?
- It's okay, I got it.
You have info like that on your computer?
And your three convictions.
Really?
Does it say that was ages ago?
I was young.
Three months ago?
You have that one, too?
Powerful computer...
It mention it was a misunderstanding?
The report has it down as fraud.
Six months suspended.
That's right.
I intend to appeal
as soon as I'm home.
We won't be able to help.
The police will take down
a complaint for robbery
and give you temporary I.D.
Look, sir...
I'm a U.S. Citizen,
protected by the Constitution
my great-grandparents fought for
all their lives.
I have the right to assistance
when in desperate need.
Your grandparents were Algerian.
If they fought for independence,
it certainly wasn't America's.
And your green card requires you
to respect certain rules,
which you clearly didn't bother to read.
These state clearly
your visa can be withdrawn
in case of serious or repeated crimes.
In your case both apply, exceedingly!
If I may voice a personal opinion,
the only person
who can do anything for you
is yourself.
Please leave quietly
or else I'll have to call security.
André! You got my money?
What do you want?
I was thinking...
I had it in mind to...
I can't take any more.
I'm at the end of my rope.
What's wrong, fella?
I'm in the shit!
I borrowed huge sums of money,
but I was a little bit off
in my calculations.
I can't pay up.
If I don't, they're gonna ice me.
You wanna file a complaint?
No way! Why'd I wanna do that?
They'll ice me twice as hard.
What can I do for you?
I thought maybe...
Lock me away
while I think this through.
Is this "Candid Camera?"
No, it's not "Candid Camera!"
I'm hanging by a thread.
Screw "Candid Camera!"
As a favor, lock me up!
An Arab without I.D.,
what's the problem?
What?
You scumbags!
Dirty cowards!
Fuck the police!
Woken up, have you?
It's too late.
I'll do myself in.
My death will be on your consciences!
Nobody gives a shit, huh?
I'll do it.
Is that what you want?
Why did you abandon me?
Why do you never answer me?
What are you doing?
Same as you.
Meaning?
No, "mademoiselle," no.
Don't worry...
I'm coming. It's okay. I'm here.
I don't fucking believe it!
I can't even kill myself
without someone fucking me up.
Can't I have a moment's peace
to die with dignity?
It's Sunday morning.
Couldn't you sleep in like everybody else?
- I couldn't sleep.
- Find your own bridge!
There's heaps of them in this town!
Didn't you see it was taken?
We had the same idea...
Funny, huh?
Yeah, I'm dying of laughter.
Tell me why you'd want to jump anyway?
Probably the same reason as you.
- I doubt that.
- Why?
My problem is I feel stupid,
ugly and completely useless.
I doubt you could relate to that.
They are exactly the same.
I am stupid and ugly...
On the inside.
Yeah, but you have the outside
to hide it.
I have nothing to hide.
I can see that.
How can a girl like you
get so down on herself?
You're young and beautiful...
You can have anything you want.
And just what do I want?
How do I know!
I'm not a clairvoyant!
To be rich probably.
Don't we all?
Travel, splash your cash...
Get dolled up.
Buy dresses and furs...
Stuff that women like!
What would you like?
To breathe!
That's what I need
and time to refocus.
I mean, look at me!
It's what's inside that counts, right?
Easy for you to say!
You're pretty well equipped.
Who'd be dead, too,
without me to save her?
Who'd be dead without me to save?
Got a smoke?
I can't face head games right now.
Not a Sunday morning.
You're right.
So, what do we do now?
What do you mean?
You saved my life.
I guess you had a reason.
I didn't think.
I just jumped, sheer instinct.
You can’t just let people die.
I completely agree.
So, what do we do now?
We do nothing.
You leave me alone.
Men! You're all the same.
You jump in, then you throw us away!
Enough!
I'm in no mood to quarrel either.
See you.
What's your name?
Angela.
If I leave you here, will you try again?
- Try what?
- Jumping off bridges!
Maybe...
- Couldn't you maybe change your mind?
- Why?
What do you mean, why?
Because you...
You're beautiful.
And it would be a waste to lose you.
And I never accomplished anything
in my life. So knowing I saved someone...
That might help me.
If you'd do that for me,
I'd appreciate it.
I'll see what I can do.
- Thank you.
- No problem.
Goodbye.
- Why not devote your life to a cause?
- Such as?
Orphans in India,
children with AIDS in Africa...
Why go so far?
You're right.
Misery is everywhere.
Then why not help people in distress
here in Paris.
- People who need you.
- People like you?
Yes, no! Me, I'm fine.
Oh, yeah, you're doing great!
Trying to kill yourself
five minutes ago.
If you had my life,
would you know what to do with it?
Give a dog a bone,
would he know what to do?
Of course, I would.
Okay, it's a deal.
I am yours.
- Are you making fun of me?
- Not at all.
It made a lot of sense what you said.
You're right.
You're a good cause.
I'm all yours.
- You're joking.
- Not at all.
Could we go buy some smokes?
You mean you'll stay next to me?
And I'll do anything you want.
No questions asked.
Now, you're making fun of me.
Try me.
Kiss me.
Again?
Okay, I believe you.
Right, can we get some smokes?
Let's start with drying off.
Okay, they're done.
- Give me your undies.
- No, it's okay.
Come on, don't be such a pussy.
I dried mine.
It feels so much better.
- They're all warm.
- I said it's okay!
You know this is the ladies' room, right?
Oh, really?
So tell the gentleman
to dress elsewhere.
Who?
The guy in the stall,
who you gave the pants to.
Oh, looks can be deceiving.
That's a woman.
Really? With a voice like that?
On the inside, he's a woman.
The outside doesn't count.
- What was that about?
- Nothing, just girl talk.
So what do we do now?
Now...
How about some breakfast before work?
I'm dying of hunger.
Less "dying," please.
Right now, I'm...
Thanks.
And give me some space,
it feels weird.
And stop saying "okay"
whenever I open my mouth.
You want half?
I'm not hungry.
Eat! You need to build up your energy.
See that? It's going down south.
I love the south.
Me, too.
I dreamed of moving...
Why didn't you?
- One day maybe.
- Why not today?
- Today's not a good idea.
- Sure it is.
Hop on a train, next stop the beach,
just the two of us.
The sea shimmers...
- You know that song?
- By heart.
- Shall we go?
- Where?
Down south.
We can’t just take off like that.
I have problems to take care of.
Problems? Can I help?
Maybe.
Super, what do I have to do?
Nothing. Just stay close by.
Is that all?
That way, they'll think...
That we're...
That we're together.
That'll blow them away.
They'll start to respect me.
See what I mean?
Not at all.
Of course not.
First, I'd like to thank you
for welcoming us.
- Cut the crap.
- Right.
I owe you money.
Not a great amount for you,
but a huge one for me.
I'm waiting for news from my business
in Argentina.
What business?
Olive oil.
It's winter.
No olive oil for five months.
True... I was relying on our stocks,
but it all got stolen.
People are starving down there.
Even so, stealing olive oil!
- Who's the girl?
- Who?
Her? She's my partner.
- So, Frank...
- First names?
- Of course not.
- Well then!
I thought, " You can't pay Frank.
Stop kidding yourself.
"You can cut him " in."
I swear I'm sitting on a gold mine.
If it's your mine, count me out.
- I cut some great deals.
- You're a loser.
The few times you barely came through,
it was cuckold's luck.
Good thing you never got married.
Look at you. A bum!
You stink a mile away.
Who'd even throw you a dime?
I'm sorry.
I had no time to shave.
I worked my ass off to get your cash.
But when you are in a hole...
Stop the drama.
You dug your hole all by yourself.
You have six more hours to get my 30,000
or I'll have two Serbs on you.
Two Serbs?
Two Bosnians, if you prefer.
Come on, Frank...
In that case...
Don't you have a little job?
A shitty job, anything.
I think I know what he'd enjoy.
Just a second...
Zip your lip.
You want to get me fired.
You're already fired.
You negotiate like an amateur.
An amateur?
Cut to it.
Quit beating around the bush?
What bush?
Just shut up
and let me close the deal...
- Some deal!
- Shut the fuck up!
Shut it.
Where were we?
Let your friend do the talking.
She seems smarter than you.
No problem.
If you want to talk with her...
We're partners.
Me or her, it's the same.
Can you take over?
Where do you want to do it?
My study upstairs will be more quiet.
Perfect.
You're the best.
This guy, he's a killer.
He'll fuck you over...
It's cool.
I'll make him an offer he can't refuse.
Be good.
Where were you? It's been an hour!
I was five minutes.
It worked out fine.
Listen to you!
The guy's a killer!
He could have croaked you.
Must be my lucky day.
Here, this is for you.
What's this?
Paper with pictures on it.
It's called money.
- What about my debts?
- History.
He wiped the slate clean.
You're virgin snow.
You can breathe again
and build yourself back up.
What did you do?
Sell your mother or what?
Course not!
Come on, tell me what happened.
What do you care?
Your problem's solved.
Look to the future now. Onward!
Onward, my ass!
If it's dirty money, I don't want it.
What's dirty money?
If you did nasty stuff, keep it.
When you got to an ATM,
do you ask where the cash is from?
From the ATM.
That's good enough for me.
I'm your ATM today.
Take your cash
and shut the fuck up!
It'll come in handy...
How much is there?
Enough to pay the Spaniard.
Ah... That's genius.
How do you know about the Spaniard?
Everybody knows about your debts.
- I don't want it!
- Why the hell not?
'Cause I'm sure you did
nasty shit with Frank.
I'm not a pimp!
- Nonsense...
- Yes, sense! Give me that.
Don't think I didn't see you shaking it.
- I was shaking it?
- Flashing your panties. I saw you.
A trick of the eye!
I saw it in his eyes.
He didn't hear a word I said.
You have to admit
you were pretty slow.
I was talking business
with its codes and language.
Body language!
You appear weak,
and then you pounce!
He's not a kitten.
You're dealing with a criminal.
And you were bad like a fifth grader.
I have my dignity. Principles.
You wouldn't understand.
So why didn't you act on them?
He was as soft as a marshmallow.
You could have gotten 10,000 easy.
No way in hell!
I thought about it.
The brain is big,
why use just a little bit?
You are so wrong.
I use it all!
I think around the clock.
Now, I'm thinking it's "adios."
You think little. Pay your little debts,
your little plane ticket,
hurry home
and sell your little studio in Brooklyn.
You know about my penthouse?
Call that a penthouse? A rat hole?
I bought it at a good price...
And the market value...
Forget your studio in Brooklyn.
That's not the problem.
Your problem
is that you're always running
without stopping, thinking...
Taking a breath!
Getting oxygen to your brain...
So it'll be happy
and help you make the right decisions.
Breathe!
That's right. Look...
Head up!
The clouds...
The birds...
Life...
It's all around.
Isn't this the most beautiful city?
How should I have handled Frank?
By telling him the truth, that's all.
What truth?
The only one you don't want to hear.
The money I owe
is tainted by prostitution, drugs...
I'll never pay it back.
I hate that shit.
This is it, slime ball,
I refuse to waste my time with lowlifes.
Bravo, André.
I should have said that?
Didn't you think it?
You can't always say what you think.
Why not?
Life might be cooler, no?
And we could make the most of Paris.
How about a cruise on the Seine?
This is no time for boat trips!
Oh, yeah?
When is a good time?
When there's no stress.
Right now, I'm stressed.
It'll only take five minutes.
Stop it.
- Anyway, I can't swim.
- Liar! You jumped in to save me!
I wasn't thinking.
Now I am and I remember I can't swim.
- Pretty please!
- No, no, no! Forget it!
When I say no, I mean it.
I always dreamed
of taking a boat ride up the Seine.
It's so romantic.
I feel sick.
I'm happy. Here. Now.
At this precise moment.
You save my life,
you fulfill my dreams...
See, you are able to do good.
It only works on you.
- We should do this again at night.
- Absolutely not!
The boats with all their lights on...
So pretty from up above,
winding downstream,
like baubles of light gliding along.
- From up above?
- Up there. From the sky.
Come on, chill a little.
You're so tense.
It makes you all wrinkly just there,
like a turtle.
You never had money problems.
No, I never had any.
What? Problems or money?
Either.
Good for you,
but I always have problems with both.
You have money now to pay your debts.
I owe the Spaniard much more.
No sweat, let's go make more money!
Let's go make more money!
Oh, snap your fingers,
here comes the moolah?
Didn't I just score 20,000 in five minutes?
That's not the same.
Yes, it is the same.
How much do you need to be happy?
- What are you talking about?
- Your debts? How much do you owe?
- In total?
- Obviously.
I've absolutely no idea.
30...
35...
With interest, let's say 50,000.
- I'm so in the shit.
- 50,000? Spilled milk!
Come on, let's go!
- Go where?
- Where there's music.
What for?
I like to work to music.
- How you doing?
- I'm fine.
You want a fuck in the restroom?
A straight-talker, huh?
Might I ask your name first?
You won't need it. Well?
How much are you willing to pay?
I see.
Why should I pay?
What you don't pay for
has no value.
Good point.
Well? How much?
- 500.
- 1,000 and I'll do it all.
That's a deal.
Here. 1,000...
What's that for?
The tall blonde said to give it to you.
Angela?
What?
- What are you doing?
- Guess.
You can't do this.
I don't want you to do that for me.
I thought you needed cash.
Yes, I do,
but I still have some moral values.
I don't want you doing this.
I'm grateful. I'm thankful.
It's a very kind gesture...
But I can't let you do it.
It's no big deal.
It is a big deal.
Of course it is!
Stop now and come out here.
Let's say I'm doing it for me
and you're keeping the money
so I don't spend it all.
I don't feel well.
Please, come out and let's go.
Just do as she asked.
Now back off, I'm nearly done!
Honestly, I...
I can't leave you here like this.
Go back to the bar
or we'll be here all night.
- I'll be at the bar.
- Go!
500, isn't it?
Party's over.
Don't be rotten. Just five minutes.
I just told you, no more!
- You had it three times!
- No, I didn't. Not even once.
I've been waiting in line for hours.
Be a good chap.
Here, I'll give you 1,000.
Keep your money!
I told you, the kid's tired.
Tired? She's had everybody here.
One more won't make any difference.
It certainly will!
Just "one more" makes me realize.
Realize what?
I don't want her being damaged.
Not for my benefit.
I don't deserve that.
And I don't want
to join the asshole club like you.
Scram before I lose my temper.
See where telling the truth gets you?
You didn't have to insult him.
Especially the stuff about his mom.
It just popped out.
Good, you're improving.
You spoke from the heart.
At this rate, I won't last the night.
You're always whining, aren't you?
Did you see the evening I had?
In a bar, pimping you out.
I'm ashamed.
You'd rather have been in my shoes?
So, drop it.
I thought having money
would cheer you up.
It's in your pocket now, so smile.
I wanna pay off my debts first.
Then I'll smile.
What are you gawking at?
Stay close by just in case.
You come across a paper bag?
- Always humiliating me.
- You don't need me for that.
There you go again.
- I treat you like you treat me.
- I should've let you drown!
- Pardon?
- Nothing.
Don't start! I'll die with shame.
No more dancing.
Don't start!
I'm kind of famous here.
Pedro!
You want me to lose my shirt?
You got some nerve coming here.
Lost your memory?
I made a quick roundtrip to Argentina.
- What for?
- Business. Didn't you know?
Well, now you know.
So you can pay me back?
That's why I'm here.
Straight up?
I'm impressed.
- Drink?
- Why not? With pleasure.
- What'll it be?
- Vodka tonic.
What about your chick?
Should I answer or cluck?
- Just answer.
- The same, please.
Two vodka tonics for my pals.
- She's pretty.
- Yeah, I know.
We met on a... In Argentina.
Very blonde for a Latina, huh?
Yeah, her mother's from Sweden.
Hi, my name's Pedro.
You can call me Pepito.
If you'd like a job here,
no problem!
In Spanish or Swedish?
Answer... Doesn't matter.
Very pleased to meet you, too.
You've got a cool place here,
it's got flavor.
Good accounts make good friendships.
How much do I owe you?
17,000 plus interest, let's say
€20,000.
Are we cool?
We're cool.
I take back all that I said about you.
- And God knows I said a lot!
- Fair enough.
I should've called when I fell behind.
Six months isn't a little bit behind...
A little bit...
Yeah, you should've called.
That's true, isn't it?
It's always nice to hear from friends.
Really?
I'm touched by that.
Plus, you're looking good, too!
I'm a little better.
- You seem more stable.
- That's true.
I'm getting there.
I wasn't in good shape.
- Now, I'm better.
- That's good!
You were on a slippery slope.
I know. I know...
I even know guys
who put contracts on your head.
Is that true?
It didn't come from me, okay?
Anyway, I'd rather die
than defaulting my debts.
- Easy now...
- I swear!
Yesterday morning,
I nearly topped myself.
I... I was on a bridge.
I climbed over the rail
and I nearly jumped.
Don't screw up now.
This one's counting on you now.
Can't let her down.
I didn't, believe me.
Let me help you get back in the saddle.
I have a nag running in Miami,
called Brutus.
30-to-1.
I have a guy, he doped the favorites.
They'll drag their feet like donkeys.
But my horse, he's on speed.
He'll blow them away!
What if they test them?
I bribed the vet.
Brutus, number 7 in the third race.
- 30-to-1. Can you imagine!
- I imagine!
- This is only for you, André.
- No problem.
- Don't drive the odds down now.
- You can trust me.
That's my gift.
For your return to business!
Thanks a lot. Seriously.
Number 7, in the third.
Live it up!
Diego, whatever my friends drink,
it's on me!
Señorita!
Did you see that?
With you next to me...
The respect I get!
He was eating out of my hand, Pepito.
Okay, what do we do now?
Make shit loads of money.
Miami. In the third.
All on number 7. Brutus.
I feel that you're
about to lose my money.
I'll pay you back. Triple.
Thank you!
Let me show you...
Come on, horsy!
He's in front!
Look at that, the Spaniard was right!
Come on, come on...
He's easing back, taking a breather.
What's going on?
Oh, it's an American tactic.
He's catching his breath.
He's gonna go for the sprint!
Come on, fight! Catch them!
He's easing off too much.
Why is he walking?
He said number 7.
He... He said put it all on 7.
I put it all on 7.
And number 1 won?
I lost it all.
With a name like that,
what did you expect?
Why'd you say that?
Brutus! Caesar's buddy.
Killed him. Stabbed him in the back.
- Why didn't you say?
- You should have listened in school!
Yeah, right.
What's with the smoking?
Where I live, there's no smoking.
Can't even sneak one.
I'm catching up.
Cancer's all you'll catch.
Give me that.
- How about some breakfast?
- I'm flat broke.
No worries.
I kept one, just in case
business went bad.
Give it to me.
It's a dodgy neighborhood.
Thank you.
Get me back in the saddle?
What a joke!
Back to earth with a bang!
Yeah, me, too.
No croissants where you live?
- He ever give you a tip before?
- Course not.
So what made you think
he'd give you one now?
- I don't know... I believed.
- Because he flattered you.
All right, he suckered me.
Happy now?
Since you have such low self-esteem,
you fall for flattery.
I fall?
You don't seem to mind when I fell for you!
And why are you busting my balls?
Who are you?
How come you dropped into my life?
I didn't come. I fell out of the sky.
Off a bridge! I was there.
So was I. Before that...
- I fell from the sky.
- What do you mean?
- From a plane?
- No, the sky. Upstairs.
That's where I live.
I'm an angel, if you prefer.
An angel?
The real thing.
Big, white wings and all.
So where are your big,
white wings and all?
You expect me to spread them in a café?
Achain-smoking angel?
Why do you give a fuck? I'm immortal.
Okay, so you're an angel.
I'm open-minded. You're an angel.
Well, it's a good start.
So what's going on upstairs?
What's happening?
Nothing special. It's just routine.
Come on, tell me honestly.
What's it like?
You don't believe me?
A leggy blonde who smokes like a chimney
isn't exactly how one pictures an angel.
You're not even gonna show me your wings.
Screw my wings!
I can't spread them here.
One, they're too big
and two, unfurling your wings
means your mission's accomplished.
And you're being an ass, it's unlikely
I'll be going home soon.
What mission?
- To help you.
- You haven't since I met you.
You mess it up by lying all the time,
even to yourself.
And not just little yarns.
You lie to yourself profoundly.
You're scared.
Scared of you, scared the whole time.
You're shut like an oyster.
You came from heaven
to tell me I'm an oyster?
To help you grasp
how things work inside there.
To help you know exactly who you are,
so you accept it.
- Is that all?
- It's enough!
You're a kind of shrink?
It won't cost you €100.
Right, let's recap.
You're an angel,
on your cloud, waiting for your mission?
Simplistic, but more or less.
Someone yells out,
"Angela, can you take case 12,737?"
You don't choose.
You take what you're given.
If angels started to pick and choose,
the dispatchers would go mad.
Yeah. Can't upset the dispatchers.
Then?
Once you get your mission,
you go to Wardrobe.
That's my favorite part!
- And what'd you pick for a costume?
- Sexy bitch!
- Sexy bitch suits you.
- Thank you!
I've already tried most of everything.
I thought it'd be fun
to try something weird for once.
- You been doing it for long?
- 300 years or so.
I'm still a junior.
What's so funny?
It's extraordinary! What a story!
I never met a girl with such imagination.
You should write books, or encyclopedias.
We'd cash in!
You still don't believe me?
No!
There is no worse pain for an angel
than to be rejected
by their human half,
having failed the mission.
Don't get in such a state.
Try to understand. I'm such a clown,
The Man Upstairs sends you?
But, yeah, what's the problem?
On earth,
we have to see it to believe it.
When were you here last?
It's a materialistic world now.
With all the satellites, science, TV,
people don't believe in miracles anymore.
They need proof, see?
Little something?
You men are all the same!
Always wanting proof, reassurance...
Isn't that my problem?
No self-confidence?
If I have faith in you,
maybe I'll have faith in me.
Don't tell anyone.
I don't want to get fired.
- I swear.
- Please don't swear!
I promise.
Does that suit you?
How did you do that thing?
Are you kidding me!
Here's your proof.
And you still don't believe me?
- How did you...
- You're a real idiot!
Forget miracles, you need hitting.
I... I didn't see the thing... Cigarette...
I... I wasn't concentrating.
Angela, I'm asking you sweetly.
Please do it again.
Please?
Last time I'll ask.
Okay.
Waiter! Another coffee
and a vodka tonic for him, please.
- Why me?
- Don't ask me. Not my department.
Surely because you're good inside,
and don't know it yet.
I'm here to help you learn.
I'm your reflection. Your image.
I am you.
- I'm a 6-foot sexy bitch?
- A little, on the inside.
- I'm not a woman.
- Yes, partly.
You're even more feminine
than masculine, in fact.
It's from there you derive
your sensitivity, humor, spirit...
Those are feminine characteristics.
Men are hunters.
You're not cut out for hunting.
From the male traits
you only kept the bad ones.
Lies, ambition,
fear of not making the grade,
fear of being judged, fear of loving.
- You see all that in me?
- All.
And let me tell you,
you're mind-blowingly hot on the inside.
The outside's my problem.
Let's go outside.
Is it me losing feathers?
On my back? Am I?
I need calcium. I have to eat.
Cheese is good for calcium.
Double cheese, double ham,
double salad, please.
Stop looking like you'll eat me.
Sorry, it's just...
I'm not used to...
Someone next to me.
- Time to learn.
- Yeah, I know.
My whole life I've been in the shit.
No one ever helped me out.
- Never.
- But it's now that you're in the shit.
Why?
Because now you have no more excuses
to stay in it.
Thanks.
- Do you have mustard, please?
- On the counter.
It's free.
Can I take a napkin?
Mustard's free.
The sandwich is €8.
I put a 10 on the counter.
Look, no €10!
- It must have blown away.
- Never put €10.
Don't mess with Romanians.
Many here! Pay!
Save your tickets for tourists.
I'm a Parisian I...
You pay!
Or else no get out alive! Get it?
Can I finish the negotiation?
"Voilà," it's better like that!
- How much do I owe you?
- It's on the house!
We clear?
Can't miss your masculine side, huh?
- Why did you do that?
- What did I do?
What is this?
- Where'd you get that?
- Why didn't you pay the guy?
Let's discuss this later.
It wasn't even your money.
I gave it to you.
Precisely, it's all we had left.
Stop sticking your finger in the dyke!
You're cracked and full of holes!
- Excuse me.
- You, shut it!
You're like a guy who takes
more bread to finish his cheese,
then more cheese to finish his bread.
And the French take more wine
to finish both,
then wonder why lunch lasts till 3:00 p.m.
What a stupid example!
I don't even like cheese.
I'm just trying to solve my problems here.
You can't understand that.
You jump off a bridge, screw around,
smoke unfiltered. No problem.
Putting down my credibility
won't elevate yours.
You're a real head twist!
Why do you intellectualize everything?
It drives me crazy!
I only point out the mechanisms
that put you in the shit.
She's right. You're in deep shit.
Listen, mate, let me settle this.
I'll be right with you.
Thought you were here to help.
Why are you sucking my light?
You were shining bright?
Maybe not bright,
but I was seeing things clearly.
So why jump off a bridge?
See?
That proves that she's after me!
Do you remember our deal?
Shut up and stay close, remember?
That's true.
All right then.
So shut up and don't say a word.
Don't even say "okay."
You shut up 100%.
You understand 100%?
Can we get down to business now?
- Angela, you know "Simon says"?
- I love it.
Simon says, crush them!
- That'll give us some air.
- What do we do now?
Not a word.
Now, we go.
We go that way!
Angela, I'd like to know more about you.
About your past, on the earth.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
I want to know.
What were you like as a kid?
We lived in the Paris projects.
I was the oldest of eight kids.
I raised them.
Mom split when I was 15.
Dad was drunk from dawn to dusk.
I took the kids to school
and turned tricks to buy food.
I died of ovarian cancer at age 23.
You poor thing, how awful!
That's not a real life.
And I thought I had problems.
- What's funny?
- You swallow anything. Like a fish.
It wasn't true?
I was a rich kid from Jersey.
Dad worked for the U.N.
And Mom brought people together
by getting laid at cocktail parties.
On my 16th birthday, I got a Ferrari
and took aim at the nearest wall,
so Daddy would notice me at last,
at my funeral.
I'm lost.
Which was your life?
Which makes your life more bearable?
I don't know.
I can invent thousands,
but yours remains the same.
You have to accept it.
I understand what you're saying.
I... I'm working on it.
I still want to know you.
Who were you?
Before?
I don't know who I am.
You don't know?
You're from up there.
You're pretty well connected.
We can't access our past.
It's top secret.
Really?
That sucks.
Do my questions bother you?
If you're really interested in me,
maybe you'll take an interest in yourself.
I'm not interesting.
Of course you are.
You're good-looking, intelligent...
- Bullshit.
- But, yes, I promise you.
It's all in there,
but you won't see it or let it out.
I'm trying...
- It's not easy.
- But, yes, it is. I'll show you.
Look into the mirror.
What do you see?
I see...
- An exceptional girl.
- Thank you.
Next to her, what do you see?
I don't know.
- You're progressing.
- You think so?
Before you saw only shit.
Now, at least, you see nothing.
You've cleaned up well.
Now, you need to fill the empty shell.
You can't leave it empty.
Look hard. In front of you.
Anything catch your eye
in this handsome face?
Not much.
Look into your eyes.
What do you see?
Kindness.
Yes, lots of it.
What else?
They're not bad-looking.
Beauty, exactly.
They're beautiful.
What else?
Maybe...
A little gentleness?
Yes, lots.
And love?
Sure, lots of love.
Too much, maybe.
If there's too much,
it has to come out.
- Say you love me.
- Pardon?
- You don't love me?
- Yes, a lot...
I mean...
I feel a sort of affection,
but it may be friendship...
Do you love me or don't you?
From the very first day.
The very first second.
So, say it.
It's hard to say.
Do you know why?
Because no one ever said it to you.
Am I right?
It's hard to love yourself
when no one reflects that.
I love you, André.
See, you've received love.
Now, you can give some in turn.
Go on...
I love you, Angela.
Or whatever your name is.
You're right.
Say it again without my name.
I love you.
That's good.
Now, look yourself in the eye
and say it.
I can't.
Of course you can.
Look at your body,
battered by the lack of love and trust...
Don't you see it deserves a little care?
Don't reject your wounded body.
It's suffered in silence all this time.
Tell your body how important it is,
that it has its place.
Give it what it deserves.
I'm proud of you.
Can we go eat? I'm starving.
You and food!
Were you starved of affection?
Stick to your own role, okay?
Sure.
- How can we pay?
- We'll do the dishes.
That worked in the times of Charlemagne.
We'll spend Christmas in jail.
Stop whining for once and enjoy it.
The wine is good, huh?
- What is it?
- Château Cheval Blanc.
That's €1,000 a bottle!
1,500.
The most expensive on the list.
It's stupid.
Price doesn't equal quality.
What do you know?
You're in olive oil.
I know a little about wine...
They must have a good bottle
at a reasonable price.
Look, Saint Chignan '98.
I'm sure that it's good.
Sommelier.
- What are you doing?
- Let's taste it.
A Saint Chignan '98, please.
Of course. It's reaching maturity.
A hint of spice, full bouquet...
A good wine and a great choice,
my favorite.
Do you do half-bottles?
Never, it's by the liter here!
You're insane!
I'm just trying to please you.
You've had a long day.
Is that your mission?
It's to teach you a lot in a little time.
So you lose your desire to jump.
If you plan to pay by hustling in the john,
I won't wait at the bar.
- Hustling?
- Don't act innocent.
I was there. I saw you.
You saw or you heard?
What?
What are you doing?
Guess.
I don't want you doing this.
Don't you need the cash?
I do, but I have some moral values.
I'm grateful for the kind gesture,
but I can't let you do it.
It's no big deal.
Yes, it is.
Stop now, ask him to leave
and come out here.
Back off, I'm nearly done!
And Frank, in his office?
What did you do?
- You didn't!
- Just kidding.
That's a relief.
Where'd you get the cash?
You didn't!
Make up your mind.
Which do you prefer?
I prefer we go.
Just one night?
Do you have any luggage?
One piece. Out front.
Feeling better?
I guess.
Are you coming to bed?
- I'm watching the moon.
- It won't leave. Come to bed.
Paris is beautiful.
I couldn't see
beyond the end of my own nose.
- Angela?
- What?
I think I love you.
Come on, you're missing something.
You lack affection,
so you latch onto the first thing.
In this instance, me.
I swear you make me feel good.
I like how you shake me up,
without ever judging me.
It makes me warm inside.
I haven't felt that for so long, if ever.
You just want to fuck.
No, I don't.
Well, yeah, but...
It's stronger, hotter.
You're getting sentimental.
- Let's fuck.
- What are you doing?
I don't please you anymore?
Of course you do,
but I don't want just a fuck.
I'd love to make love,
but only when I feel liberated.
Wake me up when you are.
It won't be long.
Come on. Come to bed now.
I can't sleep with you chewing on your bit.
I'm not. I'm enjoying the room.
It's incredible.
By the way, how will we pay?
I cut a deal with the concierge.
How's that?
He plays the ponies.
So I gave him a tip.
- A ruse?
- No, he'll win 10,000.
- You know the result?
- Every race, any place.
You're shitting me?
Why didn't you say earlier?
I did, but you had sawdust in your head.
Anyway, I can't divulge stuff like that.
It's absolutely forbidden.
If it's forbidden,
why did you tell me you're an angel?
I shouldn't have.
But why did you?
What are you doing, Angela?
Going to see your pal Frank.
In the middle of the night?
To say what?
Me? Nothing.
You'll be doing the talking.
We'll go there and you can unload on him.
That way I can go back.
Angela!
Okay and what do I say to him?
Don't start again.
I explained it to you.
The truth, nothing but the truth.
The truth, no problem.
Does it hurt there?
Feel all knotted up?
Less but it's still there.
You need to get it out once and for all.
What's out isn't in, got it?
Yeah, I got it.
What happens then?
Then, you're all clean inside.
Just need to fill up.
Can't I fill up with you?
Oh, please, not again.
Angela, I'm in love with you.
You see everything.
You sense everything.
How come
you can't see something this simple?
Concentrate, I'm begging you. Right there.
What do you feel?
- I feel something but...
- I feel exactly the same.
Now I have a name for it...
Okay, let's go see Frank,
this is starting to get out of control.
What if this is
where it starts to be something...
Like the truth for once?
I'm sick of it, Angela.
Sick of screwing up,
sick of lying...
For the first time, I want to be true.
I want to say what I feel,
whatever it may be.
Do you know what I feel?
Be quiet.
"Mademoiselle," please...
This is not the time to fuck with me!
Sorry to barge in so late at night.
André has something to say
and I've had enough.
I wanna go home.
Let's get this over with.
Excuse me?
- Who's she?
- You. Shut your face!
André, come on! He's here.
In his bed.
What the hell is going on?
Talk of breaking the rules.
The door, the bodyguards...
And he's why you chose this hotel.
You'll get fired.
That's my problem.
Get a move on,
say your piece and vamoose.
You're not gonna kill me?
Your coffee's not bad.
André, I... I'm sorry.
I know I offended you.
It was dumb of me.
- We on a first name basis?
- Course not.
I took advantage of you.
I shouldn't have, it's so low.
How about a joint venture?
If you have time?
I'm begging you.
Don't kill me.
Be cool, don't kill me.
I'm sorry I borrowed from you.
I truly regret it.
Setting foot in your shit club
cost me time and money,
distracted me
from legitimate business in Paris.
But it was meant to be.
If you think you're shit,
you're drawn to shit, that's life.
It's why we got on so well.
We enjoyed despising each other.
One day, an angel came into my life.
A magnificent woman who opened my eyes.
And God knows,
it's so good to have your eyes open.
I can watch the sun rise over Paris.
The lights flicking off one after the other.
I can see it all.
All thanks to her.
She was good enough to never judge me.
To love me for what I am.
Even if it's not much.
I'm happy for you, honestly.
But you won't kill me, will you?
I'll pity you.
See that, Angela? I showed him!
For the first time ever. Where are you?
- What are you doing?
- I'm going home.
You can't do that.
Stop! I did exactly as you asked.
I'm empty.
We can start over.
Together, choose good things to fill with.
You're a big boy, choose yourself.
I don't want to.
I want to do it with you.
Because I love you.
I want to spend my life with you.
If you leave,
I go back to square one.
All that for nothing!
Destroy it all if you want to.
I took every risk for you.
I'm sure to get fired.
Do me a favor,
live the life you should live.
What if my life's with you?
It isn't!
I know your future by heart.
In two months, you set up a company
that will become a market leader in olive oil.
You will meet Catherine,
an attractive lawyer,
you will father three beautiful children.
You want to know their names?
Find out how good they are at school?
I want to know why you're crying.
Because I always do after a mission.
I'm made for greetings not goodbyes.
Does that answer your question?
Listen to me.
What you did for me is enormous.
I'll be eternally grateful.
Eternally! Don't use words
you don't know the meaning of.
I'm sorry.
You taught me the essential.
Never lie.
That's right. It's the most important.
So, begin with yourself!
Stop... Listen! Look at me!
Look me in the eye!
Leave me alone.
Know what I see in those eyes?
A woman who doesn't want to go,
who's sick of not knowing who she is.
Nobody gave you love either
or you’ve forgotten.
Be quiet.
I love you.
I can't live without you.
What good is it to live with me?
All you'll get is a fallen angel
who burned her wings.
I don't care!
I love you as you are.
I don't know who I am!
I have no past.
Do you understand that?
I know...
How can I build anything
if you don't know where I'm from?
I've no idea where I'm from!
I know.
I know you've no past.
Let me give you a future.
What do I do?
My God!
What should I do?
Leave him out for once.
What's happening?
What's going on?
I have to go. It's time.
Don't go, I'm begging you.
I love you.
I love you, too.
I have to go.
We're going to fall!
Shit!
My name's André Moussah.
I'm 28 and I am free.