Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
Simply Releases Toppers
Simply The Best
Proudly Presents
LOVE AND OTHER DRUGS
Translated by Simply Releases Toppers
Tokke Suurtje
Want to dance?
May I join you?
That's pretty sexy.
-- I love it.
You could also as a must have.
Little weight on the shoulders, ladies.
Try more.
Feels good, right?
Follow me to the checkout ladies.
You look like you're smoking weed.
You can smoke it or buy one of these TVs.
Philips is well ...
You are high, feeling good, Samsung
fashioned Megafox, that's an explosion.
So stoned that you will feel good.
If you want small, I have this.
Watch this one.
Hi, Joan, what are you doing?
I do not know, how are you?
-- I'm great.
You're so bad.
Grab my ticket but.
Sorry, Joan.
Press them.
Harder.
What are you doing?
-- Feel that once.
We can not do.
Jerry is out there.
Then he can watch.
What makes you so damn sexy.
You have no more than 80 watts
for a living.
Sorry.
Harder.
Fucking asshole.
Christy, what ails you?
How can I ever trust you?
-- I do not know. I'm sorry.
Fujitsu makes the same
for $ 40 cheaper.
Really?
-- They sell them here.
I can get him for you,
if you want.
Is everything okay with you?
Give me your number I'll let you know
when I got him.
What's your name?
You have beautiful eyes.
Never come here anymore.
You owe me commission of
$ 54,000 for second ...
counterfeit, gray market, fake brand,
to expensive equipment, asshole.
I'll kill you bastard.
-- Send it. Christy knows the address.
Amber.
4346603.
Tell Daddy at how a hospital
Chicago really is.
A patient brought in with chills
nausea, asemia, clearly in shock.
Did you complete blood count done?
-- Our protocols did not exist ...
when you studied medicine.
-- 30 years I've been under a rock.
How do you intubations subcutaneous
personally done?
I teach, I touch patients anymore.
-- Patient touch?
Why would anyone want to do?
-- You must not participate in this conversation.
I've had more patients than you ever
'll have.
Can I drink thrown over your head?
-- What's wrong with rich?
That will no longer medicine.
-- There he right.
Help is not to justify his laziness.
-- I myself have done ...
and that called for $ 35,000,000
my first trip to the fair.
Jamie, help me.
-- He's a geek who got lucky.
A geek and always will be.
-- The geek takes your shares back.
I do not blame you. The action
was ruined when they allowed women.
I'll kill you both.
-- I'll kill you all ...
if you do not go in and sit down.
-- And we should all shares.
Josh on the sale of his company.
Whatever it may do.
Long live Medical Software.
-- And to all, stopping too early, students.
You better give away some money.
-- Will not happen.
What are you doing today, Jamie?
-- Jamie sells high--quality stereo equipment.
Not anymore.
What do you mean?
-- Jamie had a little problem with the pipe.
I thought you were in the property Sat
-- I'm looking for other opportunities.
We live by the greatest
prosperity phase in the history ...
and my brother decides to resign.
Josh had it with me
pharmaceutical sales.
Pharmaceutical sales?
Medicines so that people better.
Timmy Do you remember? My roommate from Brown?
He is a consultant at Pfizer
So I said to Jamie ...
Jamie, if you suck me and I'll make
you an interview.
Watch what you say.
-- I said no, Mama.
Why a medical representative
want to be?
Because that is the only job in America
you earn $ 100,000 per year.
These people come into our office with their bags
and samples as a door to door salesman.
Indeed they are, only what they sell
They provide 78 trillion per year.
And take a decision on drugs
and influence through advertising ...
I sell the patient nothing.
The patients see advertising on TV and requirements
which brand medications ...
the doctors and you must deliver that to them.
-- If you are not barbarians quiet ...
lamb and eat it, no one gets
of you the chocolate cake.
Yes, Mama.
If you could make money by fucking
would you still richer than me.
Pfizer guy who I'll call tomorrow morning.
Let us welcome the class of 1997.
This is not a pill. This is
tens of millions of dollars on research.
This is one thousand hours of hard work.
This, ladies and gentlemen, is software.
Your training will last six weeks.
You go away as fully qualified
healthcare professional.
33% of your telephone calls
for four hours, which are 32% less evil ...
Your job will be,
'Fight against the diseases.
Income from off--label use
not yet approved by the FDA.
You can raise through the sale of
to indicate where it can be used.
If you prescribe Zithromax ...
Hello, Doctor.
Zithromax prescribing ...
Zoloft, a drug approved only
as a treatment for depression.
Off--label use, alcoholism, bulimia,
PMS, smoking ...
social phobia.
Is there a question?
Zoloft has been associated with ideas
for teenagers to commit suicide.
Unproven.
-- Proven, but not reported.
Your job will be to this technology
sharing.
It will be your job to life
to make it.
The healthcare industry is today
Worth 2.3 trillion per year.
The top ten pharmaceutical companies
earn more money ...
than all the other 490
Fortune 500 companies combined.
Which is part of Feldene?
-- Non steroids ...
Non--inflammatory drugs and steroids.
A better world, why we are here.
Xanax, New England.
And what about you?
-- Zoloft and Zithromax in Ohio.
Welcome to Pfizer.
What are you thinking?
-- Money.
Please note that we do not sell oatmeal cookies
for Girl Guides.
You're not the Avon lady.
Do you understand what I say?
It's hardcore sale
and you have a quotas.
And people in the office to keep quotas.
Your calls, your mileage, your receipts
and how often you masturbate.
What is the quota for masturbation?
But you masturbate as many times as you want,
as long as you make lots of money.
Remember, hospitals may not
accept any gifts.
It does not mean we doctors dry
walk from their car can give.
There he is. Only this moment counts.
Keep your head in the game.
Remember, Pfizer makes his life better.
Pfizer makes the patients happier ...
So he deserves more money.
Wait, the pins.
Always let them get away with a pen.
Gifts represent reciprocity.
Jamie Randall Pfizer. How are you?
-- No, thanks.
It's wet outside, I want your immune system
not compromise ...
let's have about Zithromax.
-- What part of 'no thanks' do not you understand?
Do you have a pen?
-- No, thanks.
33% of your calls to four hours
so I want to talk to you about Zithromax.
If we give people antibiotics when they sneeze
and that do not work for viruses.
What is your name?
What we do ...
What you do is create classes
drug--resistant super germs ...
and that's not good for business.
After you create stronger antibiotics ...
and thus you ruin people's immune systems.
Thank you.
Models, beauty queens ...
Roman princesses.
Have not you heard?
They're renting striptease dancers.
I heard that.
Hi, Lisa.
Her name is not Lisa.
-- I know.
But, if I every time "Hello Lisa" say
she'll come to me eventually ...
then she says, "my name's not Lisa"
but Jennifer or something.
I offer apologies and say "I thought you
Lisa was the one who is angry because I was not called. "
And then that Jennifer or so I think
was dating a girl who looked like her.
Then she unconscious need to get
my approval.
Then it's a cinch.
Etiquette is a drug salesman at a time.
Fuck the etiquette.
Competing medical representatives are
not your friends.
Knight. Where you going?
Knight is the doctor, here is the largest
group in the city ...
fuck up a lot of students Prozac
who should use Zoloft.
Take donuts with you always?
-- Selling Drugs similar to dating.
They want you to take them along to dinner
and pretend you expect nothing in return.
No one has sex without investment.
-- Exactly.
Gail, how are you?
People who become ill.
There is a reason that we half test.
Unbelievable.
That's him.
Another time.
If we have not within five minutes
can, we're leaving. Only losers wait.
There he is.
-- Hello, beautiful. How are you?
Come here, Trey.
-- Two tickets for La Boheme on the 19th.
I hate you. Can not you go
instead of my husband?
Trey Hannigan, Lilly's Prozac drug salesman.
Top ten. The devil.
He is on the phone with Watson.
You can go in there.
He is the reason that our quota
Never take for Zoloft.
Will he go in?
-- What a dick.
5% profit every month if we can show
we go to the promised land.
The promised land?
-- Chicago.
Civilization, culture, and not coincidentally,
my wife and children.
Only the greats and near greats
get Chicago.
I feel that you and
you swinging dick ...
my card will have to
the honor division.
The doctor sees new medical sales
only if they bring a lunch.
Here is a list of available dates,
the next was about five weeks.
Here is a list of approved food.
No sushi, no salads.
No salads.
-- Give me your samples only.
Five weeks.
-- You will find me like it.
Excuse me?
-- Everybody does, sooner or later.
You know why? I do everything
for that to happen.
You can train me well.
What's your name?
Gail. Five weeks.
-- Gail, that's not fair.
I would expose myself, I'll let you
my real vulnerable side.
And now you work against me.
That's not fair!
-- Do you feel out here.
Angels of Mercy watch you sometimes.
How do the doctors ...
What do you want?
Sample somewhere that I should resign
where he will see them.
Otherwise you throw them away when I'm gone.
Gail, no sushi no salads.
Who you are embedded?
Do you know that if you prescribe Zithromax
diarrhea caused by an ear infection ...
Do you have a pen?
Well, knight in shining armor,
your time is over.
That is a long handle.
-- Want a pen?
Thanks.
-- Purple.
I got something for you.
There is another one.
For you too.
These pins, which have small buttons ...
and if you press too hard ...
Hello, beautiful.
How beautiful.
This used to work in the past
for you, but I lay it out here ...
I am for one reason
become a medical representative ...
doctors to meet.
Befriend doctors,
multiplied by doctors.
If you see me next time
do not ask for a favor, that's embarrassing.
I like Chicago.
This does not happen now.
You're 20% below your quota Z.
and 45% below your quota for Zoloft.
If you want to lose me, there is your answer.
By him taking Prozac infants
and dogs ...
and stones when they pay cash.
If a doctor for Zoloft should
writing, that the guy next to him.
Knight. Hannigan's buddy.
If he would write,
follow the rest of the doctors.
And, Windy City, here we come.
I'm very late.
-- $ 1,000.
Excuse me?
-- A check for $ 1,000.
What?
-- A Pfizer voucher and ...
your shadow to know your practice
so doctors and better service.
Buy me about?
-- No, Doctor.
It is a special voucher Pfizer,
for me to shadow you.
Is this a joke?
-- If you believe than $ 1,000 a joke?
That is 33% of your calls
for four hours.
I would earn much more per year
If I was a paid consultant.
We can talk to them about.
I give five trillion a year
to marketing ...
instead of me flying to Cancun
for a conference or other nonsense.
Give me half of that money in cash.
Mrs. Petney is on the phone
her daughter Friday that thing ...
they do 'Bye, bye birdy', she plays Kim, she
asks if you want to give antibiotics.
Of course.
Why not.
This can not be good.
A 26 year--old has Parkinson's medications
Need help?
Beth who has been there between.
If the patient asks a question, you are a trainee.
-- Can I take notes?
Of course.
Why not.
I am Dr. Knight.
-- Maggie Murdog.
In your case is
'Kind of emergency ".
There is yesterday broke into me and they
I have included Parkinson's medications.
But my symptoms are well today ...
it is a kind of emergency.
I know your medical representative, and when Hannigan
Cindy has put me in between.
Yes, Trey is a great guy.
-- I would not say.
Monotherapy?
-- Sinemet CR 50 mg twice a day ...
Domperidone and nausea at the
10 mg three times daily ...
Artane tremor at 2 mg
tablet three times daily a whole ...
Prozac and that I am not really depressed that
I have a degenerative disease in 26 years.
40 mg once in the morning.
Zoloft has fewer side effects.
Who are you?
Trainee.
So early Parkinson's.
That's pretty rare.
At first they thought it was a vibration.
When Wilson's disease ...
as Huntington's, when they gave me
the MES test, PSP, syphilis.
I was glad that it was negative.
I would not like to be a slut 19th century.
Then there was the brain tumor.
That was very frightening.
And six months searching for foreign tissue,
proved to be good old Parkinson.
Exactly.
Do not have a neurologist?
We broke up.
And the insurance?
-- Do I have insurance.
Of course. Why not.
-- Great.
Can I do anything else for you?
-- No.
Basically yes.
I have a strange spot on my chest.
I try not to get upset.
-- Let's see.
Do you see that?
This is a spider bite.
-- Is that so?
Yes, that's a spider bite.
-- Great.
Please.
-- Thank you, Dr. Knight.
Of course.
You're welcome.
You have let me pull my shirt off.
Wait, I'm hurt.
Your handle came into my eye.
I'm hurt.
Who said I was a drug salesman?
Check your bag again.
You're not going to the airport?
Bid now but your apology.
Nice if someone from the Medical Community
would apologize.
I apologize to
behalf of all those arrogant ...
faceless, closed bastards
of doctors ...
you have treated as a non--existent
person to your chest and peered.
What's your name?
You're good.
Strong eye contact ...
played intimacy,
do you get your quota.
Then come a cup of coffee.
What was that for?
-- Bag it in shit. That was that.
Wait.
I better apologize.
Because I want to know.
The same white tights that I wear every day.
You're crazy.
And nothing on underneath.
You're bad.
I am looking for a number of a patient
he saw yesterday.
One Murdock or something.
Want Maggie Murdock's number?
-- Yes.
Because they said six neurologists
and ...
Pfizer comes with Parkinson's disease medications
and I want to contact them ...
and I want lots of money.
But, that none of your business.
We can not give telephone numbers.
-- You have given me your number, naughty girl.
Know what your friends are
poor you really are?
If they knew how bad
you actually had ...
I promise you that I omdoe stethoscope
then we play the naughty nurse.
What are you doing here?
I'm the dick.
She kicked me out.
-- No right?
Can you believe it?
I think she fucks with someone else.
Why did she kicked you out?
-- I do not know.
She said I was addicted to Internet porn.
-- Are you?
Of course.
That is everyone?
I can not breathe.
I have a panic attack.
Do you Ativan?
-- Well Xanax.
Do you have samples of Xanax?
I am now very vulnerable.
Come here.
It's okay.
We are not cuddly ass.
Faster, come on.
We can do this.
Josh, put it down.
-- No.
Why did you get that picture taken?
-- Is that the girl with the boobs?
How did you get my number come?
Did you call the office of Knight?
How did you get my number?
-- From the reception.
Fuck you.
-- What does she say?
Go drink coffee with me.
-- Why?
I am a medical representative, not a freak.
Same thing.
-- Sorry I was staring at your tits, but ...
they are really beautiful.
I thought you just hung up.
Had I to do?
-- And to miss the opportunity to insult me?
Do you like to be offended?
Wait.
With the right person.
This is a sales pitch.
You stay on the phone until I say yes.
-- I mean everything I say.
Five hours. Lulu's, come on time.
Why do you answer everything with violence?
I said five hours.
Very cute.
-- You can have him.
Khaki pants, no thanks.
What's your name?
What's your game?
-- My game?
Now we talk about where we come from
and what we are majoring in high school.
You have beautiful eyes?
-- Can you do any better?
Really, they are wonderful.
-- Thanks.
My childhood?
When I was sick?
Are you always so mean?
-- I'm still pretty.
What's your quota this month
Have you already had the first appraisal?
Is that a vibration at rest.
It comes and goes.
That's none of your.
-- That happens when you're nervous.
Mr. Expert, why should I be nervous?
-- Because you're interested.
And why am I nervous?
-- Your mind tells you one ...
and your body says something else.
Let's go.
Excuse me?
-- You still want to fuck?
Now?
So I have to pretend I do not know
whether it is good ...
and then you say that there is no right or wrong.
It's just the moment.
And I say that I can not do.
I give signals that I can not do.
You do not need because you're not listening
really, this is not about a relationship for you ...
it is not even about sex.
It is about one hour to find ...
rid of the pain to be you.
And I like it because ...
I just want the same.
Does that mean I do not tip
to give?
I know what you think.
I will keep five or ten minutes.
And where I tossed my beeper.
I think not.
Lying under the table.
What's that guy again?
Bye, Johnnie.
You should get going.
-- I do not leave.
I want you to leave.
It was nice to meet you.
Same here.
Maybe we'll meet again.
Thanks.
What are you doing here?
-- I know it's late.
I have not seen anything. No glasses.
-- Turn around.
Hi, Josh.
Nice to meet you.
I can of the six causes of
mention amnesia ...
and the four stages of terminal cirrhosis.
And I know how to set up a gut feeling
in an investigation.
Why are you turned away
of your medical studies?
I'm not turned away, I could see the university
early. I could not sit through class.
Ritalin with ten.
-- Eight.
Boaster.
I thought you were pretty smart.
-- The prodigal son with ADD.
Want to know the truth?
I could not give satisfaction to my father.
This usually works for you?
What?
-- This.
That whole by dad misunderstood,
I am a sensitive guy thing.
Usually, yes.
It's okay.
-- Thanks.
But somewhere, say the sixth grade,
a girl laughed at you, or ...
there is a lot of girls laughing at you
and, Jamie is still good at something.
That was actually in fifth grade.
Why did you have a boyfriend?
I'm going.
Why?
-- Look.
The thing is, I love it
to have sex ...
and I love having sex with
you have ...
let's keep it simple.
-- I can do.
Yes, you looks like an asshole,
So it must be good.
There are alarms off in my head.
You are not quite what you seem.
No, I'm an asshole.
Believe me.
Good.
Because if it turns out you're not an asshole
that would be bad.
I'm a bastard through and through.
How are you?
It's okay.
The injured parts to acid acetonic Fri
Your body converts it to prostaglandin
so you can experience pain.
Do you surrender?
That does not help.
It takes one minute until the acid is
and until the natural morphine to work.
You know why I have you beaten?
-- No, I do not know.
Prozac has helped millions of people
with intractable mood disorders.
Has made miserable lives livable.
It has even helped me
some of my anger problems.
So if someone with my Prozac motherfuckers
then I get upset.
You know what people say about me?
-- That you hear in the national top ten.
Why is that do you?
-- On Thurs.
Why do you think that is?
I am an ex Navy man.
I destroy anyone who stands in my way.
I would do on ice as quickly as possible.
If pain persists ... radiographs.
And stay away from Maggie.
Sorry.
That more samples?
-- Go ahead.
Thanks.
I just got a job interview.
-- That's great.
That's great.
Hello, ladies.
No samples today.
-- I have great stuff for you.
Thanks.
She's just a friend.
-- No samples today, sorry.
What's going on?
Trey has talked with you or not?
What has he given you?
-- No samples today. Thanks.
Hawaii.
-- Hawaii?
No samples today. Doctors Congress,
beach resort in Honolulu.
I gotta get outta here.
-- You're not going to her?
No.
What is that?
-- Food.
To ...
That's my noodle.
-- Your face is full of noodles.
Thank God you're so selfish.
You're like my mother.
Have you slept with your mother?
What?
She's fun, it is available,
you would love her ...
They used all the oxygen in the chamber
wardrobes and all ...
beyond that you are perfect for each other.
-- Is she hotter than you?
I bet she is hotter than you.
-- She has no illness.
Does it work normally for you?
-- What?
Self--pity?
-- You're an asshole.
What?
-- Nothing.
This is fun.
It's time to get your clothes off
and me to jump.
Wait. May I say?
-- I do not know.
First, take your costs and it would
you to sleep ...
then take clean clothes and then
your razor and then it's a relationship.
I do not want a relationship.
-- You can not guarantee.
You may have a latent humanity
you know nothing about.
You may find a nice relationship ...
I said 'this is fun'.
I asked you not to marry.
I do not want to be someone who is sick.
I'm sorry.
I did that before.
And that was not good.
There was with me a diagnosis and ...
He was married and he would help me.
That did not work out so well.
You're talking about Trey Hannigan.
It's Trey Hannigan.
Are you in love with him?
No, I'm not in love with Trey Hannigan.
He said he was in love with me ...
There was a problem.
Can we just ...
-- Yes.
You get a special thanks because
've brought your food.
I did.
-- Yes, you did.
You know what?
-- What?
I gotta pee.
I'll be back.
Good.
One moment.
-- Good.
Concentrate.
Should I continue?
-- This never happens.
I see.
-- I really mean it.
It's me.
I bring bad luck.
That really helps. Tell me about all
other guy you've been to bed.
And who could not get up.
He might ...
Take it easy.
Very briefly.
Do not worry about it.
-- I am concerned about it.
Show some kindness again.
Please.
-- Lying bastard.
You really latent humanity.
You know what's going on here?
I just want to have sex.
-- Your body tells you something else.
What do you mean?
Sit down.
-- I do not sit.
Talk to me.
-- I do not talk.
What would you do differently.
You have sex all of brushed aside.
Tell me how your day has expired.
My day?
So I sneak into my room and I make
of a D B.
I had worked out nicely.
Was nothing to see.
I go to the office and give him paper
and then he pulls that face.
And I say 'what'?
He gets behind his back
copy from the school.
Genius.
You're so ambitious.
-- No.
I said I had a relationship with Trey Hannigan
and you get it no longer holds.
Trey Hannigan I do not give a damn.
You want to just beat him.
-- Bullshit.
So prehistoric.
Men spend only about performance.
But their appendix does not, if they
concerned about performance.
You're an expert.
If I am an expert, why
gives your company ...
millions on drugs so that men
to get it up?
I would like.
-- It's true. I have read.
Pfizer is a fucking drug.
-- Where did you read?
I do not know what I've read.
Just ask your boys.
I'm a slut medicine,
I read everything.
What drug?
-- I do not know. It's hard to believe.
That is 'hard' to believe?
It is something big.
When I think of the size of the problem
and the bigger ...
Really.
-- Really?
That they have the solution for
the stiffest, hardest ...
Pfizer must be bursting with pride.
Not tickle.
Please.
You have a weak sense of humor.
Talking.
-- No more talk.
Who are all these old people?
People I work with.
They're beautiful.
It looks like a photograph.
When did you make it?
When I still could hold a brush.
Here's your breakfast.
Thanks.
-- My pleasure.
I'll call you.
Do not.
-- I'll do that.
I'm not kidding.
I can not do.
I have told you.
Your problem is, you're not off.
You should tell the doctors what they need.
If someone says no, the fun begins.
Then you are inside.
My grades are going up.
-- Your Zithromax went up, so what?
We're not going to Chicago by Zithromax.
Depressed people are depressed every day.
You must focus on Zoloft.
On Zoloft.
-- Here's some advice ...
do not be a bitch.
I used your language now?
Trial separation.
-- I'm so sorry.
I need my feelings on you take it out.
I say it differently. I feel you
not a damn bitch should be.
We are going to release a new sex drug?
What are you talking about?
-- Is it true?
Where did you hear that?
-- I heard.
Sildenafil Citrate.
This is a PDE5 inhibitor.
That they encountered in testing
for blood pressure medicines ...
the boy said, all the time
a huge boner.
Where did you hear that?
-- What is it?
Viagra.
-- I want that.
Everyone wants them.
-- That I can sell.
See if some indigestion tablets
lying in the glove.
Bruce, I want that account.
Why should I give to you?
-- Who is a 'pikmedicijn "sell better than me?
Crushing married ten years.
Like the lost ten years.
My God.
I do not even know how
I have girls to decorate.
What are you doing?
-- A PDS. Do you know that?
Irritable Bowel Syndrome?
-- Advantage network.
Say who you are, why
and what you can do for them.
And just be yourself.
-- Thanks.
Look who just arrives.
This is your chance.
Let's see what you have.
Let me see.
How's your thumb?
-- How is your jaw?
Randall, you know Stan Knight right?
Stan, this is a smart young man from Pfizer.
We've met before.
-- Yeah, how are you?
Fantastic. There is a new study
on Zoloft ...
25% fewer side effects than Prozac.
So, I feel good.
It's better if you sell it
fucked has.
Need someone I can fuck?
Stan is one of the more respected
diagnostiseurs in the city ...
but his real job is whore--hopper.
I think your real professional pimp.
You fuck with Maggie Murdock?
You do.
She has great tits.
Not fair.
You do not see much in
neurological damned.
Damned why?
You are not dying of Parkinson's.
That's not really a life.
Interferon and then, the process is
stopped ...
in most cases.
-- Listen, Mr. doctors visitor.
You're an asshole.
She's a sick girl.
Have you told your wife?
-- None of your business.
Maggie has many needs. I think
as a wimp if you can not take.
And a married man is?
-- You want me to beat you again?
Join now not aggressive.
You know what?
-- Calm down.
I'm going home.
You do not.
Put your wife hello.
-- I love watching you.
Since I got the nerves.
Did he really beaten?
-- Yes, I'm afraid he does that again.
He should increase his medication.
Maybe he should take something more impact
By aggressive behavior.
Zoloft with you 30% less explosions
in adult men.
And I think that your life changes.
I know those women, all two.
What do you take home?
Here's superstar.
Confidence is key.
What do you think if we tent
blow and then another?
Thanks.
Are you ready?
-- You okay, champ?
No.
What are you doing?
Will you call her?
Did she orally satisfied you?
Farrah looks at my cock
if it is the eye of Sauron.
Hello?
-- Did you call me?
No, I did not call you.
-- I think so.
What would I have said?
-- That you want to see me?
That would be nice,
I just do not call.
Want to see me?
-- I hang up now.
Wait, do not hang up.
Why?
I like your voice be heard.
Day, Randall.
-- Maggie.
You like to hear her voice?
Shut up.
Do you have a brain tumor?
Whether you're attacked by a panda?
Have you been abducted by Aliens?
You hate women.
Why else fuck you so much?
It's time you take an overdose.
She has rejected you.
Why you want her.
The first time in history
that this happens.
I'm slightly.
Are you rich?
Why are you sleeping on my couch?
You're my big brother.
Here. For people who never
have gone through puberty.
Take six.
Is everything okay?
-- Can I pay by check?
Sam, I did not say that pharmacies
only accept cash?
Enter the bus but then talk
we are about.
Maggie, I want to talk.
I can not talk now.
I go by bus to Canada.
Canada?
-- Yes, Canada.
Those people their medication
not pay.
Maggie, there are bathroom breaks?
-- I told you there was a toilet in the bus.
When you come back?
-- Never.
Tomorrow night, late.
-- What time?
Forget it now.
Please?
What time is it?
I gotta go.
I'll call you later.
Act to know.
Know how large amounts of money
to deal ...
with harmony and love.
And the truth is that you
great ideals have ...
and that you are somebody
with great integrity.
You have all your stuff.
Come home safely.
If you break up, I hate you.
I will be cold and all hurtful
my friends say.
You can not come and live with me.
Or be friends with my friends ...
or to imagine your parents.
This is what it is, whatever it is.
Are you ready?
-- Have you been waiting here all night?
Yes.
Why am I mad at you now?
Jamie, with Brucie.
If you want to meet me ...
I very much love
in my trunk for you.
Something you'll like, Jamie.
Call me, you'll love me.
Jamie, Bruce.
Where are you?
Who are you?
Let the games begin.
Men with diabetes and prostate cancer ...
men with big penis injuries,
men with performance anxiety ...
men with any ordinary kind of incompetence
or sexual dysfunction.
Men without erectile function
years to ...
Few side effects,
safe in the long term.
This is not a pill, but a revolution.
Any other questions?
-- Yes, where are the monsters?
Here.
Are you sure you want one?
Who needs two?
Bob Dowle says his
TV commercials for Viagra ...
his wife's campaign for president
no harm.
He also says that the Viagra ads
Heather Locklear campaign to get into bed.
My brother.
Viagra, the little pill, to a gold rush
has begun for its manufacturer ...
The drug giant, Pfizer.
Ted Goldstein.
-- How are you?
Well, I have this friend ...
the radiologist, he has a small problem.
I thought maybe ...
Say no more.
Viagra is the first pill
impotence remedy that.
It's easy, effective
and there is now very much in demand.
Al oncologists, psychiatrists, radiologists ...
pediatricians prescribe it for themselves.
Pharmacies can sell 24 hours
and then not meet the demand.
We have 1200 recipes a month.
That's more than my quota for the whole year.
And you can not care.
-- A bunch of old men with a stiff?
No.
-- How can you be so indifferent?
Global lead men to shame ...
and frustration ...
You're my little blue pill.
Oh, no.
Do you think that is okay?
I do not want to see.
What are you doing?
No, this is too much information.
You take it now?
Even with close ups and stuff?
Those who hold it?
Wake up.
Again?
Come on.
I am an artist. This is work.
Say something.
This is really weird.
Hi, I'm Jamie Randall.
I do report from bed.
I just fucked my girlfriend.
And ...
-- Do not share it.
You have it all the fucking time.
-- You fuck your girlfriend.
You are.
Is that me?
-- Yes, you.
I think I am.
No, ma, it's not exciting way.
It dilates blood vessels.
A blood vessel widening drug.
No, ma ...
Yes, I have this month
2000 prescriptions sold.
A lot of money. I know.
I can not talk now.
Maggie needs me.
The 1200 regulations were anyway?
That is true.
Why did you say 2000?
Did I say that?
Are you serious?
It sounded better.
You lied because it sounded better?
She has no sense of figures ...
Do this with me?
No.
-- Why to her?
She wants me to do it right.
-- And that is true.
Why does it sound even better?
I will call her back
and correct my mistake.
Tell me four good things about yourself.
Pardon?
-- You heard me.
Four good things about myself ...
I can ...
Why are we doing this?
This is so ...
Not even four good things.
-- I can do that.
You find yourself generous?
You'll love yourself?
Not really.
-- You think you smart?
You look at that.
You are ...
a talented ...
charming, handsome, skilled, smart man.
Is that so?
Yes.
I Shake.
Does it make it longer?
-- The time or length?
And what if we take it?
-- I can.
So we can be loud?
-- No, there would be an increased lubrication.
When they come inside you,
burn it?
And in your mouth?
We want more Viagra.
-- More!
What's going on here?
-- This is Dr Stan Knight.
This is ...
-- Cassy.
But my friends call me Lisa.
Lisa wants to "marry a doctor.
Success.
Ladies, the next round of me.
Nice vest, man.
Have you fucked?
-- Yes.
Six times.
I was afraid not.
You're crazy.
Is everything okay?
Honey, your hard knocks very fast.
-- I know.
What is ...
It's okay.
Talk to me.
I ...
Just breathe.
Do not worry about it.
It's okay.
I ...
I love you.
-- What?
Give me a moment.
Really.
No, you're not.
-- Do not touch me!
Want a glass of water?
-- Sorry.
It does not matter. What water?
-- Yes.
Please.
I love you.
-- Do not keep saying.
I can not.
I love you.
You do not understand.
I have never said to anyone.
Never say?
-- No.
Never tell your parents?
No.
-- By your brother?
You're even more screwed up than me.
I said it once at a cat.
It makes me feel better.
You can hold me now.
Joshy?
That's disgusting.
Jamie? I did not know you came home.
It is not what it seems.
Well, some do.
Just do quiet.
-- Quiet?
I thought I just caught my brother
to masturbate while he sees me fuck.
I aimed at her.
Her ... My girlfriend?
-- No.
Sorry.
-- Not her.
Her body parts.
Making things more videos ...
because I did not know her
breasts were so large.
Then I saw you:
Is there a loose Anaconda?
This is so insane.
-- Do you have that big?
That was so when we were kids,
but then you find anything great.
Okay, I'm sorry.
My self--esteem prefer
you do not currently have bigger penis.
Not angry.
Walk, Josh. Run.
Calm down, we can talk about it.
You will ruin the tape.
No normal human body
fits the back seat.
That definition is not applicable to you.
-- A Hot Wheel would be even better.
My legs are numb.
Are you okay?
-- No.
I'm not against you.
Are you okay?
-- Yes.
He is waiting for you.
-- How are you?
Good.
And Maggie?
Come inside.
No, come inside.
Testosterone.
Chicago within two days.
I must prepare myself.
It's a fucking orgy, masquerading as
medical conference. You get it?
No idea.
-- How's she doing?
Great.
-- With me.
I do need a break.
That job will kill me.
I have many women need
hard for me to fall.
Talks about having ...
You are one God.
Do you really not?
-- You can do something for me.
And that is?
No longer prescribe Zoloft
instead of Prozac.
Trey is a friend of mine.
I know.
Of course, Zoloft, why not.
How was your day?
-- Great.
Your day?
-- My day was ...
great.
I went to the hospital.
For a recipe ...
and waited three hours in addition
a man 's fork in his head.
What?
And then to the pharmacist ...
the recipe to exchange.
But it was closed.
This was Maggie's story.
Are you okay?
I look bad or something?
-- I did not say.
Not aloud.
Thanks, it would taste.
Sorry.
Do not have enough, do you think?
No. But you do.
Pardon?
Tell me what's so
sexually attractive to me?
There are 600 girls
you like pipe that convention.
I'll not go.
-- Why not?
A sexy, lithe cheerleader
from Alabama to take ...
who longed for sales forecasts
and discuss sales techniques ...
or as a manager who likes horny
bake and you have your head caresses.
while discussing the bad products.
Or a normal person ...
which has energy has
fun things to do.
I would now happen to you.
-- Why?
What are you trying to prove?
That you're not unreliable?
Or are you trying to "something" to remain in your life?
You realize that you are not good
person because you're a sick girl fucks?
I almost went with someone
from the hospital home.
Do not forget your pager.
No.
It's okay.
Go to Chicago.
How you doing, man?
Good to see you.
You okay?
-- I'm going to do something feminine.
How can I reach you?
-- I beep you.
Stage 1?
Excuse me?
-- My son is in stage 3.
It is not.
Do not worry.
We are across the street.
If you are tired of being
and want to know what is really going on ...
Thanks.
To hell with soup
and shoe laces.
To hell with jewels
and brushing teeth.
To hell with your tie knots.
To hell with a shirt unbutton.
-- And with that nonsense meditation.
And who knew that God wanted
we were so good ...
in masturbation.
My husband laughs constantly.
Parkinson's is perhaps ...
sensitive and meevoelender made.
Hopefully I will go long in it.
I feel good ...
and ...
-- It's a constant struggle.
I try to maintain some dignity and grace
and so you live with what you have.
ON THE FRONT OF THE STREET
Join ME
Just hold the child
and he ends up in a tree.
A friend of mine asked
if she had to get something for me ...
and I said, new brains,
nothing special.
She said: My husband
used by him.
Wait.
No, forget it, I thought
I heard a vibration coming cure.
But there are good things.
You must understand ...
you're still yourself.
You're still
and life goes on ...
and that life is beautiful.
Thanks.
Parkinson, huh?
No.
-- Your wife.
Girlfriend.
Stage 1.
Good days and bad days.
-- Mostly good days.
You?
-- Women, since 1973.
Stage 4.
Any advice?
-- You do not need.
You learn a lot from me.
Go pack your things, leave a note
behind and find a healthy woman.
I love my wife
but I would not do it again.
Nobody tells you that disease takes away all
so you love her.
Her body, smile, memory.
Soon she loses control
on her movements.
Ultimately succeed dress anymore.
Then the fun really begins.
Her mess cleanup.
A stiff face, dementia ...
It is not a disease but a Russian novel.
I'm sorry and I'm not lying.
Take care.
Did you know that other people
who have Parkinson's?
How unusual.
Great people.
They even run marathons.
And one diving. They are furious.
So as to be sidelined. They are so cool.
I feel so good.
That was so long ago.
And you brought me here.
It was for a convention, but ...
I've been such a bitch.
And you even walked away.
This looks like ...
the first time in my life ...
I do not feel lonely.
That someone for me.
You know what that means?
I love you.
Really.
What are you doing?
Nothing.
-- I fell asleep.
A drug for Parkinson?
I ask.
-- I am a general physician.
Twenty universities,
fifteen teaching hospitals ...
every large medical company
working at it.
From the moment they discover
You will adopt the first to sell me.
But meanwhile they get worse.
What is a teaching hospital?
What do you want me to do?
Do you feel bad for Stan.
If I need to know when each patient
I can not help get the day.
What are the latest treatments?
-- No idea. Want a list?
Great. Tomorrow.
Pfizer, you're a nice kid.
You're doing well.
Want to make sure?
-- And a list of doctors ...
and someone I can contact in case
The Ministry of Health.
Of course.
Do you see this green area here?
-- Yes.
Excuse me.
Good?
Damn!
I'm sorry Mr. Randall,
The credit card was rejected.
The benefits of chelation are
each toxic metal is removed.
Complete remission in patients
with an invasive cancer ...
multiple sclerosis ...
Damn.
-- Parkinson's, Lupus ...
This therapy is life changing.
He forgot world peace.
So we flew 3000 kilometers ...
to be told that our appointment moved?
For two weeks?
I want to talk with Dr. Rosenblum.
Do I look like as if I care?
I do not care where he is.
I do not understand how ...
Call the head of the hospital.
Our whole schedule is arranged forward
and then ... No, you do not understand!
Two weeks! I want to head to speak.
I am that people are so Sat
-- I want to go home.
We do the test and then we go.
-- Randall ...
All these new protocols ...
-- Try me now nothing to sell.
Good? I'm not cured.
-- This is nonsense.
This is nonsense.
I'm tired and bored.
Why?
-- I have Parkinson's, it's not my life.
Why do I need this project?
Is what lies before me
not bad enough?
Will not you heal?
-- No. That is you.
It is important to you too suddenly.
-- What are you talking about?
Will not you cure it?
-- Yes, despairing. This does not happen.
News Item: There is no cure.
You should know that I heal,
so you can keep me.
That is ridiculous.
Get your stuff out of my apartment.
Why is that?
You're on an express train, Randall.
Chicago, management ...
Next stop: CEO.
That is not a sick man who holds you back.
-- I can do whatever I want.
I know.
You're a good person.
Even a great person,
much more than you admit.
Nobody wants to be the one who runs away.
I'm not running away.
-- It's not your choice.
Just go home,
Go even making love ...
and then you leave.
It's so crazy.
-- Stop.
You should not do.
Goodbye.
Hello, you speak with Mr. Murdock.
If I dont pick up,
I do not talk down.
This is really sad.
Do you want him in the trash or around it?
Stan, how are you?
-- That your girlfriend Lisa or Cassie ...
organized a pajama party tonight
with someone who has.
A pajama party?
-- Do all girls than pajamas?
Undress themselves?
-- You may want to take some vitamin V.
A blue pill.
I'd love to, but I can not.
-- What are you doing?
I agree, Jamie.
Yes, I'll be there. Bye.
We are going to show a pajama party.
Get ready because I have a pajamas.
I doubt, Jamie. A pajama party
has suffered since the fourth year.
What if people take off their clothes?
I did not even come. You do.
People will see me naked. I
not even pee with others nearby.
You have a beautiful body.
How often do I say?
That confuses me greatly, as you say.
Look who's here:
Our working class.
Come inside.
How do I fucking a good doctor
with fifty patients per day?
Plus visit. And every day
phone calls with family.
The fucking idiots.
They say you're wrong,
because they've looked on the internet.
I fight about taxes,
on rules ...
The insurance are determined not to pay.
And the big law firms
just wait ...
Even bet that you
that one big mistake.
This was a job came calling.
People's lives improve.
And look at me ...
Here you are in God's name.
Randall, get off the floor.
Come on.
Come on!
Are you okay?
-- Go, my son.
Be fruitful and multiply.
Software is very unstable.
You never know how the funding expires.
It changes every six months.
You never know what these hospitals
want.
On one day, the peer--to--peer activity.
The other day it goes down.
Integration into existing infrastructure.
You can touch them, if you will.
Thanks.
No, no.
-- You'll see.
I do not think we should ...
-- Turn around.
This is my friend, Khae.
She comes from Thailand.
And am eager to Thai '...
It is "eager to Jamie.
So do I.
Did I mention that my company
stand on the Stock Exchange?
Exciting, you work on something for so long ...
You'll see how it is paying off ...
I have really mixed feelings about.
We feel like Jamie.
-- We find Jamie very much.
What is it?
Sorry.
We were just talking.
We should go.
-- Now?
Nice to have met.
We keep in touch.
It feels like an ice lolly.
I did not even know this could happen.
-- It is very rare.
But it happens.
Should I amputate?
-- Shut up and drive on.
Bad joke.
Sorry, I wanted to switch.
It's so fucked.
It was really the best night of my life.
That's great.
-- Seriously.
I'm not kidding.
That I owe to you.
I never thought I
such an experience would experience.
This is incredible.
Why I am so happy.
Because I've fucked that girl.
I thought to myself, "this feeling".
I feel absolutely nothing.
That's great, Josh.
All those years I was so jealous of you
numb that you had sex.
And now I feel less sex.
At that moment I realized,
if I had not experienced ...
I did not know how much I did not want.
Now I can return home to Farrah ...
and I can for the first time in my life
feel good.
All because of you Jamie.
All thanks to my big brother Jamie ..
with that huge cock that does not want to be weak.
Thank you, brother.
Sorry, my fault.
And my shares of Pfizer
are 40%.
Can I help you?
-- I have a reaction to medication.
What reaction?
Sit down.
We'll be with you
What?
Chicago.
I got it.
Congratulations.
That's incredible.
Jamie, that's what you've always wanted.
I am very proud of you.
I am not surprised.
But I'm very proud of you.
Mom and dad are ecstatic.
Jamie Randall made it.
Unbelievable.
You should be very proud of yourself.
Boeuf Bourguignon if they serve ...
they should at least
serve a good Burgundy.
Or a Pinot.
This is Jeremy.
I'm going to the car.
-- Okay, Justin.
I tried ...
I tried to call you.
-- I am dating someone.
I see.
How are you?
Good.
Come on.
-- I gotta go.
It's nice to see you again.
You kill me, Randall.
-- There he is.
Ready to celebrate?
How are you?
-- What do you celebrate?
This young rock star is Chicago
take by storm.
You go to Chicago.
Congratulations.
Good to see you, Bruce.
I gotta go.
-- Good to see you, Maggie.
Peace.
I knew it.
Did not I tell you?
Tell him I said so.
-- You should have bet.
Where do you live?
-- In the center, perhaps.
Somewhere far away from my family.
-- In the center?
You have to go to the north.
Pussies.
Bistros, bars and pussies.
Or in your area. What outside
the city. We'll drink a beer once ...
You do not want to do.
-- Why not?
I get a big salary increase.
You're kidding.
-- Thanks to you.
Those bastards.
I had never had Chicago.
I'm far too valuable to the front.
-- I do not believe.
Give me some credit.
There is need for a trained eye for talent
at such an idiot like you to recognize.
I do not understand.
-- Not so naive. I did not go to Chicago.
I wish that you would think so
you would go to Chicago.
So you get one in the round would work
to get there.
Bruce, this is unbelievable.
-- I love the street.
I love stinky motels and country lanes
and small shops.
I like that.
Why would I want to live in my own house?
What I pay for. Why should I
want to see my kids play baseball?
Why in the same bed
if my wife want to sleep?
Why the hell would I want to do?
Talk?
I'm Maggie Murdock.
So I'll have great sex
with ...
What's your name?
Jamie and some more.
We take it on, so it's always
I know how terribly sexy. Was.
Children, when you watch this, put it
now in mummy's secret hiding place ...
or you will regret it.
There will be consequences ...
What else?
Just how happy I am.
Now, at this time.
How the light illuminates your face ...
There is a little breeze through the window ...
it does not matter if I have 10,000 of
get these moments ...
or just this one but, because ...
all the same.
Yes, just that.
Now, this moment.
I have this.
Where is she?
Come on.
Want to talk to you.
Open the door.
Sorry.
I need you.
-- Please leave.
I've driven very long to say.
-- Should I be impressed?
I do not know.
Yes.
Get off the bus,
then we can talk.
Just for a moment.
-- We are on track.
Five minutes.
Please.
You do not really like five minutes?
He's cute.
-- Five minutes.
Five minutes, I'll let you go.
I'm an asshole.
I know I'm an asshole.
Because ...
I have never in my life
given to anyone or anything.
Everyone just accepted that.
Like, "That's Jamie."
But you ...
You ...
You saw me like that.
I never knew someone ...
who truly believed that I ...
enough.
Until I had met.
And then you let me believe that.
So, unfortunately I need you.
And you need me.
False.
-- Welwaar.
Welwaar.
-- Say no more.
You need someone who takes care of you.
False.
-- Everyone needs it.
I will give you more than you need me.
That's good.
-- No, that's not good.
That's not fair.
I must draw near to places.
-- Since you're going.
Maybe I'll wear it.
I can not ask of you.
You did not do so.
Let's just say ...
that in an alternate universe
as a couple, like us.
Only it is healthy and he's perfect.
And their world is about how much money
holiday will give them out.
Who has a bad mood that day or they
feel guilty that they have a maid.
Those people would not be me.
I want us.
You, this.
I was always care about who
I would be if I was an adult.
How much money I would earn, or ...
I might ever be something big.
Sometimes, the things you most want,
that never happen.
And sometimes it happens the one you
never expected.
As my job in Chicago to give up
and everything ...
and the decision to stay.
And medical school applications.
I do not know.
You meet thousands of people ...
and none of them really touches you.
And then you meet a person ...
and your life has changed.
Forever.
Translated by Simply Releases Toppers
Tokke Suurtje
Downloaded from www.simplyreleases.com
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org