POLITICAL CONSTITUTION
OF THE UNITED STATES OF MEXICO
HEROD'S LAW
My God, they lynched a Mayor
just when the President...
is talking about modernity
and social peace.
Don't fuck this up, López.
Don't worry, Mr. Governor. We've taken
the necessary steps to deal with it.
I'm talking about
the Presidency of Mexico, no less.
If I'm not careful, that asshole
Ruiz Cortinez will beat me to it.
I want to get through this clean.
If I don't get at least a ministry,
I'm out of the game.
Don't worry, General.
I assure you that
you are valuable to the party.
Look, López.
If you want to be governor,
everything must be resolved.
If people mention our state,
they must speak well of it.
You know better than anyone
who elects who around here.
If you want my job, don't give me any
problems like this San Pedro business.
Lynching a mayor when President Alemán
speaks of modernity and justice.
Don't fuck this up, Ramírez.
Don't worry, Licenciado.
We'll find someone soon.
This has to be resolved today.
I need to arrange things
with the governor.
He said I've been chosen,
so get looking.
Find me someone not too bright.
He will hold the post
for three or four months.
What do you think of him?
- Who's he?
- The least bad, but he's straight.
- He threatened to quit the party.
- No, no.
And this?
That's ''Sticky Fingers''.
I doubt he'd accept a shitty job
like Mayor of San Pedro.
And this one who looks
like Tintán. Vargas?
He's been in the party for
years. He joined when I did.
He's a good man. He'll
probably accept.
What do you mean
''a good man''?
I mean he's stupid.
Fine. Go and get him.
''Institutional Revolutionary Party
-Juan Vargas''
''Cleaning Department
Supervisor''
Good morning.
Ramírez?
Ramírez!
Fucking Vargas, you have to
call me Licenciado now. Okay?
It's been a long time.
Is that car yours?
Yes. Licenciado López sent me.
He wants a word with you.
The governor's secretary?
What about?
You're in a fine mess. Hurry up.
He's waiting for us.
Go in.
Wait for me here.
And behave, asshole.
Yes, tell him I'll call him.
Afternoon, Vargas.
-It's an honor, Licenciado.
-Sit down.
I'll be straight with you, Vargas.
As you know, modernity
has at last come to our country.
We must embody the ideals
of the revolution...
make President Alemán's
words reality...
help the country advance...
stamp out corruption, especially the mess
caused by those who don't agree.
Certain government
workers don't understand this.
They have taken advantage of their posts
to engage in private business..
and grow rich at the
nation's cost.
This country needs true patriots,
people like you.
Thanks, Licenciado.
I'm going to need your help.
Just tell me who
I have to kill.
No, no, Vargas. Times have changed.
You heard what happened
in San Pedro de los Saguaros?
The people rioted.
There was some kind of problem there...
and now there is nobody in charge.
We have to appoint a temporary mayor
who will keep order until the elections.
Right.
And how can I help, Licenciado?
You came up short, Ramírez.
Don't be a fool, Vargas.
The party has taken note of
you and I'm informing you...
that you are to be temporary Mayor
of San Pedro de los Saguaros.
M-Mayor? Me?
So you see how the revolution
is just with people like you.
I trust you totally, Vargas.
Totally.
This is a real opportunity. Maybe even
the start of a great political career.
That's right, isn't it?
Go to San Pedro and fulfill President
Alemán and Governor Sanchez's promises:
''Modernity and social justice.''
But listen
I don't want any problems.
If they mention San Pedro de los
Saguaros in the capital...
they'd better say nice things.
No messing things up.
Understood?
Don't worry, Licenciado.
How can I thank you?
Thank the party.
Remember:
''We owe everything to the party''.
There's more.
Here, take this.
Governor Sanchez himself
gave it to me...
so it's sure to bring you luck.
There.
Thank you, Licenciado.
Now all you have
to do is go to work.
Yes, sir.
Ramírez, brother,
thank you, thank you.
Licenciado!
Thank you, Licenciado.
Excuse me, Licenciado.
Here you go, Ramírez.
President Alemán gave me this as a gift.
Now it's yours
for finding me that fool.
Nothing more and nothing less
than mayor, honey.
Finally, after so many years
in that party...
something good happens to us.
Are you happy, sweetheart?
And this is just the start.
You'll see.
If I do well,
next stop is State Deputy...
then Congressman, my golden dream.
Just imagine, your name
on a plaque in the National Congress.
Better still, imagine:
Senator and Mrs. Vargas.
That doesn't sound bad.
Not bad at all, Mrs. Senator.
Not bad at all.
Excuse me. How far is it to
San Pedro de los Saguaros?
Good afternoon.
Excuse me.
Do you speak Spanish?
I think we're lost.
How far is it to
San Pedro de los Saguaros?
It's right here.
You must be the new mayor.
I've been waiting for you
since yesterday.
I'm Carlos Pek, your secretary.
Juan Vargas, at your service.
President Alemán and
Governor Sanchez...
have sent me to bring
modernity and social justice.
We've arrived.
Welcome, Madam.
Here?
''TOWN HALL''
You should go
and see your office,Juan.
What for? This is enough for me.
A fucking little backwater.
We're better off
in the garbage dump.
Don't say that.
You were nobody at the dump.
Here you are the chief.
The mayor.
Didn't you hear how they even
called you Licenciado?
- He did call me Licenciado, didn't he?
- Yes.
Do you honestly think
we are better off here?
Of course. Don't you see?
Here we're important people.
It's just the start,
but we have to be very, very...
smart.
Good morning.
Pek? Pek?
Word is out that there's a new mayor.
Everyone wants their affairs dealt with.
Please tell them I'll
see them later.
Alright, let's get to work.
- What's this, Pek?
- Unresolved matters, Licenciado.
There are many more, but these
are the most urgent.
These are agrarian problems.
This is--
Do you know what, Pek?
I think we should talk a stroll
so that I can get to know the place.
Don't you think so?
The village is very small--
less than 1 00 inhabitants.
Most of us Indians
who've lived here all our lives.
Good morning.
Don't be offended, Licenciado.
They are good people...
but most of them
don't even speak Spanish.
Really?
Don't they learn it at school?
Licenciado.
Look.
- That was the school.
- What happened?
They built it in the days
ofTata Cardenas.
When the government changed,
they stopped paying the teacher...
and one day he left.
The same old story Licenciado.
What about the doors,
windows and everything?
That was one of
your colleagues.
What did he do?
One day, the bastard sold them...
along with the blackboard
benches and anything of value.
I don't believe it.
He didn't sell the walls because
nobody wanted to buy them.
He'd have sold the whole
village given the chance.
This has happened
with every mayor we've had Licenciado.
Listen Pek. What happened to
my predecessor?
Why did he quit?
Licenciado...
Didn't they tell you?
They cut off his head
with a machete!
What?
They cut it off, and that's not the end
of the story of the Mayors of San Pedro.
Another one was hanged,
another almost burned alive.
Three mayors killed in 5 years.
Why would they send me?
I don't know...
but they must have done
something, no?
Who knows?
But...just in case.
Good morning.
What's this, Pek?
Manslaughter.
Licenciado Vargas,
This is Doctor Morales.
Pleased to meet you, Doctor.
Six bullets.
This, like all the evils in San Pedro...
is due to that brothel.
I suppose you know it.
No, no.
With him, that's eight dead men...
not counting the diseases
half the village is infected with.
Something must be done
about that place!
Don't worry, Doctor. I'll take
the necessary steps to close...
It's your duty!
I've only arrived. I promise...
It's very easy. Do your job
and everything will be fine.
If not I promise you'll regret
ever coming to San Pedro.
Who's this man, Pek?
Doctor Morales is someone to
watch out for, Licenciado.
He's been the PAN candidate
for mayor four times...
and always complains about fraud.
Can you believe it?
From now on,
he's going to be your worst nightmare.
So it seems.
You can't imagine it.
- What shall we do, Pek?
- He had no relatives.
I suppose it's up to us.
We don't open until eight.
-I want to speak with your boss.
-She's sleeping.
Tell her it's the new mayor.
Wait here.
She says come in.
Miss, ah, how much
are you charging?
What can I do for you?
Good morning. Sorry to wake
you up at this hour, Doña...
-Lupe.
-Juan Vargas, at your service.
Sit down, Licenciado.
Get lost, you.
- A drink?
- Not in working hours.
Well, a little shot never
did any harm.
So you're the new mayor.
At your service, Madam.
And the thing is...
How can I say?
...that certain people are not
happy about your business.
Ah, Licenciado, you're just
like all the others...
...coming here for your
bribe, right?
No, madam, nothing of the kind.
It's just that people--
People or Dr. Morales? That old
son of a bitch won't leave me alone.
He turns the Indians
and everyone against me.
It's not just the Doctor.
There's a corpse outside--
someone who was shot here yesterday.
A corpse? No, Licenciado.
Someone's pulling your leg.
- Nothing like happened here.
- The thing is...
No, Licenciado, everything is in order.
Don Alfredo Garcia who was mayor
before you, gave me all the permits.
Are you going to take
this or not?
No, madam. There are things
which one can't do.
Why the hell not?
You're all the same, Licenciado.
You're not getting on your high horse
and telling me you're different.
No, Doña Lupe,
how can you say that?
I must shut this place down
for the good of the village.
Look, you fucking idiot.
Let's stop this right now.
If you have anything else to say, tell it
to the Priest. He calls the shots here.
-The Priest?
-Yes, the Priest, you heard me.
-Get out!
-Excuse me for bothering you.
-Scram.
-Excuse me.
-Shit.
-Good-bye.
And you, idiots. Get inside.
What are you doing there?
Excuse me, madam.
Doña Lupe,
what about the corpse?
Stick it up your ass!
Let's see, pal.
You said it yourself, Padre.
The flesh is weak and there
is much temptation.
Yes, but you get carried away.
-Oh, but Padre, you know.
-What does your husband say?
Nothing. He doesn't pay
me any attention.
Ego te absolvum. For penitence say
three Our Fathers and three Hail Marys.
Oh, and give me a peso
for every one of your sins.
-Oh, good morning.
-Good morning.
Chencha.
May I help you?
Good morning, Padre.
I'm Juan Vargas, at your service.
The new mayor.
I know all that.
I was going to come and see you,
but I've had a lot of work.
What can I do for you?
Well, I've got a lot of problems,
Padre.
-Spiritual ones?
-I wish they were.
I've got a corpse outside.
I just saw Doña Lupe,
and she said I should talk to you.
Not in here.
Outside, better.
Hey, my son, how much
does a Packard like this go for?
I really, don't know, Padre.
What shall we do about
the corpse?
He's starting to stink.
That's the authorities' problem.
I just do the blessing.
What about the brothel, Padre?
I spoke to Doña Lupe and she...
...said you'd given her permission.
Ah, Doña Lupe. Did you two
work something out?
What?
Did you come to
an agreement?
Padre, I'm not like that.
-Ah, come on.
-I swear it, Padre.
Don't swear! Do you think
this shepherd doesn't know his flock?
Well, she did make me an offer...
but that's not why I came
to San Pedro de los Saguaros.
You should've taken
the money.
San Pedro lacks many things...
and Doña Lupe performs
an important social function.
That's five pesos
for the blessings.
Thanks Padre.
Being mayor is exhausting, Pek.
I never imagined it would
be so difficult.
It's been a bad day,
Licenciado...
But don't give up. It's a matter
of solving the problems bit by bit.
You know what? Just before I
came here...
I heard a speech by the President
that gave me some ideas.
I think they'll work for us,
what do you think?
First, we'd have to fix the school.
Then pave the streets,
install drainage. People just shit--
If you'll allow me a few words,
Licenciado...
Wait. Don't make me lose my train
of thought when the ideas are flowing.
Something grand so that people
will remember us...
a dam or a highway linking San Pedro
de los Saguaros to the capital.
What do you think?
They're great ideas,
but there's a problem.
What?
Seven pesos.
It's all that's left of
the budget.
The last mayor, he spent it.
And since then, they haven't
given us anything.
I thought maybe
they'd sent something with you.
I'm not hungry.
You're not go to solve
anything like this,Juan.
We have to think of something.
You can't go back
to the garbage dump.
Without money,
I can't do anything.
Go and see Licenciado López
first thing tomorrow.
Tell him what your problems are
and ask him for a larger budget.
But he told me he didn't
want any problems.
But he didn't tell you
where he was sending us either.
Go see him. Play the martyr.
Take him a present.
That always works.
I know just what to give him.
In conclusion, President Miguel
Alemán declared before...
...the workers and peasant's sectors
that this devaluation...
...was painful but necessary,
and insisted that...
...by facing our problems decisively...
we can guarantee a bright future
for everyone.
No doubt there are people who
know how to do things well.
How can I tell
Licenciado López I can't do the job?
I'm putting my head on the line.
I'd rather be in your shoes.
Eat and sleep, sleep and eat.
That's life.
Fuck it!
-What?
-What happened to your car?
-The piece of shit broke down.
-Let's see if I can help you.
Get in.
Start it up.
Stop.
I think the engine's fucked.
Don't tell me.
It can be fixed,
but it won't be cheap.
Go ahead. I'll pay whatever.
Again, carefully.
-Hey, he who knows, knows.
-What do you say?
How much do I owe you?
Hey, for a Mexican friend,
just 1 00 dollars.
1 00 dollars?
Shit! But I don't have
that much money.
-Look, this is all I have.
-And the pig?
-No, it belongs to my boss.
-Well give me that.
But you'll leave me broke.
Look, this is what we'll do.
Go to San Juan de los Camotes
and wait for me there...
I'm the mayor, see? Emilio Gabriel
Fernandez Figueroa at your service.
I'll pay you there, okay?
-What?
-I said it's okay, my friend.
Don't worry. We Mexicans are
people of our word.
I'll pay you on time.
- Thanks a lot.
- Have a good trip.
Fucking Gringo,
same as the rest.
They want to take us for a ride.
But they don't know that
we Mexicans are better fuckers.
-What's this, Vargas?
-A present from San Pedro de los Saguaros.
Get that swine out of here!
-So, what's new?
-Well, Licenciado...
I don't know where to begin.
I'd like to see if it's possible
for you to give me a bigger budget.
No, Varguitas, no, no.
The elections are coming up
and all our funds...
...must go to the party
so that there are no surprises.
Ask me for anything, anything at all.
But not that. Not now.
Well, since you're giving me
the chance.
How about moving me to another town?
Fucking hell, you really
turned out to be a wise guy.
No way. It's Herod's Law here.
Either you fuck them
or you get fucked.
But there's no money left.
This makes it very difficult.
We need so many things.
Imagine if everyone asked me for money
like you.
When it runs out, it runs out.
But Licenciado, I planned
to do as you told me...
...that modernity
and social justice stuff, but--
But, the truth is, it's difficult.
I'll give you some advice.
Sit down.
Here you are.
Federal and State Laws.
Do I have to read it all?
No, no, Vargas.
This will earn you your money.
If you know how to use it,
you can get money out of anyone.
You've got fines, taxes, license fees.
Use the law to your benefit and
you're made.
Remember, in this country,
honesty gets you nowhere.
But you get me into deeper trouble.
They don't respect authority
in San Pedro.
Authority?
Come here. I'll show
you authority. Stand here.
Hit me here.
No, no, Licenciado.
Go on, man, don't be afraid.
Hit me here.
Come here, Vargas.
Do you understand?
I'm your boss. Your superior.
Get it?
Anyone who breaks the law is
messing with authority.
They'll be punished.
I'm the authority.
Got it?
But-- but the people
in San Pedro are wild.
Did you know they cut the
last mayor's head off?
They cut his head off?
That's easily solved.
Take it.
Go on. Take it.
If they threaten you with a machete,
show them the pistol...
...and see if they still
give you a hard time.
Keep it, man, keep it.
Put it away.
You'll kill someone like that. And
remember when you read it in this book:
Executive power, legislative power,
judicial power. That's you.
The maximum authority of
San Pedro of the what?
- De los Saguaros.
- San Pedro de los Aguados, you got it.
Go on, and keep the gun.
Thank you, Licenciado.
Take this little book and this gun
and enforce authority.
Thank you very much.
-Excuse me.
-Go ahead.
Gloria!
Sweetheart, I'm back.
-How did it go, my love?
-Very well.
-Are we going to move to another village?
-No.
-Then they raised your budget?
-No, sweetheart. But look.
-What's that for?
-Licenciado López gave it to me.
You're going to bring
us problems.
No, my love. On the contrary.
This is the solution to our problems.
I know how. I must
study and learn to use the gun.
Fine, but put it down.
It's making me nervous.
My pistol makes you nervous?
There are crimes against
public order, moral offenses...
...prostitution, endocinity
and white slavery.
Sweetheart, do you know what
en-do-ci-ni-ty means?
No, I don't.
Let me sleep.
Where the hell are you going?
Always trying to sneak away!
If I hadn't seen you what were
you thinking of?
I take my eyes off you and you
fuck up!
Who were you sneaking off
to see?
Get inside, asshole!
Ungrateful little tarts!
Nobody else would feed the pigs.
- Take it or I'll give it to them.
- Good morning, Doña Lupe.
What do you want,
you bastard?
With all due respect,
I have an order to close this house.
According to the penal code,
you're in violation of several laws.
Selling alcohol without a license,
involvement in manslaughter...
plagiarism, kidnapping,
procurement, rape...
corruption of minors,
threats, white slavery...
plus beating your employees
like that.
Look, this is my property,
alright Licenciadito?
In my house I'll beat up anyone
I fucking like. Got a problem with that?
Look, Doña Lupe. Here you can
read the laws where it's...
I don't give a shit about
your fucking laws!
Please, Doña Lupe. Have some respect.
I represent the Nation's Authority.
-You don't get it, asshole.
-Doña Lupe. Please, Doña Lupe.
I want us to communicate
like decent people.
Who do you think
you're going to scare?
You need balls to use that gun, asshole!
Coward! Come back, you son
of a fucking bitch!
Come back!
Son of a bitch!
What's up, Licenciado?
If they ask for me,
tell them I've gone.
No, that I don't work
here anymore.
Are you sure it was in the leg?
I think so, sweetheart.
Let's go.
Well, so what? That's what your boss
told you to do, right?
Yes. Something like that.
You're the authority, honey.
They have to respect you.
It's just that this lady...
Get back to work.
-Is your idiot boss in?
-Doña Lupe.
Come in, come in.
Good morning, Doña Lupe.
Come in.
How have you been?
- Pek please leave us.
- You too, get out.
Please madam.
You're looking very well.
I wanted to apologize.
Cut the crap, Vargas.
Let's get to the point.
How much do you
want to leave me alone?
No, Doña Lupe,
the law must be obeyed.
Then just look the other way.
What does it matter?
Your business is very crooked,
Doña Lupe.
But you only know that because
are reading that huge book.
Here's more money.
You promise nobody will know,
Doña Lupe? You promise?
Nobody will find out.
So now we understand
each other.
You're a tougher cookie
than I expected.
Let me help you, Doña Lupe.
Get off, I can manage.
And to show you I don't bear a grudge,
come to the brothel.
I'll invite you
to one of my girls.
Thank you, Doña Lupe.
See you there.
Nosy little tarts!
Look at you!
Hello.
''Entry forbidden to Women,
Minors, Soldiers in Uniform...
...Animals and Indians''.
Fifty? No way. But how?
I don't make that much.
Well, how much
can you manage?
Well...
Maybe twenty,
once in a while.
Good. We'll discuss your
taxes later, eh?
Thank you.
Oh, that sign by the door.
It's hard to understand, confusing.
Take it down.
Just look at that.
Pek, fine this asshole.
What for, Licenciado?
Let me think.
Lock him up and we'll decide later.
Don't let him out until
he pays a fine of five pesos. No, six.
Juan, come to bed.
What's that?
Where did you get
all this money?
Oh, it's not mine. You won't
believe this.
It's money from contributions,
taxes, fines.
They're calling it something else
in town. Especially Dr. Morales.
He's going around saying
you're the worst one yet.
You be careful, dear.
That old bastard could ruin
everything.
I have to convince him that I'm
doing this for the good of the community.
I know.
Why don't we organize a dinner and invite
all the important people of San Pedro?
We've the money now.
That's what all politicians do, right?
Okay.
I love you, my dear.
Good evening, friend.
I looked for you everywhere.
Where's my money?
How are you doing,
Sam, buddy?
My name isn't Sam. It's Robert.
Robert Smith. Nice to meet you.
What's this,Juan?
Gloria, this my friend, Robert.
He almost saved my life.
Hey, I want my money. You owe me,
remember?
I want you to pay me now. It's late
and I don't want to be on the road.
No, no way.
You stay with us here.
Gloria make us something to eat...
or they'll say that
we Mexicans are bad hosts.
Alright, I'll stay.
And the money?
Look friend. The country is
experiencing economic problems.
We'll talk about money tomorrow.
Go and get your things.
Okay.
Where's he going to sleep?
Look, I've got a good proposal for you.
Help me and I swear
I'll pay you everything. Plus interest.
What is it?
You play engineer and help me
modernize this village.
These people have all got money
stashed under their mattress.
Sure, but I want my money up front.
Look, I'm not talking about $1 00.
You could be making
a grand or more.
Maybe. But I want 50%
of what you get.
Fucked.
-I'll give you 20%.
-Fifty or nothing.
Okay.
As you know, we Mexicans
are men of our word.
Here, distrustful paleface.
Here's your paper.
Did you write down all
about the interest?
Yes. It's all there.
Okay, friend.
To our partnership.
-What?
-Partners. Cheers.
Cheers, partner.
-Tell me, Mr. Gringo.
-Yes?
Is it true that your countrymen
are still very angry...
about the expropriation of
the oil business?
Well, a bit. But they know that
in time we'll get it all back.
And more. Much more.
What did he say?
He says that in the US they
think we're a dictatorship.
-And I agree with him.
-The perfect dictatorship!
No, no. Forgive me, but that's
why we had a revolution.
In Mexico the vote is respected.
It's not our fault
that people always vote for my party.
If there was real democracy in Mexico,
the President would be a priest.
Don't exaggerate, Doctor or
Padre Pérez would end up as governor.
Good idea, my son.
And you, you were involved.
What do you think, Pek?
Well, the revolution brought
many changes.
But we didn't fight it
to suit a few politicians.
The worst thing is that the poorest
are still just as poor.
Yes, Pek. You're quite right.
Fortunately, we made the revolution
the basis for our institutions...
and the country's future has
never been brighter.
Please, Licenciado, what future
are you talking about?
The government is in the hands
of a bunch of crooks.
Your boss is the worst of all,
that puppy of the revolution!
You, yourself are a fine example of
the class of scalawags that govern us.
What have you done besides
extorting anyone you can?
Tell us, what have
you done for the good of San Pedro?
Doctor, let me serve
you another drink.
No, honey. Sit down.
Ladies, gentlemen,
this is why I have invited you here.
As you know, I went to the
capital a few days ago...
...to discuss the serious
problems of the village...
...with the Secretary
of the Governor.
I want to inform you that...
that modernity will at last
come to San Pedro de los Saguaros.
We'll make the promises of our President
Don Miguel Alemán come true.
And how are you
going to do this?
I have specific instructions
to start immediately...
by bringing electricity to San Pedro.
And here, straight from the US,
is the engineer Robert Smith.
And that's nothing.
Once these works are done...
President Alemán himself
will inaugurate them. Cheers!
How thrilling!
Why didn't you tell me before?
Sit down, honey. Cheers!
-Cheers.
-Hey, dear.
-What?
Didn't you get a
bit carried away?
About what?
What you said about electricity
and the president.
No, honey. It's all true.
I spoke to the governor's secretary.
Tell them to pull harder, Mr. Pek.
As you see, Doctor.
My party always delivers.
You should have closed
the brothel first.
All in good time. First things first.
And the first thing my friend
is progress, the future of our nation!
-There's your great work.
-Fucking Gringo idiot!
Sorry, Mr. Mayor.
It was these Indians.
This never happens
with American workers.
Go on! Help them!
Pull! Again! Pull!
Good morning, Doña Lupe.
Know what day it is today?
And where is Esmeralda?
That fucking shameless dwarf.
How does he manage to be so brazen?
So, you don't have enough
money to pay taxes.
But what about this? Pay me.
-To you too, idiot!
-Let's go.
What? Listen who the hell
is going to pay me?
Show some respect, Doña Lupe.
One thing is one thing...
...but this is something else.
I'm here for your taxes.
How can I pay you, asshole?
Since you came to this village
I've lost all my clients.
Do what you want.
I have nothing to pay you with.
Well, look, Doña Lupe.
Maybe we can work something out.
I'm feeling very romantic.
-Alright, let's go.
-No, Doña Lupe.
What a son of a fucking bitch!
You've got no idea how
everyone has changed.
The only thing anyone talks
about is the President's visit.
What are they saying?
They're very excited
about the electricity.
Everyone speaks well of you, honey.
They say you're the first mayor
who is going to make good his promises.
I'm excited too.
Juan, I'm preparing you a surprise...
...so that you make
a good impression on the President.
What is it?
No, it's a surprise.
I'll show you when it's finished.
Oh,Juan if you keep on like this,
you won't just be a Congressman.
You'll be much more.
And I've also got
a present for you.
Couldn't you give it
to me tomorrow, honey?
I've had a very tiring day.
Hold on, hold on.
Look, Padre, not only is he corrupt.
He's lazy too.
I'm sure the whole
thing is a farce.
Pardon, Doctor? What are
you talking about?
I heard you're in business with
Doña Lupe.
You should know we're prepared
to take the necessary steps to sack you.
Excuse me, Doctor,
but the law authorizes me...
The law? The law you apply is a farce...
an excuse to steal money
from the people.
Tell him.
Tell him what we found out.
I don't want to get involved
in your business...
but the Indians have complained
to Doctor Morales about you.
Excuse me Padre, but I simply
apply what it says here.
Do you think I go around
making up laws?
Well, I've warned you.
Either things change
or you'll hear from me.
Nothing satisfies this guy.
That is the way of the opposition's--
critical of everything.
I'm going to give you some advice.
Be careful and don't go waving
that pistol around.
Put it away!
I swear that he is
taking it the wrong way.
Don't swear in vain.
I can help you with Dr. Morales,
but you're going to have to help me.
Whatever you say, Padre.
I'd be very grateful.
I want to buy myself
a car, you know?
-A car?
-Don't worry. I have savings.
I just want something modest...
an old Ford or a Packard like yours.
It's a good car, right?
Here, Padre.
But son, this won't even
buy me a tire.
Well, here.
Those who repent
go to Heaven.
Help me buy my car...
...and you won't
have any problems.
God bless you, my son.
Good luck, Padre.
Fucking priest!
-Good morning, Doña Lupe.
-What's good about it?
Get my money ready while
I have a quickie with Perla.
This bullshit is over
you son of a bitch!
What's up, Doña Lupe?
You just won't understand, asshole.
Pancho! Pancho!
Oh, shit.
This is the asshole
I told you about.
-Hi, buddy.
-Show him who's in charge now.
Throw him to the pigs!
-Doña Lupe, Doña Lupe!
-To the pigs with him!
-What's happening, Doña Lupe?
-Squeal like a pig!
I'm the representative
of the law.
My ass! Squeal like a pig!
Give him a good kicking!
My love!
What happened to you?
I fell down back there.
-What?
-You smell like a pig.
Fuck you! What's that?
Isn't it beautiful?
Bobby brought it.
Hey, wait. Today's Thursday and
you said I'd get an advance.
Don't bother me now, Gringo.
Leave him alone, Bobby.
Can't you see how he is? PoorJuan.
Well, to cheer you up...
I'll show you the surprise
I'm making for the President.
Surprise!
Do you like it?
-It is very nice.
-Bobby helped me.
I'm so pleased you like it, dear.
Now I'll show you how
we dance in America.
I'm telling you these bitches
are fucking with me.
Don't go soft on them or
they'll do whatever they want.
Stay in control is all I'm asking
you to do. You've seen--
Vargas, you're not planning to
kill me too, are you? No, no.
Please. Look, I'll give you
everything I've got. Look.
I've got more money in the house.
Put the gun down. You're too much
of an asshole with that gun.
Don't kill me!
Shhh. I've got news
for you, Doña Lupe.
Good news and bad news.
The good news is that those
who repent go to Heaven.
And the bad news?
It's your turn to
face Herod's Law.
There, you old witch!
That's for disrespecting me...
...and that's for not respecting
the nation's institutions...
...and that's for your foul mouth.
Juan,Juan, wake up!
What? What's the matter, honey?
I've been trying to awake you all day,
but I couldn't.
Where were you last night?
Well, I couldn't sleep and
I had some business to take care of.
Don't play dumb,Juan.
I know everything.
What do you know?
That you spend all day at the brothel
with Doña Lupe's whores...
...and one day,
you'll catch a disease off them.
Oh, my love! No way!
Honorable Congress
of the Union...
fellow Congressmen,
citizens and patriots.
Thank you for this distinction
from my party.
My party?
My party!
Gloria, Gloria. Have you
seen my ''PRI'' badge?
Maybe one of your
girlfriends has it.
-Is a son of a bitch.
-No, no. Is an...
My party, my party.
My badge!
What's this, Pek?
Some locals brought them. I
was looking for you to tell you.
But, but they're dead, Pek!
Where did they find them?
-In the deep creek.
-And what else? Tell me!
They were found this morning by some
peasants who were taking their animals out.
I think it was robbery Licenciado.
They had nothing
of value on them.
-That's very strange, Pek.
-Yes.
Go and take a statement
from the peasants.
-See if they know anything else.
-Yes, Licenciado.
Fucking Doña Lupe!
Even in death you won't leave me alone.
Rest in peace.
Thank you for coming, Padre.
Is this all the salvation
of a soul is worth to you?
But Doña Lupe left us nothing.
Even her shoes got stolen.
Good-bye, Licenciado.
Don't worry, Padre.
I'll take care of it.
Good-bye, daughters.
God bless you.
Girls, you know how sorry I am.
Doña Lupe was like... like...
a sister to me.
Always so happy, so kind.
But death comes when
we least expect it.
Thanks for coming, Licenciado.
And you know you can count
on me for anything.
Hey, listen. When do we
reopen the business, girls?
See, Doña Lupe? Nobody knows
who they're working for.
Afternoon.
What's up, Licenciado? Heard anything
about the murder of Doña Lupe?
We're on the case.
There are several suspects.
Everything points to a crime of passion.
Passion?
What about the robbery?
That was a red herring.
But I didn't come to discuss that.
I want you to do me a favor.
But I've already paid
you for the month.
No, no. Nothing to do with that.
I'm here to make a business proposal.
I've got to find a place
for Doña Lupe's girls...
...and I thought we could
get together on this.
No, Licenciado.
My business isn't prostitution.
I guarantee you, we'll get loaded.
What do you say?
No, Licenciado.
Fine.
Cheers.
Look! There's my boss.
He'll make it as governor, no?
Well, it won't be easy for him.
Terrazas is related to President Alemán.
He's got the party base
behind him-- even the unions.
My chief won't allow it.
He's a good bastard.
If he wins,
I'll be in the big league. Cheers!
Pek, Lady Luck is smiling on us.
Someone did us a big favor
getting rid of Doña Lupe.
And our boss is set to be governor now.
Nothing can stop us.
Good afternoon, Doctor.
You must be pleased.
You were the only person who
wanted Doña Lupe gone...
...and now it's going to be real
hard for her to come back.
Are you insinuating I had
something to do with this crime?
You were the only one who
had anything against her, right?
That's a lie! You are a
shameless opportunist!
Don't get excited, Doctor.
I'm sure you killed her.
But you'll be sorry, Licenciado.
That's it!
Listen, Licenciado.
This isn't a good idea.
Hardly anyone here can read.
It doesn't matter, Pek.
It's got to work for something.
-Doña Lupe. Fifty pesos.
-What?
-He's asking what it says.
-Didn't I tell you?
Come.
Only you could suggest that
the Doctor was guilty!
The old bastard. They're going
to fire me thanks to him...
...just when López is about
to be made governor.
Juan, we must do something.
Let him calm down.
Then early tomorrow,
go and apologize.
Humiliate yourself if you must
but calm him down.
Who knows what the bastard's
capable of?
Make something up.
Tell him you've found a suspect.
Hey, girl, is your boss in?
-Hello, Rosita.
-Hello.
I'm sorry to be here so early
without warning...
but I must speak with your husband.
Chencha! Go and fetch some firewood!
Stop hanging around!
Come in, Licenciado.
Come in, this is your house.
Thank you.
Please excuse my appearance, Licenciado.
-Rosita, is your husband here?
-No. He isn't.
Do you know where he went?
He was very angry.
He couldn't sleep all night.
He woke up very early
and went to the capital.
He went to complain about you
to your bosses.
Rosita, this was all a mistake.
I came to tell him
we've found a suspect and...
- No! Really?
- I have to go Rosita.
No, no, Licenciado. Stay here.
I'll take your mind off it.
That's fine. You can go.
Now, what's up?
You must help me, Padre.
I'm about to find myself out of a job
and you carless!
-Why?
-Fucking Dr. Morales. We had a chat.
Now he's gone to see
my bosses to tell them who knows what.
We must stop
him or we're fucked!
Forgive him, Lord.
Help me, Padre.
What are we going to do?
J... K...
L... M, M, M, M.
M. Martinez...
Morales... Doctor.
All the stuff about his wife,
but everyone knows that.
Ah, here it is. This will fix him,
but it's going to cost you.
What is it, Padre?
You remember the girl
who works for them, right?
''Not once, but many times,
at nightfall Dr. Morales...
violently entered my room
to abuse me sexually.''
Write down her details and sign it.
The Gringo too. As witnesses.
Listen, Licenciado.
Isn't this a bit exaggerated?
It wasn't exactly what the girl said.
Isn't it true, Chencha?
We cannot allow a degenerate
like him to go free.
We must act decisively.
Now I'm sure this Doctor is also involved
in the murder of Doña Lupe.
My husband's right, Pek.
We can't leave this poor child
with that old swine.
I think Chencha should stay with us,Juan.
She can help me at home.
No, no. I know who'll take care
of her better than anyone.
I'm very sorry, Doctor, Licenciado López
won't be able to see you today.
But I've been waiting all day.
I must speak to him.
I have something
very important to tell him.
I'll tell him. But if you like come back
tomorrow and maybe he'll have time.
Fucking PAN members!
-What does that asshole want?
-The same as usual.
He says Vargas of San Pedro
is embezzling...
and he's made a fortune
in that fucking village we sent him to.
Why don't you go home?
I'll stay on guard here, Licenciado.
No, no. I'm not moving from here.
I don't know why, Ramírez,
but I think today's the day.
But, Licenciado, you haven't eaten
or slept for three days.
I think--
Yes?
At your orders, General.
Are you sure? But, General...
Yes, yes. No, don't worry.
I'm a party man.
I know the rules.
Thank you for calling.
Fucking shitty party!
What's the matter, Licenciado?
Terrazas got the nomination
in the capital!
We're fucked!
Do you think Dr. Morales would live
in a shitty place like this...
if he wasn't in trouble?
No. Do you really believe that stuff
about the girls?
Six girls have denounced him.
But he seemed so decent and educated.
I never thought--
That's the sort of hypocrites
these PAN members are!
Forgive the intrusion, Licenciado...
...but we've caught a suspect.
Confess, Filemón!
I swear on my mother,
I didn't do anything, boss!
Somebody put those shoes on me.
I swear!
Don't write that, Pek.
I think you need something
to help you remember.
Go inside and see if you
can find a bottle, Pek.
Confess and I'll pay you well,
Filemón.
Confess, you bastard!
Yes, yes, yes! I did it!
What happened, Licenciado?
-Nothing, nothing.
-What's going on,Juan?
Nothing, honey. Go back to bed.
Take this down: he confessed.
On Thursday morning,
around seven o'clock...
...Dr. Morales sent for him...
...and offered him twenty pesos...
...and a bottle to do a little job.
Bastards! They want to send me
as Ambassador to Bolivia.
Me! The party's founder!
That's how those little Licenciados
pay me back!
They want to cut me out,
cut themselves in and not share the pie!
But what do we do?
We're not just going to fold our arms.
Of course not!
We'll form a new party, López.
The Party of the Real Revolution.
You'll see how those assholes react.
I swear, in six years' time
I'll have their ass!
I'll be President!
Good, but that's a long time to wait.
What do we do now?
Give them a scare, López.
Deal with it the way we used to
in my day.
Stop looking so sad, Filemón.
I know what's bothering you.
Look what I brought.
Oh, I didn't realize. Here.
Boss, I swear by Holy God,
I didn't do anything.
You know better than I do
where those shoes came from.
I found your PRI badge there,
between the bodies.
See? Let me go and I won't tell a soul.
I swear, boss.
Look, I've got a pal in jail.
I'll tell him you're my friend and
he'll make sure you're well looked after.
What do you say?
Go ahead.
Fucking Filemón,
you're really a good sort.
I need a piss.
How about you?
Okay, Filemón.
I'm not going to
help you with that.
There.
You're a good guy.
Fucking Filemón.
Look what you made me do.
I'm telling you again, Sharkey.
Don't let me down.
When Terrazas gets out of the car,
you go up to him, Negro, and blast him!
If they catch you,
say it was an accident.
When I become governor you'll be
out of jail and stinking rich.
Sharkey...
do you understand?
My future is in your hands.
Let's get to work.
Have you given it some
thought, Licenciado?
With all due respect,
it's very risky...
killing a candidate
in broad daylight.
There's no other way, Ramírez.
The dice are rolling!
Not that one, fucker.
Play the same one.
Fucking Filemón!
Look, Perlita.
It's like when you have
an asshole client and...
...he asks you for a screwball.
Would you do it?
Do you know what
a screwball is?
Sometimes you have to do
things you don't like.
That's Herod's fucking Law.
And the girls?
Girls? Girls!
How is Chenchita doing?
Did you think about it, girls?
Five percent of what you
earn is yours to keep!
Great business!
We're not sure, Licenciado.
Looks, my dears, you can't run
this business by yourselves.
I'll be your man,
once my boss is governor.
Fucking Filemón!
I already miss you, you bastard.
Play it again, Negro!
Negro!
Girls!
Licenciado, you're a day early.
How did it go?
Fine, Pek.
What about the Doctor?
He hasn't come back yet, but
there are more accusations against him.
Do you want to read them?
Another day.
I'm not in the mood right now.
Motherfuckers!
No, no, my love.
This isn't what it seems.
Don't speak English to me, you bastard!
This is the end
of the external debt, Gringo!
Go, Bobby!
Run before he comes round.
I want to explain to you, my love.
It's not what you think.
The Gringo forced me
because of what you owed him.
It was horrible, my love.
He insisted that I pay him.
I said we had no money and
he got really violent with me.
He tore my dress off.
It was horrible, my love.
Poor little thing. I understand, baby.
These fucking Gringos
are sons of bitches...
but you... you are...
you are a fucking bitch!
Slut!
Whore!
Stop it!
Come here, you bitch!
Now you'll see!
Juan.
Juan!
I'm checking to see if that
fucking Gringo robbed me.
Please forgive me,Juan.
You went with the hookers
in the brothel...
and I never said a word.
You can't keep me
tied up here like a dog.
Don't mention those treacherous sluts,
and don't mention dogs.
They're faithful.
Licenciado, Licenciado.
Things are getting out of hand.
Calm down, Pek. What's up?
Dr. Morales is back
and the locals want to lynch him.
Licenciado.
Yes, my old friend.
Juan!Juan!Juan!
Speak to them, Pek.
Tell them to go home.
I'll take care of it.
Open the door, Doctor!
- Licenciado Vargas, have they gone?
- Yes, they've gone. Step aside.
Doctor, for your own sake,
I advise you to leave town.
But why?
It's been discovered that you were
the intellectual assassin of Doña Lupe.
We have proof
and a signed confession.
But it's a lie!
Who would dare to accuse me?
You're also accused of
corrupting minors and of rape.
Your servant told us everything.
But, my little girl.
It can't be.
Chencha?
Doctor, you'd get at least
40 years for this.
But to show you how generous I am...
I'll give you till dawn to leave town,
or I'll wash my hands.
Let's continue.
In every trial the criminal order will--
That's useless too.
Write this down, Pek:
Article number whatever.
Given that recent events have severely
affected the revenue of the municipality...
it is decreed that as of today, the 9th
of October 1 949, without exception...
all the inhabitants of
San Pedro de los Saguaros...
must pay an extra tax
on their lands...
...cows, pigs, donkeys, hens, turkeys
and all other animals...
...known or yet to be discovered.
My God, Licenciado,
everyone's already very poor.
It isn't right to be so hard on them.
Don't exaggerate, Pek.
It's for the community's good.
Once I'm governor and you mayor
of a village, do whatever you want.
Don't distract me
or I'll lose my inspiration.
Let's continue.
As of today, the term of office...
...for local mayors shall be
extended from six to twelve...
...no, to twenty years...
...with four possibilities
of reelection.
You never know.
Two hens.
What did he say? What?
He has nothing left.
He can pay you after the harvest.
No. Tell him I'm sorry, Pek...
but we won't detain the progress
of the majority for a minority.
Lock him up. Next.
Look, Licenciado Vargas,
fire me if you want...
...but I can't be an accomplice
to all this bullshit.
You're the worst mayor
we've ever had.
What was that, Pek? Don't show me
disrespect in front of people.
- Sorry, Licenciado.
- Fuck you and your apologies!
We're going to have this out inside!
And you wait here.
Fucking fucked up village!
And to think I was going
to make you mayor, asshole.
Open up.
In you go,
you subversive old bastard!
Fucking moaning Indians!
You're just holding back
social progress, idiots!
It's your own fault.
I just wasn't making enough,
Licenciado.
I offered you a deal
and you turned it down.
Get the money
and you can reopen.
See what happens when you
only think about politics?
You didn't take care
of your business.
Looks like the bullets
are flying again.
Fuck it! Why didn't you tell me
my boss didn't get nominated?
He might still manage it
if the candidate dies.
I bet it was López
who ordered him killed.
You're mad, you bastard!
Those things don't happen in my party.
Who knows? Anything's
possible in politics, Licenciado.
Be careful.
See you.
Good luck, brother.
''At the scene of the murder attempt,
the police assist Terrazas...
who is taken to the emergency clinic.''
My boss? No way!
Remember the words
of our Lord.
You should forgive
your wife.
Forgiveness is the only thing
that brings the soul peace.
Shut up! What do you
know about women?
They're all the same bitches!
Leave her chained up if you want,
but forgive her.
Have you heard three more
families left town?
Yes, yes.
Don't worry about it.
How can I not worry?
You're acting like a monster.
Not really, Padre. Don't be a fool...
You've never had it so good.
But keep worrying,
because if anything happens to me...
you're in deep trouble.
Anyway, I repented
so I can go to Heaven.
See you, Padre.
Juan...
...you can't keep
me like this forever.
You're right, honey.
Fix me some dinner.
Look, look. All this
could have been yours.
Now what's the matter?
You want to poison me,
don't you?
No, no. You're going insane,
you bastard!
Shut up! Show me
some respect, bitch!
Be very careful not to
do anything stupid!
Oh, fuck it!
Stop! Stop, I tell you!
I didn't do anything.
What's the matter
with you Vargas, eh?
Oh, Sharkey, my friend.
Licenciado López wants a word.
Hurry up. Come on, move it!
- Move it!
- The animals.
Yes, Licenciado López. I think
Mr. Vargas is sick in the head.
He treats all the
locals very badly.
Here he is, boss. He tried
to run as soon as he saw me.
Licenciado! To what do I owe
this honor? What a pleasure!
What the hell happened here, Vargas?
This man has been telling me
about all the crap you've been up to.
What have you told him, Pek?
About the Doctor? Doña Lupe?
Don't play dumb, Vargas!
Look how you got this place.
This Doctor came to see me
in the capital...
and said you were
up to all sorts of business...
in the name of the mayor's office.
Tell me the truth, asshole!
Licenciado, it's time to go.
Easy, Sharkey. Calm down.
We have time.
I want to hear
what little Vargas has to say. Well?
In fact, Licenciado...
where do I begin?
I came to San Pedro
determined to fulfill...
...the pledges and orders
of our President...
modernity and social justice.
But I felt really bad,
I was completely fucked up.
Nobody speaks Spanish,
so Mr. Pek here had to translate for me.
There was this priest and a woman
involved in various businesses...
...which didn't pay taxes.
So I realized the laws didn't
do the job...
and I changed them.
I can't believe it, Vargas.
You really changed the Constitution?
You're such a smart one.
''If the will of the people demands it...
the term of office may last
up to twenty years...
with up to four possibilities
of reelection.''
Fuck. Not even Porfirio Diaz
could have pulled this one off.
And I thought you couldn't make
any money out of this fucking village.
So, how much is there left?
All of it!
That's almost all, Licenciado.
From what you said you made
a hundred times more than this.
Don't fuck with me, idiot!
Where is it?
It's not here, Licenciado.
Oh, the money's in the bank
of San Pedro, right, asshole?
-Where the hell is it?
-It's inside... in the house.
Go and get it. Sharkey.
Keep an eye on him.
Gloria! Gloria!
Gloria!
''I went to the States with Bobby.
We'll meet in...
in Hell.''
That fucking whore!
What's the matter, Vargas?
Don't you think she's a whore?
Well, Pek. Found anything?
-No, Licenciado.
-Keep looking, asshole!
I just don't know
where he hid it.
Well, Vargas?
What have you got for me?
They took it all.
What?
Do you take me for an asshole?
It's true, Licenciado.
They took it all,
left me without a cent. Look.
What's the matter?
I had a fortune...
and a fucking Gringo and
my hooker wife left me without a cent.
Look you--
Careful, Vargas, careful!
We're being followed
and they'll be here soon.
Sharkey!
There isn't any Sharkey now.
Careful, Vargas,
better put that away.
Fucking Vargas,
you fucking clown.
Sorry, Licenciado.
but it is you or me.
I was doing fine till you
started harassing me...
saying you were the law,
the only authority, Herod's Law.
By your holy wife.
Go ahead and make fun of me,
bastard. Laugh.
Herod's Law.
It's all bullshit.
Women...
...all whores.
Cows all mad.
Gringos all sons of bitches
who want everything.
You and your good advice,
look at your advice now.
This country has no solution.
No solution, Licenciado.
Or does it? Does it?
Answer me, idiot! Answer!
Fucking moaning Indians,
you'll see now!
Out of the way!
What's going on?
Fucking Indians!
Delinquents!
This village is mine!
Transgressors of the law
and institutions!
Everything I do is for your sake.
You're poor because you want
to be poor, assholes!
Friends!
Juan Vargas.
Fellow citizens...
it wasn't me.
Juan Vargas.
It wasn't me.
I'm sorry! Forgive me, friends!
I did it all for your own good!
No! I didn't do anything.
I didn't do anything.
You down there, help!
Where's López?
I didn't kill him!
Help! Help!
Excuse me, how far is it to
San Pedro de los Saguaros?
Good afternoon.
Do you speak Spanish?
-Yes.
-I think we're lost.
Do you know how far it is to
San Pedro de los Saguaros?
This is it.
You must be the new mayor.
I've been waiting for you
since yesterday.
I'm Carlos Pek, your secretary.
Pleased to meet you...
Jesus Canales.
President Alemán and Governor Terrazas
have sent me...
to bring modernity and social justice.
We're here.
Welcome, Madam.
Here?
Hey, Pek, a question.
What happened to the last mayor?
I mean, you know,
they say so many things.
Oh, Licenciado,
I wouldn't know where to begin.
And so ends the fourth report
of President Miguel Alemán...
...reaffirming that the unity and
solidarity of the people of Mexico...
will triumph over any challenge...
that peace and social justice
are guaranteed, that the--
Hey, we've got problems
with Chino's truck again.
Call me Licenciado, asshole.
I'll finish and I'll be right there.
Honorable Congress
of the Union:
It is an honor for me to be
here at this seat of democracy...
...representing my home state.
Today, more than ever,
we Congressmen must fulfill...
...the expectations of
our nation.
We must be alert and
fight without quarter...
...against the revolution's
enemies.
Yes!Just as I did, when
I thwarted the conspiracy...
of Licenciado López, the ambitious
Secretary of the Governor...
along with a handful of evil people
to murder that great man...
...the recently elected
Governor Terrazas.
Friends...
...I am not ashamed to admit
that I have come to this Congress...
with bloodstained hands.
I don't deny it.
To ask for pardon would
be hypocritical.
But this is not the blood of a stranger
or of a brother.
It is the blood of an enemy...
an enemy of those who defend
the ideals of the revolution!
We have overcome
another obstacle...
but many more remain
because our party's challenge...
for the good of the Nation...
is to remain in power forever and ever!
Thank you my fellow countrymen.
SubtitleSync (http://www.subtitlesync.com.ar)