LOVELY LONELINESS
Hello? Hi mum.
No, nothing's wrong.
I've got a bit of a cold.
It's not flu, it's a cold.
I'm fine.
Oh yes? When?
Yes, yes, sure. It'll do me good
for you to come.
Mum, can I call you back?
I've got another call.
OK? OK. Love you, bye.
Javi... Are you there?
Hello, Javi.
Hi... yes, yes, I'm fine.
I can talk now.
Well...
No, nothing.
Yes, no.
He said...
it wasn't the right time
for us to live together,
he needed time...
for his things, his career.
He said he couldn't...
I don't know.
I don't remember.
He said a lot, I forget...
Yes, yes, I know...
Yes, no, but I can't.
No, I know.
I'm calm, the thing is...
I've got this contraction...
and my arm hurts,
it goes numb...
I'm worried it's serious...
I don't want to worry,
but it scares me.
Yes, I know.
I'm calm all the same.
No, no. Best not.
I'm fine on my home.
I'm going to bed now.
Yes, yes, OK.
If I need anything
I'll call you, OK?
OK, fine.
Love you. Bye.
Hi, this is Soledad,
leave a message, thanks.
4565-6785
Leave a message, thanks.
Hello...
Hi... It's noisy, where are you?
Down where?
What?
Nico...
I'm busy right now.
I don't want to speak,
I'm about to go to work...
It's not to talk.
I've got a practice
and my harmonica's there.
Yes, the harmonica's here.
But I'm in a hurry, you know?
- Could you bríng it down for me?
- Yes, hang on.
- I'll throw it, I have to go.
- What? No, it'll break...
It won't break.
I'll throw it down to you.
Wait, wait!
- Hello.
- Good evening.
I need to see a kinesiologist.
There's no kinesiologist now.
You'll have to call from 8 to 6
and ask for an appointment.
Is there no one to see me now?
Yes, the duty doctor.
He can see you and give you
something for the pain.
- OK...
- Your medical card, please.
Is there a cardiologist?
Yes, but first the GP will see you.
The thing is,
I've got
this terrible contraction,
and it makes my head and arm hurt,
and my arm goes numb.
And I want to make sure
it's not my heart.
Yes, sure... that's fine.
A GP will see you...
and refer you
to a cardiologist if necessary.
What if I have a heart attack?
You'll have to be admitted.
Sit there and the doctor will
call you by your surname.
OK, thank you.
- Hi!
Maybe the blue's better
because they're both...
Let me see, put it there.
- Your neighbour called...
- Ah... what did she say?
She wanted to know if you could sit
for her on Saturday night.
- Ah, I'll call her later.
- What do you think now?
- Hi...
- Hi, how's it going?
Ah, they look nice.
- Do you like them?
- A lot...
What did the doctor say?
Nothing...
There's nothing wrong with me.
All the same, it was a duty doctor.
I don't believe him.
I'm going to see my doctor.
- You can come too if you like.
- OK, I'll see, alright.
You can come too, if you want.
OK, we'll see.
Hi! You've been selected...
for our weekend discounts...
Hello love, just to confirm
I'm coming next Friday,
not this one, the next one.
Well, call me if you
need anything, love you.
Hello...
Hello?
LEZAMA PHARMACY
This is very good.
And this is just in.
Amazing.
I know this one's good.
It's like my doctor's.
But I don't know
if it'll be easy to use.
Yes, it's easy.
It's semi-automatic.
You won't have any trouble with
this one.
- It's fully automatic.
- Let's see...
It's light, easy to use.
And it has a memory function.
What's that?
You take your pressure
and it stores it in the memory.
When you take your pressure again,
- you can compare them.
- Oh, great.
And you can work out an average.
Right.
Look at this one if you like.
No, I like this one.
The Velcro's good, it's nice.
- Is this one much pricier?
- No, not much.
I'll have a look.
- It's nice, isn't it?
- Yes, and it looks great on you.
- OK, I'll take this one.
- Fine.
I like the design
of these thermometers.
They're very similar
to one you bought the other day.
Yes, but mine is thinner.
- Do you want to take a look?
- No, it's OK. Another day.
The bill. Excuse me. The bill.
- Hi.
- Hello.
- Is something up?
- No, I have to make a call.
- What did you buy?
- A digital blood-pressure meter.
Hi Nicolás, well...
I'm going to leave
yourthings in your bag...
with Carlos.
When you want to go and get them,
just pop round.
Hope you're OK, bye.
- Everything OK?
- No, but isn't it great?
I just bought it.
- Hi Carlos.
- Good afternoon.
- Good afternoon, how are you?
- Fine.
Can I ask you a favour?
Can I leave you this bag?
Nicolás will come and get it.
OK? Do you know Nicolás?
- Yes.
- I don't know when,
- but he'll come by one of these days.
- OK, leave it there.
- I'll put it away later.
- OK, thanks, thanks very much.
- Don't mention it.
- Afternoon.
- Hi, how are you?
- Hi!
- How are you?
- Hi, sweetheart.
- Come on, I'm in a hurry.
OK. We'll talk later.
Good afternoon.
I want to tell you something.
I've made a decision...
I'm going to stay single
for at least 2 or 3 years.
- Why?
- I'm tired of crying,
suffering,
waiting for a phone call...
And I feel like I have to learn
to be alone,
I want to allow myself that
experience.
I don't know,
I feel more stable.
And that in general,
people who are alone...
are OK, they do OK.
I could...
travel.
Concentrate on my work in the shop.
- Sole...
- Hi...
- Hi, how are you?
- Fine.
Hi Olivia!
- Sole, how are you, gorgeous?
- How's it going?
Hello?
- Hello.
- Hello, here we are.
- How are you?
- Come in.
- Fine, really good.
- Thank you. Were you sleeping?
- No, no.
I'll have to dash,
the taxi's waiting.
Be good now!
Are you sure you don't want her
to stay over?
Doesn't bother me.
We'll sleep together.
No, I'll get her.
Best if she's at home.
OK, thanks Sole.
- Bye gorgeous. I love you.
- Have a good time, eh?
- Bye, mum.
- Bye, gorgeous.
It's cold.
It's so pretty!
- Is it new?
- Yes.
- What's it called?
- Rain.
- I've rented a film to watch.
- OK.
And Nico?
- Nico.
- We've fallen out.
So that's why my mum told me
not to ask you.
Time!
Cold, blocked up nose,
generally unwell.
- Flu.
- OK.
Rapid heart rate.
- Tachycardia.
- OK.
Nausea and vomiting.
Pain in the upper part
of the left iliac crest,
increases when suddenly pressing
and releasing this area.
- Appendicitis.
- OK.
Feeling run-down,
doesn't tolerate changes
in position,
For example, dizzy when moving...
from horizontal to vertical.
- Low arterial pressure.
- OK.
Difficulty...
memorising and ordering
letters and numbers,
and also poor sentence structuring,
affecting both speech and writing.
Time.
- Time, time!
- Dyslexia!
Right.
- Hi.
How are you?
Fine.
- Is this the same as usual?
- Yes.
OK, I'll have one,
but could you heat it up?
- Sure.
- Yes? And wait...
Could you put the tomato here,
so it doesn't soften with the heat?
OK.
- Shall I bring it over?
- No, I'll wait here, thanks.
Hello, hello?
Hello, hello.
I can't hear you well, hello?
Excuse me, could I have another coffee
and the bill, please?
- Sorry about the shouting. No signal.
- Oh, that's fine.
- I haven't got a mobile.
- You're lucky then.
- It's coming.
- OK. Thanks.
OK, thanks. Perfect.
- Could you put it on my tab?
- OK.
OK, thanks.
- Are you off already?
- What?
Excuse me.
Maybe this sounds silly.
- What's your name?
- Soledad.
Solitude... It's what brings us
together?
That's my name. Soledad.
I know, it was a joke...
Oh, I didn't get it,
I have a thing with my name.
I have this theory that...
parents should give us fantasy names,
and when we're older...
everyone can have
the name they want.
It's not a bad theory.
Can I call you?
What?
I mean...
To go for a drink.
I can give you my business card,
if you like.
- OK...
- OK, very good.
Wait. Can you hold this?
OK, fine.
- Well...
- OK. Bye.
- Bye.
- What's your name?
- Nicolás.
But you can call me by
any fantasy name you like.
No, no, it's OK.
See you!
Hi, it's dad. Are you there?
Never mind. Just calling
to see how you were.
Bye, love you.
PLUMBING - GAS - DRAINS
Hello.
Hello?
Javi, I forgot to ask you.
Do you know a good plumber?
Plumber, no. I know a gasman...
who sometimes does plumbing.
I'll have a look...
- Hello.
I'll be right with you.
Just a second...
and I'll be with you.
That mirror, how much is it?
- 250 pesos.
- Hi.
- How are you?
- Good.
- Do you know each other?
- Yes. I...
- Yes. A little.
- Do you want to take over?
No, you serve him. No problem.
No, I'd rather you served me,
no offence!
None taken.
- Alright?
- Yes.
- Nice shop.
- Thanks.
And that mirror,
can I get it in other colours?
Yes, we have different colours,
different frames.
- Shall I show you?
- OK.
Come here.
Here you have all the frames
and colours.
I don't know if you're
looking for something more...
- This might work.
- Something opaque, you mean?
More grey.
- In that tone, yes.
- It's grey...
This is a little opaque.
Do you want to have dinner some time?
I have plans today.
Well, it doesn't have to be today,
it could be another day.
What do you say?
Listen, there's something
I didn't tell you the other day,
because I don't know you very well.
It's just right now,
I'm going through this thing.
And I need to be alone...
I'm sorry...
That's OK.
Shall we look at the colours?
- This one might work.
- This one? Yes?
This one's fine.
Do you do home delivery?
No, but I can order you a removal van.
- No, I'll come for it myself.
- This one then?
Do you fancy going on a trip?
- When?
- I don't know, in a week.
Sole, you're crazy,
I can't go away.
I've got Mili,
she's got school.
- I'd love to but I can't.
- Sure.
- Anything else?
- And one of these. Two.
- Oh, me too. Three.
- Three?
- Yes please.
- Add on those three.
And two ripe avocados, for today.
I love avocados.
Do you want to come for dinner
tonight, with Mili?
I can't tonight.
- I'm going out. With the doctor.
- Great.
- It worked.
- Yes, yes.
It seems so.
Anything else?
- Hi dad.
- Hi love. How are you? OK?
Sorry I've no time, not even a minute
for a coffee with you,
Mechi's waiting for me at home.
We've guests tonight. I'm late.
- Everything OK?
- Yes, do you like it?
Yes, I'll look at it later
in my own time. How much?
- Nothing.
- Go on, tell me how much it is.
- No, it's nothing.
- OK, don't say anything. Here.
- No, it's too much.
- Go on, take it.
- Do you need more?
- No, no, no.
- Sure?
- Yes.
You have to come
and see the new house.
Mechi's doing an amazing job.
You know what she's like.
No.
She likes artistic stuff, design,
decoration. Like you.
- You OK?
- Yes. OK, I'm off.
- Are you OK?
- Yes.
Speak to you soon, let's see if you
can come one day.
Yes, OK... bye.
- Bye.
- Ah! Your credit card renewal came,
I have to give you it.
- Ah, yes. Thanks.
- Bye.
- Say hi to Nicolás.
- OK, will do...
- Hi!
- Hi, how are you?
- Everything OK?
- Yes, fine.
Excuse me. Hello?
Yes, hang on. Is the mirror here?
- Yes, I'll get it.
- Hello? OK, fine.
OK, OK. Fine.
I'll call you back in
five minutes. Fine. Bye.
- OK, this is it.
- Do you want to open it?
- No, no.
- You sure? It looks good, eh?
No, no. Not at all.
I owe you something, don't I?
- No, it's all paid up.
- OK.
OK. Do you want to see something here?
- Anything else?
- No, not for now.
But I will leave you my card...
In case you ever need an architect.
Ah! You're an architect! Great!
- OK. I'm going. Bye.
- Bye.
- Bye, all the best.
- Bye, see you later.
I'm so stupid!
Stupid!
Hello.
Hi, it's me, sorry to interrupt.
Is Javi in?
Yes, hold on. Javi!
- Hello.
- Hi, Javi...
- Could you bring me the copy of the key?
Yes, what happened? Are you okay?
It's all good.
I got locked out.
- Okay, but...
- Will you bring it down? C'mon!
Okay, come up.
It's raining, Soledad.
No, no, no. I don't want to.
Sorry,
sorry to interrupt.
It's okay, it's cool,
come up for a second.
No, no, I don't want to, I was
doing fine at home...
- I got locked out, I forgot the key.
- Soledad...
- I didn't want to interrupt...
- Sorry...
- I'll get it and bríng it down, okay?
- Okay, thanks.
- Chill down.
Hello, hi Nicolás?
This is Soledad,
from "La Esperanza".
Remember me?
Hello? Yes, coming.
You haven't eaten anything.
No, I don't eat much at night.
You're very thin.
You need to feed yourself up.
Yes, but I eat well, you know?
All my family's like this.
Yes? You're lucky.
They're all fat in my family.
Yes? But you're OK, aren't you?
Yes, I look after myself a bit.
I bought a treadmill
forthe new house.
That's good.
You should use it.
And when will you finish your house?
In a month, I think.
The electrician's a bit behind,
he's doing some otherjob,
but I should be living there
in a month.
Did you build it from scratch?
No, but it was in a bad state...
and I did most of it up...
I did a year of architecture,
but I dropped out.
Oh, yes?
But did you do interior design
or decoration?
Yeah, I dropped out of that too.
The chance came up...
to open the shop with Javi and Darío.
You remember Javier?
- Yes, yes.
- So that year...
I stopped studying.
But the others carried on and
graduated.
I think the academic life
is for a certain kind of person...
who likes going to the same place,
all year long,
with the same people,
during a long time...
I'm not that kind of person.
But I'm envious
of the people who can do it.
- I envy you a little.
- Don't say that.
But in a good way.
You have a pretty mouth.
Thanks.
Just going to the bathroom.
- Shall we order some tea?
- Yes.
- Everything OK?
- I'm a little dizzy...
- Really? Oh dear.
- Do you want to leave?
- No, I'm fine.
- Sure?
- Yes, yes.
Ah, no, yes. I don't feel well.
I'd rather we left.
- Let's go then. Shall I get the bill?
- Yes, go on.
How do you feel?
I don't know.
I'll explain in a minute...
Hi, daughter! Are you there?
I'm here.
I'm at grandma's.
Anyway, call me when you like.
Love you.
- Morning Carlos...
- Morning.
I need to ask you a favour,
I've got a problem.
The zip on my dress is stuck.
I can't unzip it.
Could you help me?
Yes, yes, sure.
- Excuse me.
- Yes, yes.
- There we go. Good. Thanks.
- No problem.
When I bought it, I didn't realise it
was so complicated.
- Of course.
- OK, thanks Carlos.
You are welcome.
I can't believe
you didn't tell me the other day.
I don't know, I forgot.
- How big are you having them?
- I don't know. But I saw them.
No idea, but the doctor knows.
Yes, but... Does the size go with
your body? Does it go with your age?
This doesn't look like a clinic to me.
It's not a clinic,
it's a consulting room.
- There's a little operating room.
- I'm not sure about this.
Cut it out, Soledad.
I'm here now.
What do you want me to do, eh?
I can't see a nurse or an ambulance,
- if something happens.
- It's all upstairs.
Don't forget to buy me
the bra and the bandage,
I have to wear it from Monday.
Yes, yes.
Are you sure you want
to go to grandma's?
- Yes.
- How are you going to get there?
María's picking me up,
it's all sorted.
All the same, I'll be able to walk,
it's nothing.
We'll see if it's nothing.
- Elsa Schved...
- Doctor.
Pleased to meet you,
I'm the daughter.
- OK dear, take it easy.
- OK.
- Call me from grandma's?
- I'll call you.
How are you doctor?
I'm glad the day's finally come.
- Excuse me.
- Yes.
Can I ask something?
Is the operating room...
any good?
- Like what professionals use?
- It's a normal operating room.
- Well equipped, is it?
- Yes, fine. Everything will be fine.
- Don't you worry.
- OK, thanks.
How are you?
Fine, thanks. Better, yes.
Now? Look,
I'm just chatting
with friends right now,
and later I don't know...
Why?
Did you want to do something?
Yes. I don't know,
I don't want to get wet.
Yes... sure, you have a car.
No, I can't drive.
Sure, one day you can teach me,
there's no rush.
Listen, do you want to come here?
Yes, OK.
Do you remember how to get here?
OK, see you then.
My cheeks get hot when I kiss.
- Are they red?
- A bit, yes.
When I was a girl,
when I had fever,
I liked it because
it gave me this natural blush...
I'd get rosy cheeks...
and it looked good...
Anyway, I'd finish it off,
I'd make up with my saliva.
Like this, look...
Here on my eyelashes.
And a little on my lips.
When I took the bus.
I can imagine what
you were like when you were young,
I would've liked
to have known you back them.
I think we would've got on well.
- Do you think so?
- Yes.
I don't know, maybe.
They didn't put us in this month.
We forgot to send a fax.
Yes. I'll send it.
- Thanks.
- No problem.
The picture I liked has been sold,
has it?
- Yes, yesterday. I didn't tell you.
- What?
Darío got a call,
they've confirmed the Colombia expo.
- No!
- Yes!
- With this series?
- Yes.
Great. Great, how nice...
the beach, Colombia.
- No, it's in Bogotá, not on the beach.
- Oh, I see...
And now we want to see if we can find
somewhere to stay. I'm going with him.
No!
Oh, that's great, how nice.
- I'd like to get away too.
- Where to?
Don't know, do you think Brazil
would be very expensive?
No, check it out,
there are always cheap packages.
La Esperanza.
Hello.
Yes, how are you?
Yes, she's right here beside me.
Here she is. Cheers.
- Your boyfriend.
- What a pain...
Hello?
Fine, you?
What? Sorry, I didn't realise.
No, sorry, hang on, I'm coming.
- What happened?
- I locked him in.
Back in a sec.
Take your time.
Hi! Where are you?
In the bathroom.
I'm sorry.
You fixed my toilet?
- Yes.
- Why?
I thought it'd be good if it worked.
Was that wrong?
No, but I was going to fix it.
Well, I fixed it.
Anyway, I'll let you go.
Does it bother you?
No, it's fine,
it had to be done.
I'm off, I'm going for lunch.
Who with?
- Afriend.
- Enjoy!
- Thanks. Is it open downstairs?
- Yes.
It's open. Call me, OK?
See you.
- Why so many?
- I liked the Velcro on this one,
and this one here,
this one's got hooks.
Which can be a good idea too.
And another,
in case you want to change.
And the chemist told me
that these are handy,
they're what everyone uses.
Yes, I'm wearing
those, I can change them.
- Shall I show you them?
- No, what for?
I don't want to see them.
Why would I?
- Fine!
- I'll give grandma a kiss...
- and I'll be on my way.
- Careful, she's a bit mad today.
She thinks I'll take María away.
OK, I'll call you tomorrow
to see how you are.
Yes, and we still haven't had time
to talk about Nicolás.
Yes, because you decided to have
an operation. That's why...
- But now I'm out.
- Yes, luckily.
I had a boob job, it's not
as if I had heart surgery.
It could have been serious
and you'd have complicated my life.
- I?
- Yes, you.
- OK. Bye.
- Bye.
Hi Sole, are you there?
Sole? It's OK.
See you later in the shop.
OK. Big kiss.
- So when would you be going?
- Next week.
- So soon!
- The curator...
who wanted to see Darío's work...
is only in Bogotá for a week.
You don't have to open the shop,
though.
No, I don't want to close.
I want to work, I can manage.
- But you don't have to.
- I want to.
- Oh, I could look after the dog.
- No, she's coming with us.
On the plane? Do you have
to put herthrough that?
She's done it before
and she was fine.
I don't know, it can't be healthy.
- So can I confirm with Darío?
- Yes, tell him it's OK.
La Esperanza.
- Hello.
I'm a bit nauseous and
I wanted to see a doctor.
OK. Can I see your medical card?
- A GP, right?
- Yes.
And aren't you cold
wearing only that shirt?
No, no.
Sit there and
they'll call you by your surname.
Sorry, can I just ask...
is there a phone on this floor?
- Yes, there. At the end, on your right.
- Ah yes, thanks.
- You're welcome.
- Bye.
Hello? How's it going?
Are you busy?
Oh sorry, I'll call you later.
No, no, I'm not at home. No.
I'm in the hospital.
No, it's nothing.
Just feeling a bit dizzy.
No, it's not serious,
nothing to worry about.
No, don't worry.
Correa Soledad.
- This way please.
- Sorry, the doctor's calling me.
Carry on eating, don't worry.
I'll call you when I get home.
OK, take care. Sorry. Bye.
- Evening.
- How's it going?
Feeling better?
Yes, I'm better.
- What did you eat?
- Beef.
It's not good to eat protein at night,
the body can't digest it.
My body's used to it by now.
All the same.
Go like this,
hit me and rub me,
hit me and rub me.
- Do you like that?
- Yes, it soothes me.
Are you staying the night?
OK. We'll see later.
Nico?
Nico...
Hi... I was scared.
- Why? What's up?
- I don't know. I couldn't find you,
I thought something was up.
I got worried.
I went to buy breakfast.
I got scared, I was worried.
- What did you get?
- Scones, OK?
I'm going to make some tea.
Do you want some?
La Esperanza.
Hi mum. Fine, fine.
Can I call you from home?
I'm just closing.
OK, you too.
Hi, what are you doing here?
I came to see you.
Got a minute?
No, I have to go and send a fax.
I have to go.
- OK, I'll go with you.
- I'm in a hurry.
- That's OK, we'll walk fast.
- OK, it's up to you... Hello.
You look well.
Yes, I am well.
You surprised?
No, I'm glad.
- How are you?
- Fine, fine.
Lots of work, bit tired.
We finished the record.
Oh, good.
- Hi.
- I need to send this. A fax.
- Just one page?
- Yes.
- Number?
Yes. 4771-9129.
Before, I don't know why,
I couldn't be with you,
- but now I can.
- Yes, I understood...
you couldn't be with me,
I know that now.
I want to go.
- Phone booth?
- Yes.
I think it's time for us
to be together again.
No, not now.
Now I know that I love you.
- Has it gone through?
- It's going.
Look at me.
- And now?
- It's still going through.
Say something. Please.
Excuse me, could I have a phone?
- Yes, go to number 4.
- Sorry, I have to go.
- Stop, stop.
- Let me go, what are you doing?
I don't want you to love me now.
I'm alone and I'm fine,
and now I want
to check my messages, bye.
4565-6785,
leave a message, thanks.
Hi Sole, I wanted to talk to you
about something before I leave.
Don't miss me, I'll be back soon.
Love you.
Hi sweetheart. It's Dad...
I wanted to invite you
to visit my new home.
Love you.
Hi Sole. Are you there?
Talk to me, please.
- Buzios you said, right?
- Yes.
- For one person?
- With flights?
- Yes.
- Is it for you?
Do you mind if I recommend you
somewhere else?
Because Buzios is more for couples.
- What do you recommend?
- How about Love Club?
They're great places for meeting
people, have you ever been?
No, I don't want to meet people,
I want to go to the beach for a week.
The thing is there aren't generally
very many single rooms.
Wouldn't you prefer
to do something with a friend?
Because double rooms
are easier to get, you know?
I had a "Fun"...
friends and couples package.
No, my friends have plans
and this would be confirmed,
so don't look.
All the same,
this is no good...
because it's a cabin for four.
There's no room here...
The thing is, it's very last minute.
And if I find anything...
it's going to be
a lot more expensive.
Yes, that's what I've heard.
How about this?
OK, this has single rooms available.
- I'll get you a leaflet.
- Where is it?
- In Fortaleza. Heard of it?
- Brazil?
- Yes.
- No, but the name's nice.
Yes.
Great! All sorted.
Yes, Javier's very organised.
This is going to come in handy.
Walk me to the car?
OK.
The house is turning out great.
Yes?
- You have to come and see it.
- Yes, great, I'd like to.
- I bought a fish tank.
- Oh yes?
Do you like them?
I don't know.
I find they suffocating sometimes.
Also, they say fish have no memory.
And they don't remember if...
- Oh, they say that?
- Yes, they could have a broader reality.
- Do you want to come?
- Where to?
The house.
Not today. Another day,
when I have more time.
- Thanks for your help.
- You are welcome.
I can see the Velcro in you
bra from here, it's nice...
Can you use wear it
like that already?
Yes, the doctor said
the tightest the best.
Really?
I'd like it if you could go
and visit grandma.
Yes.
Sorry I can't open the door,
there are still
some things I can't do.
Please, take care with all that.
Don't worry, I'm fine.
Thanks forthe shawl.
I loved it.
Isn't it lovely?
It's very rare mink.
Sir, taxi for the second floor?
Thank you. Can you open
the door for me? Because...
Well...
- OK, take care.
- Call me when you get there.
Yes, I will.
To the airport, please.
- This is practical and modern.
- It's nice.
Yes, my dad gave me it
and I've never used it.
- But is it OK if you lend me it?
- Yes, no worries.
Thanks. I'll give it you
as soon as I come back.
- There's no rush.
- Lovely. Thanks a lot, Sole.
- Great, I love it.
- Isn't it good that you're going away?
Yes, I'm very happy.
Just three days but...
- It's great all the same.
- Yes. Just to get to know each other.
And Mili...
she staying with her dad?
Yes. I can't believe herfather.
He said yes.
- Great.
- Yes.
- Great, you've got everything sorted.
- Yes, I've got the suitcase...
- and now I have to shave my legs.
- Well, you know...
please bring me the suitcase
when you come back,
I might need it.
Sure, no problem.
Have a good trip.
- Thanks honey.
- Everything's going to be OK.
I guess, I'll tell you after.
- Yes.
- Bye.
Hi, are you there? It's me.
Right, I'm starting to pack.
Call me. Bye.
Love you.
It looks very nice.
- Do you like it?
- Yes.
And you have a hospital here,
round the corner, you know?
- Yes?
- Yes, very good.
It's very good taste, I like it.
- Well, thank you.
- And the fish tank looks good.
- What a good idea.
- Yes.
- And the mirror will look good.
- The mirror looks great.
Yes.
- You've got a barbecue.
- Yes.
The lights are great.
It's just a question of finishing it,
isn't it? I still...
Sorry I didn't help with the packing.
Don't worry, you got me the boxes.
- What's up? Are you OK?
- Yes, I'm fine.
What's up?
I don't know. It's just that it's nice
here, your house,
the area, you.
It's all very nice, I don't know.
Sometimes it happens...
that when I fall in love,
or when I like someone...
I feel like I lose my way,
like I run away from myself.
But don't think I'm not OK...
- just because I'm crying, I'm fine.
- OK, OK.
Take it easy,
everything's fine.
Don't worry about a thing,
- Don't say it's fine.
- Well...
Easy, easy,
- nothing's wrong.
- I really am OK, eh?
Don't worry.
OK. OK...
SYRIAN-LEBANESE HOSPITAL
Good afternoon, can I help you?
No, I'm just looking, thanks.
Ripeados por
Tylerg - Escuadrón Tigre
Visita www.clan-sudamerica.net
Cine de Latinoamérica y España