The musicians are magicians.
That's what I've always said.
I've always had this dream...
or this hope,
since my childhood, and...
you have to see it for yourselves.
Let me explain,
I have all this lights
shining and beating insde my head.
...
"One more Time"
One more time
One more time, we’re gonna celebrate,
oh yeah, alright, don’t stop dancing
One more time, we’re gonna celebrate, oh yeah
One more time
One more time, we’re gonna celebrate,
oh yeah, alright, don’t stop dancing
oh yeah, don’t stop dancing
One more time
Mmmmmmmmm,You know I'm just feeling,
Celebration, tonight
Celebrate, don't wait too late
Mmmmmmmm you know
We don't stop ahhhh
You can stop ahhh
We gonna celebrate
One more time
Celebration
You know we're gonna do it right
Tonight
Hey just feeling
Music's got me feeling a need
Need, yeah
Come on, alright we gonna celebrate
One more time,
celebrate and dance so free
Music's got me feeling so free
Celebrate and dance so free
One more time
Music's got me feeling so free
We’re gonna celebrate
Celebrate and dance for free
One more time
Music’s got a feeling so free
We’re gonna celebrate
Celebrate and dance for free
One more time
Music’s got a feeling so free
We’re gonna celebrate
"Celebrate and dance for free"
"One more time
Music’s got a feeling so free"
We’re gonna celebrate
Celebrate and dance for free
"One more time
Music’s got a feeling so free"
We’re gonna celebrate
Celebrate and dance for free
One more time. Music’s got a feeling so free
We’re gonna celebrate.Celebrate and dance for free
"Aerodynamic"
"Digital Love"
Last night I had a dream about you
In this dream I'm dancing right beside you
And it looked like everyone was having fun
The kind of feeling I've waited so long
Don't stop come a little closer
As we jam the rhythm gets stronger
There's nothing wrong with just a little little fun
We were dancing all night long
The time is right to put my arms around you
You're feeling right
You wrap your arms around too
But suddenly I feel the shining sun
Before I knew it this dream was all gone
Ooh...I don't know what to do...
About this dream and you
I wish this dream comes true
Ooh...I don't know what to do...
About this dream and you
We'll make this dream comes true
Why don't you play the game ?
"Harder Better Faster Stronger"
Work it... make it... do it... makes us...
Harder... better... faster... stronger...
More Than ... Hour
Hour ... Never
Ever ... After
Work is ... Over
Work it... make it... do it... makes us...
Harder... better... faster... stronger...
Work it harder, make it better
do it faster, makes us stronger
More than ever hour after hour
work is never over
Work it harder, make it better
do it faster, makes us stronger
Work it harder, make it better,
More than ever hour after hour
work is never over
"Crescendolls"
"Nightvision"
"SuperHeroes"
Marvel Super Hero ?
"HighLife"
"Something About Us"
It might not be the right time
I might not be the right one
But there's something about us I want to say
Cause there's something between us anyway
I might not be the right one
It might not be the right time
But there's something about us I've got to do
Some kind of secret I will share with you
I need you more than anything in my life
I want you more than anything in my life
I'll miss you more than anyone in my life
I love you more than anyone in my life
"Voyager"
"Veridis Quo"
"Short Circuit"
"Face To Face"
What's going on
Could this be my understanding
It's not your fault
I was being too demanding
I must admit it's my pride that made me distant
All because I hoped that you'd be someone different
There's not much I know about you
Fear will always make you blind
But the answer is in clear view
It's amazing what you'll find face to face
I turned away cause I thought you were the problem
Tried to forget until I hit the bottom
But when I faced you in my blank confusion
I realized you weren't wrong, it was a mere illusion
It really didn't make sense
Just to leave this unresolved
It's not hard to go the distance
When you finally get involved face to face
It really didn't make sense
Just to leave this unresolved
It's not hard to go the distance
When you finally get involved face to face
"Too Long"
It's been much too long, I feel it comming on
The feeling is getting strong
The feeling is in my bones
It's been much too long, I feel it comming on
The feeling is getting strong
The feeling is in my bones
Too long, can you feel it,
too long, oh can you feel it
At last the long wait is over
the weight is off my shoulder
I'm taking all control
My mind is set so free
I'm where I want to be
To get the best of me
Too long, can you feel it,
too long, oh can you feel it
I see, you feel the way I do, the feeling all so true
the good feelings coming thru
My mind is set so free
I'm where I want to be, to get the best of me
Too long, can you feel it,
too long, oh can you feel it
It's been much too long, I feel it comming on
The feeling is getting strong
The feeling is in my bones
It's been much too long, I feel it comming on
The feeling is getting strong
The feeling is in my bones
Too long, can you feel it,
too long, oh can you feel it
At last the long wait is over
the weight is off my shoulder
I'm taking all control yeah
My mind is set so free
I'm where I want to be
To get the best of me
Too long, can you feel it,
too long, oh can you feel it
You know you need it,hey I need it too but alright
you know you need it, it's good for you
We're gonna move
Dedicado a mi gran amor Betiana Barretto
Versión Castellano de M6N8 22DEC2005