Everything is fucking
difficult and beautiful.
Are there any sandwiches left?
- What?
- Sandwiches.
Thanks.
The cabins are sort of far
from the lake.
Far?
One kilometer.
Right, but that's not far.
No, you're right.
About 20 minutes.
What?
15, not 20... from the lake.
OK 15, 20, it's the same thing.
If you want we can change,
just call and get another one
No, it's fine... to walk 20 minutes.
40 really, to go there and back.
The cabins are great.
Really?
They have sauna.
Mud baths.
I love mud.
Wi-Fi
Did you get dizzy?
A bit.
- Do you want me to stop?
- No
Did you get dizzy from reading...
or from the other thing?
From reading.
If you leave the window open the
AC won't ever cool down.
I know.
Or we can open the window
and turn the AC off.
It's fine!
You haven't gotten the...
typical dizziness.. have you?
Or is it too soon for that?
I’m not pregnant any more.
Did you miscarry?
Yes.
No.
I changed my mind.
Without asking me?
It had to be done fast,
there wasn't time for...
You didn't have 5 minutes to call me.
It wasn't 5 minutes, imagine.
It had to be done fast
and it was...
It is something that has
to be solved immediately
It has to do with... with the...
It's a practical thing really,
the thing... the vacuum thing.
It’s a procedure, that's what I mean.
We were talking about our plans
for the next, what, 15 years?
They weren't plans,
don't start with that.
It was an accident.
I didn't want to.
But you said yes.
Fine, I said yes.
But the truth was I didn't want to.
I am not prepared, yet.
Sure, you are only 36...37 years old,
you still need to grow up.
It's not that, it's not the right time.
Well, that’s arguable... what is not
is that you decide without asking me.
Half that baby was mine.
Don't call it baby.
OK... half that morula,
embryo, was mine.
And the plans with that embryo.
Technically, it's less than half.
It was inside of me.
That makes me...
not only co-owner but also the...
landholder.
That’s a joke.
Because it sounds like a joke, let's
tell jokes and kill ourselves laughing.
Joel... damn, at least try...
This shit is not good for me like this.
What is not good for you?
It's not good for me, damn.
Forgive me.
You are a coward.
I know I am a coward, forgive me.
Why do you always do things this way?
I don't know.
Let's go on holidays, let's not fight.
It's self destructive.
You set traps for yourself.
Same thing at work...
Don't analyze me please,
you know I don't like that.
But it's weird.
Could be.
Everything is weird.
I have to go pee.
Come on Joel, answer.
I am in a restaurant 600 meters
south from where you left.
I will wait for you 30 more minutes.
If you don't come back
I’ll just take the bus back to Santiago.
Call me at least to know you're fine.
I hope you didn't crash.
I hope you are not bleeding
to death on the pavement,
with you brains all scattered...
That's it. Bye.
Eh, two Italians.
What do you want, son?
Two Italian hot dogs.
OK, I’ll take them to your table.
Those are the advantages of
super developed countries...
Here it's not like that at all.
...the health insurance doesn't want to
cover the surgery because it's cosmetic
...it's not for vanity
..how will he get a job on TV
all burnt like that...
C'mon aunt! the check for table 5!
Hot dog is good.
Italian.
Got avocado.
Here.
OK stop it.
I’m going to the bathroom.
What happened?
My car broke down.
No gas?
Something else.
So you’re going to
spend the night in town?
No I’ll go to Santiago now.
And what will you do with the car?
The tow truck will take it.
Your family is waiting for you.
Sure.
I have two daughters.
And you?
Me too.
You also have two daughters?
Eh, sure.
And how old are they?
Mmm... four.
Are they twins?
Sure, twins.
And are you going to town too?
No. Thanks.
I am going to a park near here.
7 tazas?
- 7 tazas
- This gringo is from Norway.
Ah, nice.
Did you know in Norway
the government heats up the water...
...and gives it out for free?
I had no idea.
That's real money...
warm water for everyone.
Are you all right?
Yes.
So you're from Santiago then?
I don't like Santiago.
I study there.
Medicine I study.
And where do you live in Santiago?
Ñuñoa
Ñuñoa?
My girlfriend lives in Ñuñoa
I don't like Ñuñoa either.
I was crazy there,
that's why I left.
She wanted me to be there all the time.
But I said “no fucking way”
She says: “Ulrik, if you leave,
I don't know what can happen!”
What's your name?
Ulrik. Ulrik Skakkebaek.
And yours?
Carla, Gutierrez.
What do you think she meant?
What do you think could happen?
New message
JOEL
I am fine
Do you think she meant something
that happens to me, to her?
I have no idea Ulrik.
It was a call from Santiago?
- Are they waiting for you there?
- No
No. It seems they are
not waiting for me.
Is that your bus?
Shit!
You can run and catch it!
No, I won't make it
Do you want me to run?
No... it's gone.
OK, run!
Sorry.
Don't worry,
it wasn't your fault.
I didn't react on time.
I am sorry.
In a way, you wanted
the bus to leave.
Don't analyze me,
I can't stand it.
It's just that I’m clumsy,
that's all.
- What is clumsy?
- Clumsy.
Clumsy...
That I do things wrong, backwards.
That I complicate everything.
Clumsy. I like that word... clumsy
And now you have to stay here waiting
until tomorrow.
Yep.
Are you sure you don't want to
come to the park with me?
Sure
Are you going to be all right?
Yes, don't worry,
I’ll go to the hotel.
Well...
Bye Ulrik.
Bye Carla.
Have a goodtime.
Hey Ulrik.
I don't know...
You already changed your mind...
clumsy.
No, no... I didn't say that.
Eh... it was, let's see.
I just wanted to make clear
that... that...
OK, we are going together...
But I’m married...I mean..
yes... anyway, sure,
I’m married.
You mean that I don't
try to win you over?
Like... flirting?
No, no, no, it's not that either.
No, I mean yes, anyway.
But on the other hand no, because
why would I think that you might want...
But well, yes! that's it.
Don't worry, I’m gay.
Homosexual?
And the girlfriend from Ñuñoa?
Actually I think I am gay.
that's why I left girlfriend
in Santiago.
You think you're gay.
Well... I think so, but I still haven't
experienced it with anybody.
- Get it?
- Yeah.
Experience, understand?
I got it.
Are we walking all the way there?
No, my trip guide says that further up
there’s a bus stop.
How far up?
Just a kilometer.
20 minutes.
And what do you think?
About what?
You think I’m gay?
What do I know?
I don't know, your intuition.
Do you see me gay?
I’m not very intuitive Ulrik.
I don't know...
could be.
How can you tell?
No idea.
But you said it could be
Well, it could be and it could not be.
Can I help you?
We have more than 250 bugs here.
Anything dangerous?
Well that depends, right?
On what we understand by danger.
Danger is so relative.
Even a fly could be dangerous
at a given moment.
If you’re walking by the edge of a cliff
for example...
... and a fly gets into your ear...
...you lose balance and you fall...
Down the cliff.
Do you want to see the spiders too?
Don't worry.
We want to camp.
Ah... You're in the
right place my friend?
No, Spanish is fine.
Just one.
“The Pollito Spider”
But this is not dangerous.
I bet the “gringo” is afraid of it.
I’m not afraid!.
Can we go now? It'll get dark.
Carla
Gutierrez
Age?
Address?
Estrella Solitaria 340, Ñuñoa
And him?
Ulrik. Ulrik Skakkebaek.
U - L- R -
I - K
S - K - A -
K - K -
E - B -
A - E - K
- Age?
- 21
So? Do you like it?
Ehem... yes.
I’m going to buy something to eat.
Want anything?
No, thanks. I’m going to bed.
I’m exhausted.
- Fine. Bye
- Bye.
Jose Ignacio what did I tell you!
Hi.
Flute is over at 7.
We already talked about that.
Did you hear that one?
Which one?
That one.
That's the Tuta.
And that one?
That one that sounds like a cry?
It's the ¡*little widow
Where?
There, on the branch
Which one?
There! Behind the trunk.
I don't see it.
What's that?
That’s a highway they’re building.
We will loose a good chunk of the park.
That's too bad.
Well, it's complicated.
Are you a “Chilean Chilean”?
Yes!
You don't look Chilean.
Because of...
the way you walk
...like stepping on eggs, nervous.
And how do Chilean women walk?
I don't know, firmly, looking forward.
Do you know that Silvio Rodriguez's
song the one about the brothers?
Yes... no, how was it?
Well, there were three brothers.
The first one always walked
looking down.
So his neck got stuck and he was
never able to look forward again.
The second one... looked forward...
... but he was always tripping on
stones.
And the other one looked up and down
like undecided.
Right. Which one's me?
The last one.
The one always changing the gaze.
One eye for each side.
So?
So what?
How does it end?
What happens to that one?
Nothing. He remains confused forever.
Finally they all do badly.
It's like a fable
Don’t fables always have animals?
Well, like a parable then.
And it wants to tells us that...
none of the options are good.
Are you sure?
Isn’t there a strophe missing?
No, it's just like that.
Do we know each other?
I don't know you.
You might know me.
Were you on TV?
You were an actor!
Once I got offered a...
You were a singer!
Yes, you were a singer!
How was your name?
Don't tell me...
Orlando.
Of course!
Don't tell me your last name...
Palma.
Orlando Palma, of course.
You were very famous.
You had that song everybody knew...
“Vanity” you mean.
That was the best known.
It was almost the only one people knew.
How was it?
Alpha Sierra to Oscar Papa,
do you copy?
I can't remember...
Oscar Papa here,
go ahead Alfa Sierra.
If you sing a bit
I’ll remember right away.
What do you want?
let's see... milk, coffee, and bread
I have some avocados.
Ripe... Creamy
A bit expensive, but they're worth it.
Want some?
Sure.
Susana! Bring some avocados!
Don't yell at me,
I have a headache.
Bring avocados.
You go, I don't know how to pick them.
Sell some bread to the lady then.
Four.
Did you arrive today?
Yes, yesterday.
From Santiago?
Santiago is beautiful.
I got my wisdom teeth pulled out there.
I have an aunt there,
in EI Bosque, you know?
Yes, I mean not specifically but yes.
Do you live here?
In Molina, but in the summer
we work here.
And what do you do in Santiago?
I’m a biochemist.
You work in a lab?
You mix things in jars,
reactions and stuff?
Precisely. And you both?
Susana studies hairdressing
and I study accounting
You are with that blond guy, right?
Is he your younger brother, your son?
A friend.
Friend or “friend friend”?
Susana, don't be intruding
Are you both called Susana?
Are you sisters?
Cousins.
What's the blond guy's name?
Ulrik, he's Norwegian.
From Oslo?
I don't know.
2.800
Sun block! Did anybody bring sun block?
No.
It's not that sunny, Mari please.
Don't start daddy, I already explained.
Fine, I’ll go.
It's not that sunny,
it's ridiculous.
It's because of the hole.
My field guide says
the hole is huge here.
The hole!
The ozone hole.
Where are you from?
From Norway.
I have a friend from Norway.
He's called Olsen Forden.
Sun block!
Is your husband like that gentleman?
No... yes, I don't know.
He's different.
In what?
He's more interesting
More handsome?
He's smart, he's funny.
And why aren’t you with him then?
I don't think that’s an issue you can
help me with
All right...
I can't help because I’m not an adult?
Because I don't have kids?
No, because it’s a complicated
issue for anyone.
You are saying
I’m an adult then?
Yes...
My girlfriend would tell me everyday
that I’m like an immature boy.
That word makes me laugh.
Like an unripe fruit.
I told her she was a rotten fruit.
I don't have that word in Norway.
Mature?
How is to be mature?
Mature, like...
...like the fruit.
Like when fruit is ready to be
eaten, it is like being ready for life.
Completely developed...
Emotionally, mentally.
Basically, it's knowing what you want,
what you like and don't like...
...being calm.
Being old essentially.
I think it's harder than being old.
But when you are mature
it's all over, then what?
Then... I don't know...
...enjoy adult life, supposedly.
Like fruit... you're there,
hanging from the tree...
...you're just enjoying the sun.
Then you begin to decay.
The birds start picking on you...
...you fall to the ground,
then tissues start to decompose and...
...I don't know.
You bite your nails!
Hi.
I have a confession to make.
Sure?
If you don't want,
I won't tell you.
Don't tell me if you don't want to.
I had a boyfriend.
Just once, in Norway.
What happened?
He left me.
He left you? Why?
I became jealous and I hit him
You hit him?
I don't believe you.
For real. A punch like this.
I can't imagine you hitting anybody.
It was the first time. Did you know
the fist hurts a lot? Hitting hurts.
That's fine, it's fair that it hurts.
Have you hit anybody?
No
And have you been hit?
No.
You probably haven't fallen off a bike.
I’m not going to compete for who
has suffered more, Ulrik.
That's because you're mature.
Don't mess with me! I am trying to rest.
Did you get mad?
Alpha Sierra to Oscar Papa,
do you copy?
Oscar Papa why don't you answer?
Turn off the radio!
Don't be do loud!
I’m bored!
You left me all alone here!
I can come back later.
- No, go ahead.
- Thanks.
Look, Orlando finished the
translation. It goes...
When routine bites and we run out
of ambition,
and resentment triumphs...
...emotions get stuck and we are
changing, taking different routes.
Then, love, love...
Love will tear us apart.
Love, love...
Well like that, 4 times,
it's the chorus.
It’s sad, isn't it?
What?
That love always tears you apart.
I like it.
Because it has never happened to you.
No? What about Jose?
You always said that José was a fool.
He was a fool, but love teared us
apart anyway.
One thing has nothing
to do with the other.
I was in love.
I couldn't fall in love with a fool.
Because you're a coward.
It's much more dangerous to fall in love
with fools because you don't get them.
They are pure mystery.
Like riding a horse,
but with your eyes closed.
That's stupid.
Why would anybody want that?
Because it's exciting.
It's risky.
That's the point! That's
how love should be.
You are such a fool, Susana.
But that's what your song says, right?
Right, but it’s a sad song and
you're saying it as a good thing.
Who's in the shower?
What a surprise.
Where are you!
You disappeared.
Well, I changed plans.
Great that you recovered
your sense of humor
I thought you were still crying over
the steering wheel.
Sorry, I didn't mean to say that.
Sorry, I told you already, it's enough.
I’m so annoying, I know.
In “Siete Tazas”, do you know it?
It’s beautiful.
Yes, I mean, more or less by myself.
Do you know who is
the park ranger here? Guess.
Well, if you're not interested
I won't tell you.
No, don't hang up, let's talk at least.
Honey!
Ximena, how are you?
I’m fine.
Sure, don't worry.
OK, you have my computer.
... go to shared files.
... folder... Time.
Open there, the file is called MDS final
...that one.
Right - click there..
Third or fourth option, I don't know
which one, but it is called Graph
Did it work?
Ok, I have to go. Joel is calling me
to go for a walk.
Bye bye
For the cold.
Thank you very much.
“Iskald”
Cold.
“skogen”
Forest.
“Tell”
Me?
Oh, the tent.
What?
Doesn't matter, nothing.
Hello!
Carla, do you think that in the future
there will be no more trees?
Eh...I don't think so.
Me neither. There're too many.
When I first came here I saw everything
like a green mass.
Almost exasperating.
I even dreamt in green.
Now I know all of them!
Should I say them?
What?
The names of the trees,
so you start learning them.
Roble
Castaño de Indias
Ciprés cordillerano
Radal
Tabaco del Diablo
These coigües are old, they can be 200
or 300 years of age, or more.
Did you know that these
are already dead inside?
But they keep living, on the outside.
Trees are the only ones that can
do that, to die and keep going.
Like me.
Marcela left home let's say on
a Friday,
and I didn't notice until Monday.
When I went to get her
at her parent's house,
she didn't even want to see me.
My mother in law came out...
...and she talked about cocaine,
the brain, Marcelita's black eye...
... and I just looked at her,
without listening.
And suddenly I realized...
...that the lady
had her sweater on inside out.
I don't know why I got stuck
on that stupid detail.
Until I couldn't resist it.
I interrupted her and said...
...excuse me madam,
you sweater's inside out.
She slammed the door...
... and never opened it again.
I was left alone.
And here I am! Strong and healthy.
Come here, touch!
It's great!
You’re very thin.
Are you all right?
Do you feel good?
Yes... more or less
Skinny and pale.
You should eat better, get some sun.
Well... I’ll try, thanks
Too much chatting already.
I better get to work.
Oscar Papa to Alfa Sierra...
Alfa Sierra to Oscar Papa
I’ll be by the Oak forest
R4, come around when you're done.
Hi.
We were talking about you.
OK, are we going home?
Let's go.
All of us?
Drink.
Hi uncle! These are Carla and Ulrik.
Good afternoon, come in.
Hi aunt Mecha.
These are Ulrik and Carla.
Ulrik is from Norway.
From Oslo?
No, from a small town near the
polar circle: Masfjorden.
No, thanks.
Eat, eat, you could use some.
Grandpa I am going to use your
stereo for a while.
Sure, darling
Thanks.
Sit down.
Let that thing go,
it will make you sick. Eat!
Come on aunt Mecha.
Let's see... a bit closer together.
A bit more.
Squeeze together
A bit more...
I’m sorry!
It doesn't matter.
Leave that chicken there boy.
Come on, let's take the picture.
Hey Susana, I already told you!
Just relax aunt!
Better go to bed madam.
Grandpa needs to rest too.
But grandpa doesn't mind,
right grandpa?
Right!
What's wrong with you faggot!
You liked it all the same.
I won't hit you because
you're a woman and wear glasses!
This way?
No, it's that way.
I am going for a walk
So late?
Are you scared?
Yes, a bit.
Then don't come.
Are you pissed off?
Sorry Ulrik.
Wait!
Come on Ulrik don't go so fast.
Fuck!
Ulrik?
What happened?
Nothing.
Are you all right?
I’m a bit lost!
Ulrik!
Is there anybody here?
Excuse me.
What happened to you?
Nothing...to you?
Nothing.
Miguel.
Hello Miguel.
Hello.
Carla... wait.
Something happened to Orlando!
What?
I don't know.
He just fainted.
I don't know what happened.
You're a medical student,
aren't you Ulrik?
Yes, he’s alive!
Hi.
How do you feel?
Tired.
Old.
Should I call someone from your family?
No, there's nobody to call.
Orlando... excuse me.
You don't have kids, right?
No.
Would you like to?
Do you ever think about that?
For example that now your kids
could visit you.
Things like that.
I do think about that.
Just imagine...
...if I’d had them with Marcelita...
...because she wanted
kids, you know?
Damn, they would be now,
what... 18?
Two good sons.
They would come and say:
Don't worry daddy, we’ll
take care of everything.
Who else would say that shit?
I don't know, friends I guess.
No.
Friends are for good times.
Maybe
Why don't you have kids now?
Now?
You should have kids when you're young.
It’s a law of nature.
It's sad you know?
Leaving this world without a trace
Who is leaving this world?
Don't be tragic.
But it is a tragedy if you think
about it.
You’re born and then you die.
And nobody remembers you.
There is no trace of your life on earth.
No trace? You’re leaving a song
that everybody knows!
A horrible song.
You’re depressed,
don't think about this now.
You brought it up.
Alfa Sierra to Oscar Papa.
You're right, sorry.
Oscar Papa here,
go ahead Alfa Sierra.
I’m waiting for you here at the hot
dog party. Are you coming?
Negative, I’m busy at the time.
Too bad, I thought that,
well... OK... over.
Ah! I authorize you to eat my hot dog.
Thanks anyway Oscar Papa.
Why do they call you Oscar Papa?
It's the R code
Carla... what was your...
Gutierrez.
You would be Charlie Golf.
Nice, I like it... Charlie Golf.
Excuse me!
We’re leaving.
Can I leave you the money I owe?
I don't want to...
You understand.
All right then...
I will give it to...
Did you have a goodtime?
Yes.
Can I ask you a favor?
How was Orlando's song?
Vanity?
Can you sing it?
I can't remember.
No, I sing too badly
Just a little bit.
It's on the tip of my tongue.
No, I’m really bad at singing.
OK, fine, have a good trip.
Where are you going?
To the hot springs.
Can I go?
lid prefer if you don't.
Please?
Will you talk to me?
Can you stop using that
stupid accent, please?
Sorry.
I like being Ulrik.
Is it so bad wanting to be Ulrik?
What's wrong with being Miguel?
Miguel is boring.
You wouldn't have travelled
with Miguel Cardenas.
OK, maybe. But what can you do?
You can't lie just to have more friends.
You lied too.
The twins were a lie.
That was different.
It was an excuse. I only did it once.
You lied all the time.
You told only lies.
They weren't all lies.
Just the name.
Everything you said.
You were acting.
I wasn't acting.
It was only the voice.
The voice is everything.
The voice is just the voice.
So, where are you from?
From Puerto Montt.
I don't believe a word you say
From Ñuñoa
You are not scared, are you?
No.
Where were you?
We were at the hot springs.
It’s very nice there.
Look what we found.
Can you play?
No.
I can play a bit.
Let's go play.
Ah, Carla!
Someone's looking for you,
down at the cabin
Thanks.
...like on a screen...
In the retina, I’m telling you!
I’ve seen a picture of retina,
and all you see is blood.
What did you want to see?
It's supposed to be like a screen.
It's not so literal,
it doesn't need to reflect light...
Lots of bugs.
How are you?
I’m good
Better.
That's how you look... better.
Yes, I’m better.
You look good.
Thanks.
Yes, l... I feel good.
How are you?
What?
How are you doing?
The same.
Joel?
When are you coming back
to Santiago?
I don't know. I’ll wait
until Orlando gets better.
Who's Orlando?
The park... Orlando Palma!
The singer, remember him?
No.
Sure you remember.
He had this song called Vanity
No... no.
Vanity, it was very well known.
I don't know it.
But everybody knows that song!
Vanity by Orlando Palma.
I’m fucking sorry.
I don't know it... so what?
Never mind... it's just a good song.
I’m sure you know it.
How was it?
Sing a little bit.
Come on, sing a little bit.
I can't remember it.
...for vanity...
...to the wind...
...a dream... for vanity...
If you want to bet,
you can offer more
than a plain feeling.
But soon you’ll see,
Things always come back to their place,
And your game is over.
I changed my freedom for
a moment.
For vanity,
I threw my luck to the wind.
To the wind...
I lost everything...
...lying.
I threw everything...
...to the wind.
OK then.
You could give me your number,
we can have lunch one day.
Really?
We are friends Ulrik...
Miguel.
Aren't we?
Do you have where to...
THE END
Ripped and Corrected by PANGI
www.clan-sudamerica.net