Colo Colo is Chile's most
popular football club.
ln the fight against
the Spanish lnvasion.
Formed ''Garra Blanca''
Kunta is one ofthe
founders of Garra Blanca.
He was stabbed 2 weeks ago.
Today, he goes home.
- Neurosurgery-
What we showed, were
images taken outside.
We were not allowed into the
stadium for the match.
l am the journalist, l am
who is doing this story.
The topic, in this case, is not...
... the violence within Garra
Blanca. lt is not Garra Blanca.
lt is the consequence, for me, that a
person who wants to follow his team
That for me...
is the main concern
Even my head has swollen
during my stay here.....
- bye lván
- bye José
Ok buddy, be well.
Be strong buddy, we
are bigger than life.
- Take good care of him
- Thanks.
The pills!, the pills!.
somebody take the TV set!.
Will you take it yourself?
go on, buddy.
The book?
The book!
''Saving Private Kunta''
To a new reality...
l don't know, l think that...
l think many things,...
... what's awaiting me now?.
my mind's blank, l mean...
- ¿uh?
- That after 2 weeks
being on a stretcher and...
... come out again,
l don't know, l am scared.
- But you will go out to be with us.
- Yes pal, you have to think about it.
- Savage fight between supporters. -
- Terror after chilean ''Classic'' match. -
- ''Garrero'' left paraplejic... -
What do l tell his family?
''Colo Colo coach complains''
''l just wanted to
calm down the fight''
Kunta is paraplegic now.
We will exterminate
the ''supporters''
1, 2, 3...
Wait, the probe, l don't
know where is it
ls it below?
l believe that before this l
didn't care much about myself.
But now l realize...
...that it is important
to live, l mean...
... l believe that l was
about to die and...
...if l had died, l had died
as a martyr for the Garra.
l am alive and l want
to keep living, l mean
...l can't give up fighting
l must be strong and...
l find support in my people.
l mean, l have a small family,
it's just me and my mom, but...
...l think my family is Garra Blanca.
The Garra is my world, l mean...
...my life is about Garra
Blanca and nothing else.
Kunta lives for the
Garra and nothing else.
This is my world and nobody
is going to take it from me.
And Colo Colo of course, l mean...
...everything is linked.
Kunta's world without Kunta
Today the ''wonderful kid''
is going to play at last.
''Damn cops'' don't even
pay their bus tickets.
Today we can't lose the match.
Motherfucking Cop
Garra Blanca jumps
on their seats...
...without police and
military we are gonna win.
As you can see,
the ''L'' and the ''R''...
...you're gonna say, ¿why?
ln English, obviously.
''L'' means left side , left!
And ''R'' means right side.
But, What can we expect
from our national police?.
As we can see...
You, don't do it!
¿Like that?, NO!
You don't do that.
lf you don't want to be like them,
learn some English,
very simple. Left, Right.
- Hey, where are we going to lunch?
- Hey boys, have lunch here
- Look, ''Cazuela'' for $900
- Fried fish with a side for $1500
Look at that bitch on TV.
There she is.
-At next wednesday's meeting...
...where the associates
will determine the form...
...to administrate the
bankruptcy ofthe Club
- How much?
- One Thousand
lt's going to have to
be bigger for me, then.
Thanks.
The last supper, that was a
party with the boys...
lt was the last blast,
madman Jesus was leaving the city
The madman Jesus is illuminated
because he drank Peyote.
he had the cocaine,
and he was selfish.
They said, ''hey bastard, give
us our grams, give us a blow''
''we don't care ifyou are the damn
prophet'', just give us the drug.
How are you?
how are you doing today?
We have your canvas.
Yes, we are in the stadium.
What?
lf, we are going to display your canvas.
l love you so much. Bye.
Kunta Be Strong.
Attention all the
''colocolinos'' in their heart...
Ce Ache l, ¡CHl!
Ele E, ¡Le!
Chi Chi CHi, Le Le Le
Colo Colo de Chile.
Now buy my beads for a buck.
- The Garra is here very crazy
-Asshole! Asshole!
- And we want to be champions
- To be champions,
let's jump on our seats
Let's scream loudly,
We will be the best.
Support the Garra Blanca.
you fuckwits! What's up?
You have to sing, fucking bastards.
Be brave, fuckwits!
What's up?
We are the Garra Blanca, ''garreros''
until death, here is my heart.
Are you getting me?, What's up?
Let's scream, guys!
My vice, my passion.
More than a religion.
My temple.
Colo Colo reflects
the marginal world...
lt's the way of a higher
class society man...
...to look at Colo Colo, like a very
typical and very chilean ''thing''.
But for the people, Colo
Colo is something bigger,
it's a passion.
An extremely popular team.
Because it represented the
feeling ofthe excluded ones,
the ones nobody ever took seriously.
And that, nevertheless, is
capable of doing great things.
lf you ask ''Why am l a Colocolino?''
Damn, l don't know, maybe my
fathertold me to be, l don't know.
Colo Colo is a feeling.
You usually get it from your parents.
and that's why it's so deep.
lt's a belonging sensation.
one loses his rationality,
and emotions appear.
lt reflects the ''radical
way'' in chilean society.
ln that angerthat lives.
ln certain social groups.
For the champions,
scream from our hearts!''
The feeling l get
when l hit my drum.
l know if the stadium is full...
...waiting for the next ''boom''.
l really enjoy that
moment, like Phew!
And then people start
tojump and scream.
l would never change
that for anything.
You can't control
emotions and feelings.
Rational decisions can change,
if there is calculation and benefit.
But it's not like that
ifthe feelings appear.
The poorer and the richer,
can feel the same passion.
Passion?
l hit the drum with passion.
To win.
To scream.
Tojump, bro'
lt's Passion, l love Colo-Colo.
Following Colo-Colo is a lifestyle.
That's my life.
1, 2, 3...
For the champion,
for the champion.
Let's scream from our hearts.
For the champion,
for the champion.
Let's scream from our hearts.
1, 2, 3...
attention all the
''colocolinos'' hearts
Ce ache i, Chi, Le
Chi chi chi, le le le
Colo Colo de Chile.
The feeling of belonging.
Hey fucker!,
how you've been, bro?
- Did you arrive early?
- No, we're just arriving now.
Last night we were
at Conejo's house.
We drank to death.
l ''scored'' my ticket.
An old man gave it to me
come and visit, or l'll
see you at the beach.
lfyou see Pirata, tell
him: ''take care ofthe bus''.
Look, there is Juan
''Flag'', go easy now.
Hello!
Fucking Kunta, l will
not tell you anything, bro.
- Today l'm back at the stadium.
- That's good, l'm glad.
l'm very nervous.
lt is a strange feeling,
l'm nervous.
4 months have passed.
So now i want to see
my people again.
Don't take him there, it's
a mess! tear gas included.
Let's go, let's do this quickly.
- Go in, that way.
- That way are the tickets.
- Give me your ticket.
- We are five.
- But let me enter, man.
- Easy, easy.
- This is a damn chaos!
- We are helping you, man!
- l'll return it to you at the end.
-And how do l do it, captain?
- You will spoil his business.
- lt's his earnings.
- Look, it's not that bad.
- l will check it there.
- Ok, check it if you want.
-Carlos, wait!.
- What happened, Kunta?
They seized my t-shirts
and hats. And i don't know why.
- l smell gas around here.
- Thanks.
- Everything all right?
- Yes.
We'll see them
come out from here.
''When the team's playing bad,
the supporters make it win''.
''We must scream louder
when we are losing''.
''That ''huevones'' is
to have real feelings''.
''When the team plays bad,
supporters make it win''.
The love for Colo Colo
is a never ending one
The true Garrero,
who loves Colo-Colo,
never gives up.
Despite that life gives
You many difficulties,
you will keep
loving Colo-Colo.
Be part of something.
Not everyone belongs
to a political party.
Especially ifyou can't
be an active member.
Because usually,
less educated people...
or the poor one, hardly
will have a carreer
in a political party.
Besides that supposes
adaptation to the media,
a certain ideology,
something more elaborated.
Same thing for religious beliefs.
But Colo Colo is Forever.
lt means so much, man.
lt goes beyond the
religion and the politics.
This, look.
This, this, this.
My underwear too?
lt is the emotional language.
Why some people, can be
so fanatical for a team.
All teams in world represent:
A university, a city,
a town, a neighborhood.
Colo Colo represents the soul
of ''people'', the soul of Mapuche.
Quest for ldentity
Garra Blanca, always have
been at ''people's side''.
As the same emblem that
Colo Colo represents for us,
lt represents the whole
people who have been oppressed,
And, as Garra Blanca, we
are the voice of the people.
The people who fight in
their villages and streets.
That movement belongs to the
people, to the excluded ones.
Garra Blanca has a peculiar
kind of organization.
lt's unique in these types of groups.
Because it's a
horizontal organization.
And the leadership inside the
Garra Blanca is disputed with force.
Like the Mapuche organizations.
This represents us because
we also live in ''community''.
And each ''community'', in their
neighborhood, is a ''piño''.
That goes out, that organizes
themselves and fights day after day.
Mapuches are still fighting
after 500 years ofwar.
They will never surrender.
They all gave up against
the spanish conquest.
And Colo-Colo represents that.
We are living historical
times here in Chile.
This is the first step,
people will see that Garra
blanca is not all about vandalism
We are in the street, giving support.
Marrichiweu
Long life to Colo-Colo
and Garra Blanca.
We are asking you to be at
the height ofthis historical process.
feeds the oppression
and the impunity...
for the police and all
the repressive system of Chile.
We are gonna shake
our fear out today.
Today, we are going to walk with
the dignity of our ancestors.
without violence
but strong enough.
Protecting each other
Marichiweu!
people to walk
down their own streets.
- Think about that,
going to been shown
all over the world.
and l hope you're happy, and
study another carreer, and...
don't have to work like cops.
- You can't walk.
- Don't forget who we are,
A lot ofyou are Mapuche.
- Just look at your own faces.
- Set free the Mapuche fighters!
l think the Mapuche warrior
never surrenders,
and it is what l have
to demostrate now.
lf l'm an indian, a ''garrero'',
- Now l have to demostrate that.
l want Colo Colo to qualify
forthe South American Cup and...
to see how l can travel.
Since the first day.
l was blocked out,
everything fell.
...for the South American Cup.
And follow Colo-Colo like in the
past but now on a different way.
l don't know how, but
l'm gonna be there.
Look at the place.
- Are we ok?
-Yes, let's go!
When your it's your love you leave,
out ofyour heart,
But when your keep your
love, and don't project it.
Then, what's love for,
ifwe don't show it?
But God loves you
so much, my bro'!
But ifyou put your faith with
God, you will be walking man.
Put your faith in God,
as you have for your team.
And you will walk my brother.
l tell you, in the name ofJesus,
you are gonna walk.
My brothers, good
afternoon, God bless you...
...is there anybody who
wants to buy bubble gum.
l'm keeping the promise l did to
myselfwhen l went to the hospital.
''l will never change my
way to follow the team''.
Here l am again!
...tired as shit, but,
...here we are.
My body.
l love it.
My heart it's Colo-Colo.
Mapuche, indian.
l love it.
- lt's meat.
- Beef.
- Alpaca meat.
As you see, l have to
pay my medical expenses.
l cannot travel quiet now.
Now, l travel with no
money, by land on a bus.
On a wheelchair.
32 hours on the bus,
and l never got down from it.
Because l'm fucked up.
- Johan Vásquez
- Motherfucker.
lost it's players in a plane crash.
The only team that
felt the same pain,
it was Colo-Colo.
ln that time Colo-Colo
gave us 4 players for free,
to Alianza Lima.
Because the solidarity
they showed as team.
As a social movement.
The gesture of helping us
in such a difficult moment.
lt's a feeling thatAlianza and
peruvian people, have on their mind.
Certainly it is an example for Chile,
that has Colo Colo as
a symbol in other places.
people are like the peruvian's.
ln this case, chilean
people are colocolino.
The biggest supporters in Chile.
And Alianza is the same
for peruvian people.
Those are things that bind us.
We take this as an example,
that football is not
about violence
or rivalry.
lt's a brotherhood thing.
ln this case, between
peruvians and chileans.
Brotherhood ofthe excluded
l come fromArgentina, bro'.
l'm a fan of Chacarita Juniors,
l came to see the Garra.
And with good mood.
lt's been 20 matches
since l last came.
They won 19 and
drew only one.
This will be their 20th victory.
Let's go Chaca!
Colo Colo is the best
team in the world!
Super Copa, Like Colo
Colo there's no other!
Who is Chile?
Colo Colo!
Who is Colo Colo?
Chile!
Ce ache i, chi, le.
Chi chi chi, le le le.
Colo Colo de Chile.
Freedom for Mapuche
brothers, motherfucking cop.
To everyone, and for Boca
Juniors supporters especially.
You ''Bosteros'' don't exist!
You don't have balls, motherfuckers.
Garra Blanca and
Chacarita, brotherhood.
Colo Colo is the biggest, man
Chacarita brotherhood, dude,
Chacarita brotherhood, dude.
''The day l die, l dont know
what will happen to my body''.
''But l know that my soul will
remain here, supporting you''.
There's an article on ''gatito
Leeb'', a Chacarita player.
He was asked about
Chacarita and he said:
When you're in
your neighborhood.
You talk to someone
about Chacarita,
not as a team,
Like a son, brother, a father.
Come on Chacarita,
man, let's go Chaca
This is Chacarita's heart.
Here's where it beats louder.
You have Chacarita in your genes.
Chile, Chile, up the arms
We pull politics aside.
Chacarita y Colo Colo, simply one.
We're going to have
a good relationship.
This is like what
happens to us.
Chacarita y Colo Colo
chased by the cops.
Get in the line.
Great brother, Chacarita,
freedom brother.
- ln the line ''Garrero'' sirs -
Get back, in the line.
One at a time.
Freedom to Mapuche brothers,
mapuches rule here in Chile
Thanks Caupolican,
thanks Lautaro, fuck!
You'll be able to scream soon.
With orwithout tickets
You'll be outside.
Esgrima fans are here.
The cops are with them.
We came toArgentina.
So?
Move on, asshole, move!
You see? dude.
- Move, you can't be here
-But sir
- Let me record here.
- No, no, move.
- Come here sir.
- But let me record.
-You can't be here
- We're working and
you cant be here.
- Ok, but don't touch me.
- Move, move!
- Ok, i'm moving.
- Get out -
- Take this sir out of here.
Well guys.
To you from Villa Maipu.
l'm entering the stadium.
Today we're gonna win.
To the ''garra''.
Can you be here
with that camera?
Chaca and Colo Colo.
Simply
One
Everywhere, ''G.B.''
is everywhere.
Look here.
As You received us
there, We receive You here.
This is ''Tato'' from the ''G.B''.
... almost after 2 months l 'm here...
... and this is as my neighborhood.
Always overthe stadium seat,
that's our battle-cry.
That represents
every ''garreros'' feelings.'
Also, it's a way to say
''this is my neighborhood''.
This wall means ''Garra Blanca''
zone and nobody touches it.
This is a Guinness Record l think.
dedicated to a football team.
120mts wide by 2.5 mts
high. o many square metres
started to keep the streets clean.
There always the oldwoman
who cares a ''shit'',
but We make ''good
neighbors'' job and...
...We clean the streets for her.
At last, all the wall belongs to us,
and it belongs to all
the neighborhood too.
The next phrase is,
''From the Cradle to the Coffin''.
We were born ''colocolinos'' and
''colocolinos'' we are gonna die.
The day of my death,
l want my coffin...
A Garrero is born
and dies ''Colocolino''.
Dear Lord, Celestial Lord.
Good faithful friend.
Companion, Lord.
Look us at this time, Celestial
Lord, we are going to you, lord.
By your poweful blood...
...the Jesus Christ blood.
Which was spilt on the cross.
Please Lord, clean us, Lord.
...now, in these words, Dear Lord.
All of us, Lord!
We want you to receive us, Dear Lord,
with a nice perfum.
You don't see our
condition, Celestial Lord.
You don't care ifwe are
drinking or if we are doped.
You don't see that, because the
heart is more important to you.
''Chavito'' rest in peace
now, he is with Jesus.
He is with you now. Dear Lord.
Make us understand, Lord.
''Chavito'', now is smiling.
And he doesn't need that we
remember him with sadness.
We wont remember him
with distress, my Lord.
We must remember
him with happiness.
Because he is with Christ,
Dear Lord, Celestial Father.
Colo Colo Stadium
Chavo's Funeral.
Ohhh, ''Chavo'' don't leave us!
And thanks again brothers.
Like a Garrero!
- ''Always in our hearts'' -
My son, no!
Ohhh, ''Chavo'' don't leave us!,
ohhh, ''Chavo'' don't leave us!
Kunta's Victory
So many people?
We'll be going on tuesday.
Just for the recent electoral
fraud they are asking you that.
Thats why they asked you.
...They ask you,
not for another thing.
They don't wanna be hostile, but
now the situation is not so good.
l wish you luck.
lt would have been better if
you played against America F.C.
See you later.
This pussy is afraid!
What's up, dude?
What's up, Kunta?
Are we getting on the boat?
Look, the ''barra brava'' is afraid!
Look, he doesn't want
to release his hand.
Tell the others guys to
come and help and carry me.
How are you going
to put me there?
Easy, easy.
Now release him, release him!.
l'm scared of this thing, man!
Don't worry, to die drowned is
the worst thing we can expect.
Assault that boat!
Tomorrow! Tomorrow!
the holders will come.
With the responsibility
to defeat Colo Colo.
To take advantage of the
''Nacional'' of Santiago.
The game is over
They are electrical touches.
No pain no game!
Here in Mexico, today.
l don't know what day it is.
But i want to dedicate this song...
...ofthis ''mariachis''...
...to my mom.
What happened to me.
l don't give this to anybody.
l believe that never before...
...l had never loved my mom.
With my mom always we
lived away from each other.
And after what happened to me.
l understood...
...and l felt that l had a mom.
Before this l didn't have a
mom, l didn't have a mother.
After what happened
to me, l valued her.
And she is the one
that gives the life.
Mom, l love you.
Mom...
...After what happened to me...
... l realize that l have a mom.
One never realizes,
what's by my side.
will be the saddest day of my life.
Mom, l love you very much.
l've never told you.
But indeed, mom,
l love you, l love you.
For many years already.
6 years, l think.
That ''Chamagol'' was coming
to my team (Atlante),
l started a friendship with him.
Friends who were coming here.
2 years or 1 year ago,
that Colo Colo came.
People of Chile could
come, to support.
4 years ago l went to
Chile, to support Colo.
lt has a good story.
The bus of ''Llaneros
de la Frontera'', man.
l'm speaking ''mexican'' now.
1, 2, 3.
l believe that on the trips,
friendship becomes stronger,
Between people whom
didn't met each other.
lt makes you know
much more the person,
A greeting like brothers.
Here on the trips, really.
You become friends.
Because already
you live with them.
l believe that the friendship
becomes much stronger,
lnside the trips ofthe Garra.
''Ponchar''.
Cigarrete papers.
Four goals we are
going to score you!
To belong to a social
group, like Garra Blanca.
Travelings, knowing what it means.
Get money for tickets
and the other things.
Are experiences that l had to
live, and l'll never forget.
l'm here with Kunta.
l never imagined to live.
The belong of ''Garra'',
to live a bankruptcy,
Being champion, to be
the scorer ofthe team.
... the fact that rival hates you.
They are beautiful things.
And l'll never forget either
my origins, or what l lived.
We are here.
-Are you happy?
- Yes, How couldn't l?
Go on Colo Colo, damn!
From Mexico to Magallanes.
We are in Mexico, Motherfucker!
Fucking asshole!.
There He is.
A Colo-Colo fan.
He came with ''Garra Blanca'' friends.
- Yeah, hello to all my
Garra Blanca brothers.
- Hello to Garra Blanca then.
They're things of life.
l don't blame anybody
for what happened to me.
l do not feel anger towards
the person who did this to me.
l've never had it. They
are things that happened.
They are twenty years
following the team.
Colo Colo and Garra
Blanca are my family.
The family that l never had.
l grew up with my mom and a
stepfather since 9 years old.
My mom worked herwhole life,
she left me to the care of others.
Being the only son in my family.
''Garra'' and Colo Colo
become part ofyour life.
''Garra Blanca''
The biggest thing after Colo Colo.
lt's like your second family.
Your people, your brothers.
Your soldiers who are by your
side ifyou have to fight.
The most of them
would give it.
Fucking cop!
Get your stick up
your ass, fucking cop!
Other problems appear, as the
lack of opportunities, for example.
The segmentation
ofthe Chilean society,
...the people who have
more anger against the system,
will approach the club
There is corruption in the police,
there is corruption in the Military.
...Pinochet has around 14
million dollars hidden.
becomes a feeling...
...of anger, of
indignation, of frustration.
''The sadly famous one''
The sadly famous one?
And they all speculate,
Saying that ''Garra
Blanca'' acted with violence.
Many times,
Garra has acted with violence,
but for consequence ofwhat?
...why ''Garra Blanca'' acted this way.
l'm Garra, l'm Garra,
l am Garra Blanca!
The society looks at us
badly, for the violence.
moves to the stadium,
nothing else.
ln Garra?, as everywhere
ln discotheques, in universities,
in schools.
Violence is present everywhere.
The Exclusion is an act ofViolence,
and all of us are responsible for that.
Many negative things of
Garra Blanca are said...
the drugs.
Because...
...to be like that,
it's not for anybody.
News.
ln a fight, for
leaderships among ''garreros''
Good night.
Pirata's life, according
to his relatives
And that passion
is now against him.
We are mapuches.
Fighting race.
Until death.
Marichiweu, marichiweu!
through the guts.
Medical diagnoses are serious.
Colo Colo is my god.
Garra Blanca my law.
We're dedicated to garra blanca
we're going to die
within our laws.
Colo Colo goes beyond players,
directors or Garra Blanca.
''El Pirata'' is still complicated
Near his home.
We talked with his family today.
They are very affected.
Wall painting ends...
''Only for being indians''
Raza Brava.
lndians indians!
Colo Colo is something...
...Sinister!
Go, Colo-Colo, Go!
Gentlemans,
me voy a ver al Colo.
Because they ''feel it'' like me.
Go Colo Colo.
Champion, Champion.
There's only one champion.
lt calls Colo Colo,
the eternal champion.
Ole ole ole oleeeee,
Bravo, Bravo.
A lot of Marihuana.
Dedicated to the rival,
playing drum with happiness.
The Eternal Champion is coming,
the champion, the champion.
- On the field.
Thanks dude.