The King Of Death
That which kills me, will remain my secret
(F. Lacenaire)
Monday
Hello, the personnel department
please!
Hello, my name is Barsch.
I wanted to inform you that I will quit my job
on the ïst of next month
Yes, but I have personal
reasons
Actually, I would like to take my unused
holiday. Is this possible?
Good, I will send you my written notice
tomorrow.
No, I took those already with me last week,
thanks.
Tuesday
Only one today?
Yes, I'll have to go to Uschis Birthday Party
Later on
Say hello from me
Jesus, I think he killed himself.
Who? Let me see
Bullshit! I don t believe this...
The guy is nuts anyway...
OK, here you go
6 marks.
Bye!
The story you are about to see is true
It is based on actual facts.
Vera - Gestapo's angel of Death
What are you doing here already?
Tell me!
Thought you would be at Uschi's birthday party...
Could you explain why
you are here already?
Wednesday
I love my wife very much
But a few months ago she started to bleed strongly
When we were,, Doing it"
I told her to see a doctor
But nothing changed.
He said, there is nothing wrong with her.
That idiot.
My wife always told me that I don't
have to worry about it.
But you know... people who say that
things like that often have mental problems.
Do YOU think this is normal?
Or not?
We tried to figure something out...
tried to be very careful...
But everytime I thought it got better,
she started bleeding again...
...like a slaughtered pig.
I guess, I didn't always have enough time for her...
Working six days a week...
Sometimes even longer...
All for us.
And the only thing I could think of during work,
was our,, problem".
But I never really could come up with something.
I was mentally blocked.
I never had problems...
with women and...
My wife seemed not to be as concerned
as I was.
Sometimes I was not sure who was ill...
her or me.
And on top of this... her
understanding comments:
,, No, it is not your fault...,,
,, No, I am not depressed"
,, I enjoy the time we have together"
Slowly I became tired
of all this...
...it made me agressive.
And when she tried to calm me down,
I became even more angry
I couldn't stand her kindness
any longer.
Do you understand?
I always tried to be a good lover.
Never just used her.
Why am I punished with her problem?
It did not make sense to me...
Am I right?
Yesterday was our
wedding anniversary.
And we wanted to do
something special.
I took a day off... even at this
Busy time.
But I wanted to spend this day
only with my wife.
First, we went to the museum...
...then to an overpriced restaurant.
...and finally to the cinema.
I had my suspicions,
but she was so happy during
that whole day.
As we went to bed early,
I knew it would...
turn out good.
First, everything worked out well...
and I was so happy.
Suddenly she started to cry.
I didn't have to ask what was going on.
I felt how,, wet" it became.
That was it...
All the hate and rage of the last months
Broke loose in me.
It was over, I did not care anymore!
I took a... and separated her head from the body
And the whole shit ran out...
...her body blew up.
...and then she burst.
Governess
Businessman
Pupil
Farmer
Schoolgirls
Gynaecologist
Apprentice
Pensioner
Unemployed
Stock Broker
Housewife
Student
Landlord
Thursday
Actor
Friday
We loose our life with pleasure (L'autréamont)
This is a chain letter. And it is a message
We demand you take your own life
According to our realization "I die, therefore I am"
In six days god created heaven and earth.
On day seven he killed himself.
Let's die!!!
Are we ready?
Is this the first reel?
Yes, reel one.
Are the colleagues all here?
...Yes!
OK, lights out.
This seems to be a test
Good, I go up now.
Attention, the sound is starting.
The person running amok doesen't
always choose his target consciously.
With his urge for
spectacular publicity he is...
...sometimes trying to correct an
imbalance.
Through the act of
killing he or she compensates...
...their own lack of celebrity
of importance.
By the end of the
twentieth century, man has come...
...to feel that he no longer has to
endure everything. No longer...
...does he accept miseries and
disasters with the stoicism of...
...a cow standing in the rain.
He has come to feel, that he
deserves justice and a degree of...
...consideration as an individual.
Where in the past he was passive,
modern man has become...
...reactive, therefore even a
person nauseated by life,
...the potential suicide, doesn't only
think of a quiet escape through...
...the backdoor.
Cheated by life,
this creature is trying to give a...
...final signal, to give its life a post-
humous meaning by its way of...
...dying. The frustration about
its own existence and its neglect...
...by a callously progressive
society manifests itself in this...
...universal act of vengeance.
The Amok-suicide seems to aim at all...
...those who always ignored him.
For once HE is making history...
...he is standing in the limelight
and finally people are interested...
...in his biography. He escapes a
"dead" life into a "living" death,
...knowing that, at least for a few
days, he will have the almost...
...undivided attention of the
general public. This absurd hope...
...is probably more authentic and
genuine than his whole virtually...
...non-existent life before.
He, the "motiveless-mass-murderer"
is the martyr of Post-modernism.
Saturday
Now, reel two.
There is some light showing
Reel three is next.
Now, the camera in the back
Sunday
This is the king of death...
he makes people want to die.