How long till we
get home, Papa?
It's still a ways.
Oh, fine.
Go to sleep, Andrea.
Lay your head down.
Do as he says, Andrea.
Your dad's right.
Lay down and take a nap.
It could be a while
before we get there.
Why does it take so long
to get home from here?
Because it's a long road.
How much more now?
40 minutes, an hour.
An hour?
When you wake up
we'll already be there, okay?
Look out!
Mommy, Mommy!
Andrea, have you been hurt?
Are you able to walk?
Luca.
Luca!
Where are you, damn it?
There's no signal.
We're in the middle
of the woods.
Come on.
Look, one bar.
One bar.
Maybe it's good enough
to call.
- Try!
- All right.
All right, I'll call
the police.
It's gonna--
it's gonna be okay.
Hello?
There's been an accident.
My husband--
my husband is--
my husband is dead.
Yes.
Hello?
Hello, can you hear me?
I got disconnected.
No.
What do we do?
- Come with me.
- Where are we going?
We'll walk out a way,
we'll find somebody
sooner or later.
- But--
- Don't talk, run.
Come on, baby, run.
Mommy, look.
There's a car.
Hold on.
Stop! Stop!
Go by the side of
the road and wait there. Go on.
Hey, you there!
Stop, please!
Help!
Help me.
Help me, please.
I beg you...
help me.
I beg you.
Mommy!
"The Last House
in the Woods."
Uh, yesterday?
I hung around with a friend.
We had a drink in a bar.
Yes, a friend.
A girl.
Don't you trust me?
You're always so suspicious.
Come on.
Yes. Okay.
Listen, could you give me
some driving lessons?
In exchange I'll give you
anything you want.
Yes, anything.
Think about it.
I said anything.
Come on now,
don't make me repeat it again.
Oh, I almost forgot.
It can't be anything to do
with sex, all right?
What's your hurry, moron?
Then there was Matteo,
Paolo and Sandro.
So that's eight, then.
Nine with you.
- Right, eight before me.
- Mmm-hmm.
No wait.
Before you there were
actually nine.
- Nine?
- Mmm-hmm.
I forgot about Maximilian.
But nothing ever really
happened with him.
What the heck
does that mean?
We just kissed.
Well, anyway,
nobody is as important
a man as Ricardo.
Me neither?
Be quiet, stupid.
It's different with you.
And what's so different?
You're a special guy.
There's nobody like you.
So am I just as important
as Ricardo then?
Mmmm.
Well?
You won't answer me?
Oh fuck,
what's with you guys?
What guys?
Men are always comparing
charts and facts.
Probably because
you're all insecure.
Fuck you.
Come on, Rino.
Did I hurt your feelings?
Forget about it.
I didn't mean it.
I was just kidding.
Aw.
You really are
important to me.
Of course
I'm important to you.
Every one of those other guys
is zero in front of me.
Don't get too cocky now.
You know I hate it when you do.
I was just kidding with you.
Okay.
Hey.
I want to make love,
but I want you to draw.
- What?
- Really.
I want to see what your mind comes up
with while we're making love.
But you have to keep drawing like this.
Don't hold back.
Okay, let's do it.
Let's see if you can
keep concentrating.
Huh?
It'll be easy.
Oh really?
We'll see about that.
It's gonna be a great drawing.
You'll see.
Oh yeah.
It'll be a masterpiece.
We'll never break up.
I--
I'll never break up
with you.
Hope in the car, Aurora.
What are you here for?
What do you want?
- I want to talk.
- Again?
We talked enough.
I said everything I had to say.
I know, but I still want to talk.
Please get in.
- Please.
- Only five minutes.
Then you'll take me to Gaia's.
I have an appointment with her.
- All right.
- And don't get crazy.
Promise.
Uh...
did you have a good time?
Yeah, but let's get
away from here.
This place is really weird.
Yeah, you're right.
Big or small,
I'm gonna bang 'em all.
Ee-ee!
Ginger, you're gonna be
a bad motherfucker tonight.
- Want to trip?
- Diego, you take a trip
and we'll have fun
with your ass.
Okay.
So what kind do you guys want,
a pink heart or a green roller?
Give me the red one,
Diego.
Diego, I want a blue one.
Ginger,
tonight is our night.
It's superbly a ee-ee!
Oh shit. Cesare, watch where the fuck
you're driving.
- What happened?
- What's up, pussy?
You got to throw up?
Don't be like Ginger.
He threw up on the side
of my car last week.
Hey, man, all the pills
fell on the floor.
Hey, what the fuck?
Ginger, do something
or I'm gonna kill that little bastard.
- Pick them up.
- Fuck you, man.
Hey, you better
do it, man
or I'll make you clean them up
with your fucking tongue.
Hey, are you all right?
Yeah.
I mean...
what do you
think we should--
well, you know.
You and l?
Oh.
It's always that.
Yeah.
I don't know, Rino.
I'm so confused.
You mean you don't want
to go out with me?
Don't start again.
What?
I don't want to be
your girlfriend.
You understand?
Diego, if I find even one
left back there tomorrow
I swear to God I'm gonna shove it
right up your asshole.
It'll be a fucking
suppository for the guy.
He'd like that.
It's your fault they fell.
You drive like shit.
Yeah, whatever.
Just give us two of them.
Come on, pass up
a couple, man.
- Two what?
- Two pills, you dickhead.
All right,
we shouldn't have made love.
I'm sorry.
You're still
in love with me.
I told you I'm not.
Well, what about
what we just did?
A moment of weakness.
But it's just not
the same thing.
I want to bang
a virgin, Cesare.
- I want to fuck a virgin!
- A nice little virgin slut.
- Man oh man.
- Cesare, pull over.
- I have to puke, man.
- What is he saying?
I've got to throw up.
What the fuck
is the fag saying back there?
- Who gives a shit?
- Pull over, okay?
- I've got to throw up.
- You're a real asshole.
Come on, I'm sick, dude.
Cesare, I need to bang a chick.
Let him hurl.
Fine then, you fuckhead.
Throw up, pussy.
Go on, man.
Give me some time
to think it over.
- How much time?
- I don't know.
- A while, I guess.
- Okay, how about a week?
Jeez, Rino.
Just don't push.
All right.
So are you mad?
Surprise!
- Get out.
- No!
No!
What do you want?
What the fuck are you
gonna do, pussy?
No! Rino!
Come on, baby.
You know you want it.
Let's see what we have here.
Oh, man.
What a pussy.
You've got only 20 bucks?
Cheap bastard.
- Let me go!
- Shut up, bitch!
- No!
- Ee-ee!
Come on, you're in deep shit.
And now we fuck
your little girl.
No! No!
No. No!
No!
Please, let me go.
Please!
Are you a virgin?
You're not a virgin?
Don't worry,
neither am l.
Please!
Get off her, you animal.
And don't move.
Come here, you little slut.
This is gonna be so fucking
fun, so enjoy it, huh?
You're a pretty little girl,
aren't you?
Yeah, you are.
Oh, man!
You put Giulio
to sleep, Clara?
Yeah, of course.
He fell asleep immediately.
It's his birthday
in a few days.
Thought about
what he would like?
Fist things first.
You give me a nice blowjob
right here and now.
Yeah, nice and sweet.
- Like an appetizer.
- Let me go!
No? Let me put it this way:.
if you don't suck my dick now
I'll give you a bigger smile
from ear to ear.
Now come on, unzip me.
Come on, I'm so horny.
Oh yeah, that's good.
Come on.
Come on, do it.
Do it.
That's good.
Come on. Come on.
Hurry up.
Oh, I can't wait.
Bravo.
That's good.
- Do it!
- Hold off. A car.
Don't worry about it, man.
They won't stop.
Stop!
- What's going on?
- Please help me!
Hey, dude.
Get back in, Clara.
Please, let's get
out of here.
Don't worry. You're safe now.
Get in the car.
Hey, Pops, you mind
your own fucking business, all right?
- You got that?
- Let's get out of here now.
Get in the car.
Go on.
Hey, bitch, we're not done
with you yet.
Don't be worried
about it, okay?
Antonio will make
everything all right.
Fuck it.
Maybe you'd better beat it.
Huh?
What part didn't you
understand?
Pops, here's the deal:
You and your chick get the fuck out now
and you leave the pretty girl
here with us. You got me?
If not, I'll cut open
your throat, all right?
Fucking better answer.
All right, man,
you're gonna--
Fucking shit, man!
Cesare, come on.
Disappear now.
Think about it.
We forget the whole thing,
you guys go home, right?
- You fucking shithead.
- Come on, man.
Man, come on.
- Cesare.
- Cesare, let's go.
Don't make me do it.
- Get out of here.
- Fuck you.
Okay, Pops.
You win.
Let's go.
- Right, let's go.
- Yeah, come on.
Rino!
Where's Rino?
- You slut.
- Come on, answer.
He's in here, okay?
You can keep sucking his dick
as long as you want.
- Assholes!
- Fuck you.
Yeah, fuck you,
you bitch.
Let's go.
Come on, let's get out of here.
Stupid bitch.
You're lucky
the old man showed up.
- Your ass was mine.
- Rino!
Dirty old skank bitch.
Rino.
Rino, please wake up.
Rino, wake up.
Rino.
Are you okay,
huh?
- Come on.
- Aurora.
Oh my God,
they hurt you.
Maybe you should come
to our house to settle down for a bit.
We don't live
far from here.
Help me.
You want tea, coffee?
A drink or something?
Yes, a tea.
Thanks.
Fine then.
I'll make it for Rino as well as Clara.
Are you sure you don't want me
to call the police?
No no.
It's really not a problem
if your concern is Clara and l.
We'd be happy to testify.
No.
No, it's all right.
I'd rather forget about it.
No big deal.
Are you sure then?
You really don't have to be
afraid of those guys.
No, it's okay really.
I appreciate your concern.
It's just it would scare
my parents.
Okay.
I'll take you home then
or back to your car.
Yeah. Yeah, back to the car
would be good.
Let's wait till
Rino's better though.
Fine then.
Sorry to have disturbed
you both.
It's okay.
Seriously.
Do you--
do you two live here alone?
Alone?
No.
There's Giulio too--
our son.
Ah, where is he?
Upstairs asleep.
He's only seven and he goes
to sleep quite early.
Listen,
mind if I ask something?
Yes, of course.
Please don't keep me
in suspense.
Okay.
How come you decided
to keep a gun?
Uh, I always have a gun.
You know,
living in this house,
being out in the middle
of the woods,
makes you-- well, it makes us feel
safe to have one.
Of course I have
a permit for it.
Does it frighten you?
No no.
I was just curious.
- Am I hurting you?
- No no.
It's fine.
it doesn't hurt.
Okay, then I'll continue.
We're almost done.
Feeling better?
Yeah.
Yeah, thanks.
Would you like to lie down
on the couch?
Oh, no.
Actually,
we'd better go soon.
My parents are strict.
Certainly.
I guess they'd be worried.
Do you want to call
to say you're all right?
No, it'll be okay.
I already said that
there was a good chance
that I wasn't going to
be home for dinner.
- So no problem.
- Fine.
You're very pretty,
you know?
I mean it.
You're a pretty girl.
The boys must all like you
a lot, don't they?
Well, yeah.
A couple, I guess.
Rino must feel lucky.
Yeah.
How have things
with you two been?
I like him a lot.
But?
Not satisfied?
No.
I love him like you'd--
well, like the way you'd
love a friend, I guess.
Or maybe a brother.
It's almost like
there's no real love left.
You could be right.
He can't give me
everything I want.
He's so different.
The one that's different
could be you.
It's normal at your age.
I...
What?
You what?
I'm not sure I feel like...
Papa, there you are.
Papa?
Now, Giulio,
didn't I tell you not
to go downstairs?
Sorry, Mom.
Say hi to the lady
and I'll bring you back upstairs.
- Hi.
And Papa.
Say good night.
Good night, Papa.
Good night, Giulio.
Look at you.
Your face is a mess.
I'm sorry about that.
Believe me, he just frightened me.
I shouldn't have done that.
- Don't worry about it.
- Forgive me, I'm so ashamed.
Really, it's okay.
Aurora, it's
a normal reaction.
Just take it easy.
I'll get the tea.
I think that I'd better
go check on Rino.
No, please stay.
Let me go.
Rino.
How is Rino?
Where is Rino?
Where's Rino?
Just stay calm now, Aurora.
I'm sorry.
I was gonna let you go.
But it's too late now.
It's impossible, Aurora.
I do it for Giulio.
I do it for our son.
Keep calm now.
Rino!
Rino, where are you?
Rino?
Aurora!
Rino!
What did they do to you?
Come on out, Aurora.
Come out now.
Hi.
What's your name?
Aurora.
I'm Giulio.
Hi, Giulio.
Come on, open up.
Open the door.
- I'll untie you, then we'll get away.
- I won't hurt you, Aurora.
Forget me, Aurora.
Please run!
- Go and save yourself.
- No, we'll go together.
Don't waste time.
Please, you must escape.
Aurora, it's not safe
in that room.
The window--
go out that way.
- Please forgive me.
- Go now, hurry.
I love you.
Yeah, me too.
Hurry.
Hurry!
Don't go, Aurora.
Don't go.
Don't look back.
Aurora, let me in.
I'm going to break down
the door.
She went out the window.
She escaped, Dad.
Aurora!
Aurora, stop.
Aurora, come back!
Aurora!
- Clara.
- What's going on?
She got away.
She climbed over the gate.
It's okay, Giulio.
Come over here.
There's nothing wrong now
so don't worry.
Your mommy's here
with you now, okay?
You're safe and sound
here with us.
Let's go.
Come on now.
Help.
Help me.
Anyone there?
Help me!
Somebody, please.
I need your help!
Anybody!
Hi.
Well done,
Emidio.
Well done!
Ha ha ha ha!
Are you serious?
It was fucking
unbelievable.
- She was hot.
- All right!
- What a babe, man.
- She was hot.
She was a real slut too,
I tell you.
- Hey, what'd she do to you?
- Yeah, come on, tell us.
Okay okay, we were on
the dance floor making out.
You saw that. And then she drags me
into the men's room.
She throws me up against the wall
and she unzips my fly.
- What a whore!
- What then?
What do you fucking
think, man?
- She gave me a blowjob.
- Fucking A.
She sucked out
my brains, man.
She swallowed every drop
until I was fucking bone-dry.
- That slut!
- Oh, come on, come on.
- How about after that?
- She gave me her phone number
and then later on I saw her making out
with some other guy.
What'd the bitch say?
She said, "lf you have to empty your
balls, give me a call. Call anytime."
Can you believe that?
- What the fuck is this?
- What?
- What's going on?
- We're out of gas.
- No fucking way.
- You've got to be kidding me.
Oh, fuck.
- Out of gas?
- Yeah! Shit.
Fuck, I knew it!
Come on!
Why didn't you get
gas before, man?
- What do we do now, bro?
- Easy, Diego.
Yeah yeah, fuck you!
It's always the same thing.
I knew it! I shouldn't
have come out with you!
- It's always the same shit.
- Shut up!
What the fuck are we gonna
do all the way out here?
- Tell me that.
- Diego, fuck, man!
I'm gonna kill you tonight
if you don't shut up!
Easy.
Diego, look, just call
the Viking.
Tell him to come
pick us up.
Why do I have to call?
Let's not get into it.
We're already in deep shit here.
- Can't you see?
- Why do we always got to use my phone?
Look, I'm out of credit
and so is Ginger.
And if both of us are out of credit,
that leaves you.
So what?
I have credit.
"Diego is always there
with his phone.
He's always got credit so
let's use his phone."
You don't care about me.
Hey, we got no
fucking money. You know that.
So what do you care?
I got credit, right?
I always pay for everything.
You guys never have any cash.
- That's it. I'm gonna gut you.
- Easy easy.
- Take it easy.
- Give me that phone, you motherfucker.
- Come on. Asshole.
- Fuck you.
There are zero
credits left.
Please enter
your credit card number--
Sucker's out of credit.
Diego, go fuck off, asshole.
What was that?
Shut the fuck up.
Let me listen.
They banging a girl
out there?
- Wanna go see?
- Shit, yeah.
Wait.
No no no.
We shouldn't go.
Look, shut your hole.
Take your cell phone
- and follow us.
- No, guys, hold on.
Guys, please.
It's cold and it's dark.
Why do we want
to go in the woods?
Guys!
Guys, hey, come on!
Wait!
Good morning,
pretty princess.
She's awake.
She's awake now.
- Yeah, she's awake.
- Yeah.
Glad to see you
return to us, Aurora.
Return to the family.
Prepare the room.
Help me!
I didn't want you to
see any of this, Aurora.
But you just
wouldn't listen.
And now...
you'll see it all.
Dude, what now?
What do you mean?
We go in.
They were banging
a girl, right?
Now we go in
and we bang the girl.
No. No.
No way, Cesare.
- I say we go in.
- No no.
We beat up all the men,
we bang all the ladies
and we walk out with all
their fucking DVD players.
Wait, that's trespassing
and stealing.
Who fucking cares, man?
- Hey, cut it out.
- What the fuck's the matter with you?
Pussy. Let's go.
Hey, let's use Diego
as a ladder.
We should.
Let's help the little baby.
Up you go.
- Come on.
- Let's go, guys.
What are we doing here?
Shut up.
What the fuck
are we doing?
Be quiet.
Shit, let's go.
- Keep low.
- Shh.
We gotta get out of here.
The lights are on.
- There's people in there.
- Man, that's the point.
Shut up. Christ,
let's not get caught.
- Come on, come on.
- Let's forget this.
Let's go.
Come on.
Quiet!
This is a stupid
fucking idea.
Shut up!
See that window?
We get in that way
and surprise 'em.
Hey, I gotta get back.
I gotta take my mom to
the doctor tomorrow morning.
Shut the fuck up.
Why is she upset, Papa?
Because she has been
a bad girl, Giulio.
Now she'll get the punishment
she deserves.
Come on, come on.
You go first.
You're the smallest.
- Are you nuts?
- I said get up there, shorty.
- Move it.
- Why do I have to go first?
Just get your ass
up there.
Let go.
Cut it out.
Come on.
Lean on me.
Let's go!
Someone--
someone's out there.
I saw somebody
running away.
Antonio?
I'll go see.
Don't.
It may be dangerous.
Don't worry, Clara.
You've had
enough to eat.
Come on now.
Mama.
What do you want
us to do?
You put Giulio to bed.
I'll be back soon.
You both keep
the girl here and watch her.
- We keep her here.
- Keep her here.
Holy shit.
Hey, isn't that guy--
Quiet, asshole.
Cesare, that's that fucking
pops we met on the road, man.
So I see.
Guys, come on.
- He's got a motherfucking gun.
- No way.
We burn that sucker.
You both just
heard your papa.
I'll bring Giulio upstairs
and you two stay here.
- Yes, Mama.
Mama, I don't want
to go up yet.
I want to wait
for Papa.
No, Giulio.
You have to listen
to your mama.
What's that, Mom?
No-- nothing, sweetheart.
Who's out there?
Good boy.
Sleep well, Giulio.
Sleep now,
my darling son.
I'm gonna break your
fucking face, motherfucker.
Got that?
You're gonna beg me to
kill you fucking faster.
Cesare, come on, man.
That's enough.
- Come on, man. Cesare!
- You fucker!
Whoa whoa!
Oh, fuck it.
Shit, man,
you killed that guy.
You saw.
He deserved what he got.
The bastard.
No.
This wasn't
in the plan.
Fuck it, man.
We're going in.
Huh?
Ain't that right, Ginger?
- Uh-huh.
- Right?
We're going in, Diego!
Huh? We beat 'em all.
Let's go. Let's do it.
Beat those motherfuckers.
Huh?
We crush
those suckers! Huh?
Come on, come on.
Come on, let's go.
The door's open.
Come on.
Holy shit.
- What the fuck?
- Fuck.
What?
Oh, man!
- What the fuck happened here?
- This is gross.
Please help me now.
- They're all monsters.
- What the hell is this shit?
- Who did this?
- They're monsters.
- It's impossible.
Cesare, let's go.
Let's go.
- Let's get out of here.
- Hey, come on!
Shut the fuck up!
Who's there?
Cesare.
Diego.
The priest always told me
that I should behave.
Check upstairs.
Go on.
- Man, I can't.
- Listen, Ginger.
- But I can't.
- Get a grip.
Move.
Come on.
Come on, Ginger.
- It's gonna be fine, man.
- No more.
- No more, no more.
- Listen, bro.
Okay?
You gotta get a grip, bro.
I need you to
be focused right now.
Okay, Ginger?
Aren't you Ginger, the ass-kicker?
Aren't you Ginger
with a giant dick?
Hey hey, look.
Look here.
These are just what
you want, right?
Huh?
See?
One for you and...
one for me.
And now we go get them.
Let's split up.
You go by the window,
- I go by the garage.
- Okay.
Got me? We don't know
how many there are,
but we will fucking
kick their asses!
Eee! Eee!
Go.
They have a kid.
No no!
No!
Sweetheart, Mommy has
to leave for a minute.
But I'll be back
right away, okay?
- Cesare.
- Ginger.
Cesare.
Ginger.
I'm sorry, Cesare.
I'm sorry.
Ginger!
Ginger.
- Eee!
- Ginger.
Ginger!
How could you do it?
My brother!
You monster.
You freak.
Come on!
Monster!
Will you help me?
Yeah.
Thank you!
Come on now.
Let's go.
No!
You did all this,
you little slut.
Let me go!
Let me out of here.
Antonio.
What's this?
What is this?
It's a boy.
Can't you see?
A boy who came here
to visit us.
Why?
But why?
Why what?
Why did you do this
to him?
Tell me what
I should have done.
I don't understand.
How could you?
You are a spoiled girl.
How could you possibly
understand what it's like
to love your son?
A parent would do
anything for their child.
Yes, even if that means that they
have to bring pain to others.
Giulio was a monster.
We don't know why.
He was born like that.
Those teeth.
We brought him to
this house in the woods,
me sure it was
far away from everybody,
pPretended he
was ordinary.
We went so far as to give him
two monsters for brothers.
We made believe
they were ours--
our children.
All of this so he would think
this was a normal life.
But things began to change.
It's like we had both
ran out of ideas.
We were going crazy.
Then one day
something changed.
It made perfect sense.
You see,
that was the day
Giulio bit Antonio's hand.
He bit off one of
his fingers.
And we knew
what he wanted
and what we had to do.
So we went out
and started to kill...
to feed our child.
I mean, we did all this
for our little boy, right?
Any parent would.
And then this child...
this poor child...
Help me!
Open the door!
So similar to
our own son.
If only that night I hadn't
given birth to a monster.
Mommy?
Kill me.
Oh!
Rino.
Rino, let's go.
Come on.
Wake up.
It's all over now.
Rino?
Rino, answer.
Rino, let's go, please.
I'll never forget you.
Goodbye.