Selling or showing this fllm
to persons who are under 18 years old
should be forbidden, because of the
many graphic deciptions
of cruelty and brutality in the film.
It was ln April 1985, the tlme of
full cherry blossoms in Tokyo,
bizarre cartoonist Hideshi Hibino
received one horrible parcel
from an unidentified person who calls
himself an enthuslastic fan
of the cartoonist, Hideshi Hibino.
The parcel contained one 8mm film,
54 still pictures and a 19-page letter.
The letter told the cartoonist
that a horrible and bizarre crime seemed
to have been performed by the person
of aesthetic paranoia in some secret
place. The 8mm film was considered to be
a vivid and authentlc film showing
an unidentified man chop the body
of a woman into pleces and put her into
his collection. Therefore, this film
should not be shown to other people.
Hideshi Hibino newly created this vldeo
as a restructured Semi-Documentary based
on the 8mm film, pictures and letter.
No!
Look! This ls your fate!
The women is at present in a state
of ecstasy from an injection of drugs.
She feels no paln at all, as you see.
Not only does she feel no pain
but the feeling is rather pleasurable.
When her bright red blood starts to creep
voluptuously and creature-like on her
white skin, like blossoms of blood
and flesh blooming in a sea of red,
truly a dazzling, intoxicating rapture.
There ls absolutely nothing
more beautiful ln life than this.
I am going to show you
the ideal of beauty.
First of all, red blossoms of blood
blooming from her wrist.
Next, full blossoms from her shoulder,
and from her red lips.
Now, for the last moment, a big flower
emerges around her petal
and wreps her body
with blooms and fragrance.
And now, her bowels start dancing wildly
on her body and bloom many blossoms.
Next she wears a necklace
of brlght red blooms around her neck.
Well, now, the finishing touch
is to take out her precious jewels.
Ah, thls is the most beautiful thing
of a woman's body. This is it!
Finally, blood and flesh
blooming perfect flowers.
Now, I will put them into my collection.
Now, I am golng to present
my collectlon to you.
Fall, fall, fall
to the bottom of Hell,
pool of blood,
sea of fire
and needle mountains.
Fall man to hell.
Fall, fall,
demons of Hell are calling you,
pool of blood,
sea of fire
and needle mountains.
Can't you hear the groan of the dead?
Fall, fall,
the darkness of Hell is boundless,
pool of blood,
sea of fire
and needle mountains.
It is the lullaby of hell.
This is the summarlzed story
of the contents of the 8mm film,
still pictures and letter.
It is assumed that at least two criminals
where involved in the crime.
One has executed the person
and the other has taken this film.
At the same time,
many women have been victimized.
According to our source,
the police started
a secret investigation.
It is also assumed that such an
unprecedented bizarre crime
is in the criminal record of Japan and
will become clear in the near future.