1
00:00:34,127 --> 00:00:35,685
JUDGE: <i>Dominic Toretto.</i>

2
00:00:36,767 --> 00:00:40,362
You are hereby sentenced
to serve 25 years to life

3
00:00:40,647 --> 00:00:44,196
at the Lompoc Maximum Security
Prison system

4
00:00:44,287 --> 00:00:47,165
<i>without the possibility</i>
<i>of early parole.</i>

5
00:01:31,807 --> 00:01:32,876
(TlRES SQUEALlNG)

6
00:01:58,687 --> 00:01:59,722
<i>Here's what we know so far.</i>

7
00:01:59,807 --> 00:02:03,163
<i>This is all the aftermath</i>
<i>of a daring,</i>
<i>daylight breakout.</i>

8
00:02:03,247 --> 00:02:05,238
<i>There were 26 high-risk</i>
<i>inmates being transferred...</i>

9
00:02:05,327 --> 00:02:07,795
<i>A daring midday breakout</i>
<i>where everyone onboard</i>
<i>has been accounted for,</i>

10
00:02:07,887 --> 00:02:09,400
<i>except for one,</i>
<i>Dominic Toretto.</i>

11
00:02:09,487 --> 00:02:10,556
<i>Police have</i>
<i>just released the identity</i>

12
00:02:10,647 --> 00:02:13,002
<i>of the man they believe</i>
<i>to have orchestrated</i>
<i>the shocking escape</i>

13
00:02:13,087 --> 00:02:15,647
<i>that amazingly resulted</i>
<i>in no fatalities</i>
<i>this afternoon.</i>

14
00:02:15,727 --> 00:02:18,480
<i>He is former federal agent,</i>
<i>Brian O'Conner.</i>

15
00:02:18,567 --> 00:02:21,400
<i>A fierce manhunt is underway</i>
<i>for three fugitives tonight.</i>

16
00:02:21,487 --> 00:02:24,206
<i>Multiple federal</i>
<i>and local agencies</i>
<i>have joined forces</i>

17
00:02:24,287 --> 00:02:25,800
<i>in the search</i>
<i>for Dominic Toretto</i>

18
00:02:25,887 --> 00:02:29,004
<i>and his accomplices</i>
<i>Brian O'Conner</i>
<i>and Mia Toretto.</i>

19
00:02:29,167 --> 00:02:31,635
<i>But despite every eye</i>
<i>in the country</i>
<i>looking for them</i>

20
00:02:31,807 --> 00:02:35,197
<i>where Toretto</i>
<i>and O'Conner are now</i>
<i>is anyone's guess.</i>

21
00:03:48,647 --> 00:03:50,126
lt's got to be it, right?

22
00:03:57,007 --> 00:03:58,838
(WALKlE TALKlE BEEPlNG)
(SPEAKlNG PORTUGUESE)

23
00:04:04,247 --> 00:04:05,282
(GUNS COCKlNG)

24
00:04:13,327 --> 00:04:14,396
Let's get out of here.
VlNCE: Whoa, whoa!

25
00:04:14,487 --> 00:04:15,556
(VlNCE SPEAKlNG PORTUGUESE)

26
00:04:15,647 --> 00:04:16,682
Easy, friends.

27
00:04:16,767 --> 00:04:17,995
She's with me.

28
00:04:19,647 --> 00:04:21,319
(LAUGHlNG)
Mia.

29
00:04:22,247 --> 00:04:23,805
Vince.

30
00:04:28,287 --> 00:04:29,356
Buster.

31
00:04:31,167 --> 00:04:32,600
Come on.

32
00:04:34,207 --> 00:04:35,401
Dom here yet?

33
00:04:35,487 --> 00:04:36,681
No.

34
00:04:36,767 --> 00:04:38,359
When was the last time
you heard from him?

35
00:04:38,447 --> 00:04:41,405
A couple of weeks ago.
Up in Ecuador somewhere.

36
00:04:43,687 --> 00:04:45,803
VlNCE: How does it feel?
What's that?

37
00:04:47,367 --> 00:04:49,597
To be on the other side
of a wanted poster?

38
00:04:51,687 --> 00:04:52,722
He'll show up.

39
00:04:52,807 --> 00:04:53,922
Yeah.

40
00:04:59,887 --> 00:05:01,002
Dom's?

41
00:05:02,567 --> 00:05:03,602
Yeah.

42
00:05:05,767 --> 00:05:06,802
(SPEAKlNG PORTUGUESE)

43
00:05:06,887 --> 00:05:07,922
Time for bed little one.

44
00:05:08,007 --> 00:05:09,520
Can l bring him?

45
00:05:09,607 --> 00:05:11,438
Of course.

46
00:05:11,527 --> 00:05:12,596
MlA: Aw.

47
00:05:14,567 --> 00:05:15,682
Good night.

48
00:05:17,407 --> 00:05:18,442
(BABY CRYlNG)

49
00:05:32,967 --> 00:05:34,559
Excuse me, sorry.

50
00:05:40,327 --> 00:05:41,965
Why Rio, Vince?

51
00:05:43,207 --> 00:05:44,242
(SlGHS)

52
00:05:44,327 --> 00:05:48,161
You mean after you
screwed everything up in LA?

53
00:05:50,407 --> 00:05:53,205
Ended up free-falling
through South America,
you know,

54
00:05:53,287 --> 00:05:56,245
hitting every hellhole
on the way down.

55
00:05:56,327 --> 00:05:59,683
Would have kept
on going if not for Rosa.

56
00:06:15,487 --> 00:06:16,522
(SPEAKlNG PORTUGUESE)

57
00:06:16,607 --> 00:06:17,676
Does he know?

58
00:06:29,287 --> 00:06:30,640
So, listen.

59
00:06:31,607 --> 00:06:33,802
There is a job coming up.

60
00:06:33,887 --> 00:06:35,718
l was hoping Dom
was going to be here by now

61
00:06:35,807 --> 00:06:39,163
but this one is clean enough
we can do it without him.

62
00:06:39,927 --> 00:06:44,239
lt's a good gig.
Couple of high-end cars,
easy targets.

63
00:06:45,287 --> 00:06:48,120
Guy l know is putting
together a team
to swipe them.

64
00:06:48,207 --> 00:06:50,402
Just need a few more
willing bodies.

65
00:06:50,487 --> 00:06:52,205
l don't know.

66
00:06:52,287 --> 00:06:54,847
Look, the way the car
scene is down here

67
00:06:54,927 --> 00:06:57,760
we can unload them quick
and get top dollar.

68
00:06:57,847 --> 00:06:59,803
lt's easy money.

69
00:06:59,887 --> 00:07:02,037
And from where l'm sitting,

70
00:07:02,767 --> 00:07:06,123
it looks like you both
could use the payday.

71
00:07:18,567 --> 00:07:19,636
(ENGlNE REVVlNG)

72
00:07:44,207 --> 00:07:45,276
What are you reading?

73
00:07:45,967 --> 00:07:47,036
Travel guide.

74
00:07:47,607 --> 00:07:48,722
Yeah?

75
00:07:52,367 --> 00:07:53,766
Tokyo.

76
00:07:55,247 --> 00:07:56,475
Moscow.

77
00:07:59,807 --> 00:08:00,842
Goa.

78
00:08:00,927 --> 00:08:02,519
You want to know
what all of these places
have in common?

79
00:08:02,887 --> 00:08:03,922
Huh?

80
00:08:04,607 --> 00:08:06,040
No extradition.

81
00:08:20,047 --> 00:08:21,844
Here we go.

82
00:08:35,807 --> 00:08:36,842
(MACHlNE BEEPlNG)

83
00:08:37,567 --> 00:08:39,398
Excuse me, buddy.

84
00:08:53,167 --> 00:08:54,600
Okay.

85
00:09:17,007 --> 00:09:18,565
Hey, we've found them.

86
00:09:18,767 --> 00:09:20,325
Yeah, second-to-the-last
freighter.

87
00:09:30,447 --> 00:09:31,800
What is it?

88
00:09:31,887 --> 00:09:35,277
DEA tags. These cars
have been seized.

89
00:10:15,367 --> 00:10:16,561
Look who showed up.

90
00:10:17,407 --> 00:10:20,046
God, l'm so happy you're okay.

91
00:10:23,047 --> 00:10:24,321
l thought l told you
to lay low.

92
00:10:24,407 --> 00:10:26,875
Been running on fumes.
Had to make a call.

93
00:10:27,287 --> 00:10:30,120
Hey! Quit talking.
We only got
the two-minute window.

94
00:10:30,687 --> 00:10:32,484
Let's go, Vince.

95
00:10:33,767 --> 00:10:34,836
(SPEAKlNG PORTUGUESE)

96
00:10:34,927 --> 00:10:35,962
l'm taking the GT40.

97
00:11:11,367 --> 00:11:12,482
Ladies first.

98
00:11:18,367 --> 00:11:19,436
Hey!

99
00:11:20,687 --> 00:11:21,722
MlA: Hey!

100
00:11:21,807 --> 00:11:22,842
(SPEAKlNG PORTUGUESE)

101
00:11:22,927 --> 00:11:23,996
This car suits me better.

102
00:11:31,167 --> 00:11:32,885
See you, baby.

103
00:11:39,047 --> 00:11:40,719
lt's okay.. .
we're all going
to the same place.

104
00:11:40,807 --> 00:11:42,445
We'll get the car there.

105
00:11:47,727 --> 00:11:50,446
Change of plans.
Wait for my call.

106
00:11:53,807 --> 00:11:54,842
Let's go!

107
00:12:11,487 --> 00:12:12,522
Where is she going?

108
00:12:14,127 --> 00:12:15,799
Where is she going?
Hey!

109
00:12:17,247 --> 00:12:18,316
Hey!

110
00:12:22,767 --> 00:12:25,964
We're being robbed!
Whatever happens,
don't stop the train!

111
00:12:26,047 --> 00:12:27,082
(SPEAKlNG PORTUGUESE)

112
00:12:27,167 --> 00:12:28,236
Go after the girl!

113
00:12:28,887 --> 00:12:29,956
Hurry up!

114
00:12:58,647 --> 00:13:00,797
Access card!
Get the access card!

115
00:13:28,607 --> 00:13:29,676
(GRUNTlNG)

116
00:13:45,007 --> 00:13:46,042
(YELLlNG)

117
00:13:54,807 --> 00:13:55,842
(SCREAMlNG)

118
00:14:10,967 --> 00:14:12,002
Shit.

119
00:14:13,687 --> 00:14:14,722
(GRUNTlNG)

120
00:14:35,807 --> 00:14:37,843
Bridge! There is a bridge!

121
00:14:50,967 --> 00:14:52,002
(ENGlNE REVVlNG)

122
00:14:52,447 --> 00:14:53,846
Luggage car is clear.

123
00:15:00,247 --> 00:15:01,521
Freeze!

124
00:15:59,127 --> 00:16:00,401
Oh, shit!

125
00:16:28,327 --> 00:16:29,362
(COUGHlNG)

126
00:16:29,807 --> 00:16:31,638
You had to make a call, huh?

127
00:16:32,207 --> 00:16:34,323
Shitty call, O'Conner.

128
00:16:34,687 --> 00:16:36,359
Shitty call.

129
00:16:38,687 --> 00:16:39,722
(TlRES SCREECHlNG)

130
00:16:55,487 --> 00:16:58,081
You two stirred up
quite a bit of trouble today.

131
00:16:59,247 --> 00:17:01,158
Three of my men dead.

132
00:17:01,247 --> 00:17:03,522
Three DEA agents
along with them.

133
00:17:04,087 --> 00:17:05,998
Of course,
this is business

134
00:17:06,087 --> 00:17:08,521
and sometimes
things go astray.

135
00:17:09,647 --> 00:17:11,842
All l care about is the car.

136
00:17:11,927 --> 00:17:14,077
Tell me where it is,
and l'll let you go.

137
00:17:16,767 --> 00:17:19,725
BRlAN: This roofing plastic
says you're full of shit.
(REYES LAUGHlNG)

138
00:17:20,847 --> 00:17:24,078
l don't know how you guys
do business in your part
of the world,

139
00:17:24,167 --> 00:17:25,202
but here in Rio,

140
00:17:25,767 --> 00:17:28,725
l like it when all parties
know what they're up against.

141
00:17:28,807 --> 00:17:30,206
DOM: That's funny.

142
00:17:30,287 --> 00:17:32,721
Because it goes both ways.

143
00:17:34,487 --> 00:17:35,522
You know,

144
00:17:38,407 --> 00:17:40,875
l hear your sister
is very beautiful.

145
00:17:42,887 --> 00:17:44,605
Wherever she hides

146
00:17:45,927 --> 00:17:47,155
l will find her.

147
00:18:18,207 --> 00:18:19,242
(SHOUTlNG)

148
00:18:22,047 --> 00:18:23,082
(GRUNTlNG)

149
00:18:29,527 --> 00:18:30,960
(NEWSCASTER SPEAKlNG
PORTUGUESE)

150
00:18:31,047 --> 00:18:35,882
<i>The American fugitives</i>
<i>killed three DEA agents</i>
<i>during a train robbery...</i>

151
00:18:35,967 --> 00:18:38,765
<i>...Police warn</i>
<i>they are armed and</i>
<i>extremely dangerous.</i>

152
00:18:38,847 --> 00:18:42,123
<i>Anyone with information</i>
<i>should contact law</i>
<i>enforcement immediately...</i>

153
00:18:42,207 --> 00:18:43,242
(DOOR OPENlNG)

154
00:18:52,567 --> 00:18:53,966
BRlAN: Mia?

155
00:18:54,847 --> 00:18:55,882
Hey.

156
00:18:58,487 --> 00:18:59,715
You okay?

157
00:18:59,807 --> 00:19:01,638
Yeah, you all right?

158
00:19:04,087 --> 00:19:05,122
Hey.

159
00:19:10,567 --> 00:19:12,398
Hey, yeah.

160
00:19:13,607 --> 00:19:14,835
Just like a Toretto.

161
00:19:16,807 --> 00:19:17,842
Where's Vince?

162
00:19:18,407 --> 00:19:19,601
That's a good question.

163
00:19:21,007 --> 00:19:22,520
He'll be here.

164
00:19:22,607 --> 00:19:23,676
Guys, we're all over
the news.

165
00:19:23,767 --> 00:19:26,998
They're blaming us
for the killing of those
DEA agents on the train.

166
00:19:27,087 --> 00:19:29,999
Which means we just jumped
to the top of the wanted list.

167
00:19:30,087 --> 00:19:32,521
The feds have got
to show everyone
their agents are off limits

168
00:19:33,047 --> 00:19:35,277
and they're going to send
their best guys. We got
to get out of here.

169
00:19:35,607 --> 00:19:38,485
One thing we know for sure

170
00:19:39,887 --> 00:19:41,445
is that they wanted this car.

171
00:19:43,207 --> 00:19:44,242
Because something is in it.

172
00:19:44,327 --> 00:19:47,797
lf we find out what it is,
we'll know what we're
up against.

173
00:20:04,487 --> 00:20:07,160
HOBBS: All right, listen up!
The men we're after
are professional runners.

174
00:20:07,247 --> 00:20:09,966
They like speed and are
guaranteed to go down
the hardest possible way

175
00:20:10,047 --> 00:20:11,366
so make sure you got
your funderwear on.

176
00:20:11,447 --> 00:20:14,200
We find them, we take them
as a team, and we bring
them back.

177
00:20:14,287 --> 00:20:18,599
And above all else,
we don't ever, ever let
them get into cars.

178
00:20:18,687 --> 00:20:21,155
Crime scene is 10 hours old
and counting, men.
Let's go hunting.

179
00:20:24,487 --> 00:20:27,160
<i>Agente</i> Hobbs!
Chief of Police,
Joäo Alemeida.

180
00:20:27,247 --> 00:20:28,362
Luke.

181
00:20:28,927 --> 00:20:31,521
Sorry to hear about
the loss of your men.

182
00:20:31,607 --> 00:20:33,563
ls all this really necessary
to apprehend two men?

183
00:20:33,647 --> 00:20:35,126
Let me tell you something
about these two men.

184
00:20:35,207 --> 00:20:37,596
One is a former federal
officer, been in deep cover
for five years.

185
00:20:37,687 --> 00:20:39,439
He knows every way
you're going to come
for him.

186
00:20:39,527 --> 00:20:42,485
The other one is
a professional criminal,
escaped prison twice,

187
00:20:42,567 --> 00:20:45,001
spent half his life
on the run avoiding
folks like you.

188
00:20:45,087 --> 00:20:47,806
Well, if there's anything
we can do to help the DSS.. .

189
00:20:47,887 --> 00:20:49,843
Two things.
One, l need a translator.

190
00:20:49,927 --> 00:20:51,360
We have plenty
in the public relations
department.

191
00:20:51,447 --> 00:20:53,165
Elena Neves.

192
00:20:54,687 --> 00:20:56,006
A patrol officer?
You heard me.

193
00:20:56,767 --> 00:20:58,837
But why?
We have many
more experienced people.

194
00:20:58,927 --> 00:21:00,838
l like her smile.

195
00:21:00,927 --> 00:21:02,758
What's the second thing?

196
00:21:03,967 --> 00:21:06,561
Stay the fuck out of my way.

197
00:21:08,887 --> 00:21:09,922
(DRlLLlNG)

198
00:21:16,487 --> 00:21:17,966
Brian.
Hm?

199
00:21:19,367 --> 00:21:20,720
l have something
l have to tell you.

200
00:21:20,887 --> 00:21:22,400
(DOOR OPENlNG)
VlNCE: God damn.

201
00:21:23,167 --> 00:21:24,202
What a mess!

202
00:21:25,927 --> 00:21:27,519
Where you been, man?

203
00:21:28,127 --> 00:21:29,162
(CHUCKLlNG)

204
00:21:30,167 --> 00:21:31,964
You better check that tone.

205
00:21:32,047 --> 00:21:33,799
And you just better answer
the goddamn question.

206
00:21:33,887 --> 00:21:35,320
Stop it!
Both of you.

207
00:21:38,607 --> 00:21:39,676
Where were you, Vince?

208
00:21:40,847 --> 00:21:43,645
Guys all over
the favelas asking
about you.

209
00:21:43,727 --> 00:21:46,241
Couldn't get out of there
without leading them
straight to you.

210
00:21:46,327 --> 00:21:47,362
Had to wait them out.

211
00:21:47,447 --> 00:21:49,119
That is such horseshit.

212
00:21:49,207 --> 00:21:51,163
(SHOUTlNG) That was your job,
and those were your guys!
Hey!

213
00:21:51,247 --> 00:21:52,760
Hey! Enough, O'Conner!

214
00:21:52,847 --> 00:21:54,565
lf he said he didn't do it,
he didn't do it.

215
00:21:54,647 --> 00:21:55,682
Go walk it off.

216
00:22:10,207 --> 00:22:13,597
REYES: Look, l would love
to expand my operations
into your countries

217
00:22:13,927 --> 00:22:17,522
but, quite frankly,
your business methods
are too violent.

218
00:22:18,567 --> 00:22:20,717
Let me tell you a true story.

219
00:22:20,927 --> 00:22:25,045
Five hundred years ago,
the Portuguese
and the Spanish came here,

220
00:22:25,127 --> 00:22:28,437
each trying to get the country
from their natives.

221
00:22:30,607 --> 00:22:34,885
The Spaniards arrived,
guns blazing, determined
to prove who was boss.

222
00:22:37,127 --> 00:22:40,278
The natives killed
every single Spaniard.

223
00:22:42,087 --> 00:22:45,875
Personally, l prefer
the methods of the Portuguese.

224
00:22:47,487 --> 00:22:49,000
They came bearing gifts.

225
00:22:49,087 --> 00:22:51,282
Mirrors, scissors, trinkets.

226
00:22:52,127 --> 00:22:55,642
Things that the natives
couldn't get on their own,

227
00:22:55,727 --> 00:22:58,844
but to continue receiving
them, they had to work
for the Portuguese.

228
00:22:59,967 --> 00:23:03,198
And that's why
all Brazilians speak
Portuguese today.

229
00:23:04,007 --> 00:23:07,556
Now, if you dominate
the people with violence,

230
00:23:08,447 --> 00:23:11,723
they will eventually
fight back because
they have nothing to lose.

231
00:23:12,327 --> 00:23:14,318
And that's the key.

232
00:23:14,407 --> 00:23:18,036
l go into the favelas
and give them
something to lose.

233
00:23:19,007 --> 00:23:20,759
Electricity, running water,

234
00:23:20,847 --> 00:23:22,883
school rooms for their kids.

235
00:23:24,407 --> 00:23:27,160
And for that taste
of a better life,

236
00:23:28,647 --> 00:23:30,524
l own them.

237
00:23:31,647 --> 00:23:32,716
Gentlemen.

238
00:23:34,527 --> 00:23:35,562
(KNOCK ON DOOR)

239
00:23:36,007 --> 00:23:37,042
(SPEAKlNG PORTUGUESE)

240
00:23:37,127 --> 00:23:38,242
l apologize for
the interruption.

241
00:23:38,767 --> 00:23:41,201
Señor Reyes,
may l speak with you?

242
00:23:41,287 --> 00:23:43,676
We've found them.

243
00:23:45,087 --> 00:23:46,998
Pardon me, gentlemen.

244
00:24:01,567 --> 00:24:03,637
DOM: Almost wish
l didn't see that.

245
00:24:06,847 --> 00:24:08,678
Almost.

246
00:24:08,767 --> 00:24:10,723
Wait, Dom.

247
00:24:11,327 --> 00:24:12,885
Mia was on that train.

248
00:24:12,967 --> 00:24:14,525
(SHOUTlNG)
My sister!

249
00:24:15,207 --> 00:24:17,641
l didn't know.
l wouldn't do
anything to hurt her.

250
00:24:17,727 --> 00:24:19,957
You set up the deal!

251
00:24:20,407 --> 00:24:22,557
l thought the job
was for the cars.

252
00:24:23,007 --> 00:24:24,679
l didn't know.

253
00:24:24,767 --> 00:24:26,166
All they want is the chip.

254
00:24:28,087 --> 00:24:29,725
Damn!

255
00:24:30,367 --> 00:24:31,925
You should've come clean.

256
00:24:32,007 --> 00:24:33,520
What's going on out here?

257
00:24:34,207 --> 00:24:35,526
Nothing.

258
00:24:35,647 --> 00:24:38,923
Please, Dom, just let
me have the chip.
l can take this to them.

259
00:24:39,167 --> 00:24:41,078
They'll give it to Reyes
and set things right.

260
00:24:42,047 --> 00:24:43,082
Get out.

261
00:24:46,207 --> 00:24:47,765
What?

262
00:24:47,847 --> 00:24:48,882
Get out!

263
00:24:56,127 --> 00:24:58,595
You never listen to me.

264
00:24:58,687 --> 00:25:02,202
Not when l told you
he was a cop, and not now.

265
00:25:03,167 --> 00:25:06,796
You never trust me
and look where it's gotten us.

266
00:25:07,407 --> 00:25:09,079
Look at our family now.

267
00:25:09,567 --> 00:25:14,004
l can't go home!
Your sister is stuck
in this life!

268
00:25:14,847 --> 00:25:15,962
Where's Letty, Dom?

269
00:25:18,367 --> 00:25:19,402
Where's Letty?

270
00:25:42,807 --> 00:25:44,206
Plasma cutter.

271
00:25:44,287 --> 00:25:47,404
Wilkes, l want a list
of every place within 50 miles

272
00:25:47,487 --> 00:25:49,159
that distributes
compressed gas tanks.

273
00:25:49,247 --> 00:25:51,283
Pass me that manifest.

274
00:25:57,647 --> 00:25:59,603
Officer Neves.
Been waiting for you.

275
00:25:59,887 --> 00:26:01,957
You asked for me?
l did.

276
00:26:02,207 --> 00:26:03,640
May l ask why?

277
00:26:04,687 --> 00:26:06,040
My smile
is not that great.

278
00:26:09,407 --> 00:26:11,967
Your husband was
an officer who was
gunned down in the favela.

279
00:26:12,047 --> 00:26:13,844
Six months later,
you upped and joined
the force.

280
00:26:13,927 --> 00:26:15,121
You're motivated.

281
00:26:15,967 --> 00:26:18,765
Plus, l figure you're
the only one in Rio
who can't be bought.

282
00:26:18,847 --> 00:26:20,246
Am l right?

283
00:26:21,487 --> 00:26:23,523
Yes.
Of course l am.

284
00:26:23,607 --> 00:26:24,676
Good news, bad news.

285
00:26:24,767 --> 00:26:26,405
You know l like
my dessert first.

286
00:26:26,487 --> 00:26:28,364
Back-checked
the rail line like you asked.

287
00:26:28,447 --> 00:26:30,358
Found a couple of spots
where they unloaded the cars.

288
00:26:30,687 --> 00:26:32,086
One set of tracks
headed west

289
00:26:32,167 --> 00:26:34,727
until it hit the main highway,
then disappeared.

290
00:26:34,807 --> 00:26:36,035
But another set
of tracks headed east.

291
00:26:36,127 --> 00:26:38,357
A 107-inch wheelbase,
eight-and-a-half-inch tread.

292
00:26:38,847 --> 00:26:40,963
The GT40 that was missing
from the manifest.

293
00:26:41,047 --> 00:26:42,560
Followed the trail
a couple of miles.

294
00:26:42,647 --> 00:26:43,796
Pretty easy in this scrub.

295
00:26:44,087 --> 00:26:45,566
Can't move without
leaving a sign.

296
00:26:45,647 --> 00:26:47,046
Give me the damn veggies.

297
00:26:47,127 --> 00:26:50,278
The ground rolls into
a hardpack and we lost
that track, too.

298
00:26:51,567 --> 00:26:53,000
Not necessarily.

299
00:26:53,487 --> 00:26:56,365
That road heads up
through the hills
into the favelas.

300
00:26:56,447 --> 00:26:58,677
Couple of years ago,
it was washed out by a storm.

301
00:26:59,007 --> 00:27:00,998
lt's all dirt a mile
from where you were.

302
00:27:01,087 --> 00:27:04,159
lf they headed that way,
we'll pick up
their tracks there.

303
00:27:04,247 --> 00:27:06,397
You come prepared.

304
00:27:06,487 --> 00:27:07,886
l'm motivated.

305
00:27:08,567 --> 00:27:09,636
HOBBS: All right, then.

306
00:27:10,207 --> 00:27:12,038
Let's find ourselves a car.

307
00:27:40,287 --> 00:27:41,322
(MACHlNE WHlRRlNG)

308
00:27:41,527 --> 00:27:42,596
What do you think?

309
00:27:42,687 --> 00:27:44,996
Well, it's definitely
a custom chip.

310
00:27:45,567 --> 00:27:48,525
Look at all these side menus
here for data entry.

311
00:27:48,607 --> 00:27:50,359
Let's check this one.

312
00:27:54,927 --> 00:27:56,280
Look at that.

313
00:27:56,367 --> 00:27:58,676
Same building,
same order every week.

314
00:27:58,767 --> 00:28:00,678
lt's a delivery schedule.

315
00:28:20,767 --> 00:28:21,802
What's this?

316
00:28:22,967 --> 00:28:24,036
Drugs?

317
00:28:24,127 --> 00:28:26,925
No. That's a dealer pack.

318
00:28:27,007 --> 00:28:28,838
See, most major players,
they weigh their money

319
00:28:28,927 --> 00:28:30,758
so they don't have
to constantly count it.

320
00:28:30,847 --> 00:28:32,121
Right there,
that's 49 kilos.

321
00:28:32,207 --> 00:28:34,038
49 kilos is a million
in twenties.

322
00:28:34,687 --> 00:28:36,996
You're saying each one
of these shipments
is worth 10 million dollars?

323
00:28:37,087 --> 00:28:38,122
Yeah.

324
00:28:40,087 --> 00:28:41,122
(GUN COCKlNG)

325
00:29:00,287 --> 00:29:02,039
l thought so.

326
00:29:04,407 --> 00:29:05,965
So what is that?

327
00:29:06,047 --> 00:29:08,561
A 100-million plus
in cash houses?

328
00:29:08,647 --> 00:29:10,444
That's how he keeps it
off the grid.

329
00:29:12,927 --> 00:29:15,361
l think it's safe to say
that Reyes is smart
to want this back.

330
00:29:15,447 --> 00:29:18,086
lt's his whole network
right there, just laid
out on a chip.

331
00:29:18,167 --> 00:29:19,236
(GLASS TlNKLlNG)

332
00:29:33,767 --> 00:29:34,802
(YELLlNG)

333
00:29:40,647 --> 00:29:41,921
Wilkes, Fusco,
up the middle.

334
00:29:42,007 --> 00:29:43,599
Mac, Chato,
flank north.

335
00:29:43,687 --> 00:29:45,279
What about me?

336
00:29:45,367 --> 00:29:46,402
Stay here.

337
00:29:49,807 --> 00:29:50,876
(YELLlNG)

338
00:29:54,967 --> 00:29:56,036
(SPEAKlNG PORTUGUESE)

339
00:29:56,127 --> 00:29:57,162
Go that way!

340
00:29:57,247 --> 00:29:58,566
The other two
went over the wall!

341
00:30:23,487 --> 00:30:24,522
(BOTH GRUNTlNG)

342
00:30:40,167 --> 00:30:41,202
Come on, go! Go!

343
00:30:53,927 --> 00:30:54,962
(YELLlNG)

344
00:31:35,607 --> 00:31:36,676
(SPEAKlNG PORTUGUESE)

345
00:31:37,087 --> 00:31:38,679
Get on the ground.

346
00:31:39,487 --> 00:31:41,637
l got Toretto.
Four blocks north of your.. .

347
00:31:46,927 --> 00:31:48,599
They already know
who you are.

348
00:31:48,767 --> 00:31:49,802
(YELLlNG lN PORTUGUESE)

349
00:32:09,567 --> 00:32:10,602
(GASPS)

350
00:32:19,327 --> 00:32:20,680
Let's go.

351
00:32:30,687 --> 00:32:31,756
(SPEAKlNG PORTUGUESE)

352
00:33:04,287 --> 00:33:05,640
You okay here?

353
00:33:05,727 --> 00:33:09,242
Yeah. l'm good.
Thank you.

354
00:33:42,527 --> 00:33:45,246
They're going to be looking
for the three of us
together now.

355
00:33:45,407 --> 00:33:47,875
We need to split up.

356
00:33:47,967 --> 00:33:50,720
You and Mia head south,
l'll lead them away.

357
00:33:50,807 --> 00:33:51,842
No.

358
00:33:52,567 --> 00:33:54,046
Dom is right.

359
00:33:54,127 --> 00:33:55,719
Look how lucky we just got.
What happens next time?

360
00:33:55,807 --> 00:33:56,842
We have no choice
but to split up.

361
00:33:56,927 --> 00:33:58,121
l'm pregnant.

362
00:34:02,767 --> 00:34:04,200
l already lost
my family once.

363
00:34:06,207 --> 00:34:08,641
l'm not going through
that again.

364
00:34:09,087 --> 00:34:11,157
Are you kidding me?
No.

365
00:34:16,247 --> 00:34:18,761
l'm not going
anywhere. Okay?

366
00:34:21,047 --> 00:34:22,082
Dom?

367
00:34:23,007 --> 00:34:24,998
Promise me
we stick together.

368
00:34:32,447 --> 00:34:34,199
l promise.

369
00:34:38,647 --> 00:34:41,002
Our family
just got bigger.

370
00:34:58,367 --> 00:35:00,039
Something
doesn't add up.

371
00:35:00,487 --> 00:35:01,920
Toretto and O'Conner.

372
00:35:02,407 --> 00:35:06,798
They stay when they're
supposed to run, they steal
gas then give it away?

373
00:35:06,967 --> 00:35:08,446
Now they're killing
federal agents?

374
00:35:09,727 --> 00:35:11,080
lt doesn't make any sense.

375
00:35:11,167 --> 00:35:12,919
Here's what makes sense.

376
00:35:17,407 --> 00:35:18,920
All these guys are
is names on a list.

377
00:35:19,007 --> 00:35:20,360
They come up,
we take them down.

378
00:35:20,447 --> 00:35:22,836
Not a phone call more,
not a bullet less.

379
00:35:22,927 --> 00:35:24,565
Wilkes, we get anything?

380
00:35:24,927 --> 00:35:26,246
Standard forensics.

381
00:35:26,327 --> 00:35:28,045
Shoe prints.
Hair and fiber.

382
00:35:28,127 --> 00:35:29,196
Prints are all over the car.

383
00:35:29,287 --> 00:35:30,322
Anything else?

384
00:35:30,407 --> 00:35:32,602
Yeah, we tracked the owner
off the vehicle lD.

385
00:35:32,687 --> 00:35:34,086
There are a couple
of shell companies
in between,

386
00:35:34,167 --> 00:35:36,522
but we finally
traced it back
to a corporation

387
00:35:36,607 --> 00:35:39,167
owned by an investor
down here named
Hernan Reyes.

388
00:35:39,247 --> 00:35:40,282
lnvestor?

389
00:35:41,367 --> 00:35:44,484
lf there's anything
illegal happening in Rio,
Reyes is involved.

390
00:35:44,567 --> 00:35:46,125
Okay, then so are we.

391
00:35:46,207 --> 00:35:48,323
lf he could get us
any closer to our guys,
l want everything on him.

392
00:35:48,407 --> 00:35:49,681
Chato, you're
on the roof.

393
00:35:49,767 --> 00:35:51,962
l want you on overwatch
in case somebody comes
back for something.

394
00:35:52,047 --> 00:35:54,277
Mac, give me a cross-check
on Reyes, full specs.

395
00:35:54,367 --> 00:35:56,517
lf he goes to the john,
l want to know how
many times he shakes it.

396
00:35:56,607 --> 00:35:58,837
You got it, boss.
Wilkes, Fusco!

397
00:35:59,567 --> 00:36:01,364
Let's put all this
mess back together.

398
00:36:03,647 --> 00:36:05,239
That's going to take a while.

399
00:36:05,327 --> 00:36:06,521
Then you better get started.

400
00:36:06,927 --> 00:36:08,440
They were taking
this car apart for a reason.

401
00:36:08,527 --> 00:36:10,245
Let's put it back together
and find out what's missing.

402
00:36:10,367 --> 00:36:11,436
(EXHALES DEEPLY)

403
00:36:36,807 --> 00:36:39,958
Hey, Dom,
what do you remember
about your father?

404
00:36:42,367 --> 00:36:43,959
My father.

405
00:36:47,967 --> 00:36:50,162
He used to.. .

406
00:36:50,807 --> 00:36:54,038
He used to have a barbecue
every Sunday after church.

407
00:36:54,687 --> 00:36:56,917
For anybody
in the neighborhood.

408
00:36:57,847 --> 00:37:00,122
lf you didn't go to church,
you didn't get any barbecue.

409
00:37:01,887 --> 00:37:05,482
Every single day he was
in the shop, and every
single night,

410
00:37:05,567 --> 00:37:10,357
he was at the kitchen table
with Mia, helping her
with her homework.

411
00:37:11,767 --> 00:37:14,281
Even after she went to sleep,

412
00:37:14,367 --> 00:37:17,279
he'd stay up
for a few more hours

413
00:37:17,367 --> 00:37:21,155
so he could learn
the next chapter
and help her the next day.

414
00:37:22,367 --> 00:37:23,959
l remember everything
about my father.

415
00:37:25,527 --> 00:37:26,755
Everything.

416
00:37:27,807 --> 00:37:29,081
That's just it.

417
00:37:29,487 --> 00:37:30,920
l don't remember shit
about my dad.

418
00:37:34,487 --> 00:37:35,886
l don't remember
him yelling.

419
00:37:35,967 --> 00:37:37,366
l don't remember
him smiling.

420
00:37:39,327 --> 00:37:41,761
To be honest with you,
l don't even remember
what the hell he looked like.

421
00:37:43,847 --> 00:37:45,883
l don't remember.
He just.. .

422
00:37:47,647 --> 00:37:48,966
He was just never there.

423
00:37:51,087 --> 00:37:53,123
You ain't going
to be like that, Brian.

424
00:38:09,087 --> 00:38:11,123
We can't keep
running, Dom.

425
00:38:12,727 --> 00:38:14,285
We got to get out.

426
00:38:14,367 --> 00:38:16,198
We got to get out now.

427
00:38:17,367 --> 00:38:18,641
You're right.

428
00:38:29,767 --> 00:38:31,359
Here's how we're
going to do it.

429
00:38:35,407 --> 00:38:36,556
We're going to use this.

430
00:38:37,687 --> 00:38:39,439
We're going do one last job.

431
00:38:39,927 --> 00:38:42,122
We're going to take
all of Reyes' money.

432
00:38:42,407 --> 00:38:43,920
Every dime of it,

433
00:38:44,807 --> 00:38:46,399
and disappear.

434
00:38:49,887 --> 00:38:50,922
Forever.

435
00:38:52,327 --> 00:38:53,442
New passports.

436
00:38:53,527 --> 00:38:55,836
New lives
with no more looking
over our shoulder.

437
00:38:55,927 --> 00:38:57,440
And we're just going
to buy our freedom.

438
00:38:57,527 --> 00:38:58,596
That's right.

439
00:38:58,687 --> 00:39:00,200
You realize we're
talking about going
up against

440
00:39:00,287 --> 00:39:01,561
the most powerful guy
in all of Rio?

441
00:39:01,847 --> 00:39:03,246
Yes, we are.

442
00:39:04,607 --> 00:39:06,199
Then we're going
to need a team.

443
00:39:12,767 --> 00:39:15,042
Let's run through
the bases real quick.
Who do we got?

444
00:39:15,127 --> 00:39:16,446
First we're going
to need a chameleon.

445
00:39:17,887 --> 00:39:21,641
<i>Someone who can</i>
<i>blend in anywhere.</i>

446
00:39:22,487 --> 00:39:23,556
What else?

447
00:39:23,647 --> 00:39:24,682
A fast talker.

448
00:39:25,527 --> 00:39:27,916
<i>Someone who can</i>
<i>bullshit their way</i>
<i>out of anything.</i>

449
00:39:28,367 --> 00:39:29,402
l got that.

450
00:39:31,087 --> 00:39:32,600
This guy is going to have
a lot of surveillance.

451
00:39:32,687 --> 00:39:34,279
We're going to need someone
who's good with circuits.

452
00:39:36,367 --> 00:39:38,881
DOM: <i>And with those circuits,</i>
<i>Reyes is going to have walls.</i>

453
00:39:38,967 --> 00:39:41,162
We're going to need guys
to punch through those walls.

454
00:39:43,087 --> 00:39:44,122
MlA: <i>What else?</i>

455
00:39:44,567 --> 00:39:46,205
Utilities and weapons.

456
00:39:46,287 --> 00:39:48,926
<i>Someone who ain't</i>
<i>afraid to throw down.</i>

457
00:39:49,847 --> 00:39:51,724
<i>Someone to back up</i>
<i>every position.</i>

458
00:39:51,807 --> 00:39:53,286
BRlAN: <i>Yeah, what else</i>
<i>do we need?</i>

459
00:39:53,367 --> 00:39:54,959
DOM: <i>Most importantly,</i>

460
00:39:55,967 --> 00:39:58,083
we're going to need
two precision drivers.

461
00:39:58,167 --> 00:40:00,681
Guys that don't crack
under pressure.

462
00:40:00,767 --> 00:40:02,166
Guys that never lose.

463
00:40:03,447 --> 00:40:04,675
You know we got that.

464
00:40:23,407 --> 00:40:24,442
(ENGlNE REVVlNG)

465
00:40:25,087 --> 00:40:26,440
(HlP HOP BEAT PLAYlNG
ON CAR STEREO)

466
00:40:29,807 --> 00:40:30,876
(MUSlC STOPS)

467
00:40:31,447 --> 00:40:33,358
Aw, hell, no!

468
00:40:34,287 --> 00:40:36,847
l see they really scraped
the bottom of the barrel, huh?

469
00:40:36,927 --> 00:40:39,122
l guess they did,
since your ass is here.

470
00:40:40,847 --> 00:40:43,725
When are you going
to give Martin Luther King
his car back?

471
00:40:43,807 --> 00:40:46,480
As soon as you give
Rick James his jacket back.

472
00:40:47,127 --> 00:40:48,196
(LAUGHlNG)

473
00:40:49,567 --> 00:40:51,603
What's up, man?
What's up?

474
00:41:02,447 --> 00:41:03,516
Hmm.

475
00:41:04,127 --> 00:41:06,197
Sexy legs,
baby girl.

476
00:41:06,287 --> 00:41:07,436
What time do they open?

477
00:41:08,287 --> 00:41:11,916
They open the same time
as l pull this trigger.

478
00:41:12,447 --> 00:41:13,846
Want me to open them?

479
00:41:15,887 --> 00:41:17,002
(TEGO SPEAKlNG SPANlSH)

480
00:41:17,087 --> 00:41:19,840
l told you the skinny
chick had balls.

481
00:41:19,967 --> 00:41:22,356
Looks like she started
the party without us.

482
00:41:22,927 --> 00:41:25,441
Hey, anybody can talk shit
in Spanish, homie.

483
00:41:26,007 --> 00:41:28,237
What's this guy saying?

484
00:41:28,927 --> 00:41:30,758
Ugly is still ugly in
Spanish or in English.

485
00:41:31,247 --> 00:41:33,807
(BOTH TAUNTlNG lN SPANlSH)

486
00:41:33,927 --> 00:41:35,918
Who are these clowns, man?
Circus clowns.

487
00:41:36,007 --> 00:41:37,122
(ALL CHATTERlNG ANGRlLY)

488
00:41:37,967 --> 00:41:40,845
l thought cockfights
were illegal in Brazil.

489
00:41:40,927 --> 00:41:42,918
l see you all have met.

490
00:41:44,567 --> 00:41:46,558
You know when you called me
to come to Rio

491
00:41:46,647 --> 00:41:49,207
l assumed it would be
for something more
exciting than this.

492
00:41:49,287 --> 00:41:50,402
Look at this guy.

493
00:41:50,487 --> 00:41:52,523
Long time.
l missed you, man.

494
00:41:52,607 --> 00:41:53,642
Good to see you.

495
00:41:53,727 --> 00:41:55,558
Brother.
What's up?

496
00:41:55,647 --> 00:41:57,638
Yo, check this out.
This is Tej.

497
00:41:57,727 --> 00:41:59,558
Best circuit man
on the East Coast.

498
00:41:59,647 --> 00:42:01,080
And this is my boy,
Roman Pearce.

499
00:42:01,407 --> 00:42:03,557
We go way back,
l met this guy in juvie.

500
00:42:03,647 --> 00:42:05,205
l pulled that job
with him in Miami.

501
00:42:05,287 --> 00:42:06,640
l've heard about you.

502
00:42:07,767 --> 00:42:09,200
Nice digs.

503
00:42:09,287 --> 00:42:11,005
Yeah, well,
the Ritz was sold out.

504
00:42:11,527 --> 00:42:13,199
So what's this
all about, Dom?

505
00:42:13,287 --> 00:42:16,484
Yeah, man, why did
you drag us halfway
around the world?

506
00:42:16,567 --> 00:42:18,285
Because we got a job.

507
00:42:19,247 --> 00:42:21,761
All right,
so our target's name
is Hernan Reyes.

508
00:42:21,847 --> 00:42:23,485
And he runs
the drug scene down here.

509
00:42:23,567 --> 00:42:26,001
He's never been busted
because he doesn't
leave a paper trail.

510
00:42:26,087 --> 00:42:28,043
No paper trail
means no banks.

511
00:42:28,127 --> 00:42:30,118
And no banks means
cash houses.

512
00:42:30,207 --> 00:42:32,516
That's right.
Ten of them,
to be exact.

513
00:42:32,607 --> 00:42:34,677
Spread throughout the city.

514
00:42:34,767 --> 00:42:36,519
And we're going
to hit them all.

515
00:42:37,927 --> 00:42:38,996
All of them?

516
00:42:39,287 --> 00:42:40,322
All of them.

517
00:42:40,407 --> 00:42:42,238
That sounds crazy.

518
00:42:42,327 --> 00:42:44,204
You bring us
to a whole other country

519
00:42:44,287 --> 00:42:46,243
so we can rob
the dude who runs it?

520
00:42:47,327 --> 00:42:48,885
l thought this was business.

521
00:42:49,167 --> 00:42:50,395
Sounds personal to me.

522
00:42:51,287 --> 00:42:52,845
ls that what this is?

523
00:42:52,927 --> 00:42:56,556
l got love for y'all,
but personal ain't
good business.

524
00:42:58,127 --> 00:43:00,277
l can't do this, homie.

525
00:43:01,487 --> 00:43:05,446
So what we're talking
about is $100 million.

526
00:43:05,607 --> 00:43:07,484
You say what?

527
00:43:07,567 --> 00:43:11,037
Hundred.. .
See, sometimes l be
over thinking, man,

528
00:43:11,127 --> 00:43:14,039
and l know we just met,
but you just, kind of,
got to.. .

529
00:43:14,127 --> 00:43:17,722
That's right, $100 million,
and everything we take,

530
00:43:17,807 --> 00:43:19,160
we split even.

531
00:43:19,247 --> 00:43:20,999
TEJ: That's a little over
$1 1 million apiece.

532
00:43:21,927 --> 00:43:23,246
l am down.

533
00:43:23,727 --> 00:43:24,762
l'm in.

534
00:43:26,247 --> 00:43:27,600
Eleven million.

535
00:43:28,007 --> 00:43:30,601
Sounds like a whole lot of
vaginal activity to me.

536
00:43:31,047 --> 00:43:33,242
You can't pull off 10 heists
on the same mark.

537
00:43:33,327 --> 00:43:34,362
You just can't.

538
00:43:34,447 --> 00:43:35,960
As soon as we hit
the first one,

539
00:43:36,047 --> 00:43:38,641
they're going to do
everything they can
to protect the rest.

540
00:43:39,607 --> 00:43:41,279
Exactly.

541
00:43:57,527 --> 00:43:58,562
(CASH MACHlNES WHlRRlNG)

542
00:44:01,287 --> 00:44:02,322
(DOORBELL BUZZlNG)

543
00:44:17,167 --> 00:44:18,202
(GRUNTlNG)
(SPEAKlNG PORTUGUESE)

544
00:44:18,287 --> 00:44:19,356
Nobody move!

545
00:44:19,447 --> 00:44:20,596
(WOMEN SCREAMlNG)

546
00:44:33,927 --> 00:44:35,076
That's all of it.

547
00:44:35,167 --> 00:44:36,316
You a dead man.

548
00:44:36,407 --> 00:44:37,442
You're all dead men!

549
00:44:38,287 --> 00:44:39,686
You don't have
a place to hide.

550
00:44:42,367 --> 00:44:43,516
Who's hiding?

551
00:44:43,607 --> 00:44:44,835
THUG: Are you crazy?

552
00:44:44,927 --> 00:44:46,076
Are you crazy?

553
00:44:46,167 --> 00:44:48,920
Do you know whose house
this is? Whose money
are you stealing?

554
00:44:58,967 --> 00:45:00,320
We ain't stealing it.

555
00:45:08,887 --> 00:45:11,879
You tell your boss
exactly who did this.

556
00:45:13,407 --> 00:45:14,840
Tell him there's more coming.

557
00:45:20,287 --> 00:45:21,356
<i>Voilà.</i>

558
00:45:22,167 --> 00:45:23,236
Turn it over.

559
00:45:26,367 --> 00:45:27,436
(ENGlNE STARTlNG)

560
00:45:29,047 --> 00:45:32,119
She's running on all eight.
Checks out fine.

561
00:45:34,607 --> 00:45:36,404
Keep looking.

562
00:45:36,927 --> 00:45:37,996
(SlGHlNG)

563
00:45:38,367 --> 00:45:41,803
Boss, if something
was missing, we'd know.

564
00:46:06,367 --> 00:46:09,882
lt's a goddamn shame
putting bullshit
like that on a classic.

565
00:46:10,207 --> 00:46:12,163
You may as well slap
neon lights on it.

566
00:46:19,167 --> 00:46:20,236
(BEEPlNG)

567
00:46:23,007 --> 00:46:24,884
They took the chip.

568
00:46:24,967 --> 00:46:28,562
We got a hit on the police
scanner. Armed robbery at
a house in Leblon.

569
00:46:28,647 --> 00:46:30,000
Address cross-checks
against property

570
00:46:30,087 --> 00:46:31,725
owned by one
of Hernan Reyes' corporations.

571
00:46:31,807 --> 00:46:32,876
All right,
if that's our guys

572
00:46:32,967 --> 00:46:35,435
then whatever was on
that chip led them
directly to that house.

573
00:46:35,527 --> 00:46:36,676
lt's them, for sure.

574
00:46:36,767 --> 00:46:38,041
How do you know that?

575
00:46:38,127 --> 00:46:42,086
Because no one else in Rio
is stupid enough to rob Reyes.

576
00:46:54,287 --> 00:46:55,322
(SPEAKlNG PORTUGUESE)

577
00:46:55,407 --> 00:46:56,476
Explain.

578
00:46:56,567 --> 00:46:58,205
They invaded
the Leblon house.

579
00:46:58,487 --> 00:46:59,761
Who invaded?

580
00:46:59,847 --> 00:47:02,122
The men from the train.

581
00:47:10,087 --> 00:47:12,237
How much did they take?

582
00:47:12,407 --> 00:47:14,125
They didn't
take anything.

583
00:47:14,287 --> 00:47:17,677
They burned it!

584
00:47:17,927 --> 00:47:19,485
They burned my money?

585
00:47:19,567 --> 00:47:22,559
Yes. And said
there's more coming.

586
00:47:27,687 --> 00:47:28,756
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)

587
00:47:30,287 --> 00:47:31,356
Okay.. .

588
00:47:39,567 --> 00:47:41,478
Then this.. .

589
00:47:43,287 --> 00:47:44,686
...is what
we're going to do.

590
00:47:50,967 --> 00:47:52,480
Clean the houses.

591
00:47:52,807 --> 00:47:56,800
l want that money
under lock and key.. .

592
00:47:58,247 --> 00:47:59,282
...within an hour.

593
00:47:59,367 --> 00:48:01,483
Understand?

594
00:48:03,607 --> 00:48:05,165
<i>Understood.</i>

595
00:48:23,367 --> 00:48:25,676
Number One
is on the move, man.

596
00:48:39,487 --> 00:48:40,966
ROME: Two is on the move.

597
00:49:04,687 --> 00:49:05,722
l got mine.

598
00:49:25,807 --> 00:49:27,718
l got eyes on Five.

599
00:49:53,287 --> 00:49:56,484
l know y'all said
they were consolidating
the money somewhere, but,

600
00:49:56,847 --> 00:49:59,680
y'all ain't going
to believe this.

601
00:50:08,887 --> 00:50:11,276
Well, this job just got
a lot harder.

602
00:50:11,927 --> 00:50:13,645
lf he's moving it
into a police station

603
00:50:13,727 --> 00:50:16,002
he's got some serious
brass in his pocket.

604
00:50:16,087 --> 00:50:17,122
(SPEAKlNG SPANlSH)

605
00:50:17,207 --> 00:50:18,640
Looks like this is going
to be a shorter trip
than l thought.. .

606
00:50:18,727 --> 00:50:19,876
Hell, yeah,
we can't do this.

607
00:50:19,967 --> 00:50:23,323
''Can't''? You mean,
''shouldn't.' '

608
00:50:24,287 --> 00:50:26,278
l think this doesn't
change a thing.

609
00:50:29,247 --> 00:50:31,442
l say we stick to the plan.

610
00:50:31,527 --> 00:50:33,165
You say what?

611
00:50:33,247 --> 00:50:34,839
This just went
from <i>Mission</i>/ <i>lmpossible</i>

612
00:50:34,927 --> 00:50:36,724
to Mission:
ln-freaking-sanity.

613
00:50:38,847 --> 00:50:40,041
Whatever, man.

614
00:50:40,127 --> 00:50:43,358
l ain't scared, l'm just
letting you all know, going
in that building is crazy.

615
00:50:43,447 --> 00:50:44,766
BRlAN: l got this.

616
00:50:48,287 --> 00:50:49,515
What time
was the robbery?

617
00:50:49,607 --> 00:50:51,359
Around 1 1 :00.

618
00:50:52,887 --> 00:50:54,036
Here we go.

619
00:50:56,127 --> 00:50:57,560
Enhance it.

620
00:50:59,607 --> 00:51:00,960
Their faces are covered.

621
00:51:01,047 --> 00:51:02,116
Run it through FRS.

622
00:51:07,967 --> 00:51:09,525
Well, hello,
you son of a bitch.

623
00:51:12,287 --> 00:51:15,199
Wilkes! Run the photos
of known associates
of Toretto and O'Conner

624
00:51:15,287 --> 00:51:18,006
against customs entries
into Brazil in the last
two weeks.

625
00:51:18,087 --> 00:51:21,124
Check planes, trains,
boats, everything short
of the goddamn space shuttle.

626
00:51:27,247 --> 00:51:30,159
They can change their names
but they can't change
their faces.

627
00:51:30,247 --> 00:51:31,965
Something big
is going down.

628
00:51:33,607 --> 00:51:34,960
That's a 1970 Charger.

629
00:51:35,047 --> 00:51:37,083
Fusco! Upload these specs
into the database.

630
00:51:37,167 --> 00:51:39,362
Have the computer cross-check
it with overhead satellites

631
00:51:39,447 --> 00:51:41,358
every 15 minutes,
the van behind it, too.

632
00:51:41,447 --> 00:51:44,086
lf these vehicles move
in the streets of Rio,
l want to know about it.

633
00:51:51,447 --> 00:51:52,482
(SPEAKlNG PORTUGUESE)

634
00:51:52,567 --> 00:51:53,602
Everything okay?

635
00:51:53,687 --> 00:51:54,722
Everything is okay.

636
00:51:54,807 --> 00:51:57,367
Who is this Hobbs?
This Federal Agent
running around town?

637
00:51:57,527 --> 00:51:58,596
Some American cowboy.

638
00:51:59,207 --> 00:52:00,242
He's handled.

639
00:52:00,407 --> 00:52:01,760
He killed sixteen
of our men.

640
00:52:02,487 --> 00:52:03,636
<i>Handle him better.</i>

641
00:52:03,807 --> 00:52:08,881
Look.. . He requested
a rookie patrol officer
as his assistant.

642
00:52:11,527 --> 00:52:12,562
They won't be a problem.

643
00:52:40,287 --> 00:52:42,118
lt's all here?
Yes.

644
00:52:43,567 --> 00:52:45,239
What about Toretto
and O'Conner?
Where are they?

645
00:52:45,687 --> 00:52:46,722
Nothing yet.

646
00:52:47,647 --> 00:52:49,399
But l have all our
officers searching.

647
00:52:50,207 --> 00:52:51,276
Not good enough.

648
00:52:52,127 --> 00:52:53,480
Put a price
on their heads.

649
00:52:53,647 --> 00:52:55,000
High enough.. .

650
00:52:55,567 --> 00:52:57,603
...to get every pair
of eyes in the city
searching for them.

651
00:53:04,767 --> 00:53:07,156
The beauty of public offices?

652
00:53:09,967 --> 00:53:11,002
Public records.

653
00:53:11,327 --> 00:53:13,636
This is where he's keeping
the money. The vault
in the evidence room.

654
00:53:14,687 --> 00:53:18,839
Um. Uh, yeah. Can l get
everyone's attention,
right here, for a second?

655
00:53:18,927 --> 00:53:22,442
We're talking about
breaking into
a police station.

656
00:53:22,527 --> 00:53:24,165
ls anyone listening
to those words?

657
00:53:24,247 --> 00:53:25,726
Anybody? Popo?

658
00:53:25,807 --> 00:53:28,275
Five-O. One-time. Pigs.

659
00:53:28,367 --> 00:53:29,595
People we don't like.

660
00:53:29,687 --> 00:53:32,485
You know, police stations
are designed to keep
people in, not out.

661
00:53:32,567 --> 00:53:33,795
That's why it's
a stealth mission.

662
00:53:34,207 --> 00:53:36,801
We'll be in and out
before they even know
we were there.

663
00:53:36,887 --> 00:53:38,366
Well, we'll need
to get eyes in there.

664
00:53:38,447 --> 00:53:40,802
At least to find out
the make and model
of that vault.

665
00:53:41,047 --> 00:53:44,244
So the vault
and then, so.. .

666
00:53:44,327 --> 00:53:45,726
lt's crazy.

667
00:53:45,807 --> 00:53:48,526
Who's supposed
to do all this?

668
00:53:56,607 --> 00:53:58,438
What do you mean?

669
00:53:59,607 --> 00:54:00,596
Why me?

670
00:54:00,687 --> 00:54:02,518
Because you got
the biggest mouth.

671
00:54:02,607 --> 00:54:04,518
That's for damn sure.

672
00:54:05,967 --> 00:54:07,036
(ELEVATOR DlNGS)

673
00:54:07,287 --> 00:54:08,322
(HUMMlNG)

674
00:54:10,967 --> 00:54:12,036
Ooh.

675
00:54:13,647 --> 00:54:15,160
Hello, beautiful.

676
00:54:15,247 --> 00:54:17,761
Look at those dimples.
Sexy, sexy.

677
00:54:17,847 --> 00:54:19,803
Love those glasses.
Where did you get them from?

678
00:54:19,887 --> 00:54:22,196
Are those like Gucci frames
or something?

679
00:54:22,287 --> 00:54:23,402
No English?

680
00:54:23,487 --> 00:54:26,160
No, no, no. Damn.

681
00:54:26,687 --> 00:54:27,722
How are you, sir?

682
00:54:28,127 --> 00:54:31,802
Special Agent O'Conner.
US Federal Bureau
of lnvestigation.

683
00:54:31,887 --> 00:54:33,036
lt says Caucasian.

684
00:54:33,327 --> 00:54:35,966
That's a tan.
You know, a tan?

685
00:54:38,767 --> 00:54:42,646
Look, l'm working
this case and l got some
evidence here to be held.

686
00:54:42,727 --> 00:54:44,922
But l need to get in
and check your
storage facility first.

687
00:54:45,007 --> 00:54:46,042
Nope.

688
00:54:46,127 --> 00:54:49,278
Look, l know you're
a true professional,
and l respect you, l promise.

689
00:54:49,367 --> 00:54:51,437
You know, it looks like
you work out
a little bit, too.

690
00:54:51,527 --> 00:54:53,882
What do you bench,
about 350?

691
00:54:54,287 --> 00:54:55,322
Ah, shit.

692
00:54:56,367 --> 00:54:57,641
Look, l'm just trying
to do my job, man.

693
00:54:57,727 --> 00:55:00,400
My boss sent me here
to just make sure
that everything was safe.

694
00:55:00,487 --> 00:55:01,522
lt will be safe.

695
00:55:01,607 --> 00:55:03,598
Let me just come in
and take a quick peek.

696
00:55:03,687 --> 00:55:04,722
Nope.

697
00:55:04,807 --> 00:55:07,162
Come on, man.
Hook a brother up,
please?

698
00:55:07,247 --> 00:55:08,805
Nope. And you're
not my brother.

699
00:55:08,887 --> 00:55:10,081
Brother from
another mother?

700
00:55:10,167 --> 00:55:13,239
Look! No one enters
the facility but authorized
evidence personnel.

701
00:55:13,327 --> 00:55:14,396
Now stop wasting my time.

702
00:55:14,487 --> 00:55:15,556
l'm going to call
the embassy.

703
00:55:15,647 --> 00:55:17,046
No, no, no!
No, we're good.

704
00:55:17,287 --> 00:55:19,323
We don't need to call them.
For what? We're good.

705
00:55:19,407 --> 00:55:21,875
Here, l got the box.
We're all good.

706
00:55:21,967 --> 00:55:24,765
l promise you.
Thank you so much
for your time.

707
00:55:24,847 --> 00:55:26,963
Swear to God, if you
were on the other
side of that glass

708
00:55:27,047 --> 00:55:29,322
l'd bust your damn face in.
Now translate that.

709
00:55:46,447 --> 00:55:49,996
lt's done. See, l think
l make a better special
agent than you ever did.

710
00:55:50,087 --> 00:55:51,122
(LAUGHlNG)

711
00:55:51,687 --> 00:55:53,882
Well, that depends
on how you define ''special.' '

712
00:55:56,807 --> 00:55:58,035
TEJ: Come on, now.
Let's see what we got.

713
00:55:58,127 --> 00:55:59,560
Not funny.

714
00:56:01,247 --> 00:56:02,316
(MACHlNE WHlRRlNG)

715
00:56:06,607 --> 00:56:08,245
All right, come on.

716
00:56:13,087 --> 00:56:14,520
Dawg,
you still can't drive.

717
00:56:16,087 --> 00:56:18,965
Now, l see why
you're always
getting into accidents.

718
00:56:19,047 --> 00:56:21,163
You can't even drive
a damn remote control car.

719
00:56:21,247 --> 00:56:23,078
l'm going to need you
to shut up right now.

720
00:56:23,167 --> 00:56:25,203
l'm not going to shut up.
Shut up.

721
00:56:25,287 --> 00:56:26,606
Strap him in his
safety belt, man.

722
00:56:29,687 --> 00:56:31,166
Give me the remote,
dawg. Go left.

723
00:56:31,247 --> 00:56:33,283
lt looks like something
right over there
to the left. What is that?

724
00:56:33,367 --> 00:56:34,482
BRlAN: What is that?

725
00:56:35,647 --> 00:56:36,716
Bingo.

726
00:56:37,807 --> 00:56:39,718
What is that,
six-by-six?

727
00:56:39,807 --> 00:56:40,842
Eight-by-twelve.

728
00:56:40,927 --> 00:56:42,360
Seven-by-twelve.

729
00:56:42,447 --> 00:56:45,439
Fitted with 18-inch-thick
steel reinforced walls

730
00:56:45,527 --> 00:56:48,917
with a insulated copper
core to protect
against thermal lance.

731
00:56:49,007 --> 00:56:52,317
A Class-3 electronic
lock with a surefire
Griffin retumbler

732
00:56:52,407 --> 00:56:54,045
and a biometric palm scanner.

733
00:56:54,127 --> 00:56:56,516
Ten tons of
top-of-the-line security.

734
00:56:56,607 --> 00:56:58,199
Do l want to know
how you know all that?

735
00:56:58,287 --> 00:57:00,198
l had a life before
you knew me, O'Conner.

736
00:57:00,287 --> 00:57:02,039
Let's just leave it
at that, all right?

737
00:57:02,127 --> 00:57:03,719
She is a beauty,
though, man.

738
00:57:03,807 --> 00:57:05,877
A ''beauty''
as in ''good''?

739
00:57:05,967 --> 00:57:08,606
''Beauty'' as in, she's
going to start off
playing hard to get.

740
00:57:08,687 --> 00:57:12,760
Then, no matter how much
l caress her, no matter
how much l love her,

741
00:57:12,847 --> 00:57:15,964
in the end,
she still ain't going
to give up that ass.

742
00:57:16,327 --> 00:57:17,362
(ALL LAUGHlNG)

743
00:57:21,207 --> 00:57:22,242
(SPEAKlNG SPANlSH)

744
00:57:22,327 --> 00:57:23,760
Two to one says
you blow the wrong pipe.

745
00:57:24,087 --> 00:57:26,043
Yo, why you got to be
so negative all the time, man?

746
00:57:26,127 --> 00:57:27,116
(SPEAKlNG SPANlSH)

747
00:57:27,207 --> 00:57:28,481
l ain't negative.

748
00:57:28,567 --> 00:57:31,286
l'm just <i>positive</i>
you're going to mess it up.

749
00:57:31,607 --> 00:57:34,485
l'm telling you, man,
you got issues.

750
00:57:39,127 --> 00:57:42,642
Next time if
there's no elevator,
l'm not coming.

751
00:57:43,127 --> 00:57:46,005
You need to learn
to relax, <i>loco.</i>

752
00:58:02,007 --> 00:58:03,042
(TlMER BEEPlNG)

753
00:58:05,687 --> 00:58:06,676
(SPEAKlNG SPANlSH)

754
00:58:06,767 --> 00:58:08,723
You better hurry up,
we got less than a minute.

755
00:58:08,807 --> 00:58:14,518
<i>Why do you always set</i>
<i>the timer so short?</i>

756
00:58:30,127 --> 00:58:31,162
(SCREAMlNG)

757
00:58:35,767 --> 00:58:36,916
(RlCO SPEAKlNG SPANlSH)

758
00:58:37,007 --> 00:58:38,201
l hope you know
where you're going.

759
00:58:38,287 --> 00:58:41,006
l got this. Relax, man.

760
00:58:41,167 --> 00:58:42,919
Relax.

761
00:58:47,047 --> 00:58:48,162
(WHlMPERS)

762
00:58:53,447 --> 00:58:54,562
(SPEAKlNG SPANlSH)

763
00:58:54,647 --> 00:58:56,239
...a police station.

764
00:58:56,567 --> 00:58:57,920
Relax.

765
00:59:06,647 --> 00:59:07,682
(EXCLAlMS)

766
00:59:08,167 --> 00:59:09,156
(SPEAKlNG SPANlSH)

767
00:59:09,247 --> 00:59:10,999
You used too much
explosive! Again.

768
00:59:12,087 --> 00:59:13,645
Too much, too little.. .

769
00:59:14,207 --> 00:59:15,242
lt's all the same.

770
00:59:15,807 --> 00:59:20,437
That's some Buddha shit
you learned from a book in
the prison library, isn't it?

771
00:59:21,567 --> 00:59:23,046
And what you're doing
there on the wall.. .

772
00:59:23,127 --> 00:59:25,846
You got that from
the same book, huh?

773
00:59:26,287 --> 00:59:27,276
You're so negative, bro.

774
00:59:53,007 --> 00:59:55,237
Can l have some light?

775
00:59:58,527 --> 01:00:00,802
MlA: Got it. We got it!

776
01:00:00,887 --> 01:00:02,479
BRlAN: Yeah, we're looking
at four cameras.

777
01:00:02,767 --> 01:00:04,883
Yo, that's some
high-end shit, too.

778
01:00:04,967 --> 01:00:06,002
Marker optics.

779
01:00:06,487 --> 01:00:08,239
Hundred-degree
field-of-view.

780
01:00:08,567 --> 01:00:09,966
Ten seconds oscillation.

781
01:00:10,047 --> 01:00:12,003
Yeah, that's
a narrow window, man.

782
01:00:12,087 --> 01:00:13,645
Can't we just tap in
and replace the image?

783
01:00:13,727 --> 01:00:15,638
No, it's hooked
into a digital sync.

784
01:00:15,727 --> 01:00:17,638
They would know we were
in the system.

785
01:00:17,727 --> 01:00:19,683
The best we can do is peek.

786
01:00:19,767 --> 01:00:22,235
We're going to need
some real fast cars
to get through this.

787
01:00:22,327 --> 01:00:23,760
Not just fast.

788
01:00:24,007 --> 01:00:26,123
You got a hard right
and a hairpin.

789
01:00:26,207 --> 01:00:27,845
We're going to need
something agile.

790
01:00:27,927 --> 01:00:29,565
You guys mock up a track.

791
01:00:29,647 --> 01:00:30,636
O'Conner.

792
01:00:31,887 --> 01:00:33,240
Let's go get some cars.

793
01:00:33,687 --> 01:00:34,802
Nice.

794
01:01:12,407 --> 01:01:14,637
Home sweet home.
(LAUGHlNG)

795
01:01:31,807 --> 01:01:32,876
BRlAN: Or that.

796
01:01:33,727 --> 01:01:36,116
How about that?
All motor, no tuning issues.

797
01:01:36,207 --> 01:01:38,437
l always wanted one of those.

798
01:01:38,527 --> 01:01:41,997
Held the record
on the Avenida
three years running.

799
01:01:42,207 --> 01:01:43,242
(SPEAKlNG PORTUGUESE)

800
01:01:43,327 --> 01:01:44,362
Damn, bro.. .

801
01:01:44,447 --> 01:01:46,961
You got a lot of balls
to bring your problems
here, Toretto.

802
01:01:47,327 --> 01:01:50,080
Not to mention a cop.

803
01:01:50,167 --> 01:01:52,317
Yeah, we can keep
that on the low.

804
01:01:52,407 --> 01:01:55,205
Word on the street is
a lot of people are
looking for you two.

805
01:01:56,127 --> 01:01:57,196
What?

806
01:01:57,407 --> 01:01:59,045
You didn't think
we'd recognize you?

807
01:02:00,407 --> 01:02:02,318
No, we're kind
of counting on it.

808
01:02:02,687 --> 01:02:04,917
That little coupe
may run the streets
around here,

809
01:02:06,367 --> 01:02:10,246
but that monster
has never seen
a set of tail lights.

810
01:02:10,927 --> 01:02:12,201
Ever.
Well, she's about to.

811
01:02:13,047 --> 01:02:14,116
(DlOGO SPEAKlNG PORTUGUESE)

812
01:02:14,207 --> 01:02:15,276
Dominic Toretto's
ride in my garage.

813
01:02:16,327 --> 01:02:20,320
Now <i>that...</i>
will be a nice trophy.

814
01:02:22,007 --> 01:02:24,475
Let's go, legend.

815
01:02:25,367 --> 01:02:27,801
Car for car.

816
01:02:27,967 --> 01:02:29,639
Car for car?

817
01:02:30,007 --> 01:02:31,440
DlOGO: You want it,
come and get it.

818
01:02:33,167 --> 01:02:34,236
(ENGlNE REVVlNG)

819
01:02:35,967 --> 01:02:37,719
Let's see what they got.

820
01:02:42,647 --> 01:02:43,762
(ROME LAUGHlNG)

821
01:02:43,927 --> 01:02:45,042
Really?

822
01:02:46,647 --> 01:02:49,764
Where did you get
that from? Papa Smurf?

823
01:02:49,847 --> 01:02:52,361
<i>Okay, O'Conner,</i>
<i>give it your best shot.</i>

824
01:03:14,567 --> 01:03:15,682
How was that one?

825
01:03:15,767 --> 01:03:16,802
Camera caught you.

826
01:03:17,367 --> 01:03:19,164
What?
Yeah, it still caught you.

827
01:03:19,247 --> 01:03:21,124
Man, l was milking
the hell out of
that thing, too.

828
01:03:21,847 --> 01:03:23,360
We're going to need
a faster car.

829
01:03:24,567 --> 01:03:25,636
(SHOUTlNG lNCOMPREHENSlBLY)

830
01:03:27,927 --> 01:03:29,599
l want my money.
Come on, man.

831
01:03:33,167 --> 01:03:34,202
Yeah!

832
01:03:36,647 --> 01:03:38,444
Let's get it! Watch this.

833
01:03:44,847 --> 01:03:48,237
That's exactly why your ass
ain't been driving.

834
01:03:59,327 --> 01:04:00,919
l think l'm in love.

835
01:04:04,567 --> 01:04:06,000
That was real solid work.

836
01:04:06,087 --> 01:04:09,318
l think Camera 3
still caught you, though.

837
01:04:09,407 --> 01:04:10,442
Let's do it again.

838
01:04:17,847 --> 01:04:19,724
TEGO: That's the piggy bank
you ordered.

839
01:04:19,807 --> 01:04:21,684
You're kidding me.
Yep.

840
01:04:23,447 --> 01:04:26,120
Where in the hell
did y'all get one of these?

841
01:04:26,807 --> 01:04:28,559
Well, we had a life
before you met us.

842
01:04:29,847 --> 01:04:32,998
All right, l'll get to work
on the electronic tumbler

843
01:04:33,087 --> 01:04:35,157
but there's still
another problem.

844
01:04:35,807 --> 01:04:37,126
Palm scanner.

845
01:04:37,207 --> 01:04:38,879
And without Reyes' handprint,

846
01:04:39,207 --> 01:04:41,243
Houdini himself
couldn't open this bitch.

847
01:04:41,327 --> 01:04:43,238
How do you know
it's Reyes' handprint?

848
01:04:43,327 --> 01:04:44,999
You got $100 million
in a safe.

849
01:04:45,087 --> 01:04:46,725
You going to put
somebody else's
handprint on it?

850
01:04:47,047 --> 01:04:49,686
(TALKlNG SPANlSH)
Now there you go
with that negativity, man.

851
01:04:49,767 --> 01:04:51,041
That shit is eating
you alive.

852
01:04:51,127 --> 01:04:52,321
You check that.

853
01:04:52,407 --> 01:04:54,398
Yo, check that.
Shut up!

854
01:04:54,487 --> 01:04:56,443
How are we supposed to get
Reyes' handprint?

855
01:04:57,687 --> 01:04:59,166
DOM: Han.

856
01:04:59,247 --> 01:05:00,236
You're up.

857
01:05:02,167 --> 01:05:04,840
Sure. Nothing like
the easy stuff.

858
01:05:05,687 --> 01:05:07,325
Let's go. l'll drive.

859
01:05:25,047 --> 01:05:26,924
l make six bodyguards.
Seven.

860
01:05:27,767 --> 01:05:30,725
You think that guy
with a fanny pack
is a tourist?

861
01:05:35,607 --> 01:05:37,916
So, how long were
you in the army?

862
01:05:38,007 --> 01:05:40,726
That gun you pulled
the other day was
a Jericho 941 .

863
01:05:42,007 --> 01:05:43,679
Thumb-racking the slide?

864
01:05:43,767 --> 01:05:45,519
That was
straight-up Mossad.

865
01:05:46,527 --> 01:05:48,483
l got out of the military

866
01:05:49,647 --> 01:05:52,480
probably the same time
you quit smoking.

867
01:05:52,567 --> 01:05:54,444
The amount
of chips you eat,

868
01:05:54,887 --> 01:05:57,845
the way you always
have to keep your hands
and mouth busy,

869
01:05:57,927 --> 01:06:00,395
you were a
two-pack-a-day man
for sure.

870
01:06:02,407 --> 01:06:03,965
Unfiltered.

871
01:06:07,487 --> 01:06:08,886
Well, this is a bust.

872
01:06:09,967 --> 01:06:13,198
We're not going to be
able to get his
fingerprints out here.

873
01:06:13,287 --> 01:06:16,199
We need to do some
more recon, call in
a couple of extra guys.

874
01:06:16,287 --> 01:06:17,515
Or

875
01:06:17,887 --> 01:06:20,003
you don't send a man
to do a woman's job.

876
01:07:15,887 --> 01:07:18,526
We're going to figure
this out, l promise you.

877
01:07:21,687 --> 01:07:22,961
What's up?

878
01:07:23,527 --> 01:07:25,961
l thought you were
more of a thong man.

879
01:07:26,047 --> 01:07:27,321
We got the print.

880
01:07:28,887 --> 01:07:30,081
Where?

881
01:07:32,007 --> 01:07:33,884
Okay, that's crazy.

882
01:07:35,527 --> 01:07:39,839
So, did he just slap
that ass or did he grab
and hold on to it?

883
01:07:40,127 --> 01:07:41,162
(BOTH LAUGHlNG)

884
01:07:42,327 --> 01:07:44,283
Hey, this will work.

885
01:07:44,887 --> 01:07:46,081
TEJ: l'm impressed.

886
01:07:46,167 --> 01:07:48,078
Got it?
TEJ: Got it.

887
01:07:48,167 --> 01:07:49,839
But you still didn't
answer the question.

888
01:07:55,607 --> 01:07:57,882
Oh, no. Guys, guys!
Guys, we have a problem.

889
01:07:57,967 --> 01:08:00,117
The whole team just got burnt.

890
01:08:01,487 --> 01:08:03,284
Now we're all wanted.

891
01:08:05,327 --> 01:08:06,396
GlSELE: How did this happen?

892
01:08:06,487 --> 01:08:09,877
US Diplomatic Security Service
issued the warrants.

893
01:08:09,967 --> 01:08:11,719
Agent L. Hobbs.

894
01:08:12,087 --> 01:08:13,156
Hold on one second.

895
01:08:14,167 --> 01:08:15,202
Hey, Dom.

896
01:08:16,727 --> 01:08:18,445
ls that the guy you saw
in the favela?

897
01:08:21,167 --> 01:08:22,236
Yeah.

898
01:08:22,607 --> 01:08:25,917
Hobbs is the leader
of the elite task force
for the DSS.

899
01:08:26,007 --> 01:08:27,076
So he's good.

900
01:08:27,167 --> 01:08:30,125
When the FBl wants
to find somebody,
that's who they call.

901
01:08:30,207 --> 01:08:31,879
Because he never
misses his mark.

902
01:08:31,967 --> 01:08:34,720
This guy is Old Testament.

903
01:08:35,087 --> 01:08:37,965
Blood, bullets, wrath of God.
That's his style.

904
01:08:38,327 --> 01:08:40,636
And right now
he's hunting us?

905
01:08:40,727 --> 01:08:42,399
Dom, we got to move up
our timeline.

906
01:08:42,487 --> 01:08:43,522
ROME: Yeah, but how?

907
01:08:43,607 --> 01:08:46,917
This thing's already been
difficult without Wyatt Earp
on our asses.

908
01:08:47,487 --> 01:08:49,159
lf anything,
we need more room
to breathe.

909
01:08:51,407 --> 01:08:52,726
Roman's right.

910
01:08:55,447 --> 01:08:57,802
Think we need to get
some fresh air.

911
01:09:01,567 --> 01:09:03,558
We've got a hit.
'70s Charger.

912
01:09:03,647 --> 01:09:05,558
Let's get a move on!

913
01:09:08,847 --> 01:09:11,361
Eastbound on
Avenida Atlantica.

914
01:09:11,447 --> 01:09:12,766
Move, move, move, move!

915
01:09:18,807 --> 01:09:20,365
lt stopped about
a block ahead.

916
01:09:21,007 --> 01:09:22,360
Park it.
We're going on foot.

917
01:09:44,727 --> 01:09:45,796
Hey, Toretto.

918
01:09:53,567 --> 01:09:55,125
You're under arrest.

919
01:09:55,407 --> 01:09:56,522
Arrest?

920
01:09:57,687 --> 01:09:59,484
l don't feel like
l'm under arrest.

921
01:10:00,247 --> 01:10:01,441
How about you,
Brian?

922
01:10:01,527 --> 01:10:02,596
No, not a bit.

923
01:10:04,487 --> 01:10:05,681
Not even a little bit.

924
01:10:05,767 --> 01:10:07,917
Just give it a minute.
lt'll sink in.

925
01:10:11,207 --> 01:10:13,596
BRlAN: We didn't kill
those feds. That was Reyes.

926
01:10:13,687 --> 01:10:14,881
HOBBS: l don't give a shit.

927
01:10:14,967 --> 01:10:17,640
l'm just here to bring
in two assholes whose names
hit my desk.

928
01:10:17,927 --> 01:10:21,044
Yeah, that sounds
like a real hero.

929
01:10:23,927 --> 01:10:25,440
That's funny.

930
01:10:25,527 --> 01:10:28,485
From a guy who took the oath
of a cop, then went against
everything it stood for.

931
01:10:28,567 --> 01:10:30,239
Or some wannabe
tough guy prick

932
01:10:30,327 --> 01:10:32,557
who beat a man half
to death with
a socket wrench.

933
01:10:33,287 --> 01:10:34,436
Yeah, real tough.

934
01:10:35,447 --> 01:10:38,484
You turn around
and put your hands
behind your back.

935
01:10:39,607 --> 01:10:40,960
l don't think so.

936
01:10:41,047 --> 01:10:43,515
Your mistake is
thinking you got
a goddamn choice, boy.

937
01:10:47,527 --> 01:10:49,040
And your mistake?

938
01:10:49,687 --> 01:10:51,086
Thinking you're in America.

939
01:10:54,167 --> 01:10:57,523
You're a long way from home.

940
01:10:59,887 --> 01:11:02,321
This is Brazil.

941
01:11:16,887 --> 01:11:19,037
Come on, boss.
Another day.

942
01:11:20,687 --> 01:11:23,042
Come on, H,
it's a lot of heat.

943
01:11:28,087 --> 01:11:30,282
l'll see you soon,
Toretto.

944
01:11:31,567 --> 01:11:34,035
l look forward to it, cop.

945
01:12:09,687 --> 01:12:10,756
Yep.

946
01:12:10,847 --> 01:12:12,166
Tracker's on.

947
01:12:13,487 --> 01:12:14,522
Got them.

948
01:13:17,767 --> 01:13:20,042
l don't understand.
Why come here?

949
01:13:20,527 --> 01:13:23,246
Why risk it all
for $20 worth of silver?

950
01:13:26,687 --> 01:13:27,881
Because it's worth it.

951
01:13:31,527 --> 01:13:33,006
You should run,
you know.

952
01:13:33,727 --> 01:13:35,080
Hobbs will find you.

953
01:13:37,687 --> 01:13:40,485
You have every reason
to leave. Why stay?

954
01:13:47,607 --> 01:13:49,598
Why do you?

955
01:13:51,087 --> 01:13:52,998
My husband was
a good police officer.

956
01:13:53,807 --> 01:13:55,365
An honest man.

957
01:13:56,727 --> 01:13:58,365
We both grew up here.

958
01:13:59,367 --> 01:14:01,517
Two years ago he was
murdered in the street

959
01:14:01,607 --> 01:14:03,279
right outside our door.

960
01:14:05,687 --> 01:14:09,282
Reyes owns this favela now.
He gives things to people.

961
01:14:11,527 --> 01:14:13,722
But everything
has a price.

962
01:14:16,367 --> 01:14:18,005
The people here
need a new start.

963
01:14:18,567 --> 01:14:20,046
They need
to be free.

964
01:14:27,847 --> 01:14:28,882
(SlGHS)

965
01:14:29,487 --> 01:14:31,079
You didn't kill
those men in the train,

966
01:14:31,687 --> 01:14:32,915
did you?

967
01:14:37,327 --> 01:14:39,966
Now, why would you
believe anything
l would tell you?

968
01:14:46,567 --> 01:14:47,795
Hey!

969
01:14:51,047 --> 01:14:52,685
Was she so special to you?

970
01:14:57,327 --> 01:14:59,522
l never thought anyone
could understand how much.

971
01:15:02,847 --> 01:15:04,166
But you do.

972
01:15:26,407 --> 01:15:27,442
Yeah!

973
01:15:38,127 --> 01:15:39,355
Close, but not enough.

974
01:15:39,887 --> 01:15:41,400
Dom, the window
is too small, man.

975
01:15:41,487 --> 01:15:45,082
Only way we're going to
beat the cameras is
with invisible cars.

976
01:15:47,687 --> 01:15:49,962
And l know just where
to get them.

977
01:15:53,007 --> 01:15:54,201
Let's take a ride, boys.

978
01:16:01,767 --> 01:16:03,758
Don't hurt yourself.

979
01:16:21,647 --> 01:16:23,922
lt's been a while since
l've been behind the wheel
of one of these.

980
01:16:24,207 --> 01:16:26,004
First time l've ever
been in the front seat.

981
01:16:26,647 --> 01:16:27,682
(CHUCKLES)

982
01:16:33,487 --> 01:16:34,966
Rome, what took
you so long?

983
01:16:35,287 --> 01:16:38,962
l thought for sure you'd be
showing up with some
chrome spinners or something.

984
01:16:40,047 --> 01:16:41,082
Real funny.

985
01:16:42,447 --> 01:16:45,917
<i>l got $100,000 that says</i>
<i>l can take you all</i>
<i>in the next quarter-mile.</i>

986
01:16:46,007 --> 01:16:47,440
Yeah, your broke ass
has got a hundred grand.

987
01:16:47,527 --> 01:16:49,757
<i>lf we pull off this job,</i>
<i>l will.</i>

988
01:16:50,167 --> 01:16:51,520
<i>The next two lights.</i>

989
01:16:51,807 --> 01:16:52,922
<i>Hundred thousand.</i>

990
01:16:53,847 --> 01:16:56,566
We don't pull this job off,
we're probably dead anyway.

991
01:16:57,047 --> 01:16:59,003
Let's make it a million.

992
01:16:59,847 --> 01:17:02,077
l like that.
All right,
a million-dollar quarter-mile.

993
01:17:03,287 --> 01:17:04,766
All right, then.

994
01:17:05,047 --> 01:17:07,481
<i>You only live once.</i>
<i>Let's do it.</i>

995
01:17:07,967 --> 01:17:09,036
What do you say, Dom?

996
01:17:09,647 --> 01:17:11,000
We talking or we racing?

997
01:17:12,407 --> 01:17:13,476
Just don't cheat this time.

998
01:17:14,047 --> 01:17:16,561
Got to let that go.

999
01:17:16,807 --> 01:17:17,842
(ENGlNES REVVlNG)

1000
01:17:34,407 --> 01:17:35,806
Yeah!

1001
01:17:38,807 --> 01:17:39,842
Typical, Roman.

1002
01:17:39,927 --> 01:17:42,236
l'm going to get
this money. l'm hungry.

1003
01:17:50,207 --> 01:17:51,799
Don't make it too
easy for me, boys.

1004
01:17:54,527 --> 01:17:55,596
No!

1005
01:17:56,687 --> 01:17:58,359
Not this time, Dom.

1006
01:18:03,007 --> 01:18:04,645
You got to want it, Brian.

1007
01:18:31,727 --> 01:18:35,402
Yeah! Owned you! Owned you!

1008
01:18:49,567 --> 01:18:51,762
Good race, O'Conner.
Thanks, Dom.

1009
01:18:53,607 --> 01:18:56,326
Do you know how long
l've been waiting
for that shit?

1010
01:18:56,407 --> 01:18:58,284
l told you
he didn't see it.

1011
01:18:58,487 --> 01:19:00,125
Your man right there?

1012
01:19:00,207 --> 01:19:02,482
He let off the throttle
at the line.

1013
01:19:02,567 --> 01:19:05,206
You didn't do nothing.
He let you win.

1014
01:19:06,087 --> 01:19:07,759
Bullshit.
(SCOFFlNG)

1015
01:19:28,047 --> 01:19:30,720
Vince, what are you doing?
Quiet! They've been
tracking you.

1016
01:19:37,847 --> 01:19:38,882
(SPEAKlNG PORTUGUESE)

1017
01:19:38,967 --> 01:19:40,002
l know she's here!

1018
01:19:42,407 --> 01:19:43,522
Find her!

1019
01:19:43,687 --> 01:19:45,166
Go! Go! Go!

1020
01:19:58,967 --> 01:20:00,559
lt's okay. Wait!

1021
01:20:00,647 --> 01:20:03,559
Reyes' guys were waiting
for me at the market.

1022
01:20:04,487 --> 01:20:06,045
Vince saved my life.

1023
01:20:11,247 --> 01:20:12,646
DOM: You hungry?

1024
01:20:15,687 --> 01:20:17,996
Yeah, sure.
Good.

1025
01:20:19,687 --> 01:20:20,836
Because you're saying grace.

1026
01:20:23,927 --> 01:20:25,280
Thanks, Vince.

1027
01:20:30,967 --> 01:20:32,036
(SPEAKlNG SPANlSH)

1028
01:20:32,127 --> 01:20:33,162
Yo, you burned it!

1029
01:20:33,247 --> 01:20:36,080
Yo, this is how my momma
does it. Relax.

1030
01:20:36,167 --> 01:20:38,397
Yeah, but your mom is the
worst cook in the world.

1031
01:20:38,527 --> 01:20:41,246
Yo, don't you be talking
about my momma.

1032
01:20:43,327 --> 01:20:45,716
Yeah, come on, baby.
Who's good living?

1033
01:20:45,807 --> 01:20:47,843
To you, bro.
Cheers, cheers, cheers.

1034
01:20:47,927 --> 01:20:50,077
ROME: So, we in Brazil.
lt's the good life.

1035
01:20:50,167 --> 01:20:51,202
Yeah.

1036
01:20:51,287 --> 01:20:54,836
So, you got a little more
than $10 or $1 1 million
coming.

1037
01:20:54,927 --> 01:20:55,996
What you going to do
with your money?

1038
01:20:56,087 --> 01:20:57,679
Me?
Yeah.

1039
01:20:57,767 --> 01:21:00,406
Actually, man, l been
thinking about opening up
a garage back home.

1040
01:21:01,327 --> 01:21:04,000
Place where people can
bring their cars and not get
completely ripped off.

1041
01:21:04,087 --> 01:21:05,156
You know what l mean?

1042
01:21:05,247 --> 01:21:06,521
Really?
Yeah.

1043
01:21:06,607 --> 01:21:09,405
So, your dream is
to start a day job?

1044
01:21:09,487 --> 01:21:11,523
That's stupid.
Like, why would.. .

1045
01:21:11,607 --> 01:21:14,041
No, it's not stupid at all.
l love what l do.

1046
01:21:14,127 --> 01:21:15,162
That don't make
no sense to me.

1047
01:21:15,247 --> 01:21:17,966
l know what l'm going
to do with my money.

1048
01:21:19,887 --> 01:21:21,684
Buying some cooking lessons
for my man.

1049
01:21:22,167 --> 01:21:23,566
See? See?

1050
01:21:23,647 --> 01:21:25,842
There you go with
that negativity, man.

1051
01:21:25,927 --> 01:21:27,883
You know me.
Money ain't a goddamn thing.

1052
01:21:27,967 --> 01:21:30,401
lt's going to take
a little more than money
to learn how to cook.

1053
01:21:30,487 --> 01:21:31,681
That's horrible.

1054
01:21:32,207 --> 01:21:35,722
But l heard they was looking
for a chef down at
this animal shelter.

1055
01:21:35,807 --> 01:21:36,842
You might want to.. .

1056
01:21:36,927 --> 01:21:38,565
l know the manager.

1057
01:21:43,767 --> 01:21:45,359
Hey, Dom.

1058
01:21:47,967 --> 01:21:49,400
Listen.

1059
01:21:50,127 --> 01:21:53,676
l know that you're all set
for this job tomorrow,

1060
01:21:53,767 --> 01:21:55,439
but if you need
an extra man, l could.. .

1061
01:21:55,527 --> 01:21:56,846
You're in.

1062
01:22:04,887 --> 01:22:06,366
There's always
room for family.

1063
01:22:12,567 --> 01:22:13,682
Thank you.

1064
01:22:17,967 --> 01:22:19,082
Get something to eat.

1065
01:22:20,767 --> 01:22:22,325
Yeah.

1066
01:22:24,127 --> 01:22:25,799
Can you believe
Mia calls this a curse?

1067
01:22:29,407 --> 01:22:31,477
She might be right.

1068
01:22:35,647 --> 01:22:38,002
You really like doing
that stuff, huh?

1069
01:22:38,247 --> 01:22:42,320
When your life is on
the line that's when you
learn about yourself.

1070
01:22:47,127 --> 01:22:48,765
That's a fair deal.

1071
01:22:51,927 --> 01:22:55,886
We're less than 24 hours
from the biggest celebration
of our life.

1072
01:22:55,967 --> 01:22:58,162
Y'all need a refill.
This is serious stuff.

1073
01:22:58,247 --> 01:22:59,521
No, l'm good.
Cheers, baby.

1074
01:22:59,607 --> 01:23:01,120
l'm good.
No, thank you.

1075
01:23:01,207 --> 01:23:02,242
No, she can't.

1076
01:23:04,327 --> 01:23:06,238
What do you mean?
She can't.

1077
01:23:06,567 --> 01:23:09,161
What do you mean
she can't? What is.. .

1078
01:23:13,127 --> 01:23:15,277
Are you serious right now?
(LAUGHlNG)

1079
01:23:15,367 --> 01:23:18,962
ls that the reason you let him
beat you in the quarter-mile?

1080
01:23:20,247 --> 01:23:23,364
That was a baby gift.
No, that's messed up.

1081
01:23:23,447 --> 01:23:24,960
No, you're not taking
that from me.

1082
01:23:25,047 --> 01:23:26,560
Wait, wait,
hold on a second.

1083
01:23:26,647 --> 01:23:30,799
So, did he just smack
the ass or did he grab
and hold on to it?

1084
01:23:31,087 --> 01:23:32,122
Which one was it?

1085
01:23:32,207 --> 01:23:34,596
Congratulations.
Thank you.

1086
01:23:34,687 --> 01:23:36,405
ROME: How can you keep
this a secret?

1087
01:23:36,487 --> 01:23:38,398
Crazy, huh?
ROME: lt's your boy.

1088
01:23:38,527 --> 01:23:41,917
ROME: Why would you keep
something like that
away from me?

1089
01:23:42,247 --> 01:23:43,965
Baby gift, huh?

1090
01:23:44,247 --> 01:23:46,920
l have no idea
what they're talking about.
Oh?

1091
01:23:47,007 --> 01:23:49,885
TEJ: What happened
to the pull-out method, man?

1092
01:23:50,967 --> 01:23:52,878
Toast.
Toast.

1093
01:24:00,887 --> 01:24:04,038
Money will come and go.
We know that.

1094
01:24:05,087 --> 01:24:08,318
But the most important
thing in life will always
be the people in this room.

1095
01:24:09,687 --> 01:24:10,915
Right here.

1096
01:24:13,407 --> 01:24:14,442
Right now.

1097
01:24:17,407 --> 01:24:18,476
(SPEAKlNG lTALlAN)

1098
01:24:19,367 --> 01:24:20,720
(ALL REPLYlNG lN lTALlAN)

1099
01:24:28,447 --> 01:24:29,960
l'm all set.

1100
01:24:30,927 --> 01:24:33,805
HAN: Yo, Santos. Van good?

1101
01:24:34,847 --> 01:24:36,917
You know we're
always good, bro.

1102
01:24:40,647 --> 01:24:43,286
Hobbs is on the other side
of the city.

1103
01:24:43,367 --> 01:24:45,881
We're not going
to get a better window.

1104
01:24:45,967 --> 01:24:48,117
Okay, guys,
it's show time!

1105
01:24:48,207 --> 01:24:49,720
First team in position,
let's go.

1106
01:24:49,807 --> 01:24:51,001
TEGO: Come on, let's do this.

1107
01:25:02,807 --> 01:25:03,876
Hey, Dom.

1108
01:25:05,527 --> 01:25:06,596
l got eyes on Mia.

1109
01:25:11,367 --> 01:25:14,359
Moscow, Bali, Goa, Hong Kong.

1110
01:25:14,967 --> 01:25:16,719
And what do they all
have in common?

1111
01:25:16,807 --> 01:25:17,876
No extradition.

1112
01:25:19,887 --> 01:25:22,481
We're one hour away
from the rest of our lives.

1113
01:25:22,567 --> 01:25:23,795
Yeah.

1114
01:25:25,447 --> 01:25:26,482
Cops!

1115
01:25:28,927 --> 01:25:30,201
Come on. Go.

1116
01:25:41,367 --> 01:25:42,880
You just made a big mistake.

1117
01:25:44,327 --> 01:25:46,204
Took me a while to find
that tracking chip.

1118
01:25:46,687 --> 01:25:48,006
But not as long
to flip the receiver.

1119
01:25:48,087 --> 01:25:49,520
You're going down, Toretto.

1120
01:25:49,847 --> 01:25:51,519
l'm right here.

1121
01:25:51,767 --> 01:25:52,836
(BOTH GRUNTlNG)

1122
01:27:03,407 --> 01:27:04,442
(YELLlNG)

1123
01:27:16,087 --> 01:27:17,998
Dom!
Stand back. l got this.

1124
01:27:23,647 --> 01:27:27,435
Pull off!
Dom! Please, stop!

1125
01:27:32,847 --> 01:27:33,882
Dom!

1126
01:27:42,567 --> 01:27:43,841
Dom!
(DOM SCREAMlNG)

1127
01:28:41,967 --> 01:28:43,002
(WALKlE TALKlE BEEPlNG)

1128
01:28:43,807 --> 01:28:44,796
Yeah.

1129
01:28:46,167 --> 01:28:47,998
We're coming in now.

1130
01:28:49,527 --> 01:28:52,087
Have the marshals meet us
at the airport when we land.

1131
01:28:59,647 --> 01:29:01,000
Ambush!

1132
01:29:17,887 --> 01:29:21,004
Wilkes, suppression fire.
Shut them down.

1133
01:29:25,047 --> 01:29:26,639
Stagger-step. Cover me.

1134
01:29:31,447 --> 01:29:32,516
Watch them!

1135
01:29:43,567 --> 01:29:44,602
Cut us loose!

1136
01:29:44,687 --> 01:29:46,564
Come on! Cut us loose!

1137
01:31:40,207 --> 01:31:41,481
We're good?
Yeah, let's go, let's go!

1138
01:31:51,687 --> 01:31:52,756
(TlRES SCREECHlNG)

1139
01:32:02,687 --> 01:32:03,756
(SPlTTlNG)

1140
01:32:13,407 --> 01:32:14,965
VlNCE: Hey, Dom.

1141
01:32:20,967 --> 01:32:23,037
You've got to meet my son.

1142
01:32:23,327 --> 01:32:24,999
Nico.

1143
01:32:29,567 --> 01:32:30,966
l will.

1144
01:32:33,767 --> 01:32:34,961
He's a good kid.

1145
01:32:38,647 --> 01:32:41,161
You know,
we named him after you.

1146
01:32:42,927 --> 01:32:44,201
''Dominic.' '

1147
01:32:51,127 --> 01:32:53,038
You've got
my word, Vince.

1148
01:32:59,327 --> 01:33:01,318
You were
always my brother.

1149
01:33:10,567 --> 01:33:12,956
l got eyes on Nico now.

1150
01:33:23,207 --> 01:33:25,516
We need to move.
We don't have that much time.

1151
01:33:25,607 --> 01:33:26,676
l got us a flight out.

1152
01:33:26,767 --> 01:33:29,235
We can leave Rio
in the rearview
in the next five hours.

1153
01:33:29,327 --> 01:33:31,045
Not to run away.

1154
01:33:32,407 --> 01:33:33,920
To finish the job.

1155
01:33:34,727 --> 01:33:37,036
Are you crazy, Dom?
We can't.

1156
01:33:37,607 --> 01:33:39,120
ROME: lt's a suicide mission.

1157
01:33:40,167 --> 01:33:41,759
That's your man
over there on the table.

1158
01:33:43,087 --> 01:33:45,043
The plan is busted!

1159
01:33:45,327 --> 01:33:47,716
This is bullshit, man.
Reyes knows we're coming!

1160
01:33:47,807 --> 01:33:49,126
TEJ: He's right.

1161
01:33:49,407 --> 01:33:52,080
They tripled the detail
at the police station.

1162
01:33:52,487 --> 01:33:54,637
TEJ: lt's going to be
a wall of gunfire.

1163
01:33:56,767 --> 01:33:58,758
Reyes doesn't get
away with this.

1164
01:33:58,967 --> 01:34:00,002
lt's a trap, man.

1165
01:34:00,087 --> 01:34:01,440
You know that.

1166
01:34:02,087 --> 01:34:04,317
Dom, listen to them.

1167
01:34:04,967 --> 01:34:07,435
Run, before it's
too late. Leave Rio.

1168
01:34:08,767 --> 01:34:10,041
You can be free.

1169
01:34:12,127 --> 01:34:14,038
Running ain't freedom.

1170
01:34:15,447 --> 01:34:16,800
You should know that.

1171
01:34:21,687 --> 01:34:23,996
You know you're all free
to make your own choices.

1172
01:34:28,047 --> 01:34:29,116
HOBBS: l'm in.

1173
01:34:38,127 --> 01:34:39,685
l'll ride with you,
Toretto.

1174
01:34:42,847 --> 01:34:45,281
At least until we kill
that son of a bitch.

1175
01:34:53,367 --> 01:34:54,880
BRlAN: So what's
the plan, Dom?

1176
01:34:55,687 --> 01:34:57,643
We can't just go
sneaking around anymore.

1177
01:34:59,087 --> 01:35:00,964
We don't sneak.

1178
01:35:01,727 --> 01:35:04,719
The only thing
he cares about
is his money.

1179
01:35:04,927 --> 01:35:06,246
We pull that,

1180
01:35:07,167 --> 01:35:08,566
we pull him.

1181
01:35:20,327 --> 01:35:21,362
(SECURlTY DOOR BUZZlNG)

1182
01:35:24,167 --> 01:35:25,156
(SPEAKlNG PORTUGUESE)

1183
01:35:25,247 --> 01:35:26,236
See?

1184
01:35:27,367 --> 01:35:29,881
l called in every cop
on our payroll.

1185
01:35:31,327 --> 01:35:33,079
We're covered.

1186
01:35:34,687 --> 01:35:36,040
We've got every
entrance covered
with weapons teams.

1187
01:35:36,127 --> 01:35:38,800
<i>God Himself couldn't</i>
<i>get at your money</i>
<i>if He wanted to.</i>

1188
01:35:39,287 --> 01:35:43,439
God isn't my worry.

1189
01:35:52,847 --> 01:35:53,916
You ready?

1190
01:35:55,967 --> 01:35:57,002
l'm ready.

1191
01:36:32,927 --> 01:36:33,996
(POLlCE OFFlCERS CHATTERlNG)

1192
01:36:51,767 --> 01:36:52,836
(SPEAKlNG PORTUGUESE)

1193
01:36:52,927 --> 01:36:53,962
What's happening?

1194
01:36:54,047 --> 01:36:55,446
They're taking the vault!

1195
01:36:55,527 --> 01:36:57,165
What?
<i>The vault!</i>

1196
01:37:06,327 --> 01:37:09,399
Follow me! Quickly!

1197
01:37:13,567 --> 01:37:15,000
Let me through!

1198
01:37:24,647 --> 01:37:25,682
Don't move!

1199
01:37:26,807 --> 01:37:28,081
Stay down.

1200
01:37:56,887 --> 01:37:58,161
Call it out, Mia!

1201
01:37:58,247 --> 01:37:59,726
You've got a straight shot
for two blocks.

1202
01:38:01,167 --> 01:38:02,600
Go right.
Got it.

1203
01:38:10,007 --> 01:38:11,122
(PEDESTRlANS SCREAMlNG)

1204
01:38:24,087 --> 01:38:25,600
Well, the plan is working.

1205
01:38:25,687 --> 01:38:30,317
You guys have every
corrupt cop in Rio on your
tail. You have to move fast.

1206
01:38:30,407 --> 01:38:31,442
What's the best route?

1207
01:38:31,527 --> 01:38:34,644
Okay, keep going straight
another half-mile
onto Rua Fonseca,

1208
01:38:34,727 --> 01:38:36,558
<i>and then go left.</i>

1209
01:38:40,167 --> 01:38:41,202
That ain't going to work.

1210
01:38:43,167 --> 01:38:44,725
Spikes ahead, Dom.
We got spikes!

1211
01:38:45,087 --> 01:38:46,645
We're going right!

1212
01:38:47,927 --> 01:38:49,155
No, it's too tight,
we're not going to fit.

1213
01:38:49,247 --> 01:38:50,646
We've got no choice. Now!

1214
01:38:59,687 --> 01:39:00,756
(PEOPLE SCREAMlNG)

1215
01:39:09,527 --> 01:39:10,642
Shit!

1216
01:39:17,047 --> 01:39:18,241
Holy shit!

1217
01:39:18,327 --> 01:39:21,080
Guys, l am hearing
all this chatter. Did you
just take out a bank?

1218
01:39:29,807 --> 01:39:30,922
Two inbound!

1219
01:39:33,047 --> 01:39:34,446
All right, there's an alley
coming up on your left.

1220
01:39:34,527 --> 01:39:36,119
Yeah, l got it.

1221
01:40:14,047 --> 01:40:15,082
(GUNSHOTS)

1222
01:40:20,807 --> 01:40:21,876
(BRAKES SCREECHlNG)

1223
01:40:22,367 --> 01:40:23,436
(GRUNTlNG)

1224
01:40:27,327 --> 01:40:28,885
You little bastard!

1225
01:40:51,127 --> 01:40:53,687
All right, good job, Dom.
Right-hander, right here,
right-hander.

1226
01:40:59,807 --> 01:41:01,763
Guys, there's a big group
coming at you from the south.

1227
01:41:01,847 --> 01:41:03,599
You have to do something now!

1228
01:41:06,327 --> 01:41:07,316
Hey, go wide.

1229
01:41:28,407 --> 01:41:29,476
(WOMAN SCREAMlNG)

1230
01:41:30,047 --> 01:41:31,082
(CHUCKLlNG)

1231
01:41:38,807 --> 01:41:39,842
Yeah!

1232
01:41:57,727 --> 01:41:58,762
(POLlCE CAR HONKlNG)

1233
01:42:16,407 --> 01:42:17,442
(BULLETS HlTTlNG CAR)

1234
01:42:41,487 --> 01:42:42,522
(GRUNTlNG)

1235
01:42:50,567 --> 01:42:51,841
You're all clear on the left.

1236
01:42:51,927 --> 01:42:53,679
Good afternoon, officer!

1237
01:42:55,607 --> 01:42:57,882
License and registration,
please!

1238
01:43:03,847 --> 01:43:06,600
Yes! This is big-boy stuff!

1239
01:43:06,687 --> 01:43:08,086
We're clear on the right.

1240
01:43:08,287 --> 01:43:09,356
Oh, man.

1241
01:43:15,847 --> 01:43:16,882
Thanks, guys.

1242
01:43:17,207 --> 01:43:18,276
Any time.

1243
01:43:18,367 --> 01:43:19,846
l'll see you on
the other side.

1244
01:43:19,927 --> 01:43:22,395
You guys just carved out
a 10-second window.

1245
01:43:22,487 --> 01:43:23,840
<i>Make it count!</i>

1246
01:43:29,807 --> 01:43:30,842
(SPEAKlNG PORTUGUESE)

1247
01:43:30,927 --> 01:43:31,996
Zizi, stay on them.

1248
01:43:57,447 --> 01:43:59,278
They can't outrun us
on the bridge.

1249
01:44:01,207 --> 01:44:02,242
Shit.

1250
01:44:08,927 --> 01:44:10,076
They have no way out.

1251
01:44:12,007 --> 01:44:13,042
No!

1252
01:44:13,767 --> 01:44:14,802
There's too many of them.

1253
01:44:14,887 --> 01:44:16,764
Hey, there's too many of them.
We're not going to make it.

1254
01:44:20,367 --> 01:44:21,356
You're right, we aren't.

1255
01:44:22,447 --> 01:44:23,482
You are.

1256
01:44:23,567 --> 01:44:24,761
What are you talking about?

1257
01:44:25,007 --> 01:44:27,316
Just let the vault go.
Get out of there.

1258
01:44:27,407 --> 01:44:28,999
You're a father now, Brian.

1259
01:44:29,087 --> 01:44:31,157
No, l'm not leaving you.
Now you stick with the plan!

1260
01:44:31,847 --> 01:44:33,200
lt was always the plan.

1261
01:44:33,887 --> 01:44:35,115
<i>Take care of Mia.</i>

1262
01:44:35,207 --> 01:44:37,562
Dom, you listen
to me now. Okay?

1263
01:44:37,647 --> 01:44:39,365
<i>You cut loose right now.</i>

1264
01:44:54,927 --> 01:44:55,962
(SPEAKlNG PORTUGUESE)

1265
01:44:56,047 --> 01:44:57,036
Hey, what is he doing?

1266
01:45:00,807 --> 01:45:01,876
We've got him!

1267
01:45:18,047 --> 01:45:19,275
Close down the bridge!

1268
01:45:52,087 --> 01:45:53,406
<i>Do something, asshole!</i>

1269
01:46:05,047 --> 01:46:06,082
Kill him, dammit!

1270
01:46:17,047 --> 01:46:18,400
Kill him now!

1271
01:46:48,247 --> 01:46:49,282
(SCREAMlNG)

1272
01:47:13,207 --> 01:47:14,242
(PANTlNG)

1273
01:47:27,167 --> 01:47:29,806
l thought l told you
to go on.

1274
01:47:31,647 --> 01:47:33,763
Yeah, l had
to make a call.

1275
01:47:47,727 --> 01:47:48,762
(GROANlNG)

1276
01:47:50,647 --> 01:47:52,000
Help me.

1277
01:47:54,327 --> 01:47:56,238
That's for my team,
you son of a bitch.

1278
01:48:00,247 --> 01:48:01,839
lt's a hell of a mess.

1279
01:48:02,527 --> 01:48:04,085
Yeah, it is.

1280
01:48:05,527 --> 01:48:07,245
You know l can't
let you two go.

1281
01:48:07,727 --> 01:48:09,206
l ain't made that way.

1282
01:48:11,847 --> 01:48:14,407
The way l see it,
you've earned
yourselves 24 hours.

1283
01:48:15,567 --> 01:48:16,602
The money stays, though.

1284
01:48:17,807 --> 01:48:19,877
lf l were you,
l'd use the time.

1285
01:48:20,167 --> 01:48:23,079
Make peace with
whatever demons
you got left.

1286
01:48:27,327 --> 01:48:29,158
Because come tomorrow,

1287
01:48:30,487 --> 01:48:31,522
l will find you.

1288
01:48:42,927 --> 01:48:44,121
Toretto!

1289
01:48:45,047 --> 01:48:46,241
l'll see you soon.

1290
01:48:49,007 --> 01:48:50,804
No, you won't.

1291
01:49:30,527 --> 01:49:31,562
Thanks, guys.

1292
01:49:31,647 --> 01:49:33,080
l'll see you
on the other side.

1293
01:49:37,807 --> 01:49:40,162
<i>You guys just carved out</i>
<i>a 10 second window.</i>

1294
01:49:40,247 --> 01:49:41,441
<i>Make it count!</i>

1295
01:49:56,647 --> 01:49:57,716
(LAUGHlNG)

1296
01:50:11,447 --> 01:50:12,516
(COMPUTER BEEPlNG)

1297
01:50:22,167 --> 01:50:23,759
Come on, baby.

1298
01:50:23,887 --> 01:50:25,684
Don't be mean.

1299
01:50:27,807 --> 01:50:28,842
Come on.

1300
01:50:30,327 --> 01:50:31,362
(VAULT SCANNER BEEPlNG)

1301
01:50:34,127 --> 01:50:35,526
(VAULT UNLOCKlNG)
(SlGHlNG)

1302
01:51:05,247 --> 01:51:06,282
(SPEAKlNG SPANlSH)

1303
01:51:37,487 --> 01:51:40,763
<i>''For Rosa and Nico.</i>
<i>See you soon,</i>
<i>-Uncle Dom''</i>

1304
01:51:47,407 --> 01:51:50,683
MONACO

1305
01:51:52,207 --> 01:51:53,196
(SPEAKlNG SPANlSH)

1306
01:51:53,287 --> 01:51:54,322
You sure about this?

1307
01:51:56,087 --> 01:51:57,440
You know l am.

1308
01:51:59,327 --> 01:52:00,726
You don't need to do this.

1309
01:52:01,687 --> 01:52:03,917
Just leave me alone.

1310
01:52:04,007 --> 01:52:05,998
Bro, l'm not trying
to be negative,
but casinos

1311
01:52:06,167 --> 01:52:08,761
are the kinds of places
designed to take money
from guys like you and me.

1312
01:52:08,927 --> 01:52:12,442
When l win here
l'm buying you a lifetime
supply of antidepressants.

1313
01:52:12,727 --> 01:52:15,525
You don't put
ten million on red!

1314
01:52:15,607 --> 01:52:16,642
Enough already.

1315
01:52:16,727 --> 01:52:18,001
You put it on <i>black.</i>

1316
01:52:19,367 --> 01:52:20,436
(SPEAKlNG FRENCH)

1317
01:52:20,527 --> 01:52:21,562
No more bets.

1318
01:52:46,527 --> 01:52:48,643
Right this way, my dear.

1319
01:52:50,647 --> 01:52:52,399
You stay right here,
l'll be right back.

1320
01:52:54,167 --> 01:52:56,203
So, this is
your dream, huh?

1321
01:52:56,287 --> 01:52:57,561
lt's enough for me, man.

1322
01:52:57,647 --> 01:52:58,966
l take it that's
your dream.

1323
01:52:59,047 --> 01:53:01,561
Absolutely. What up, boy?
What's going on?

1324
01:53:01,647 --> 01:53:03,365
You good?
Yes, yes.

1325
01:53:03,447 --> 01:53:04,562
You know what's crazy?

1326
01:53:04,647 --> 01:53:07,115
There's only four
of those cars
in the whole world.

1327
01:53:07,647 --> 01:53:10,002
Yeah, l got the only one
in the Western Hemisphere.

1328
01:53:10,487 --> 01:53:14,605
l made a sheikh
in Abu Dhabi an offer
he could not refuse.

1329
01:53:14,927 --> 01:53:17,077
Huh. That's a nice
lady you got there, too.

1330
01:53:17,167 --> 01:53:20,398
Absolutely.
What's happening?
(LAUGHlNG)

1331
01:53:21,207 --> 01:53:23,323
We got to go, man.
Let's do this.

1332
01:53:23,407 --> 01:53:24,965
Okay, l'll drive.

1333
01:53:25,047 --> 01:53:27,481
ln that?
Come on, man,
no way.

1334
01:53:27,567 --> 01:53:29,762
No, no. Not in this.

1335
01:53:29,847 --> 01:53:30,962
ln that.

1336
01:53:37,047 --> 01:53:38,526
Are you serious right now?

1337
01:53:39,287 --> 01:53:40,606
Man, this is crazy!

1338
01:53:40,687 --> 01:53:45,044
Yes, l guess that means
there are two in the
Western Hemisphere, huh?

1339
01:53:45,887 --> 01:53:48,117
What's your smart ass
got to say now?

1340
01:53:48,687 --> 01:53:51,918
You know what?
We can always
shine together, baby.

1341
01:53:52,007 --> 01:53:54,282
Get dressed, man,
we got things to do!

1342
01:54:06,207 --> 01:54:07,640
So, where to now?

1343
01:54:07,727 --> 01:54:09,160
l don't know.

1344
01:54:09,247 --> 01:54:11,522
Never been to Madrid.

1345
01:54:11,607 --> 01:54:14,246
l thought you wanted
to go to Tokyo.

1346
01:54:14,327 --> 01:54:16,397
We'll get there.

1347
01:54:16,487 --> 01:54:18,045
Eventually.

1348
01:55:14,967 --> 01:55:16,719
BRlAN: Nice surprise.

1349
01:55:20,207 --> 01:55:21,799
Crazy, right?

1350
01:55:29,647 --> 01:55:32,559
This is the happiest
l've ever seen my sister.

1351
01:55:33,567 --> 01:55:35,478
lt's because we're free.

1352
01:55:48,287 --> 01:55:50,437
You know,
l want another shot.

1353
01:55:53,847 --> 01:55:54,916
Yeah?

1354
01:55:56,807 --> 01:55:58,399
Yeah.

1355
01:55:58,487 --> 01:56:00,239
No wagers, nobody else.

1356
01:56:00,327 --> 01:56:02,443
Just you and me,
once and for all.

1357
01:56:09,207 --> 01:56:11,084
You sure you can handle
the disappointment?

1358
01:56:11,927 --> 01:56:13,280
Are you?

1359
01:56:15,487 --> 01:56:17,478
All right, O'Conner.

1360
01:56:17,567 --> 01:56:19,319
Let's see what you got.

1361
01:58:22,567 --> 01:58:26,924
DlPLOMATlC SECURlTY
SERVlCE HEADQUARTERS -
WASHlNGTON, D.C .

1362
01:58:29,847 --> 01:58:30,916
(TYPlNG)

1363
01:58:41,127 --> 01:58:42,845
You need to look at that.

1364
01:58:46,607 --> 01:58:48,484
Berlin, 3:00 a.m .
this morning.

1365
01:58:48,727 --> 01:58:51,446
A team of drivers
hijacked a military convoy.

1366
01:58:51,527 --> 01:58:53,279
Toretto?
Nope.

1367
01:58:54,047 --> 01:58:55,116
l ain't interested.

1368
01:58:55,207 --> 01:58:57,926
Yes, you are.
Keep looking.

1369
01:59:08,967 --> 01:59:10,719
Do you believe in ghosts?

1370
01:59:15,727 --> 01:59:18,116
THE MOTOR VEHlCLE ACTlON
SEQUENCES DEPlCTED
lN THlS FlLM ARE DANGEROUS.

1371
01:59:18,207 --> 01:59:20,198
ALL STUNTS WERE PERFORMED
lN CONTROLLED ENVlRONMENTS

1372
01:59:20,287 --> 01:59:22,323
WlTH PROFESSlONALLY TRAlNED
STUNT CREWS ON CLOSED ROADS.

1373
01:59:22,407 --> 01:59:24,443
NO ATTEMPTS SHOULD BE MADE
TO DUPLlCATE ANY ACTlON,

1374
01:59:24,527 --> 01:59:26,995
DRlVlNG OR CAR PLAY SCENES
HERElN PORTRAYED.

