In My Skin
At three words an hour
you'll never finish, Esther!
- Are you off?
- Yes. I'm going home to work.
I'm tired of this.
We should rent a place together.
With only one salary?
I want to Iive in luxury!
You had a steady salary before.
Yeah.
See the house?
Be great when it's finished.
He's a skirt-chaser. Go for it!
He's friends with the boss.
- Gee, thanks!
- I'm joking. That's him in the suit.
Good evening.
Is there any way
I can speed things up at the agency,
other than that,
to see what my chances are?
Not now, please!
I'll wish I hadn't got you in.
- Come on, there they are.
- I'll join you.
Shit!
Thanks.
I fell and tore my trousers.
My jacket's filthy, damn it!
I was out in the yard. Big place!
- He bought it for peanuts, apparently.
- Really?
You're ridiculous.
No, this is mine! Get your own.
Don't be mean!
Can I borrow her?
I've got to go.
- You're joking!
- Sorry.
I promised my friends.
I'll phone you for a lunch date.
I may ask your advice
about my work.
I don't do lunch dates.
I do dinner.
As you like.
Thanks. Bye.
Esther?
Esther!
Where have you been?
- Sorry, I'll explain. Let's go.
- Just a sec.
Henri and I looked everywhere for you.
It was weird!
There was blood on the bathroom floor
but nobody there.
We were scared we'd find a corpse!
Any luck?
I looked everywhere.
Forget about it.
I'm off home.
Henri should call the police.
No one reported an accident.
- So, where the hell were you?
- Walking in the yard.
I'm not tired.
How about a final drink?
- Okay.
- A quick one then.
Well, well!
The joint and Iigaments
escaped by an inch.
Had your tetanus shots?
- I think so.
- We'll give you a booster.
How did you do it?
I fell on some metal on a building site.
A tool, I think.
You and building sites don't mix!
This happened some hours ago.
Why didn't you come sooner?
I didn't know I was hurt.
I only noticed later.
Then I went to a bar.
I didn't think it was...
Didn't notice? Didn't it hurt?
No.
It does now, and in the bar,
but not then.
And it was too dark to see.
That's not normal.
Shock has strange effects, but still.
You should have felt it.
I feel my leg normally now.
I guess I wasn't thinking.
Scatterbrain!
Are you sure it's your leg?
Just a joke. I'm tired.
Can you feel my hand?
Yes.
I'll do a test.
Round or sharp? Don't look.
Don't look.
Round.
Sharp.
I didn't touch you.
Good.
I'll anesthetize it.
You'll feel a pinprick, then nothing.
You may need surgery
to replace the tissue.
- It won't all heal back.
- What do you mean?
Your skin will heal unevenly.
Like this.
A graft will fix it.
A few days in the hospital.
I'll consider it.
Medically, there's no need
but it won't look pretty.
If there's no need, I'd rather not.
Think about it.
The dressing will need changing.
We'll discuss it then.
There you go.
Hello.
Why didn't you go
straight to the hospital?
You gash yourself
and calmly go out for a Coke?
I guess I was in shock.
I want to go out. I did a hard
night's work. Let's eat out.
I don't fancy it.
Alright.
It's strange that you felt nothing.
The doctor said everything's normal.
How about a boat ride on the canal?
Don't fancy it either?
You suggest something.
- What was that?
- Nothing.
When you rip up your leg,
you don't feel it.
When I touch you,
you jump and scratch.
Admit it's weird.
Say something.
No answer?
If you don't want to go out,
just say so.
Don't endlessly change the subject!
I said I didn't want to.
And I don't want
to discuss the accident!
Esther.
Don't go to any more parties
without me.
You were on the make. Admit it.
Are you sure?
Walking in dark yards all alone
sounds fishy to me.
I've had a proposition too.
From a woman?
A job offer.
What job?
In a bank.
They head-hunted me.
They want a new image.
They need a business journalist.
I'd help to design
their new P.R. strategy.
- Excellent!
- I'm not so sure.
Exciting, yes.
Good money, new job,
but it feels like selling out.
I'll show you the dossier.
You'll wear a suit!
When I do this, can you feel it?
No.
No?
There you go.
Here, I've read it.
I added some notes
to clarify things for the client.
- Fine.
- For Wednesday, okay?
It's short, but I promised.
Wednesday morning if you can.
Sure.
The rest is fine.
It's a good analysis.
Merci.
My job stinks.
Nothing but bureaucratic bullshit.
Gives me a headache.
My job's okay
but the deadlines are tiring.
Pierre, can you come?
Damn!
We'll have that coffee later.
Coming for coffee?
Not now.
I'm up to my neck.
If I stop, I'm sunk.
Don't stop, then.
I'll never finish
with you hanging over me.
Take it easy.
I won't bother you. I just wanted
some coffee and fresh air.
Come on! I'll finish your work.
It can't be hard.
Joke!
I've been cooped up all day.
Not even a lunch break.
In my office.
Then I cut myself in the storeroom.
The storeroom, my office.
The air-conditioning,
no windows open, can't breathe...
I'll be okay.
If you're hurt, the first aid box
is by the photocopier.
Is it? I'll get it.
Wait. How did you cut yourself?
On a metal thing.
I guessed that.
What were you doing with it?
Cutting myself.
Flesh wounds. Nothing serious.
I was already injured but...
Forget it. Some other time.
Why did you do it?
I don't know.
I think I may have misused
a word, ''alternatively,''
in the first part
of my report this morning.
What are you working on?
A presentation to the Ministry.
Neat! Takes a special kind of writing.
Daniel gave me back my report.
I have to rewrite some of it,
but not all.
On the whole, it was good.
I'll let you get on.
No, let's have coffee. It can wait.
No, I should...
I should check that mistake
or it'll bug me.
- Don't worry about it.
- Wait!
Is Vincent home tonight?
No. He's got to work.
- Stay at my place.
- Really?
Thomas is coming
but you can sleep on the sofa.
Esther!
Coming!
Esther, answer!
Why is the door locked? Open it!
Open!
Sorry. I locked it without thinking.
But I did answer you.
- Here.
- Thank you.
God! You didn't do that?
No.
It's mostly the accident
at the party.
Don't look. Go, I'll disinfect it.
Stop staring at me.
Can you leave me alone
for a minute?
I hope you didn't touch my pans!
I'm the chef tonight.
I've decided to treat you
to my cooking skills.
Not that they're any good, but still.
It smells good.
Here.
I had a twelve-pack sent up.
The grocery downstairs
takes orders by phone. It's handy.
I have to work tonight
to meet my Wednesday deadline.
Okay.
I don't know what to say
about your cuts.
Say nothing.
But I'm worried.
You won't do it again, will you?
No, I did it without thinking.
You could see a doctor.
Get some pills.
I do, if I'm depressed or anxious.
You could see my doctor.
But he'd probably have you certified!
I know you,
but it looks sick to an outsider.
Anyhow, there's no need.
- Isn't Thomas coming?
- No.
He canceled.
Not that I care,
so long as I have company.
How's your presentation going?
So-so.
I'm so fed up.
I deserve a more responsible job.
With my experience and clients,
I should be a project manager.
I'd like that. Especially the money!
You'll soon be a research analyst.
I feel like a stooge.
I'm not so sure I will.
Tomorrow, at the office party,
I'll ask Modier
if I get the job and when.
I wouldn't.
You could blow your chances.
- So?
- I got the job!
I start in ten days
with that jewelry firm.
Congratulations.
Who's in charge?
Me.
I'll be project manager,
not just an analyst.
Junior manager, that is.
My Middle East knowledge
clinched it.
Well!
Fantastic.
You're not very experienced, but...
Junior manager!
Good going.
Do you mind?
No. I got you in here.
It feels a bit weird.
I've been here five years,
but I'm happy for you,
if you think you're fit enough.
Yes.
It'll be hard work at first
but I'll cope.
I'm sure you will.
So maybe I'll work for you?
Maybe.
Sandrine, please don't think I-
In the water!
Like everyone else!
- I've got no swimsuit!
- Who cares?
Go in your undies!
Sandrine!
- Off with her trousers!
- Sandrine!
Enough. Let her go.
It's your loss, girl.
The water's great!
I'm sorry. It was stupid.
Doesn't matter.
Sorry.
I panicked and froze.
She's jealous.
Like she was at college, only worse.
Her failures aren't my fault.
I don't want to see her again.
I was thinking this afternoon.
With my new salary
and yours at the bank,
why don't we buy, not rent?
We'll get a loan
and renovate a nice place.
How do I know
it won't happen again?
You can't explain it!
It was only once.
I don't intend...
Fuck your intentions!
Did you expect that?
Look at yourself! Show me again.
I didn't expect it
but it won't happen again.
What else can I say?
You ignore my new job-
I didn't ignore it!
I'm glad about it,
I'll inquire about loans.
But that! I can't handle it.
Talk about it! Why can't you?
I told you. It came over me,
a mindless urge.
I won't do it again.
What gave you the idea?
What did you want? That?
Do you like that?
Do you like it?
- Stop, you're scaring me!
- You scare me!
Is it my fault?
No.
Don't you like your body?
Yes, I do. But...
This all started with your accident
the other day, right?
Maybe. I don't know.
Stop questioning me.
Okay, I'll stop.
I know you. I'll take your word
it won't happen again.
Sorry I lost my temper.
Let's dress up
and celebrate your job.
I'll move in with you tonight,
since I don't work at home now.
I'll feel easier that way.
Okay?
Hello.
We need precise details
of Ivar's brand image abroad,
in markets where luxury
has other referents.
Our main aim
is to send our local agents
the data on which to devise
their independent strategies.
We need data on the luxury market,
especially jewelry,
the market leaders, their images,
and naturally the image
of Ivar itself.
We'll want to access surveys
from North America, Brazil,
Asia and the mid-East.
We're ready to spend.
The stakes are high
but we can't study every country.
Two countries should yield
a fairly accurate picture,
provided the cultural zone
matches your target markets.
Daniel says you're an expert
on the Middle East.
Yes. I'm not a specialist but I've
studied the area, its economics,
and I've spent time there.
- You could orient us.
- I hope so.
We'll draw up a proposal.
Esther will handle that aspect.
An international project.
Just what you wanted!
You're lucky.
Better than packaging surveys!
You bet!
I'll leave you to plan it.
Schedule several phases.
They seem to have money.
Give it the works.
Okay.
This will be cleared.
Chair okay?
Thanks. Everything's fine.
How's it going?
Fine.
Still got my beige trousers?
The laundry couldn't
get the stains out.
I'll write you a check to replace them.
No...
Actually, yes.
They cost me 900 euros.
I'm kidding.
90.
I'm busy now.
I'll leave it with the receptionist.
Yes.
The bedroom or verandah?
What did he say?
How many square meters?
Got to go. My dinner's here.
Around the clock! Bye.
- Thanks.
- No! Leave it to me.
Let me smell that.
Leave it to me, I said!
You should uncover it soon
to let it dry.
I'll see.
Sweetheart! Your cute Iittle face
on a magnetic card!
See?
Look in my bag.
I made appointments
to see three apartments.
The descriptions are in my bag.
- Whereabouts?
- You'll see.
In the blue folder.
I may be having dinner
with clients tomorrow.
What's that on your hand?
Let me see.
Hurry up!
Sorry.
I'm sorry, I thought...
I hope you'll agree it's delicious.
- It's a superb vintage.
- No, thank you.
- You don't like wine?
- No alcohol. Just water.
It's not alcohol,
it's a very good wine. Shame!
It's no everyday wine.
You've tempted me. I'll try it.
You'll see.
Excellent. Really excellent.
Well?
Delicious, I admit.
I'll do without water.
You see?
To return to business,
that was an interesting group.
Aside from the usual
generalities about luxury,
our image came out clearly.
A hard meeting to run too.
You coped well.
That woman on your left
kept contradicting the others!
Thank you.
Please.
A few years ago, we issued
a worldwide press package.
We had to withdraw it from Japan
because one detail upset them.
What was it?
The postures of the people in the ad.
There was a hand gesture
which we saw as being very elegant.
It deeply shocked the Japanese.
It was like a gesture of disdain.
For the reader, it signified refusal.
Talk about details!
Crucial details!
Often, the whole thing
hangs on such subtleties
in the local culture.
We have to be careful
not to send negative signals.
They say a translation error
brought Japan into World War II!
Communications are
different in Japan.
We have a global strategy
but Japan is an exception.
We have a marketing team there.
It's so unlike Europe and the U.S.
I didn't know Japan
was so unique in that way.
Some years ago,
we ran our global ads there.
The tests were catastrophic.
Two different cultures.
It did our image more harm than good.
Status symbols, especially,
are perceived very differently.
The Japanese marketing department
ignored guidelines from France.
They were almost completely useless!
We devised local strategies instead.
You worked in Japan?
For ten years.
I trained there and stayed on,
but Iiving so far away was hard.
I missed France.
I worked in Germany,
then back to Paris.
What drew you to Japan?
I studied Japanese history,
then got an M.B.A.
I knew the language and
the country fascinated me,
less for its present than its past.
It was like a dream.
Seeing for real
the things I had studied,
or what was left of them.
If you study a language,
you want to use it.
That was another motive.
I'm sure.
I'd like to travel too,
in a few years.
We're part of a European group.
We can move around.
- Where would you go?
- Lisbon.
Oh? Why?
I go there on vacation.
I like the feel,
the superior quality of Iife,
the people, the mentality.
It's only a 3-hour flight.
- That's quick.
- A good compromise.
Foreign, but still European.
I doubt I could Iive
in a totally alien culture,
but I like Lisbon.
Excuse me.
- Sorry. Go ahead.
- No hurry, Madam.
I don't like the way
Lisbon has changed since the Expo.
I used to like the city's
timelessness and authenticity.
The Expo changed so much.
The Vasco da Gama bridge,
the Barrio Alto...
I found it lost its charm.
Not at all. The innovations
were very good for the city.
They made Iife easier.
Creativity has blossomed.
You see creativity?
Definitely. AlI those places, like...
There's an interesting split
between everyday Iife,
which is more provincial
than metropolitan,
and the style and ambiance
of dinner at the Alcantara
or a place like the Lux,
or the Kremlin. Fabulous!
Much more inventive
than most places in Paris.
I don't know Lisbon.
You'd advise me to go?
I think it's a marvelous place.
Life there is stress-free
and pleasant,
but the entertainment
is first class.
Rather like Rome, no?
Rome is the exact reverse.
It has the cultural poverty
of a provincial town,
and all the aggravation of a big city.
- You're exaggerating.
- You don't like Rome?
Not much, no.
- Why not?
- I don't know.
My remark was offhand.
But whenever I was there,
I felt uncomfortable.
- Perhaps it was you.
- No, not really.
It's like I said.
I found it very aggravating.
Cars, horns,
scooters, traffic jams...
The smallest practicalities
become exhausting.
- And that wind...
- The sirocco.
It's infuriating!
I didn't take to the people.
They're less friendly
than elsewhere in Italy.
The women about town are so vulgar.
The way they walk!
Even their manners are bad.
The city itself is superb.
Its monuments, yes. Its museums
always seem to be closed.
For entertainment and nightlife,
it's poor.
Few cinemas. Only one arthouse.
Not many bars or clubs.
Not that they're my scene,
but my friends there
feel bored and cut off.
True, Paris has more entertainment
but it's improving.
More screens are opening.
And it's so beautiful.
I'm happy just walking.
One of our project managers
works in Rome now.
- For your agency?
- No, he ''reoriented,'' as they say.
Besides, our agency is in Milan.
He spent a few years in Milan,
but now he has another job in Rome.
He rents a place there
and keeps one in Milan.
Whatever he thinks of Rome,
he prefers Italy to France.
I don't think he plans to come back.
Would you like to move
to the Middle East?
So, in a nutshell,
Rome's awful, Lisbon's spoiled.
- What city do you like?
- Paris, of course.
The world's most beautiful city.
Harmonious architecture,
unspoiled, outstanding surroundings,
pleasant Iifestyle.
Those trendy clubs of yours,
they're not my criteria.
I have nothing against them,
but for me, that kind of place
can never replace
the daily pleasures
of our local bars and bistros.
Which always greet us so warmly!
Not always,
but don't let's generalize.
You must have missed
all that in Tokyo.
Definitely!
To return to what we were saying,
how do you go about working with
market research agencies in Japan?
Their methods must be different.
It can't be easy.
The air-conditioning is strong.
Excuse me.
Coming! I'm getting wine.
We researched
the whole concept of luxury,
how people feel about luxury goods,
be it perfumes or jewelry.
Trifles, let's say,
but expensive ones.
We tried to gauge public attitudes.
- Will you have a dessert?
- No thank you.
- Coffee?
- Not for me.
We could ask for the check.
Waiter! The check.
The survey
was originally designed to confirm...
It's down there.
Your friend's there, in the ambulance.
I was so scared.
Have you broken anything?
No, this is all.
- You took quite a fall.
- Yes.
I drove a client home
to the suburbs, around 11 p.m.
I got completely lost
with those traffic things,
sending you here, there,
making no sense...
So I got lost,
then I saw this road thing,
a kind of sign.
I completely lost...
I lost control and went over.
See? I tore my trousers.
How's your head?
Will they X-ray it?
No, I told them I'm okay.
The dinner yesterday went badly.
I want to get to work on time.
I'll go to the hospital
if I feel anything.
You look tired.
It's almost the same place.
Naturally, your knee took the weight...
but it's high.
You must have laid
on the ground a long time
to get those dents.
I don't know.
I guess it's that.
Something wrong?
I couldn't sleep.
It's about time I got up as well.
Bad luck, but it'll heal.
Don't think about it.
It wasn't just bad luck.
I shouldn't have drunk.
You couldn't know.
Cut out the drinking,
cut out the problem. Make sense?
Yeah.
You're still shocked and tired.
Don't sweat it.
You learned your lesson.
It won't happen again.
Think about something else.
Me, your job,
me again...
We're seeing that place
again at 5, remember?
We could move on Saturday.
I won't forget.
Your dinner problem will blow over.
Yes.
I'll pick you up tonight.
The apartment,
then the travel agency.
Eric and Justine prefer Italy.
Me too. Is that okay?
Yes, me too.
I wish they'd taken X-rays.
I hope you're okay.
Don't worry.
I'll take a shower.
We should bring a tape measure.
Their plans may be inaccurate.
Right!
Come in.
Good morning.
Sorry to bother you.
- I'm sorry I wasn't good at dinner.
- No, you weren't.
That kind of dinner is not for fun,
or to have a good meal. It's work.
Your professional behavior
was seriously lacking!
I've known you two years.
I won't judge you on one lapse.
I was very embarrassed,
both towards them
and to find you were less mature
than I thought.
There.
I have nothing to add.
Your survey was well done,
so you're in credit overall.
A second lapse
would jeopardize your place here,
at least at your level
of responsibility.
Understood. It won't happen again.
Thank you.
We have until Friday.
The vendor's giving us priority.
Oh, cool.
- We'll be set in no time
- Yes.
What did you want to
discuss with the builder?
The plumbing in the kitchen
and the bedroom windows.
Same as you.
And that load-bearing wall.
Yes. Hang on, I need some cash.
If that wall has to stay, it's no deal.
Pity, because I really like the place.
It's perfect on the whole,
but for that one potential problem.
Even if it's load-bearing,
there must be solutions.
Are you Iistening? What's up?
Nothing. Just a sec.
The whole wall can't be load-bearing.
We could cut it in half
to feel less boxed-in.
We can't knock it all down.
What are you up to?
What's wrong?
I've forgotten
my wretched PIN number!
I know it.
There's nothing to cry about.
How much? 200?
We must answer by Friday.
It's only Wednesday.
I've been thinking about your job.
If they're training an in-house team
rather than outsource the work,
maybe they intend
to create permanent jobs.
Perhaps they're planning to expand.
It's strange, since they already have
P.R. and personnel departments.
But there must be a reason for it.
Does that sound stupid?
I don't know. I've had a tiring day.
What's the matter?
Nothing.
Something's wrong.
Not with me.
I don't cry in the street.
I'm a normal guy.
You must be so happy with me
if you cry over a PIN number!
I'm thinking, what can I do?
Probably nothing.
I'm not a drag or a pain, am I?
If I'm not the problem,
it's something I don't know about,
so I don't know you.
You do know me. You do.
You always look for meanings.
Maybe I do.
People get tense, strung out.
The car accident...
I don't know.
I'm turning in. You should too.
We'll feel better tomorrow.
I'm coming.
Good morning.
I need some formalin.
I don't sell it. It's illegal.
Try asking a lab,
but they won't give you any.
A hospital, maybe.
What's it for?
I had a piece of bad skin removed.
I want to preserve it.
You're sentimental!
I never saw that before.
What's it in, water?
Is that how they packed it?
I broke the other flask.
It's water.
They didn't strain themselves!
But things deteriorate,
even in formalin, over the years.
I don't see what could...
Skin is tanned, normally.
Human skin not often, thankfully!
But it's the same.
What did they suggest?
I forgot to ask.
How do I tan it?
Will it stay smooth and soft?
Yes, like anything made of leather.
Wallets, clothes... They're tanned.
Tanned and treated.
It's a whole technique.
To do it yourself, try potassium alum.
Dilute it in water, smear it on,
roll it out flat. That will tan it.
It won't be treated or dyed,
but tanned. It won't budge.
Press it hard.
It shouldn't be too thin.
May I?
No problem.
What's bad about it?
It looks fine.
It wasn't.
That's all I have to do to tan it?
That's all.
Anything else?
Yes. Foundation cream
and aspirin or paracetamol.
Yes, it's me.
Can you call me back?
I'm on my mobile.
I'm afraid I won't be home tonight,
but please call me.
Take care. Bye for now.
Esther here.
I'm sorry. A mass of things
has kept me from coming to work.
Can you apologize to Daniel,
say I'll be in at 9 sharp tomorrow?
No need.
No, that was a friend.
He didn't know.
Can you give me Elodie?
Hello. This is your wake-up call.