Well, perhaps.
But truthful.
Okay.
[PHONE RINGS]
[music]
I did at Albanyfest?
[TOILET FLUSHES]
CADEN:
Jesus.
WOMAN: You better eat this.
I will.
Vivian Malone Jones.
.
Stroke, 63
[music]
God! Somebody! Adele, help!
n it.
Oh, God, I can't tur
Oh, wait.
There. I think that should--
Let's see.
No, honey, today is Friday.
So, what exactly did he say?
A different kind of pipe, honey.
All right, bye.
Caden, stop it
.
I don't want blood.
Thanks for getting me in
right away.
Was it the bump to the head?
No.
I just thought you sai
d "urologist."
Just for a look-see.
The eyes are part of the brain
, after all.
it?
No, that's not true, is
Like morally correct,
or "right" as in accurate?
I don't know.
Accurate, I guess?
And the first thing you know--
Ben, where do I...?
Willy! No!
it.
Ambivalently.
Yeah, I saw that. I liked
Um.
Okay.
DAVID:
I-I think 15.
...
Uh. Hm
So now what?
S]
[CHUCKLE
Yeah, Dr. Heshborg said
I should see a Dr. Scoriano.
rk.
My pupils don't wo
I think
I have blood in my stool.
That stool in your office?
Yes, please do.
I've fantasized
about Caden dying.
Okay, good.
[DOOR CLOSES]
ere.
It's a nightmare in th
I'm sorry.
Yeah?
Yeah.
t.
You're not an idio
"In fact, Hazel, you're very
bright, and I love your eyes."
Do you?
Oh, you're a darling.
Because it's dirty.
Go ahead.
I've seen boy parts.
Yeah, sure. I guess.
NG]
[URINE TRICKLI
Great.
[CLEARS THROAT]
CADEN:
Gorgeous.
Yeah.
.
We got through it thou
gh. That's really pretty
Caden, I'm sorry, I--
r.
I have to figure out
what I'm gonna wea
[CROWD CHATTERING]
Hey.
[DOOR CLOSES]
It's all right
, I came back.
Oh. I hated myself tonight.
[SIGHS]
Mm. Sweetheart.
r.
Good work.
Don't worry, it'll get bette
Yeah, thank you.
Me neither.
?
Do you get high, my friend
You know, sometimes.
h,
I-I get kind of, u
You know,
.
You're absolutely zero fun
When are the reviews
gonna get here?
Don't know.
go?
Hi, Caden. How'd it
Great. We're a hit.
MARIA:
Wow, it's really lat
e-- Early.
Can we get Maria a ticket?
your artistic satisfaction
, Caden.
[music]
[COUGHS]
one.
I-- I never thought
I'd buy a house al
Oh, I don't know.
Would you like to meet my so
n? Derek.
Hey, Mom.
CLAIRE:
I want just a minute.
[MUSIC PLAYS OVER PA]
I never...
Forgive me, dear.
I can't cry.
I don't know what it is,
but I can't cry.
We're free and clear.
We're free. We're free.
[APPLAUSE]
d.
So we're both tire
No, I cuddled with Olive
all night. It was great.
ng.
Morning. Morni
[LAUGHS]
I'm going to.
I know. You're right. Bye.
My joints are stiff.
Who was that?
e.
Caden, I think I wanna
go to Berlin with just Oliv
Morning, kiddos.
to something like that?
Want me to zip your coat up?
Yeah.
les.
Uh, it's pustu
't.
I could, but I don
Can I ask you something, Ad?
Have I disappointed you somehow?
We're just spending
a little time apart.
We'll talk when I get back,
okay?
The more you know someone,
it just...
I mean, I don't know.
[CRYING]
I don't know what I'm doing.
I don't know.
We'll talk when I get back.
Okay?
[SNIFFS]
when it's your turn to fac
the challenges of chemotherapy.
[music]
?? You fell
Then you died ??
Yes. Anything else?
I'm hurt.
Yes. And?
.
I'm afraid I'm gonna die
That's $45.
Five. Five.
Five.
He'll probably recommend
gum surgery.
Have fun--
[GRUNTING]
[DIALING]
I'm sick! I'm sick!
Ma'am?
?
NURSE:
Mr. Cotard
Mr. Cotard.
.
Mr. Cotard
Maybe you can learn
some sort of manual override.
[music]
Anyway, I don't wanna
make you uncomfortable, I...
And what do we do
with all this?
[WHISPERING]
You wanna come ove
r to my place, Cotard?
It's been a week.
ndar.
I'm gonna buy you a cale
Okay.
Just for one drink.
ok.
Come on. Scraps
for my scrapbo
drink very much
because of my condition.
[CHUCKLES]
Does it make you wanna kiss me?
Please, Hazel.
On your knees.
Just for fun.
Why am I doing this?
For fun, baby.
Oh, kiddo.
.
[GROANS]
No, no, no
rry.
What is it?
I don't know, I'm so
rry.
I'm so
, um...
What?
I don't know, I'm just
rry.
I, um.
.. I'm so
k.
I'm really, uh
-- I'm really sic
ing.
And I think I'm dy
d.
I have a kid
, and I'm marrie
I had a good time, and I thi
nk you're a very nice person.
That is just the wrong thing
to say right now, Caden.
You should go.
[COMPUTER DICTATES
NONSENSICALLY]
[DOOR OPENS]
I don't know yet.
Written by a 4-year-old?
Jefferson.
u?
I said, why would yo
.
Oh, I don't know
There it is.
King Lear.
WAITRESS:
Okay, here you go.
Here's your salad.
Here's your
soup.
Thanks. Ahem.
y.
Thank you.
Enjo
ng.
The biofeedback traini
I'm not sure I can work
with you, Caden.
t.
I just wanna normalize i
I think we'd have
a lot of fun together.
.
[CHOKING
]: I miss you
.
Really disturbing.
I know
I like chocolate,
and my favorite color is pink.
This is pink.
CLERK: Next.
CUSTOMER: Hi.
I'll begin.
I will be dying.
And so will you.
[CLEARS THROAT]
We're all hurtling
towards death.
each of us knowing
we're gonna die,
each of us secretly
believing we won't.
It's brilliant.
g.
It's everythin
It'sKaramazov.
You do not wanna cross m
e.
Don't I?
.
Hi, Claire
Yes, I recall Mr. Cotard.
g--
Yeah. I'm waitin
Oh.
Heh.
Why am I bowing? Okay, bye.
Yeah, I guess so.
Really? Why?
I don't know.
ry.
HAZEL: Don't say
that, not to me.
DEREK: Sor
My mother died last night.
Oh, my God. I'm so s
orry. What are you doing out?
Yeah, it's a Freudian slip,
right?
To meet, you know?
Like, to meet.
Oh.
I have to fuck you.
I have to.
There will be
no other before you.
Okay. Hold it. Ahem.
CLERK: That'll be $40.
We've had Ariel. I think peopl
e know that we've fucked.
Okay.
For example, look to your left.
[BOTH CHUCKLE]
You know, I'm not sure
I'm getting the book.
ow.
You're almos
t non-recognizable n
Thank you.
[FLIGHT ATTENDANT
SPEAKS IN GERMAN]
Hello.
They?
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
She-- She's almo
st over 11 now.
e.
She's my mus
[GRUNTING]
CADEN:
You don't love her!
Where is she?
What did you do
to my daughter?
[SOBBING]
Oh, God.
[GASPING]
[INDISTINCT SPEECH OVER PA]
Death comes
faster than you think.
You can get dressed.
No.
?
What are you
doing here
Yeah, for--
For a while now.
Yeah. I-I thought you knew.
Ah.
?
How about with you
You wear a lab coat.
.
Oh, good to see you, Hazel
Hey! Hey!
[DOOR OPENS]
Ariel. Ariel. Fuck.
[SIGHS]
Ariel.
[PHONE RINGS]
Please.
[MAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
Okay.
My father died.
Oh, baby.
That he went in
because his finger hurt.
They said he suffered horribly.
And that he...
That he called out for me
before he died.
He said he regretted his life.
And they said
he said a lot of things.
Too many to recount.
nd.
to keep him
from rattling arou
All right.
[ANSWERING MACHINE BEEPS]
CADEN:
Sorry.
Hi, Derek.
Just tell me what to do?
MAN [OVER RADIO]:
In Pakistan today,
the government--
.
You know I'm sorry
y.
I don't want you to be oka
I mean, I do, but
I-- It just, uh...
too.
And I'll--
I'll help you through
I'm fine.
I have Derek.
Okay, I'm going.
[music]
Olive?
Olive.
Olive, it's Daddy.
f!
Get of
Brutal.
When are we gonna
get an audience in here?
It's been 17 years.
fucked-up being.
every day
from my god!
Get to work!
[music]
They fired me.
I mean, that's all there is.
Uh...
Please, Caden. I...
Please, Caden.
Sammy Barnathan?
This is Sammy Barnathan.
or a picture.
n...
Well, I've bee
and you'll see
who you truly are.
Peek-a-boo.
Okay.
the way I feel about you.
that look only at each other,
that whispers to itself.
Okay.
You've got the part.
[TOILET FLUSHES]
I've never seen
your shit gray.
It's new.
That's a good-
- Good boy.
[SIREN WHOOPS]
]
[CLEARS THROAT
e?
if I doesn't play
with my pee-pee no mor
Yeah.
I'm not sure.
It, uh...
[LAUGHS]
I'm gonna start thinking
about myself.
[BOTH LAUGH]
?
Why did we
leave Adele, Caden
She left us.
Now, you know that
better than anybody.
o.
Sweet pussy to
How do you know that?
Oh, I read it.
[BOTH CHUCKLE]
Anyway...
baby.
f.
and see how you lo
se even more of yoursel
Research.
[music]
[BEEPS, DOOR OPENS]
[DINGS]
Hold it, please.
t.
but I think it was too late.
You didn't press i
ks.
Yeah, than
Okay, thanks.
.
Oh, sweetheart
CADEN:
Adele?
Take what you want.
I had to think.
ck?
Are you wearing lipsti
No.
I wouldn't know.
You are. What the fu
ck is wrong with you?
Beautiful, Sammy.
l.
I can't explore without a Haze
Hurray.
Best, Ellen.
.
I had to think
I have a right
to fucking know.
lace.
I've been goin
g to Adele's p
And cleaning it.
[KNOCKING CONTINUES]
Okay, I'll take that
as my cue.
Maybe I will.
k.
I got an offer to do
Needleman in a Haystac
I didn't say it!
for a Claire
replacement.
But I'm afraid
I'm gonna have to move on.
I'm sorry. Okay.
t.
All of i
.
Claire
All right.
It's just a thought.
Kisses, A.
ll.
I'm afraid I'm gravely i
"Home," I say.
Home.
This is to hear.
?
So words--
English here, yeah
.
infected and they're dying
Of course,
she introduced me to myself.
I just want--
I have no time.
I need you to ask
for forgiveness.
Can you ever
forgive me?
with my homosexual lover, Eric.
I will, I'll say it.
For abandoning you...
with my homosexual
lover, Eric.
No.
No, I'm sorry.
I cannot.
[GROANS]
I'm not happy.
Make it personal.
Move along.
Dating, birth, death,
life, family...
ou.
It's not real.
I can't hear y
[TRAFFIC NOISE]
Hi, Sammy.
Sammy likes you.
I can give you
the interiors later.
A few days?
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
Millicent Weems?
Hazel, what do you
think of this title?
Unknown, Unkisse
d and Lost?
Meh...
CADEN:
Have a seat.
How are you
at cleaning?
Great. Okay.
inScrub-A-Dub
at the Pantages.
for this character.
Glad to be weirdly close.
MAURICE:
Sorry, everybody.
Yes, sir.
rry.
I'm so
Line, please?
Yes, I'm Ellen.
Did you hear that?
What?
Adele?
Caden.
I'll be out in a second.
Watch. Watch this.
Watch this.
Where's, uh,
Hazel and Sammy?
[BOTH LAUGHING
]
Sammy.
...
I was being you, I
Ten minutes,
everybody!
She is dead.
He was a big guy.
Anyway...
Thanks for coming with me.
That's okay.
.
and you're the next best thing
I mean, it's not that
you're the next best thing
but because you play her,
it feels comforting.
[LAUGHS]
But you play her
very well, though.
m.
I'll have another talk with hi
I need to go to the bathroom.
Hmm.
Thanks, Yammy.
It's your dime.
m.
You can stay
in my parents' roo
[GASPS]
CADEN:
I thought someone
would have cleaned it up.
I don't know. Someone.
e?
Don't you want to sleep with m
ay.
If you think it's ok
In front of someone
is different.
TAMMY:
Yeah, I suppose it might.
Do you want to fuck?
I do. Um, do you?
y.
I'm very, very lonel
I don't, ah...
I'm sorry.
I mean, can--? Can you
understand loneliness?
Yeah. I mean--
I feel okay, mostly.
Fucking might help.
Take your clothes off.
Sometimes I wish
I could be pretty like that.
It's kind of a drag
in a lot of ways.
Well, I'm getting cold.
.
Thanks for saying that
Come to bed, pretty Caden.
I shouldn't have drunk
so much fucking beer last night.
We need to fire him.
him.
We don't need to fire
It needs to be shorthand,
like, "Jeremy, big."
nk?
Caden, what do you thi
I-- I feel like we could
-- We could try it.
Great.
Fuck.
[COUGHS]
Maybe it could happen
at the director's table.
[CLEARS THROAT
] Fuck.
le?
Since when are you availab
Derek left because of you.
Oh, oh...
ng.
It was nice.
It wasn't earth-shatteri
[SCOFFS]
You're making progress.
e.
Okay, I cried a little befor
t?
Don't you know tha
I breathe your name
in every exhalation.
[music]
Caden.
CADEN:
Sammy!
A man stopped me before
I jumped. Get up!
I didn't jump.
t.
Come over tonigh
Please.
.
God, Caden
I'm aching for it being over.
Yeah.
It's okay.
[SIGHS]
[music]
I have a title.
The Obscure Moon
Lighting an Obscure World.
ch.
I think it might be too mu
[CHUCKLES]
MAN:
Sir, could you come
up here, please?
Oh.
[music]
[SOBS]
I know how to do the play now.
It'll all take place
over the course of one day
and that day will
be the day before you died.
It was the happiest
day of my life.
See you soon.
for today's rehearsal?
Oh.
You'll see, it means a lot.
I'd very much like
to play Caden.
Okay.
I saw it as much more hopeful.
They're all leads
in their own stories.
No, this is tedious.
This is nothing.
.
You don't move around like tha
t. You don't talk to people
t.
Okay, everybody, let's run i
Something to make
you feel loved.
And the truth is
I feel so angry.
I feel so fucking sad.
just for--
because they have their own.
Well, fuck everybody.
Amen.
[music]
I'm out of ideas.
I'm dead.
It's a choice role.
I do like to clean.
[music]
Ellen?
You're to keep
it in all the time.
of Adele's neighbor
so close to death.
I will indeed.
Wrap some around your hand.
Wipe yourself.
Meaning.
c?
Everything okay, Eri
ELLEN:
He hates me.
I disappointed him,
and he hates me.
Everyone is disappointing
when you know someone.
Baby, that the loveliest thi
ng I've ever heard.
Sorry, Mommy. I'm sorry.
Where is my little girl?
MILLICENT [OVER RADIO]:
Look at the night table
for a note from Adele.
You may stay on if you like.
MILLICENT [OVER RADIO]:
Stare out the window.
Stand up.
[music]
.
The room doesn't care either
[INDISTINCT YELLING]
[YELLING STOPS]
[CRASH]
MILLICENT [OVER RADIO]:
Hello?
[CRIES OUT]
There's nobody running
the elevator anymore.
[MAN SCREAMS]
[RADIO CRACKLES]
MILLICENT [OVER RADIO]:
Walk.
gone.
CADEN:
Where is everybody?
Some have left.
Because I'm very t
ired and-- And lonely.
[EXHALES]
Hmm.
Yes.
I didn't mean to s
ay you looked old.
Ah--
CADEN:
There's everyone's dre
ams in all those apartments.
it.
That's the truth of
I wanted to do that picn
ic with my daughter.
Yes.
I love you.
[SOBS]
[music]
.
I know how to do this play now
MILLICENT [OVER RADIO]:
Die.
Who will look at me and say ?
You're the one
I've waited for ??
Let's have some fun ??
So let's have some fun
I'm glad I found you
I like the best ??
And we'll go out and play