First Avenue, Kabuki-cho
- Are you sure, Mr Fujiwara?
- You know what the boss said.
He doesn't need a bodyguard.
At least not in the apartment.
But why not let me keep
a look-out outside his door?
While he's fucking a girl?
That's not what I mean.
You're only a bodyguard, so just
shut the fuck up until you're needed.
Hello.
Is that you, Takeshi?
You're coming home soon, aren't you?
You're not leaving too, are you?
No Takeshi, I won't leave you.
I'm at work.
- I'll call back later.
- Dad, Dad...
Tadanobu Asano
Hideo Yamamoto
Takashi Miike
Stop it. No!
No!
Cut it out.
No.
Stop.
How does that feel?
Who's there? Who the hell...!
Ichi The Killer
It's me,
- Inoue, don't!
- I thought I'd strengthen my resolve
No need.
Ichi will take care of everything.
Lately we only go in
to clean up after Ichi.
Found it.
I thought I told you to quit.
What the hell?
If I can't shoot up,
you can't use my phone.
Let's go.
He did it again. As gross as ever.
What's this guy Ichi like, anyway?
Let's get started.
What the hell happened here?
You were guarding
the boss last night.
- So was Kaneko.
- Don't try and pass the blame.
Sorry. My apologies.
Mr Kaneko,
any idea where he might be?
Has Anjo really disappeared?
How much money is missing?
About 3 million yen.
Then I guess Anjo took the money...
and ran off with the girl.
Sir, the boss
would never do such a thing. Never.
All that time he spent in jail...
must have softened his brain.
A guy grows old
gets obsessed with a broad
and can't even tell
his ass from a hole in the ground.
Probably some other gang
is behind it, sir.
There are many who bear us a grudge.
It's not Anjo who made enemies.
You did.
The boss is not dead.
Please excuse us.
- Don't you have a girlfriend?
- No. It gets lonely, you know.
- Why don't you get yourself a pet?
- I used to have an alligator
but they get hard to handle
so I flushed it down the toilet.
I see.
- What kind?
- A mongrel.
He was so cute.
But this bloke next door...
He made fun of it.
So I started praying.
Welcome.
- Is Karen here?
- She's there. Follow me.
- My wish was fulfilled.
- Really?
It died.
It did?
C'mon, have another.
- Masa.
- Did you hear?
The boss has disappeared.
If he ran off at all
it would've been with you.
Another gang have got him.
What are you going to do now?
He's not dead. I'll find him.
Yes, I'm sure you will.
Don't fool with me, Karen.
He's alive. I'm dead sure of it.
He's just waiting for me to find him.
Yeah, but...
You're the boss's woman.
What are you talking about?
I'm sorry.
- It's my birthday.
- Today's your birthday?
- Then this is your present.
- I thought I told you to quit.
Kakihara of the Anjo gang.
Murder, arson, smuggling and rape.
How have you been?
So you're back in Shinjuku, huh?
This is the only place...
where guys like us can make a living.
Did you hear
what happened at our place?
More or less.
When you hear anything,
I want to know. There'll be a reward.
I see.
Kill yourself.
I'm sorry.
I can't hear you.
Hurry up and die. Hurry up and die.
I'm sorry.
I have no use
for your stupid apologies.
Stop crying.
You can shed all the tears you want.
I'll only forgive you
when you're dead.
You stupid son of a bitch.
I don't want to hear
that you haven't found him yet.
Give me that.
I want you
to turn Shinjuku inside out
until you find the boss!
Don't show your face until you do.
Chief, so far
we haven't found any clues.
That doesn't mean, of course...
that I've abandoned all hope.
I'll find him. Just leave it to me.
I'll get it.
It's just a rumour.
Hard to say how much of it is true.
But the Funakis belong to
the Sanko syndicate, just like us.
They even share the building with us.
Exactly.
That way they can keep tabs...
on who's coming and going.
- They probably staked out your boss.
- Why do that?
Well, Mr Kakihara...
three years ago you yourself
cut Mr Suzuki of the Funaki family
out of a porn video sales racket.
Word has it that he hasn't forgotten.
So, you think Suzuki
is behind all this?
It's only a rumour.
But behind your back
Mr Suzuki is bad-mouthing you.
He's spread
some pretty ridiculous stories.
Such as that
you had a crush on boss Anjo.
What the hell are you talking about?
Takayama, bring him here.
Bring who?
Suzuki, of course.
But...
You got cold feet?
That's not the problem.
We don't have any proof.
Since when do you care about proof?
If he lies
we'll give his corpse to Funaki.
Get on with it, Takayama.
OK.
Jijii, go buy some shrimps.
Shrimps?
Kakihara?
Tempura?
What the hell's going on here?
Kakihara! What the fuck is this?
You look fantastic, Mr Suzuki.
Where is the boss?
The boss? You mean Anjo?
He and that girl bolted.
Made off with your money, right?
I don't get what you say.
Wait. Stop, damn it!
You think I took boss Anjo?
I know you're pissed off because
I dealt you out of that video deal.
You've been going around
bad-mouthing us.
No, I haven't.
Yes, you have.
Ain't that right, Jijii?
Who the hell are you?
You say you didn't dub adult videos
behind Mr Kakihara's back?
That proves you can't be trusted.
OK, it's true about the videos.
I'll admit that.
But I know nothing about your boss.
You have to believe me, please.
I'll ask you again.
Where is the boss?
I don't know. I really have no idea.
- Chief, that's too...
- Wait.
Hey, wait!
I wonder how Jijii managed
to get a camera and a mike in there?
- I put them there.
- You did?
Jijii talked me into it before
I was kicked out of the Anjo gang.
So you were buddies with Kakihara?
He wouldn't recognise me now.
I had a face job.
Plastic surgery?
Why did you choose this face?
Shut up!
Right, I have to make a call.
You about ready to come clean?
I'm going to kill all of you.
Once again. Where is the boss?
How would I know?
Somebody's already killed him!
He's still alive.
So what?
If you won't talk,
maybe your little one will.
No. Don't do that.
Give me a break, damn it! I'll do
anything you want if you just stop.
What the hell?
Is that you, Suzuki?
Kakihara! What the fuck
do you think you are doing?
Just a little torture.
- What did Suzuki do?
- Don't!
Put that back, Mr Kaneko.
Who the hell are you?
You tell us first
what you are doing here, Mr Funaki.
Someone called to say Suzuki
was in big trouble with your gang.
He thinks I kidnapped his boss.
Suzuki would never
do such a stupid thing.
Let him go.
- In this together, are you?
- What?
We were tipped off
that Suzuki had taken the boss.
By who?
That guy there.
- Well, who?
- That guy Jijii.
What guy?
You! Go and find him!
Hello.
So you came back.
You are the only one
who enjoys seeing a girl's body
all black-and-blue.
How...?
What do you mean, 'how'?
Tell me about the beating
you got yesterday?
What do you mean?
Did it hurt?
I thought I was going to die.
The bastard. I wish he would die.
Die...
Yes, I wish he would die.
Shall I kill him for you?
- Ten million yen?
- No, you idiot. A hundred million!
That seems like a fair sum.
We don't have that much.
So hand the video business over to us
and that'll settle the matter.
All of our money
disappeared with the boss.
Take our video business too
and we'll have to fold.
You think
I'd let you off that easily?
Throw this guy out of the syndicate.
That makes it a lot easier.
Maybe you're right.
I'll make a sincere apology.
This is not a matter
of cutting one or two fingers.
- I have a taste for sweet things.
- So what?
To apologise,
I'll cut my source of pleasure.
What do you mean?
Ka-en?
All right, I'm on my way.
I'm going to look for the boss.
Boss!
I had to stop at the hospital.
The hospital?
That's disgusting.
Look, it's amazing.
It's all right.
The human body regenerates itself.
If I keep talking it'll get better.
Who is it?
It's Karen, from the Hirando club.
Good morning.
Have you heard from him?
I don't owe you a thing
so why should I tell you anything?
If you're not here to score,
just fuck off.
How dare you come here empty-handed
and ask me for a favour.
Who the hell do you think you are?
This is Kakihara.
The guy with the body piercings
from the Anjo gang.
Hey, who said you could come in?
I don't care who he is.
I don't associate
with the likes of you.
The boss is going to die.
What's this guy talking about?
If I don't hurry, the boss will die.
Like I said, if you're not here
to score you're in the way.
So get the hell out. Scram!
Do you know
what'll happen if he dies?
Jijii, hurry back here
and give me a hit.
He was already in there
when we arrived.
I taped it up
in case he tries to escape.
Where's the boss, Jijii?
What's this?
That's our office.
Look what I found.
Boss Anjo...
So you guys kidnapped him.
Where is boss Anjo?
I'll tell you
if you shoot me up first.
I'm asking you. Where's the boss?
He's long dead and buried.
If I'm not getting a shot then hurry
up and kill me, brother Kakihara.
Who are you?
I know your methods.
If you're going to kill me anyway
just get it over with,
brother Kakihara.
Kano?
Jackpot.
Are you Kano?
But your face is different.
So you killed the boss?
It was Ichi who did it.
Who is this 'lchi'?
I only cleaned up after him.
It seems that Ichi's next target
is you, brother Kakihara.
You had the hots for Anjo,
didn't you?
Not because you're queer
or because you admired his balls.
It was because you relished
the pain that he inflicted
when he beat you up.
That's why you want
to find him so badly.
Am I right?
You need him to hurt you again.
Kakihara,
I'm going to get you for this.
I'll never forget what you did.
I'm going to kill you, you bastard.
What did you do with the girl?
He asked where Anjo's girl is.
The girl?
We want the girl
you took along with Anjo.
Return her to us right now.
Wait a minute.
You're also making a mistake.
We'll kill you. If you don't say
something, we'll kill the whole gang.
Will you listen, damn it?
I didn't do it.
I've got nothing to do with it.
I'm innocent.
Believe me, please.
Ask somebody else, please.
- Time is running out.
- Time's up.
What do you mean?
We'll cut you here.
It won't hurt much.
No, please. Help!
Hello?
I understand.
Someone says he saw a man with
a torn mouth attack Anjo's office.
That's Kakihara. I knew it!
I can't breathe in this mask.
I should've cut the eyes
a little higher.
It fogs up when I breathe.
Hi Myu-Myu. How are you?
- This is it?
- Stop it!
- You know what I'm saying?
- Stop hitting me!
Tell me.
You can suck dicks, you have a cunt
and this is all you earn?
How can I get clients
if you keep busting my face?
Shut up, you bitch!
How does that feel?
Who the fuck are you?
Come in here, you little shit.
What the fuck are you doing?
Are you some kind of pervert?
What the fuck is this costume?
Say something.
Can't you talk, asshole?
I'm sorry.
Don't bullshit me saying 'I'm sorry'.
Why are you crying?
- I'm not crying.
- Yes, you are.
- No, I'm not.
- I can see it.
- You're fucking crying!
- No, I'm not!
What the fuck?
What did you do?
I killed him for you.
I promised I'd kill him for you.
But don't worry.
From now on I'll beat you up.
You'll beat me up instead?
Thank you.
Kakihara, you are expelled
from the Syndicate.
The Syndicate came to this decision
due to the arrogance shown
in your actions and those of your men
during the search for Anjo,
your torture of Suzuki
and your refusal
to bargain with Funaki.
Have you anything to say?
Are you listening?
Kakihara!
Is that all you wanted to say?
I guess so.
Then I thank you for everything.
That was a piece of cake.
Hey, Suzuki.
Are you sure
we're doing the right thing?
It's strange
the way he took it lying down.
You think he's bent on revenge?
- I forgot to mention one thing.
- What?
I'm taking over the Anjo gang.
So we've been expelled?
That's right.
Every yakuza in Shinjuku is after us.
Whoever wants out, better say now.
I'm sorry.
I'd like to hand back the sake cup
- With which I pledged allegiance.
- Do you, now?
They expelled Kakihara.
Where's the money?
- I've put half into the account.
- Only half? That wasn't the deal.
I'll deposit the rest
when you've carried out our deal.
3 million yen is a lot of money.
What if you blow it?
In the next three or four days
you kick everyone out
of that yakuza apartment.
They'll only get in the way.
Can you do it alone?
Don't worry.
I'll get on it right away!
Make sure you squash Kakihara,
good and proper.
Where are you going?
What do you want me to do?
Just wait here. Don't move.
Ichi...
Ichi!
I dreamt about Ms Tachibana.
Who helped you when they bullied you?
The girl that got raped?
When they raped her
she cried for me to help her.
But my legs were shaking so violently
that I couldn't move.
I still dream
about how she cried out.
You wanted to save Ms Tachibana
so badly?
I felt like raping her.
Surely you wanted to save her?
She wanted me to rape her.
Ichi! Open your eyes, damn it!
Why would Sailor
do such a thing to me?
Who are you talking about?
Why would Sailor
do such a thing to me?
Get a grip on yourself, Ichi.
Huh? What's the matter?
You've been expelled
from the Syndicate, haven't you?
Letting you in puts me in jeopardy.
Who do you think you're talking to?
That hurts.
Mr Kakihara, please stop.
You'll tear it off. It's stretching.
Karen, Karen!
Karen, do something, please!
Help me!
Karen!
Can I join in?
That hurts.
What the hell are you doing, Karen?
Masa, you know what?
What do you want?
I'll tell you everything.
Take off your shoes!
You're so fucking slow!
- Hurry up.
- Go and get it.
Get a move on.
- Hey, give it back to me.
- What?
Your father got fired from the police
because he lost his gun.
What an idiot.
He's as big an idiot as his dad.
Those guns are paid for
with tax money.
Give us our money back, asshole.
Hurry up and bring it back.
Can't you hear what I'm saying?
Hey, you.
Quit staring.
Get lost, you jerk.
You want to be my woman, don't you?
Then give it to me
like you did before.
- Does that hurt?
- Keep going.
Listen, when you're hurting someone
don't think of the pain
that he feels.
Only concentrate
on the pleasure of causing him pain.
That's the only way to show
true compassion for your partner.
It's OK.
Do it like you want to kill me.
The boss was a lot better at this.
That's enough.
You let me down.
Hey, come back!
These guys need to be killed.
Go in fast, and finish them off.
- I can't.
- Sure you can.
They're all bullies. They work for
the guy you killed before.
It's easy. Just go in
and do your thing.
- No way. There's too many of them.
- Come on.
You want revenge, don't you?
Weren't you going to rid the world
of all the bullies?
Those guys extort money
from the poor.
They beat up on the weak
and pretend to own the world.
Vengeance is yours.
See the guy with the shaved head?
Doesn't he look like
that kid lmamura...
who bullied you back in high school?
And isn't the guy next to him
the spitting image of that kid Tokito
who scribbled all over
your textbooks?
Well, Ichi?
He does look like him.
You must take revenge.
Killing is bad.
I told you not to worry.
They're just a big bunch of bullies.
The people I just killed
were not the ones
who used to bully me.
They're bad people.
Of course they had to die.
How did it feel today?
I don't want to kill any more.
Don't be a fool.
If you don't kill the bad guys,
who will?
I don't want to kill.
You'll go on killing, won't you?
I don't want to any more.
Kill the bad guys.
Kill.
Thank you for protecting me
back there.
What's wrong?
Are you all right?
What's your name?
Ichi.
We're friends, aren't we?
Shit.
What the hell happened?
Chief, what happened?
He showed up, finally.
Isn't this amazing.
I'm scared.
Hey, all of you! Don't run away!
Everyone is bolting.
You're not running?
Not until we avenge the boss.
Well...
This is really something.
Look at this.
The human body is made out of a
single tube like this.
I'm sorry, chief.
They've all gone.
Don't bother.
Takayama, call the East Shinjuku
police station.
- You're reporting this?
- No, I'll get them to help us.
I was being bullied when this strong
guy turned up and kicked their asses.
Teach me, too.
- Go back home.
- I'll grow strong and get revenge.
Takeshi.
Takeshi!
I'm on a very important job now.
It may be that one day
I won't be able to come home.
If something should happen to me,
promise me you'll go and live
with your mum.
I won't.
Don't worry.
I can take care of myself.
Takeshi.
What's taking you so long?
Go and find Ichi.
I don't know what he looks like.
Find anyone who smells of blood.
Now go and get him!
What the fuck
do you think you're doing?
Got it?
First you puke all over
one of our girls
and then you say you've no money?
Who the fuck do you think you are?
Answer me, you bastard.
What's so funny?
Give us our money back right now.
Just sell off your kidneys.
As long as we get our money, asshole.
How much does he owe you?
Who the hell are you, anyway?
How much did he borrow?
500,000 yen.
- Who do you work for?
- None of your business.
Watch your mouth.
What are you looking at?
Hasn't he had enough?
In that case,
why don't you pay off his debts?
Watch out, or you'll get hurt.
- What gang are you with?
- The Anjo gang.
I don't know what backwater
you're from,
but you have "sitting duck"
written all over your forehead.
Aren't you Japanese?
Don't you understand
what I am saying?
Anyhow, get out of here.
Get a move on, I said.
Don't be shy. Eat up.
Boss Anjo, he's the cop
who lost his gun.
He became known as
an Olympic marksman.
You must be hungry.
Go ahead and eat.
Mom won't come back, will she?
She left you for another man.
But I'll always stay with you.
Stop jabbering and eat.
Where are you from? China?
This is no place for you.
You understand?
Don't be so jittery.
I'm not bullying you.
You remind me of myself
a long time ago.
The guy who picked me up
when I was down has been murdered.
He took me in when I drifted
with nowhere to go.
I must find his killers
and avenge him.
Eat up, or the noodles will go soft.
How are you feeling?
Where are we?
Seems you had bad dreams.
You'll find photos inside.
Taken of the biggest bullies.
The ones that bullied me?
Just like them.
They are even worse than the boys
who bullied you.
Those were not
the only bad people around.
The ones that stood by and did
nothing are even worse.
You must go after all of them.
That's why you grew strong, isn't it?
But...
Ms Tachibana tried to help me.
Back then you were too weak
to help her.
But now you are strong enough
to defeat all of them.
You can have your revenge.
Revenge...
You mean killing people?
Right.
I mean to kill.
- I don't want to kill any more.
- What?
I hate killing people.
Running away from things
will never make you a man!
My dick's hard.
- Since when?
- I don't know.
Why didn't you tell me?
lt'll start to rot.
That's what you get for not doing
what I tell you.
Take some tranquillizers.
They'll calm you down for a while.
What's wrong? Take the damn things.
I don't want to kill any more people.
We'll talk about that later.
Just take the damn pills.
No!
Ichi!
I've been a detective forever but
I've never seen anything like this.
Even you can't do that, brother.
I could, if I wanted to.
There's something inhuman
to this carnage.
Most people have a touch of both
sadism and masochism inside them
I can't wait to meet him.
But he'll come here anyway, won't he?
There's no pattern to it.
It's all just a game.
If I'm not ready to die
when he comes,
I'll become increasingly desperate.
But if I know he's coming,
I'll do all I can
to stop him from killing me.
So you will tell me where this Ichi
is even if you don't want to.
Do you have any clues?
Somebody I know stumbled upon
this Chinese pal of Ichi
who goes around pimping.
Find him
and you'll discover much more.
A Chinese pimp, huh?
I picked it up
from a girl in this club.
Well, big brother?
We can't turn down a request
from Kakihara, can we?
Without him we wouldn't even be
detectives. We owe him a lot.
We'll find that dickhead
soon enough.
There aren't so many
Chinese pimps around.
Hey, it's Kaneko.
Damned if it isn't. The cop
who got fired for losing his gun.
What are you doing here?
- I'm a gunman.
- You're kidding!
A guy loses his gun and next thing
you know, he becomes a gunman.
Are you? Really?
What are you waiting for?
Go find him.
I want to fuck, fuck, fuck.
No use.
Hello. Myu-Myu? It's me, Longie.
Can I come over right now?
Did you plant the information
about that girl?
I did.
Then it's only a matter of time...
before Long gets caught.
What happens next?
- Ichi is going through a bad patch.
- A bad patch?
He gets hard,
but he cannot ejaculate.
Really? That's weird.
Tell me, what is this Ichi like?
I can't tell you that.
Come on, tell me about him.
OK, if you insist.
- He's kind of cute.
- Your type?
Not especially.
- He is a crybaby.
- What's that?
He was bullied when he was a kid.
Even now, when he gets mad
he starts to cry.
At first he keeps it under control,
then suddenly he lashes out to kill.
So he's sick, isn't he?
Most of the time,
he's quite a nice young man.
But when he loses it,
he turns into a killer.
I sort of understand that.
But he was never really bullied,
you see.
After he killed his parents,
I messed around with his memory.
I made him believe
that he used to be bullied.
So now every time I need him
for a job, I feed him more stories.
And he believes all of that?
Does that post-hypnosis stuff
really work?
Yes, but I think I overdid it
on that rape story.
I told him he was bullied
in high school
and that the girl who stood by him
ended up getting raped.
That got him terribly excited.
Rape?
Yes, a story about a girl
who was raped.
Can I ask you something?
What?
Did you also put me under
some kind of hypnosis?
I wouldn't dare.
No!
Shut up!
I feel sorry for you, Kaneko.
First you lose your gun
and get kicked of the force.
Then you become a yakuza,
which is OK.
But now you have a killer
on your heels.
You're an unlucky monkey.
I have no regrets.
I've got lots of them.
The only reason I ended up in this
business is because I was tough.
Sometimes I look at those
salary slaves...
imagining I could have easily ended
up that way, living such a life.
What will you do
when all this is over?
I only want revenge for boss Anjo.
There will be no one left
to taste our revenge.
Think about your son.
He'll have to manage on his own.
I have only one thing on my mind.
I've never seen such a tough bitch.
Jiro, you've lost your touch.
She's just too tough.
Time for sleuthhound Saburo
to step into the ring.
That brings back memories.
- OK, I know where to find Long.
- I'm impressed.
Takayama, keep an eye on the girl.
Where are you going?
Did I tell you to come?
But...
I didn't ask you to come, did I?
Can't you sense my mood?
I'm sorry, Longie.
God, this is terrible.
Are you all right?
I'm so sorry, Longie.
You want some water?
I said, do you want some water?
Do you want some or not?
I'm so sorry, Longie.
Hey.
Say something!
Cut it out.
Cut it out!
How come Jijii doesn't answer?
Kakihara.
Good evening.
This one's for Inoue!
Put some feeling into it!
Giving pain is a serious business.
There's no love in your punches.
What's taking him so long?
What the fuck?
Sorry. I'm so sorry.
Are you all right?
Are you hurt?
Ichi?
Don't you remember me?
It's me, Tachibana.
Long time no see.
It's been a long time.
Yes, it has, Ms Tachibana.
Is it really you?
I told you so.
I'm sorry.
Then why didn't you
come to my rescue?
I'm sorry.
I wanted to die.
- Despair.
That's right, despair.
I like to be abused.
I met someone through the Internet
who said he was a sadist.
I was so disappointed.
Slice me up neatly.
Slice you up?
What? You have a hard-on, already?
You wanted me to rape you?
You really wanted me to rape you,
Ms Tachibana?
You wanted to be raped because
you didn't want to be raped.
You didn't want me to do it
because you wanted me to do it.
Of course.
Like Sailor didn't want me to do it
cos she wanted me to do it.
That's it, Ms Tachibana.
What's the matter?
I will slice you to pieces,
Ms Tachibana.
What?
I understand now.
You don't want this
because you want it.
Myu-Myu?
What happened? Why is she dead?
I guess he wanted to get something
from her
but just went a little too far.
That's right, isn't it, Kaneko?
Don't get in my way all the time.
I told you it wouldn't be pretty.
I'll ask you again. Where is Ichi?
I told you, I don't know.
Ichi is even more depraved
than you could ever imagine.
He's a monster who kills
without any feeling for his victims.
Is that so hard to understand?
Hello?
Do you think that what you're doing
will make everything inevitable?
No matter how hard you try,
it'll all be in vain, you asshole.
People like you who can only watch
know absolutely nothing.
I'm pulling the strings. Even yours.
I'm controlling everything.
Don't you feel it's all running
a bit too smoothly, you creep?
Your fate
is without a shred of meaning.
You'll be killed senselessly by Ichi.
No more, no less, asshole.
Your penalty for not knowing Ichi.
A split and pierced penis.
Great. Let's do it.
Takayama, get some scissors.
This'll put an end to your pimping.
No!
I'll try to remember about Ichi!
I'll be outside.
Call me when it's over.
Really?
You feel up to it again?
OK, come to the yakuza apartment.
There's lots of work to do.
I can't stand that stuff.
That bastard Jijii.
Where's Ichi?
Behind you.
Ichi has no time to be playing
with a dumb gorilla like you.
No! If you do that, I'll die.
What was that?
Takayama...
He's all broken up.
Hold it.
Don't. You'll never make it.
Hey!
Bastard.
This Ichi's a real monster.
Even big brother Jiro
couldn't do this.
Watch what you say.
I'm getting scared.
We'll go look for him, too.
You stay here.
It's you and me guarding the coop.
Do you think it's possible
to yank someone's arm off
with your bare hands?
I said, is it possible to yank
an arm off with your bare hands?
Of course not.
That's impossible.
I can't hear you.
- It's impossible.
- Really?
I'll have little Saburo
shaking in his boots.
Ready? I'm going to try now.
So you're back?
Where are the bullies, Jijii?
First, listen carefully.
That man who treated you
to a bowl of noodles -
he's your long, lost brother.
So the next time you see him,
make sure you pay him your respect.
My brother?
My big brother?
Damn, the whole world
looks down on me.
I can do it!
I'm sure I can kill Ichi. Ichi!
My brother.
Who's there?
Saburo, what kind of guy
is this Ichi?
- He must be some kind of monster.
- I'm scared.
Even the infamous Kakihara
is scared now?
No, I'm scared of myself.
All this anticipation.
It's been years since I felt such
a mix of anxiety and anticipation.
The few times I've felt this,
I was let down in the end.
I really want to lose myself
in desperation.
What if Ichi also lets me down?
What's the matter?
- It's Jiro. He's dead.
- Really?
It's exactly the same feeling
as when our big brother Ichiro died.
Are you sure? Then let's go back.
Kaneko. Ichi has arrived.
Damn.
I was looking forward to
killing Jiro myself one day.
That's interesting.
Oh, fuck!
The same as ever.
Takeshi.
He looks like that guy...
He's called Ichi.
- What did you say?
- Ichi.
He's the guy who used karate
to help me.
Damn! Damn!
Takeshi.
Don't move an inch.
Wait a minute.
You're scaring me. Wait.
You're so fucking scary!
You're coming at me again?
Ichi!
Hey.
What will you do now?
Don't let me down.
Why are you doing this to me,
brother?
Why?
Hey, wait a minute.
Tell me, brother.
Tell me.
Why?
Why, brother?
Stop right there!
Daddy.
Takeshi...
I'm sorry.
Your mind is in chaos.
You are truly demented.
Get up, Ichi.
Get up.
What's the matter with you?
Come on, damn it!
Do you hear me?
Get up.
Come on.
Stop fucking around.
What are you playing at?
How can we have our challenge match,
if you act this way?
Come on, Ichi.
Get up and fight. Come on.
You're so selfish.
What are you doing?
Damn...
Nobody left to kill me.
Wow, this is amazing!
Ichi!
Tadanobu Asano
Omori
Moro Morooka
Shinya Tsukamoto, Susumu Terajima,
Houka Kinoshita, Hiroshi Kobayashi
Maiko Shigofuki,
Shun Sugata, Toru Tezuka
Yoshiki Arizono, Kee, Satoshi Niizuma
Mari Murata, Masao Tomita
Hirotake Fukuzawa, Shuhei Kii
Yukari Shimada, Banshou Shinra
Isao Urano
Wood Office, Excellent Film
Hideo Yamamoto, Takashi Miike, 2001