FARSA PRODUCTIONS presents
Sir, We have a problem.
Be specific.
Do you remember project 395/027?
Are you talking about Mission Kaihoro?
No, sir.
This is worse, much worse.
I'll show you.
It's about the alien virus.
According to the contract...
The aliens were allowed
to test their virus...
...in a restricted area.
In exchange we would be
receiving protection. I know.
But... What's the real problem, agent?
They did the test, sir.
They were supposed to
use a radios of 1 km.
But the virus has spread.
Day 1, 0:.00 am
Day 1, 4:.42 am
Day 1, 8:.1 5 am
Day 1, 8:.36 am
The whole town is infected.
Day 1, 1 :1 0 pm
God Damn it, agent!
Something must be done!
That's not all, sir. We
caught some of the survivors.
A young man in a coma
called Max Giggs...
...another young man
called Bill Johnson,
John West...
...Tony Peck... -That's enough!
Let me explain something
that you should know by now.
Only our President...
...has the authority to order
the execution of that many people,
But the President...
...has more important
business to take care of.
So you give me no option.
Release the prisoners inside the town.
-But, sir...
-That's an order, agent.
-That's an order.
-Sir, they are dangerous!
-That's an order!
Sir, they must be
exterminated right now!
That's an order!!!!
Zombie Plague: Mutant Zone
Close the border, cut all
lines of communication...
...That town never existed.
Now what?
Hey, excuse me.
I'm gonna kill you!
Bill?
What's going on with you?
It's me John... your pal!
I saw you die.
Max!
Max are you okay! Max, talk to me!
My computer!
- God damn it!
My computer! My computer!
- How do you feel?!
Max.
- My computer!
I wanna go home.
Where am l?
Take me home.
- Bill.
John, Bill, Here I am!
Oh! Damn!
Gentlemen...
On the count of three...
Let's get out of here.
One...
Two...
John, help me!
Bill, what the hell are you thinking?
He might still be alive. Come on!
Max, Come on!
Take it easy, if we stand
still, they won't see us.
Zombies, I hate them!
Bill!
John! Max! Let's get out of here!
That way!
Damn! This is worse than I feared.
Yeah.
Well, now what?
Let's find some weapons.
John, we have two options.
Wait a second, Bill!
It's been thirty hours
since I last slept.
Can I at least go to the bathroom?
Max, help me! They're getting
in! They're getting in!
Max, help me!
Be careful! Let him go! Let him go!
The bag, Max! The bag!
Don't worry! Don't
worry! I'll stay here!
Jooooooohn!
Jesus! Max, what's going on here?
Bill told me to keep an eye on the bag.
Yes, but didn't you notice
that he was in trouble?
But Bill told me to
keep an eye on the bag.
You have an attitude problem, Max.
We'd better go and look for Bill.
Yes... if he's still alive.
What's matter with you?
Are you crazy or what?
You are sick, right? You're
sick. That's what's going on,
God damn it.
John, come and see this!
Oh my God! This is terrible!
Bill could end up in one of
those mountains of flesh....
...just for looking
after this goddamn bag.
The only thing I know is that
we must leave this town...
Right now.
Scott Lee Ray.
Easy! Easy, buddy!
- Help, me!
They left me, those fuckers
left the town without me.
what are you talking about?
A zombie bit me and they thought l
would infect them...
But these zombies are very
different from the others....
I'm getting out of here.
Don't do it, pal! The street is...
Unknown to us, I know.
Everything is infected.
Where are you planning to go?
Out of this town.
John, look at that zombie.
It's disgusting!
Horrendous!
You can handle it, right?
Sure.
Zombie... zombie...come here....
Max, no, no, Max, no, Max, nooooooo!
Come on.
Don't you get it, pal? This
is the end of the human race...
We're all gonna die...
When they come back, we'll die.
They're inside, getting ready for war...
And when they attack it'll be the end.
What are you talking
about? I'm out of here.
But I have a map...
City limits.
... a map showing the only
way out of this damn town!
But if you want it...
You'll have to work for me.
Get lost.
But this is the only way out!
Listen to me...
What?!
Damn! Now what?
Calm down, Max.
Calm down? Did you see what I saw?
Take it easy. Know what? We'll go
to the other side of town...
....and we'll look for a way out.
This reminds me of the
Variety Fair of 93'...
You were there? I was there
too! I was doing a show.
That was you?
I don't understand your language!
Hold it! Hold it! Hold it!
Slowly..., slowly...
Lollypop!
Max!
John!
Bill, we went to the city
limits..., It's terrible!
We got there and...
...suddenly there was
this... deep...Very deep...
I didn't know what to do...
It was far... impossible to cross and...
Terrible! Terrible! This is terrible!
Oh, Damn!
Look at this mess!
Wait here...the computer is upstairs..
Bill, come and see this.
It's not here. It's not here!!
O.K. ready.
Contents of drive A.
Reading...
MAP. FBl
Calculating decoding time.
I think this is going to take a while...
Too much.
That's not a problem, I can wait.
That's true... This
seems like a safe place.
Perfect! We'll have a guard
like when I was a boy scout!
Scotty!
Scott...
Buddy!
Scotty! Scott Lee Ray. Are you there?
Lieutenant, it's a lost
cause. He's probably dead...
...or became one of them...
Yes, yes, I'm listening.
Mother of God, Scott! W e're sorry,
we arrived at the base and we...
...noticed you weren't
with us. Are you O.K.?
Yes, I'm fine.
Alright, pal, tell us
your exact position.
We are at the house of Max Giggs'.
Roger that, Scott, stay there.
A helicopter will pick
you up in a few minutes.
Excellent, we'll wait.
Roger, over and out.
Damn it, John! What are you doing?
What am I doing? I've just saved
your life! You should thank me!
Damned fool! The FBl is
using us as guinea pigs...
They blew your head off!
Do you think they're
going to rescue you?
That's true.
We must leave this
place as son as possible.
Do you think this is gonna work?
DO NOT TOUCH! EXPLOSlVE!!!
Max.
They want to negotiate.
they want to negotiate.
Max, listen to yourself,
you are talking crazy.
They want to negotiate.
Don't you get it? Negotiate!
Max...
Enough.
Let's get out of here!
Move it!
Bill!
O.K. this is the plan:
we'll look for a car,
Max, you drive, and then...
Why?
Max, you drive.
But why?
Max, I can't drive.
Stop it!
Bill, are you O.K.?
I was just wondering......
Why?
Max, turn down the next street.
We're close to my house...
Once we get there, we can
wait without being in danger...
At least...
...until the map decoding is ready.
Come on in Max... Make yourself at
home.
Oh, no! My trophies!
They were here too.
John West loses everything.
Do you like it?
Unbelievable, right?
Go on Take a look.
Know what, Max?
I think this is the beginning
of a beautiful friendship.
My name is John West.
My arms are made out of
steel and my legs of titanium.
I was born to win... and
that's what I'm gonna do!
He comes from the west,
riding on his horse.
Friend of the kids, he's John West.
He's fair with the good guys,
and severe with the bad guys,
...stronger than a rock, he's John West.
My arms are made out of
steel and my legs of titanium.
He fights for good, he's John West.
Saving stagecoaches, girls in trouble...
strong as a rock, he's John West.
John West, John West. He is the best.
John West, John West. He's the champ!
A hero, a cowboy, he's John West...
John West, John West. He is the best.
John West, John West. He's the champ!
A hero, a cowboy, he's John West...
John West, John West. He is the best.
John West, John West. He's the champ!
A hero, a cowboy, he's John West...
John West, John West. He is the best.
John West, John West. He's the champ!
A hero, a cowboy, he's John West...
John West!
John, John!
Max! I would like to
introduce you to somebody...
Remember the bag? There
was someone inside!
Tell him, boy... tell him your name.
Max!
Look, John, I have...
You gotta remember this...
You gave it to me at the
Variety Fair back in 93'...
Where is it? Where did l
put it? You gotta remember...
You gave it to me at the
Variety Fair back in 93'...
Here it is! This is you...
And I have your autograph as well!
Boy... I think you need a
new one! Follow me upstairs,
I have something you're gonna like.
You're a lucky guy...
There aren't many of
those things in the world.
There's no food.
I'll order some pizzas.
Do you want some pepperoni
pizza, hot dogs or some steaks?
Steaks! Steaks!
Well... I think we'd
better go get some burgers.
Bill...You come with me...
Max...You stay and
take good care of Max.
He's a good guy...
They'll get along fine.
What does it feel
like to be one of them?
I saw you die, and now you
are walking by my side...
It seems to me you're
one of the living dead.
Bill...Are you still
going on about that?
OK. I'll tell you all
about it. Remember when...
Look Max! It's... it's
John! Do you like it?
Turn it around.
We're all there.
That's me...that's John...
And that... that's Bill...
And this... this... this is you!
It's you Max! It's you! It's you
Max! it's you! It's you! It's you!....
This is you!
Look, Max!
My name is... my arms... John
West, John West, He's the best,
John West, John West, He's the champ,
John West, John West, he's the best...
...a hero, a cowboy, he's John West,
John West, John West, He's the best...
John West, John West, He's the champ,
John West, John West, he's the best...
John West, John West, He's the best...
John West, John West, He's the champ,
John West, John West,
Look Max! I can't stop
dancing! I can't stop!
What's going on, Max?
What's going on? What's...
Tough on the bad guys... T ough on the
bad guys... Tough on the bad guys...
Max!
Tough on the bad guys... T ough on the
bad guys... Tough on the bad guys...
Max!
Tough on the bad guys... T ough on the
bad guys... Tough on the bad guys...
Max! Help me! Someone
cut the lights, damn it!
Take it easy! We only
have to find the switch...
Let me go! Let me go! No,
no not to the window!!!
Not to the window!!! No!!!
John! Help me...
John.
Are you okay?
Bill... Max didn't make it.
Damn it.
What about Max?
Neither.
Bill...
What's going on, agent?
They're still alive... perfect.
Bill?
Billy?
Billy, what's going on?
William Johnson, 23, medical student...
And here we have... Mr.
John West, 26, wrestler...
Two scumbags.
Now it's my turn. My name is James
Dominick Dana...35, federal agent.
A lovely wife, two kids,
expecting the next...
...a wonderful house in the
suburbs with a swimming pool...
And a salary of 1 20,000 dollars a year.
I could say my life was perfect...
Until you showed up!
I'll be more specific.
An agent called Scott Lee Ray...
...stole a map of the city. We know
you have some information about it...
I need that map! Do you understand?
And... what does this mean?
Do Not Touch! Explosive!
It's a bomb.
Don't you know Max Giggs?
20, mathematician...
Touch it and we'll all die.
What do you think, agent?
I don't know.
Listen, you morons! I don't care
about your lives, your bombs, nothing!
I just want the goddamn map...
It sounds like they're
trapped in here too...
Very clever...
Agent!
The map, now!
West, you know something, don't you?
Yep...
I broke the handcuffs.
Damn it!
That's impossible...
No...
My name is John West...
My arms are made of steel
and my legs of titanium...
I was born to win...
and that's what I'm gonna do.
Retreat! Retreat!
What the hell are you going to do to
me?
Now I'm the one who asks the
questions!
No.
What the hell is going on here?
Speak, you fool! Why do you want to
turn this town into a zombie town?
You'd never understand!
Why?!
And if you could it'd be the end!
What the hell are you talking about?
The answers will come. In its due time.
What??
The destiny of mankind is
not in our hands anymore!
DO NOT TOUCH! EXPLOSlVE!
Decoding ready in...
Decoding complete, please wait...
Insert disk 2.
Damn bastard! Give me the disk!
Give me the damn disk #2!
And now what?
I think this could be the end.
OK, we have two options...
Bill, there's no option this time.
What are you talking
about? Are you giving up?
No. They're too many!
Damn it John! We've been in
worse situations than this!
We've no weapons and
they far outnumber us...
What are you afraid of?
They're just zombies!
You know, Bill.
These zombies are not
as stupid as we thought.
Damn!
- John, listen to me...
Bring my computer! Bring my
computer!
Brother Zombies...
Welcome to my party!
Everything's as I expected...
- Max, Max!!
The last truck full of
humans has arrived...
And that's why I am gathering
all the zombies from town...
to decide the destiny of our community.
Today at sunset...
...we'll end the negotiations...
...and I'll get you
out of this damn town!
Of course I'll leave too,
because I deserve to...
Max!
Bill?
But my main goal is to set you free!
Anyway, It's not going to be easy,
but everything's going to be fine.
The only things you have to
do is trust me and follow me!
We will leave in groups...
Zombies first... women
and children, later!
We'll get together at 1 800 hours
at the agreed meeting point...
You can bring your
friends, if you want...
Yes.
But be careful! Because
I once had a friend
and he betrayed me!
His name was John West...
He was tall...fat...
and he looked like a stupid cowboy!
Damn bastard...
If I find him... I'll destroy him...
after cutting him into little pieces...
and then I'll make him into minced
meat!
I can assure you it will be
very... very unpleasant...
The reunion.
The time... has come...
...and...
Kill them!
Now, rebels!
Kowalski... Anderson...
Plissken... Vega...
Attack!
I'll kill you all!
You wanted to escape, huh?
You wanted to escape!
But nobody escapes from me...
Because I'm John West,
got it? I'm John West!
You're not John West
anymore! You are a looser!
You've lost everything! You're a nobody.
Don't you see? You've been
living in the past for years!
No! I am John West!
No, no you are not John West.
Yes! I'm John West!
- No! You are not!
I'm John West! I'm John West!
- You're not, you're not... you are not...
I Am John West! I'm world champion!
- You're not, you're not, you're not!
I'm... I'm...I'm John W est!
- No, you are not John West.
No, no, no....
What the hell is going on here?
Distribute the knives!
John... John, stop it!
No.
John, stop it!
Damn it, stop it!
Stop it!
Stop it, John! Stop it! No, no! Stop it!
You wanna fly, Max?
Max.
Well, I'll make you fly then!
Yes, I'll fly! I'll fly
and I'll leave this town!
And once I've done it,
I'll destroy the map!
Max, do you have disk #2?
And then I'll be president...
Max, listen to me! Do you have disk #2?
And then I'll pass a law to destroy
all the cowboys and wrestlers!
John, please, stop!
And I'll also destroy...
Don't you dare get in the
way of John West again!
Leave Max alone, John.
Bill, don't you see? He's a murderer!
No!
I don't know what the
hell has happened...
but I do know that he can
get us out of this place!
Bullshit! That's bullshit, Bill!
Don't you listen to him, got it?
John... God Damn it! Let me go...
Tighter! Tighter!
Damn it, John...
Get your hands off me, you dirty ape!
Tighter!
Max, shut up!
But, John...
- Shut up!
Bill...you have to understand...
Behind you!
Easy, Max, It's over...
It's all over now, buddy.
We'll leave this town...
and everything will go
back to normal again.
Bill, listen to me...
-You shut up you!
Don't you realize what you've done?!
Max, you do have disk #2, don't you?
Easy, pal...
everything's going to be normal again...
You just have to give me the map, Max.
Max, give me the map.
No, No, no, no! That's the only
thing you care about, right?
The damn disk #2!
Max, take it easy!
Let me tell you one thing, Bill...
Nothing's going to be like it was before!
Everything's like this because of
you! You wanted to keep the damn bag!
What for? We could
barely save ourselves,
but you wanted to keep the bag!
Max, shut up!
- And... who put you in charge?
Because I didn't... Did you, John?
You are always telling everybody
what to do... "This way!" "That way!"
Shut up!
-... "Let's find some weapons!"
"Give me the bag! "
"The bag! The bag!"
No, No.
No. John! John,
say something!
Yes... I will say something....
"This way! That way! This way!"
Know what, Bill?
"The bag! The bag!"
All this has gone too far...
I don't know who's
responsible for all this...
but I do know that whatever
is happening down there...
is worse than anything...
It's pure evil...
And if we want to stay alive,
we have to work together...
so we can get the hell out of here.
Because we are stronger,
we can fight them.
We have to show those
damn zombies what we can do.
I want to find the person responsible
for all this, dead or alive...
I want infinite justice, so we
can achieve enduring freedom...
This is not a war
between us, my friends...
This is a war against terror...
This is strike against terror!
This is only the humble opinion...
of a simple cowboy...
who once entertained children...
and who is now merely
trying... to save the world.
Alright, John...
I forgive you for not saving me
while the zombies ripped off my arm.
I didn't save you
because you killed Max!
You didn't save him?
- No, he didn't! He didn't!
Shut up!
...the whole town is infected...
Oh, Damn!
...release the survivors...
...slowly...
...Iook at this mess...
...they were here, too...
...now rebels!...
...Iet's find some weapons...
...I don't understand your language...
...they want to negotiate...
...today at sunset...
...Iisten to yourself,
you're talking crazy...
...we'll end the negotiations...
...they want to negotiate,
got it? Negotiate...
...and I'll get you out
of this damn town....
...when they come back, we'll die...
...now I'm the one...
Who's asking the questions.
....they are inside...
...what the hell is going on here?
It's about the alien virus...
...and when they attack
it'll be the end...
Why?
What are you saying?
They are inside...
...Iollypop...
...distribute the knives...
...Iollypop... distribute the knives...
...Iollypop......Iollypop......Iollypop...
John...
I think it's time for you to tell me...
...how come you're still
alive... when I saw you die?
Bill, it's a long story.
Come on, John, tell me. I'm all ears.
Okay Bill, I'll tell you.
It all started when...
And now what?
We could run away,
search for a safe place...
but there's no point.
What's going on, Bill?
What's happening?
This is the end of the human race, John.
We have to do something!
I think it'd be better...
to sit here... and wait.
Alright...
Iet's do it.
On the count of three...
Let's get out of here!
One...
Two...
FlVE YEARS LATER
CONTRACT
You know what? This is the
return I was waiting for...
And it's all thanks to you...